<bill session="113" type="s" number="2268" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-04-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-04-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Border Health Security Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish grant programs to improve the health of border area residents and for all hazards preparedness in the border area including bioterrorism, infectious disease, and noncommunicable emerging threats, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400413"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2014-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412281" joined="2014-04-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="5221"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Chemical and biological weapons"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Dental care"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Sex and reproductive health"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/29/2014--Introduced.
Border Health Security Act of 2013 - Amends the United States-Mexico Border Health Commission Act to: (1) revise the duties of the United States-Mexico Border Health Commission to include cooperating with the Canada-United States Pan Border Public Health Preparedness Council and serving as an independent and objective body to recommend and implement initiatives that solve border health issues, and (2) authorize appropriations.

Designates the Commissioner of the U.S. section of the Commission as the Chair (currently, leader) of the section. Authorizes members of the Commission and the Council to provide advice or recommendations to the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), Congress, or any Member of Congress concerning issues that are considered by the Commission or Council.

Requires the Secretary to award grants: (1) to eligible entities to improve the health of individuals residing in the U.S.-Mexico and U.S.-Canada border areas, and (2) for Early Warning Infectious Disease Surveillance to eligible entities for infection disease surveillance activities in such areas.

Requires the Commission and the Council to each: (1) prepare (every five years) a binational strategic plan to guide its operation, (2) develop and approve (every two years) an operational work plan and budget based on the strategic plan, and (3) issue a biannual report to the Secretary that provides independent policy recommendations related to border health issues.

Requires the Comptroller General (GAO) (every two years) to conduct an evaluation of Commission and Counsel activities.

Requires plans, systems, and activities supported under such Act for all hazard preparedness, and general border health, to be coordinated with authorities in Mexico, Canada, and the United States to the extent practicable.

Authorizes the Assistant Secretary for Preparedness and Response to coordinate with the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) in establishing a health alert system that: (1) alerts clinicians and public health officials of emerging disease clusters and syndromes along the U.S.-Mexico and U.S.-Canada border areas; and (2) warns of health threats, extreme weather conditions, disasters of mass scale, bioterrorism, and other emerging threats along such areas.</summary>
</bill>
