<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="H228746C4771A4F54AE2209726D9E0529" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Enrolled-Bill" resolution-type="house-concurrent" star-print="no-star-print" key="H" stage-count="1" public-print="no"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title> HCON 15 ENR: Providing for a conditional adjournment of the House of Representatives and a conditional recess or adjournment of the Senate.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2013-02-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form display="yes">
<distribution-code display="no">IV</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">One Hundred Thirteenth Congress of the United States of America</congress> 
<session display="yes">At the First Session</session><enrolled-dateline display="yes">Begun and held at the City of Washington on Thursday, the third day of January, two thousand and thirteen</enrolled-dateline> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. CON. RES. 15</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no"/> 
<action display="yes"> 
<action-date date="20130215" display="yes">February 15, 2013</action-date> 
<action-desc blank-lines-after="0" display="yes">Agreed to</action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type display="yes">CONCURRENT RESOLUTION</legis-type> 
<official-title display="no">Providing for a conditional adjournment of the House of Representatives and a conditional recess or adjournment of the Senate.</official-title> 
</form> 
<resolution-body style="traditional" id="HAD573D384DA7434ABDFBD269E5831782" display-resolving-clause="yes-display-resolving-clause"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HA880129D1A9E477AAC46F4D6796B07FB" commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That when the House adjourns on any legislative day from Friday, February 15, 2013, through Thursday, February 21, 2013, on a motion offered pursuant to this concurrent resolution by its Majority Leader or his designee, it stand adjourned until 2 p.m. on Monday, February 25, 2013, or until the time of any reassembly pursuant to section 2 of this concurrent resolution, whichever occurs first; and that when the Senate recesses or adjourns on Friday, February 15, 2013, on a motion offered pursuant to this concurrent resolution by its Majority Leader or his designee, it stand recessed or adjourned until noon on Monday, February 25, 2013, or such other time on that day as may be specified in the motion to recess or adjourn, or until the time of any reassembly pursuant to section 2 of this concurrent resolution, whichever occurs first. </text></section> <section id="H650066827ADF43A7B8445CA6A33BEBBC" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Speaker of the House and the Majority Leader of the Senate, or their respective designees, acting jointly after consultation with the Minority Leader of the House and the Minority Leader of the Senate, shall notify the Members of the House and the Senate, respectively, to reassemble at such place and time as they may designate if, in their opinion, the public interest shall warrant it. </text></section> 
</resolution-body> 
<attestation><attestation-group><role>Clerk of the House of Representatives.</role></attestation-group><attestation-group><role>Secretary of the Senate.</role></attestation-group></attestation> 
</resolution>
