<bill session="113" type="s" number="2289" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-05-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Defense Base Closure and Realignment Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Department of Defense Cooperative Threat Reduction Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize appropriations for fiscal year 2015 for military activities of the Department of Defense and for military construction, to prescribe military personnel strengths for such fiscal year, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300066"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2014-05-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2649"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4435"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4730"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/5/2014--Introduced.
National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2015 - Authorizes FY2015 appropriations for military activities of the Department of Defense (DOD) and for military construction. Authorizes military personnel strengths for FY2015.

Authorizes FY2015 appropriations to DOD for:

 procurement, including aircraft, missiles, weapons and tracked combat vehicles, ammunition, shipbuilding and conversion, the Joint Improvised Explosive Device Defeat Fund, and other procurement; research, development, test, and evaluation; operation and maintenance; military personnel; working capital funds; the Joint Urgent Operational Needs Fund; chemical agents and munitions destruction; drug interdiction and counter-drug activities; the Office of the Inspector General; and&#160;&#160;&#160; the Defense Health Program. Sets forth provisions or requirements concerning:

 end strengths for active and reserve forces; military personnel policy, including education and training, sexual assault prevention and response, and military justice and legal matters; military pay and allowances; military health care; acquisition policy and management; DOD organization and management; financial matters; counter-drug and counterterrorism activities; civilian personnel matters; matters relating to foreign nations; cooperative threat reduction; and military construction and military family housing. Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2015 - Authorizes appropriations for FY2015 for military construction for the Armed Forces and defense agencies, including the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) Security Investment Program and base realignment and closure (BRAC) activities.</summary>
</bill>
