<bill session="113" type="h" number="5540" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">America Realizing the Informational Skills and Initiative of New Graduates Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">America RISING Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a grant program for stipends to assist in the cost of compensation paid by employers to certain recent college graduates and to provide funding for their further education in subjects relating to mathematics, science, engineering, and technology.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400199"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412571" joined="2014-09-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Training" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/18/2014--Introduced.
America Realizing the Informational Skills and Initiative of New Graduates Act of 2014 or the America RISING Act of 2014 - Directs the Secretary of Labor and the Secretary of Education to jointly establish a program providing grants to:

 eligible employers to defray the cost of compensation they pay to recent graduates from institutions of higher education (IHEs); and such graduates to enable them to defray the cost of undertaking further postsecondary education at an IHE for up to 24 months in subjects relating to mathematics, science, engineering, or technology. Defines an "eligible employer" as a small business concern or a major corporation that has an operation located in an enterprise zone or in an area in which the unemployment rate exceeds the national average unemployment rate by more than 2%.

Allows college graduates who are participating in the program, either as grantees or beneficiaries of grants to their employers, to defer payment on their federal student loans under title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 until their participation in the program ends.

Requires graduates who are awarded a program grant to be eligible to receive federal student aid under title IV without regard to whether they have been or are delinquent on title IV loans.</summary>
</bill>
