<bill session="113" type="s" number="2694" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ensuring Access to Primary Care for Women &amp; Children Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to extend the application of the Medicare payment rate floor to primary care services furnished under Medicaid and to apply the rate floor to additional providers of primary care services.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400050"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400013" joined="2014-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2014-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2014-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412281" joined="2014-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412200" joined="2014-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2014-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2014-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2014-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412194" joined="2014-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2014-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2014-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2014-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412507" joined="2014-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2014-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2014-11-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="5723"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/2014--Introduced.
Ensuring Access to Primary Care for Women and Children Act - Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to require that the primary care services furnished in 2015 and 2016 by a physician with a primary specialty designation of family medicine, general internal medicine, or pediatric medicine be paid at a rate that is not less than 100% of the payment rate that applies to such services and physician under Medicare part B (Supplementary Medical Insurance).

Extends this 100% of Medicare payment floor under certain conditions to the following providers, who are self-attested as Board-certified and at least 60% of whose services billed for under Medicaid must be for primary care services: (1) physicians with a primary specialty designation of obstetrics and gynecology; (2) advanced practice clinicians; (3) rural health clinics, federally-qualified health centers, or other specified health clinics; and (4) nurse practitioners, physician assistants, or certified nurse-midwives.

Excludes from coverage of primary care services any such services provided in an emergency department of a hospital.</summary>
</bill>
