<bill session="113" type="s" number="2326" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-05-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nuclear Plant Decommissioning Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 to provide for consultation with State and local governments, the consideration of State and local concerns, and the approval of post-shutdown decommissioning activities reports by the Nuclear Regulatory Commission.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400357"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2014-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2014-05-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="4667"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC)"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes and releases"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/13/2014--Introduced.
Nuclear Plant Decommissioning Act of 2014 - Amends the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 to require a Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) licensee, after consulting each affected state and local governments, to develop and submit to the NRC a post-shutdown decommissioning activities report (PSDAR) for any of the licensee's shutdown facilities for which a PSDAR is required.

Requires the NRC to: (1) solicit written comments on the proposed PSDAR from the public and conduct at least two public hearings in the facility's host state; and (2) invite the host state to file a statement of support, of conditional support with specific recommendations for changes, or of nonsupport for the proposed PSDAR.

Directs the NRC, after receiving the state's statement of support or nonsupport, to determine whether the proposed PSDAR is adequate or inadequate on the basis of specified considerations, and issue a decision of approval or disapproval, as appropriate.

Prescribes requirements for determining whether a proposed PSDAR is permissible if the host state files a statement of conditional support.

Requires a licensee to develop and submit a new proposed PSDAR if the first one is rejected.

Prohibits the NRC from approving a proposed PSDAR unless it includes a requirement that the licensee comply with state law relating to air, water, or soil quality or radiological standards if they are more restrictive than federal law.</summary>
</bill>
