<bill session="113" type="h" number="4692" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Coastal Communities Ocean Acidification Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, to conduct coastal community vulnerability assessments related to ocean acidification, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412307"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY18" subcommittee="Environment" name="House Science, Space, and Technology"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Social sciences and history"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/20/2014--Introduced.
Coastal Communities Ocean Acidification Act of 2014 - Amends the Federal Ocean Acidification Research And Monitoring Act of 2009 to expand the ocean acidification program within the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) to include an ongoing mechanism that allows affected industry members, coastal stakeholders, non-federal resource managers, and outside scientific experts to provide input on research, data, and monitoring needs that are necessary to support on-the-ground management, decisionmaking, and adaptation related to ocean acidification and its impacts.

Directs the Secretary of Commerce, acting through NOAA, to conduct and update at least once every five years an ocean acidification coastal community vulnerability assessment with a corresponding public report. Requires such assessment to identify: (1) U.S. coastal communities, including island communities, low-population rural communities, and subsistence communities, that are most dependent on coastal and ocean resources that may be impacted by ocean acidification; (2) the nature of those communities' social and economic vulnerabilities; (3) impacts from changes in ocean and coastal marine resources that are not managed by the federal government; and (4) key knowledge gaps where research could be devoted to better understand the possible ocean acidification impacts, risks, threats, and possible adaptation strategies for such vulnerable communities.

Requires the strategic plan for federal research and monitoring on ocean acidification developed by the Joint Subcommittee on Ocean Science and Technology of the National Science and Technology Council to make recommendations for research that should be conducted, including in the social sciences and economics, to address the key knowledge gaps identified in the community vulnerability assessment report.</summary>
</bill>
