<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H7270ACFEF09D4E1D8CB3714E3F6B9B0A" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HR 5805 IH: Andrea Sloan CURE Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2014-12-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 5805</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20141208">December 8, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act with respect to expanding access for breakthrough
			 drugs, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HC04E52FE190A40F19CD97F9E0A4387C1" style="OLC">
		<section id="H039928F01FE84C24B4F82AD7DDC75E9F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Andrea Sloan Compassionate Use Reform and Enhancement Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote>Andrea Sloan CURE Act</quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="HE73C163BA3A8496EA6E7D64C2D901E90"><enum>2.</enum><header>Expanded access policy as condition of expedited approval</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 561 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360bbb">21 U.S.C. 360bbb</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
			<paragraph id="H10446810358F427BB7FA40AD97854C11"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (d) and (e) as subsections (e) and (f), respectively; and</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H4F6853B4A55646D6915F2DC7BD94F920"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (c) the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H44BFFAD4D3404CD488C0032BE58FFDFF" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H2D9F9B8006A049568047A82B76B432E0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Expanded access policy required for covered breakthrough drugs</header>
						<paragraph id="H589AF154BBA74388BCE16D565F6BE974"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to a qualified breakthrough drug, not later than 30 days after the date on which the
			 drug meets the definition of a covered breakthrough drug (as specified in
			 paragraph (2)), the sponsor of the covered breakthrough drug shall submit
			 to the Secretary and make publicly available the policy of the sponsor
			 with respect to requests submitted under subsection (b). In the case of
			 such a policy under which the sponsor accepts such requests, such policy
			 shall include—</text>
							<subparagraph id="H7FDCFCC2D13249759D93F4BEAC017754"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a single point of contact who receives and processes such requests;</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFDEA7578EB244A78BE05C084385FC281"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">procedures for making such requests;</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF468D28C6BA64B528446126053F37214"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the minimum criteria for the sponsor’s consideration or approval of such requests; and</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H63B8712738264051B5B3EDCC2ADEAACC"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount of time the sponsor anticipates will be necessary to make a decision on such requests.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB1693DCD6899421DBAC053A1544634F9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered breakthrough drug</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>covered breakthrough drug</term> means a drug—</text>
							<subparagraph id="H2CA431E0128E48F88A24C71B9D4525FD"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that is designated as a breakthrough therapy or as a fast track product or is approved under
			 accelerated approval under section 506;</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB14B22670B23467DAEC8C8C9D0F8B490"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that is designated under section 505E(d) as a qualified infectious disease product; or</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC4A57602E1DE49048F278B18786D1C6C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the sponsor of which is awarded a priority review voucher under section 524 or 529.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H357BDA3AB04544B6B4B58F772B1366C7"><enum>3.</enum><header>Notification of submitters of compassionate use requests</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 561 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360bbb">21 U.S.C. 360bbb</external-xref>), as amended by section
			 2, is further amended—</text>
			<paragraph id="H6939874A7DBE42E5ACC4E8765354B80B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (e) and (f) (as redesignated by section 2(1)) as subsections (f) and
			 (g), respectively; and</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HC8337298FAB146ACA7CA082A43FAF70C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (d) (as inserted by section 2(2)) the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HECAA81D2488546339D40246C5341BD85" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H4D984BE1DCC14405B4C1FA4E8D3A8DEF"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Notification of submitters of requests</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of the denial by a manufacturer or distributor of a request under subsection (b), not
			 later than 5 days after the date of such denial, the manufacturer or
			 distributor, as applicable, shall submit to the person (or physician) who
			 made the request written notice of the denial, including an explanation
			 for the denial.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H4C53F6B2918941FA894EF8A517528DDB"><enum>4.</enum><header>GAO qualitative analysis on individual patient access to unapproved therapies and diagnostics</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act and each year thereafter, the
			 Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committee on
			 Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on
			 Health, Education, Labor and Pensions of the Senate a report containing a
			 qualitative analysis of the extent to which individual patients have
			 access to investigational drugs pursuant to subsection (b) of section 561
			 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360bbb">21 U.S.C. 360bbb</external-xref>) and
			 recommendations for improving such access. In preparing such report, the
			 Comptroller General shall conduct a qualitative analysis of the following:</text>
			<paragraph id="H3EF996F7AD5F471AAA0D5412BA737781"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether there are any identifiable patterns in requests submitted under subsection (b) of such
			 section, such as the types of indications for which requests for
			 individual patient access are sought or the reasons for the denial of such
			 requests.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H973DAC138CAA452D9016AE118C46D818"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">What the primary barriers are to drug sponsors granting requests for individual patient access.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HD6BD9E2DC84144FF9486C867EAD4E894"><enum>(3)</enum><text>How the Secretary evaluates safety and efficacy data submitted in connection with such requests.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H386D564BA4EC43F7A398FFB4CE6FDC60"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The amount of time that—</text>
				<subparagraph id="HCBED7560B65D43D5ABF2A5AA5157F0C2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a physician typically takes to complete the paperwork necessary to make such a request;</text>
				</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8D4504FE12384881B8677E0B4E3DF1B9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a drug sponsor takes to process such a request and to issue a decision with respect to the request;
			 and</text>
				</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8084BDCF94C847298EE9084439065F69"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Secretary takes to process such a request and to issue a decision with respect to the request.</text>
				</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDEFAF21B920D4F7FBDDC5BEF5F606889"><enum>(5)</enum><text>How regulations, guidance, policies, or practices may be modified, streamlined, expanded, or
			 discontinued to reduce or prevent delays in approving such requests.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H3EC79BC11141491F9DE005898BBA5AA7"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The number of such requests that, for the period covered by the report—</text>
				<subparagraph id="H243E034EB60540D1AC06075EBE2481FD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>were approved by drug sponsors and the Food and Drug Administration;</text>
				</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H23E227CDC87C43E19964ADD3A7E3351D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">were approved by drug sponsors but denied by the Food and Drug Administration; and</text>
				</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC5567C9B5B1741CDAA1D212897591188"><enum>(C)</enum><text>were denied by drug sponsors.</text>
				</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBA0EF9A8BCDA4B4C9879D2EFD15DB58F"><enum>(7)</enum><text>How to encourage drug sponsors to grant requests for expanded access under such section 561,
			 including requests for emergency use, intermediate-size patient
			 populations, and large patient populations under a specified indication.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H86A6BA85D7084E1D96B28CC826BC0BAD"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Whether and to what extent adverse events reported to the Secretary as a result of individual use
			 of an investigational drug or investigational device under such section
			 561 affected the development or approval of any drug or device.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H2ACA0B9BAF384374AFE218409D3F562D"><enum>5.</enum><header>Expanded access task force</header>
			<subsection id="H2B10AFABAAEA4052B89EF76463E6C034"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><italic></italic>The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall establish a task force within the Department of
			 Health and Human Services to explore mechanisms for improving the access
			 individual patients have to investigational drugs pursuant to subsection
			 (b) of section 561 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (21 U.S.C.
			 360bbb), to be known as the <quote>Expanded Access Task Force</quote> (in this section referred to as the <quote>Task Force</quote>). Not later than 90 days after the date on which the Comptroller General of the United States
			 submits the first report required under section 4, the Task Force shall be
			 convened.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H21B6CC7EA1AA47068BD937205E097627"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header>
				<paragraph id="HEB65C58532514181A633104B07D3F94E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Composition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Task Force shall be composed of not more than 9 voting members appointed as follows:</text>
					<subparagraph id="H6360113BA1BD44178B303C16C304A532"><enum>(A)</enum><text>One member to serve as Chairman of the Task Force, appointed by the Speaker of the House of
			 Representatives.</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A9FB0596A58409DA00CFBFAE735EF10"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">One representative from the Department of Health and Human Services, appointed by the Secretary of
			 Health and Human Services.</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H015A4C6984EF44D79438D5915DBB2D81"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Four representatives appointed by the Majority Leader of the House of Representatives, in
			 consultation with the Minority Leader of the House of Representatives, and
			 the Chairman and the Ranking Member of the Committee on Energy and
			 Commerce of the House of Representatives, including—</text>
						<clause id="HE180292012A34FEB9E5F15A121D3B555"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">one representative of a biopharmaceutical company of less than 250 full-time employees;</text>
						</clause><clause id="HD2CB7020BC344A44B3D25F0F0B6107D5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>one representative of the rare disease patient community;</text>
						</clause><clause id="H0AD2FC3F9C724E99A2AA61E723753AE8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>one representative of the health care provider community; and</text>
						</clause><clause id="H7EF5731109264C0D9EB0A2824E9EE71D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>one bioethicist.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB21E9F8EDF1D4E348FEFDFED549BCCD9"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Three representatives appointed by Majority Leader of the Senate, in consultation with the Minority
			 Leader of the Senate, and the Chairman and the Ranking Member of the
			 Health, Education, Labor and Pensions Committee of the Senate, including—</text>
						<clause id="H245C54100EF949B6ABD113DB5E7B2F42"><enum>(i)</enum><text>one representative of the biopharmaceutical industry;</text>
						</clause><clause id="HCA06E7CC533E450195B0C037B9282784"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>one representative of the patient community; and</text>
						</clause><clause id="H3B66041B353D43B9BC92726C576AF49F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>one representative of the health care payor community.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H555759552DD549BF8AEDAE3196CBA42B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text>Members of the Task Force shall serve without compensation.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H30D6A88C6F1F49F19AE16E45FD5CC326"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Task Force shall comprehensively evaluate the access individual patients have to
			 investigational drugs pursuant to subsection (b) of section 561 of the
			 Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360bbb">21 U.S.C. 360bbb</external-xref>), taking into
			 account—</text>
				<paragraph id="H41942AC3581742FCAD71B2495897B247"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the unique challenges faced by children with likely fatal diseases for which there is not a
			 comparable or satisfactory alternative therapy available;</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H3B46C6C465CF45EA99B15F4F6FEA907F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>possible incentives for biopharmaceutical companies and providers to approve requests submitted
			 under such subsection;</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H3847C139BE9B4158AD3C8A6B1DE809E7"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how the Secretary of Health and Human Services interprets and takes into consideration adverse
			 event data reported in the case of data from use under a request submitted
			 under such subsection;</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HAA83E96CF1FE44A58A133D73AC6C760C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>ways to streamline and standardize the process for submitting requests under such subsection; and</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H36CA9C8E91104E43A168D10BA4EE83EF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the costs incurred by biopharmaceutical companies for the time, effort, and delivery of
			 investigational drugs to patients for the diagnosis, monitoring, or
			 treatment of a serious disease or condition under such subsection.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE1DB8F8371F446C6BA773C1C7AB6FEF4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date on which the Task Force is convened, the Task Force shall
			 submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of
			 Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor and Pensions
			 of the Senate a report in an electronic format describing the specific
			 recommendations of the Task Force for improving the access individual
			 patients have to investigational drugs pursuant to subsection (b) of
			 section 561 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (21 U.S.C.
			 360bbb).</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HFFDE0D5B8D7A4D73B0616335429865F6"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The task force shall terminate upon submission of the report required under subsection (d).</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HBDC5E40B9AD0401A86C6027EC130A146"><enum>6.</enum><header>Finalizing draft guidance on expanded access</header>
			<subsection id="H39648645B9FA4677B900DA9060367018"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date on which the Expanded Access Task Force established under
			 section 5 submits the report under subsection (d) of such section, the
			 Secretary of Health and Human Services shall finalize the draft guidance
			 entitled <quote>Expanded Access to Investigational Drugs for Treatment Use—Qs &amp; As</quote> and dated May 2013.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HA619440679EC48609B462B1E3DDFEF8F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The final guidance referred to in subsection (a) shall—</text>
				<paragraph id="HDBF4D6C15E5A4DEB947D5DC07DD2D24D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>clearly define how the Secretary interprets and uses adverse drug event data reported by
			 investigators in the case of data reported from use under a request
			 submitted under section 561(b) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act
			 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360bbb">21 U.S.C. 360bbb(b)</external-xref>); and</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H985407DD91C748BCB6DB5A75EA6B24D8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>take into account the report of the Expanded Access Task Force submitted under section 5(d) and the
			 first report of the Comptroller General of the United States submitted
			 under section 4.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


