<bill session="113" type="s" number="1550" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-09-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-09-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-09-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Battlefield Excellence through Superior Training Practices Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">BEST Practices Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 10, United States Code, to require the Secretary of Defense to use only human-based methods for training members of the Armed Forces in the treatment of severe combat injuries.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300100"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-09-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3172"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Animal protection and human-animal relationships"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/25/2013--Introduced.
Battlefield Excellence through Superior Training Practices Act or the BEST Practices Act - Requires the Secretary of Defense (DOD), no later than: (1) October 1, 2016, to develop, test, and validate human-based training methods for training members of the Armed Forces in the treatment of combat trauma injuries, with the goal of replacing live animal-based training methods; and (2) October 1, 2018, to use only use human-based training methods for such purposes. Prohibits the use of animals in such training after the latter date. Provides an exception when the Secretary determines that human-based training methods will not provide an educationally equivalent or superior substitute for live animal-based training methods.

Requires an annual report from the Secretary to the congressional defense committees on the development and implementation of the human-based training methods, as well as any exceptions implemented.</summary>
</bill>
