<bill session="113" type="s" number="1699" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-11-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-11-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-11-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Continuous Coverage Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to permit individuals to renew certain health insurance coverage offered in the individual or small group markets and to provide that such individuals would not be subject to the individual mandate penalty.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400412"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2013-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2013-11-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-11-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/13/2013--Introduced.
Continuous Coverage Act - Provides that, notwithstanding any provision of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (PPACA) or the Health Care and Education Reconciliation Act of 2010:

 a health insurance issuer shall offer an individual the opportunity to renew enrollment in coverage offered in the individual market if the individual was enrolled in such coverage on September 30, 2013, and continues to meet the requirements of eligibility for such coverage; an individual may renew enrollment in such coverage for plan years through December 31, 2015; the coverage shall not be required to meet PPACA essential health benefits requirements; and the coverage shall be deemed to meet the Internal Revenue Code minimum essential coverage requirement (thus not subjecting the taxpayer to a penalty).</summary>
</bill>
