<bill session="113" type="hr" number="654" updated="2015-09-01T10:18:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Relating to the application of Article II, section 3, clause 5, of the Constitution of the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400196"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Rules, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-07">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-07">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU10" subcommittee="Constitution and Civil Justice" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hr" number="655"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hr" number="656"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional-executive branch relations"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/7/2014--Introduced.
Declares that the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) has failed to meet the specified requirement of the U.S. Constitution to take care that a law be faithfully executed, with respect to the departmental policy providing for the authorization, approval, renewal, modification, or extension of any experimental, pilot, or demonstration project under the Social Security Act (SSA) that waives compliance with a mandatory work requirement by eligible states and state plans for participation in block grants under SSA title IV part A (Temporary Assistance for Needy Families) (TANF).

Requires the House of Representatives to bring a civil action in the U.S. District Court for the District of Columbia for declaratory or injunctive relief to challenge the Secretary.</summary>
</bill>
