<bill session="113" type="h" number="5683" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-11-13">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-11-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-11-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ensuring Access to Justice for Claims Against the United States Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure appropriate judicial review of Federal Government actions by amending the prohibition on the exercise of jurisdiction by the United States Court of Federal Claims of certain claims pending in other courts.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412526"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412470" joined="2014-11-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-11-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-13">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-11-13" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-12-08T16:10:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 113-650.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-12-08T16:10:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="488">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 488.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2769"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction and venue"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/8/2014--Reported to House without amendment.
Ensuring Access to Justice for Claims Against the United States Act - Amends the federal judicial code with respect to the jurisdiction of federal courts over civil actions pending in, or on appeal from, the U.S. Court of Federal Claims (USCFC) when the plaintiff also has pending in another federal court a civil action that includes a claim against the United States (or an agency or officer of the United States) arising from the same set of operative facts.

 Requires the court presiding over the action that was filed later to stay the later action until the action that was filed first is no longer pending. (Currently, the USCFC is prohibited from having jurisdiction of any claim in which the plaintiff has pending in any other court any suit or process against the United States or any person who was acting or professing to act under the authority of the United States.)

Provides an exception to the requirement to stay the later action if: (1) the parties in each of the actions agree, or (2) the required stay is not in the interests of justice.</summary>
</bill>
