<bill session="113" type="s" number="51" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-02-06">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-02-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Fish and Wildlife Foundation Reauthorization Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">National Fish and Wildlife Foundation Reauthorization Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reauthorize and amend the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation Establishment Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300011"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300005" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="2013-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2013-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2013-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2013-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="2013-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2013-01-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-02-06" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-06-05">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported by Senator Boxer without amendment. With written report No. 113-183.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-06-05" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="413">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 413.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="263"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1660"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1996"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2363"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/5/2014--Reported to Senate without amendment.
National Fish and Wildlife Foundation Reauthorization Act of 2013 - Reauthorizes through FY2019 and revises the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation Establishment Act.

 Increases from 23 to 28 the number of directors appointed by the Secretary of the Interior to the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation's Board of Directors. Makes uniform the experience required of each such appointee. Requires the Foundation to have an Executive Director who is appointed by the Board and is knowledgeable and experienced in matters relating to fish and wildlife conservation.

Gives the Foundation the power to receive and administer restitution and community service payments, amounts for mitigation of impacts to natural resources, and other amounts arising from legal, regulatory, or administrative proceedings, as long as the funds are used for the conservation and management of fish, wildlife, plants, and other natural resources.

Repeals provisions authorizing the Foundation to establish a national whale conservation endowment fund.

Authorizes the Foundation to: (1) assess and collect fees for the management of amounts received from federal agencies; and (2) use such federal funds for matching contributions made by private persons, state and local agencies, and other entities (current law requires such use).

Authorizes the Foundation to perform functions that the National Park Foundation is authorized to conduct, unless exclusive authority is given to the National Park Foundation.</summary>
</bill>
