<bill session="113" type="s" number="1965" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-18">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-06-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-01-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the East Bench Irrigation District Water Contract Extension Act to permit the Secretary of the Interior to extend the contract for certain water services.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300005"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2014-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412602" joined="2014-06-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-01-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-27">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 113-284.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-06-18" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Landrieu without amendment. With written report No. 113-228.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-07-31" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="515">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 515.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG07" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="4508"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4508"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2014--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Amends the East Bench Irrigation District Water Contract Extension Act to permit the Secretary of the Interior to extend the contract for water services between the United States and the East Bench Irrigation District until the earlier of: (1) that date that is 10 years (currently, 4 years) after the date on which the contract would have expired if such Act had not been enacted, or (2) the date on which a new long-term contract is executed by the parties to the contract.</summary>
</bill>
