<bill session="113" type="h" number="4405" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-04-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-04-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preventing Gun Violence Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend chapter 44 of title 18, United States Code, to prohibit the possession of a firearm by a person who is adjudicated to have committed a violent juvenile act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400195"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/4/2014--Introduced.
Preventing Gun Violence Act - Amends the federal criminal code to prohibit the trafficking in or possession of a firearm by a person who has been adjudicated of committing a violent juvenile act.

Defines a "violent juvenile act" as: (1) an act by a person under the age of 18 that, if committed by an adult, would be punishable by a prison term exceeding one year and that either has, as an element, the use, attempted use, or threatened use of physical force against another person or involves, by its nature, a substantial risk that physical force against another person may be used; and (2) such an act that is committed by a person who has attained age 18 but not age 21 for which the person is tried as a juvenile or youthful offender under state law.</summary>
</bill>
