<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="Hc1aaeade-9ff2-499a-826c-df4e4d72efd4" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Reported-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HRES 266 RH: Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1947) to provide for the reform and continuation of agricultural and other programs of the Department of Agriculture through fiscal year 2018, and for other purposes; and providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1797) to amend title 18, United States Code, to protect pain-capable unborn children in the District of Columbia, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2013-06-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<calendar display="yes">House Calendar No. 33</calendar>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 266</legis-num>
		<associated-doc display="yes" role="report">[Report No.
		  113–114]</associated-doc>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF
		  REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20130617">June 17, 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc><cosponsor name-id="F000450">Ms. Foxx</cosponsor>, from
			 the <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</committee-name>,
			 reported the following resolution; which was referred to the House Calendar and
			 ordered to be printed</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Providing for consideration of the bill
		  (H.R. 1947) to provide for the reform and continuation of agricultural and
		  other programs of the Department of Agriculture through fiscal year 2018, and
		  for other purposes; and providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1797) to
		  amend title 18, United States Code, to protect pain-capable unborn children in
		  the District of Columbia, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<resolution-body id="H97b199f7-a9da-4a75-a6ed-f975b5c43e53" style="traditional">
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="Hafaaad9f-b7cb-4ac4-9f69-4895fadeeb12" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That at any time after the adoption
			 of this resolution the Speaker may, pursuant to clause 2(b) of rule XVIII,
			 declare the House resolved into the Committee of the Whole House on the state
			 of the Union for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1947) to provide for the
			 reform and continuation of agricultural and other programs of the Department of
			 Agriculture through fiscal year 2018, and for other purposes. The first reading
			 of the bill shall be dispensed with. All points of order against consideration
			 of the bill are waived. General debate shall be confined to the bill and shall
			 not exceed one hour equally divided and controlled by the chair and ranking
			 minority member of the Committee on Agriculture. After general debate, the
			 Committee of the Whole shall rise without motion. No further consideration of
			 the bill shall be in order except pursuant to a subsequent order of the
			 House.</text>
		</section><section id="H7C9429943FDD4FBB85363EDDEA1068D4"><enum>2.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon the adoption of this resolution it
			 shall be in order to consider in the House the bill (H.R. 1797) to amend title
			 18, United States Code, to protect pain-capable unborn children in the District
			 of Columbia, and for other purposes. All points of order against consideration
			 of the bill are waived. In lieu of the amendment in the nature of a substitute
			 recommended by the Committee on the Judiciary now printed in the bill, an
			 amendment in the nature of a substitute consisting of the text of Rules
			 Committee Print 113-15 shall be considered as adopted. The bill, as amended,
			 shall be considered as read. All points of order against provisions in the
			 bill, as amended, are waived. The previous question shall be considered as
			 ordered on the bill, as amended, and on any amendment thereto to final passage
			 without intervening motion except: (1) one hour of debate equally divided and
			 controlled by the chair and ranking minority member of the Committee on the
			 Judiciary; and (2) one motion to recommit with or without instructions.</text>
		</section></resolution-body>
	<endorsement>
		<action-date>June 17, 2013</action-date>
		<action-desc>Referred to the House Calendar and ordered to be
		  printed</action-desc>
	</endorsement>
</resolution>


