<bill session="113" type="s" number="364" updated="2015-09-01T17:50:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-11-21">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-11-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rocky Mountain Front Heritage Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Rocky Mountain Front Heritage Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Rocky Mountain Front Conservation Management Area, to designate certain Federal land as wilderness, and to improve the management of noxious weeds in the Lewis and Clark National Forest, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300005"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2013-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412602" joined="2014-03-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-30">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands, Forests, and Mining. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 113-85.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-11-21" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-06-02">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Landrieu without amendment. With written report No. 113-177.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-06-02" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="404">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 404.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG03" subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3979"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Pedestrians and bicycling"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/2/2014--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Rocky Mountain Front Heritage Act of 2013 - (Sec. 3) Establishes the Rocky Mountain Front Conservation Management Area in Montana consisting of approximately 195,073 acres of federal land managed by Forest Service and 13,087 acres of federal land managed by the Bureau of Land Management (BLM).

Permits the Secretary of Agriculture with respect to Forest Service land or the Secretary of the Interior with respect to BLM land (the Secretary concerned) to only allow uses of the Conservation Management Area that would conserve, protect, and enhance the benefit and enjoyment of present and future generations of the recreational, scenic, historical, cultural, fish, wildlife, roadless, and ecological values of the Area. Sets forth provisions for the management of the Conservation Management Area regarding motorized vehicles and vegetation management projects. Allows the Secretary concerned to permit grazing within the Conservation Management Area if it was established before enactment of this Act.

(Sec. 4) Designates specified land within the Lewis and Clark National Forest in Montana as wilderness. Adds the land to the National Wilderness Preservation System.

Permits livestock grazing and the maintenance of existing grazing facilities to continue if it was established before enactment of this Act.

Authorizes the Secretary concerned to take necessary measures to control fires, insects, and diseases.

(Sec. 6) Directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to prepare a comprehensive management strategy for the prevention, control, and eradication of noxious weeds in the Rocky Mountain Ranger District of the Lewis and Clark National Forest.

(Sec. 7) Authorizes USDA to conduct a study for improving nonmotorized recreation trail opportunities, including mountain bicycling, on land within the District that is not designated as wilderness.

(Sec. 8) States that nothing in this Act affects Montana's jurisdiction over fish and wildlife management, including the regulation of hunting and fishing.

(Sec. 9) States that nothing in this Act affects the jurisdiction of the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) respecting the airspace above the wilderness or the Conservation Management Area nor the continued use, maintenance, and repair of the Benchmark (3U7) airstrip.</summary>
</bill>
