<bill session="113" type="hr" number="746" updated="2015-09-01T10:18:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing support for the people of Bosnia and Herzegovina as they seek to hold government officials accountable, prepare for elections at the state, entity, and cantonal level, and consider constitutional or other reforms to enhance the country's prospects for European and Euro-Atlantic integration.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400380"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412435" joined="2014-09-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Bosnia and Herzegovina"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="European Union"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Political movements and philosophies"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/18/2014--Introduced.
Supports: (1) the sovereignty, unity, and territorial integrity of Bosnia and Herzegovina within its internationally recognized borders; and (2) the people of Bosnia and Herzegovina as they seek democracy, economic prosperity, and successful European integration.

 Expresses dissatisfaction with the inability of Bosnia and Herzegovina's political leaders to agree on necessary reforms.

Views the October 12, 2014, elections as an opportunity for voters to address Bosnia and Herzegovina's current political stagnation as well as to express support for reform and European integration, and calls upon authorities to ensure these elections are conducted in a free and fair manner.

Encourages the growth of peaceful, civic activism.

Calls upon the European Union (EU) and the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) to clarify the integration steps Bosnia and Herzegovina needs to take.

Supports the maintenance of an international presence in Bosnia and Herzegovina and the retention of all powers accorded to the international community to meet the objectives and conditions set by the Peace Implementation Council.

Urges the United States and members of the international community, in all aspects of their relations with Bosnia and Herzegovina, to place emphasis on respect for the human rights and fundamental freedoms held by the individual, which should not be compromised by privileges accorded to a group, ethnically based or otherwise.</summary>
</bill>
