<bill session="113" type="s" number="1823" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-12-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-12-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-12-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strengthening the Child Welfare Response to Human Trafficking Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend part E of title IV of the Social Security Act to better enable State child welfare agencies to prevent human trafficking of children and serve the needs of children who are victims of human trafficking, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412491"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412493" joined="2014-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2014-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="2014-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2014-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2014-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2014-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412324" joined="2013-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2014-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2014-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412542" joined="2014-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2014-09-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-12-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1732"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/13/2013--Introduced.
Strengthening the Child Welfare Response to Human Trafficking Act of 2013 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to develop and publish guidelines to assist state, Indian tribe, and tribal organization child welfare agencies and juvenile and family courts in efforts to serve appropriately youth who are victims of trafficking and youth at-risk of becoming such.

Amends part E (Foster Care and Adoption Assistance) of title IV of the Social Security Act to require a state plan for foster care and adoption assistance to require reasonable efforts be made to: (1) identify as a victim of trafficking and document appropriately in agency records each child who is such a victim over whom the agency has responsibility for placement, care, or supervision; and (2) specify in agency records the type of trafficking to which the child has been subjected.

Requires the plan to require the agency to report within 72 hours to appropriate law enforcement agencies for entry into the National Crime Information Center database the identity of each child to whom the agency is providing child welfare services who is missing or has been abducted or is identified as a victim of trafficking.

Amends the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act to require the state plan for use of a grant for a child abuse or neglect prevention program to contain an assurance that the state law has in place provisions and procedures for the assessment and identification of victims of trafficking, as well as comprehensive training and services to serve such victims.</summary>
</bill>
