<bill session="113" type="h" number="5665" updated="2015-09-01T17:50:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Clear the Air with Congress Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To promote transparent, collaborative, and cost-effective national ambient air quality standards for ozone under the Clean Air Act and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412574"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400046" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400068" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412482" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400206" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412474" joined="2014-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400367" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400381" joined="2014-09-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/18/2014--Introduced.
Clear the Air with Congress Act of 2014 - Amends the Clean Air Act to require the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to submit to Congress a report, made available to the public, before issuing any rule proposing a new or revised: (1) primary national ambient air quality (NAAQ) standard for ozone (for pollutants considered harmful to public health), or (2) secondary NAAQ standard for ozone (for pollutants considered harmful to public welfare).

Requires the report to contain:

 the proposed standard (in parts per million), all scientific and technical data relied upon to support the proposed standard in a manner sufficient for independent analysis and substantial reproduction of results, a description of all technologies and strategies that may be utilized to achieve the standard and their costs, an economic impact analysis estimating the total costs of the standard, a list of each U.S. area of the United States that would exceed the standard for ozone and thereby receive a nonattainment designation for ozone under the Act, and an identification of the level of ground level ozone in each U.S. county that is naturally occurring or produced outside of the United States. Requires the EPA to consider the cost and economic and technological feasibility of attaining the standard when establishing a NAAQ standard for ozone.

Prohibits a NAAQ standard for ozone from taking effect unless a federal statute is enacted approving it.</summary>
</bill>
