<bill session="113" type="h" number="4175" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-03-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-03-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-03-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Victory for Veterans Stamp Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the issuance of a Victory for Veterans stamp, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400233"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-03-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-06">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-06">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR10" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/6/2014--Introduced.
Victory for Veterans Stamp Act of 2014 - Directs the Postal Service to issue a special stamp, to be called the Victory for Veterans Stamp, at a cost of $1 each. Makes such Stamp valid for postage for first-class mail.

Requires Stamp sale proceeds to be used as follows: (1) one-third for funding Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) veterans' vocational rehabilitation programs, (2) one-third to the general fund of the Treasury for deficit reduction, and (3) one-third for the Postal Service for modernization and fiscal administration.

Requires such Stamp to be made available to the public within six months after the enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
