<bill session="113" type="s" number="2443" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rape Survivor Child Custody Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Attorney General to make grants to States that have in place laws that terminate the parental rights of men who father children through rape.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400050"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412493" joined="2014-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400013" joined="2014-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2014-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412324" joined="2014-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2014-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300078" joined="2014-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2014-06-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2772"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Separation, divorce, custody, support"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/5/2014--Introduced.
Rape Survivor Child Custody Act - Directs the Attorney General to make grants to states that have in place a law that allows the mother of any child that was conceived through rape to seek court-ordered termination of the parental rights of her rapist with regard to that child, which the court shall grant upon clear and convincing evidence of rape.

Limits such a grant to: (1) an amount that is not greater than 10% of the average of the total funding of the 3 most recent awards a state received under the STOP Violence Against Women Formula Grant Program and the Sexual Assault Services Program; and (2) a 1-year term, subject to renewal for not more than 3 additional years.

Requires a state that receives such a grant to use: (1) 25% of grant funds for permissible uses under the STOP Violence Against Women Formula Grant Program, and (2) 75% of funds for permissible uses under the Sexual Assault Services Program.</summary>
</bill>
