<bill session="113" type="sc" number="41" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A concurrent resolution denouncing the use of civilians as human shields by Hamas and other terrorist organizations in violation of international humanitarian law.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412573"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2014-07-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4911" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hc" number="107"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Arab-Israeli relations"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Gaza Strip"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Palestinians"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="War crimes, genocide, crimes against humanity"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/24/2014--Introduced.
Condemns the illegal tactic by Hamas and other terrorist organizations of using innocent civilians as human shields.

 Calls on the international community to recognize the grave breaches of international law committed by Hamas in using human shields.

 Places responsibility for launching the rocket attacks on Hamas and other terrorist organizations, such as Islamic Jihad, in Gaza.

 Supports Israel's sovereign right to defend its territory and stop the rocket attacks on its citizens.

 Expresses condolences to the families of the innocent victims on both sides of the conflict.

 Supports Palestinian civilians who reject Hamas and all forms of terrorism, desiring to live in peace with their Israeli neighbors.

Calls on Mahmoud Abbas to condemn the use of innocent civilians as human shields by Hamas and other terrorist organizations.</summary>
</bill>
