<bill session="113" type="s" number="1878" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-12-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-12-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-12-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Youth At-Risk for Sex Trafficking Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to better enable State child welfare agencies to prevent sex trafficking of children and serve the needs of children who are victims of sex trafficking, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300005"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2013-12-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2013-12-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="2013-12-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="2013-12-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400325" joined="2014-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2013-12-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2014-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2013-12-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-12-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1870"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Homelessness and emergency shelter"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Separation, divorce, custody, support"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/19/2013--Introduced.
Protecting Youth At-Risk for Sex Trafficking Act - Amends part E (Foster Care and Adoption Assistance) of title IV of the Social Security Act (SSA) to require the state agency under its foster care and adoption assistance program plan to demonstrate to the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) that it has developed, and is implementing, policies and procedures for identifying and screening any child who the state has reasonable cause to believe is a victim of sex trafficking or is at risk of being a victim of trafficking.

Prescribes additional case plan and case review system requirements for placement of a child in another planned permanent living arrangement.

Requires a permanency plan for a child age 14 or older to be developed in consultation with the child, and allows the child to choose up to two members of his or her case planning team.

Requires foster youth to be discharged from care only if provided with an official birth certificate, a Social Security card, a driver's license or equivalent state-issued identification care, and a fee-free (or low-fee) bank account. Subjects any state to an administrative penalty for noncompliance.

Requires the state plan to require the state agency to: (1) identify and document each child who is a victim of sex trafficking or a victim of severe forms of trafficking in persons, and (2) report to law enforcement authorities within 24 hours after receiving any information on missing or abducted children for entry into the National Crime Information Center (NCIC) database of the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI).

Amends part A of SSA title XI to require the head of each federal agency to report to Congress recommendations for expanding safe housing for youth victims of trafficking.

Directs the Secretary to establish a National Advisory Committee on Domestic Sex Trafficking.</summary>
</bill>
