<bill session="113" type="s" number="1978" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-01-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-01-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-01-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Increasing Primary Care Access Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to increase access to primary care services through training and accountability improvements.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400413"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412281" joined="2014-02-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-01-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1759"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/30/2014--Introduced.
Increasing Primary Care Access Act of 2014 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to make grants to, and enter contracts with, schools of medicine and osteopathic medicine to assist the schools in supporting programs of excellence in primary care.

Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to require the Secretary to establish and implement procedures under which the amount of payments that a subsection (d) hospital would otherwise receive for indirect medical education costs for discharges occurring during an applicable period is adjusted based on the performance of the hospital on measures specified by the Secretary.

(Generally, a subsection [d] hospital is an acute care hospital, particularly one that receives payments under Medicare's inpatient prospective payment system [IPPS] when providing covered inpatient services to eligible beneficiaries.)

Prohibits the Secretary from consulting with an organization representing physicians on adjustments to the fee schedule for physicians' services if the organization uses a group to formulate recommendations regarding such adjustments unless at least 40% of the group are board certified and practicing physicians in specified primary care fields.

Directs the Secretary to establish a pilot program to provide funding for graduate medical residency training programs in primary care.

Requires the Secretary to award grants or enter into contracts for the establishment of six to eight Regional Centers for Health Workforce Analysis to allocate funds to in-need primary care residency programs.

Increases the federal medical assistance percentage (FMAP) for amounts expended on targeted graduate medical education in certain areas in need of primary care health professionals for a state which expanded Medicaid under the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act.

Reauthorizes a program of payments to teaching health centers.</summary>
</bill>
