<bill session="113" type="h" number="5215" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Clatsop-Nehalem Restoration Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the restoration of Federal recognition to the Clatsop-Nehalem Confederated Tribes of Oregon, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412501"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-08-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee Indian and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII24" subcommittee="Indian and Alaska Native Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/28/2014--Introduced.
Clatsop-Nehalem Restoration Act - Extends federal recognition to the Clatsop-Nehalem Confederated Tribes of Oregon.

Restores all rights and privileges of the Tribe and the members of the Tribe under any federal treaty, Executive order, agreement, statute, or other federal authority that may have been diminished or lost under the Act approved August 13, 1954. Makes the provisions of such Act inapplicable to the Tribe and its members.

Makes the Tribe and its members eligible to receive all federal services and benefits furnished to federally recognized Indian tribes, without regard to the existence of a reservation for the Tribe. Deems members of the Tribe residing in Tillamook and Clatsop Counties in Oregon as residing on or near a reservation.

Declares that no hunting, fishing, or trapping rights of the Tribe or of any member are granted or restored.

Establishes and opens the membership roll of the Tribe.</summary>
</bill>
