<bill session="113" type="s" number="2125" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-03-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-03-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-03-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Public Safety and Economic Security Communications Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Communications Act of 1934 to ensure the integrity of voice communications and to prevent unjust or unreasonable discrimination among areas of the United States in the delivery of such communications.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300058"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400013" joined="2014-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2014-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2014-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2014-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2014-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2014-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300080" joined="2014-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2014-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2014-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412602" joined="2014-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2014-04-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-03-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1655-1656"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission (FCC)"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/13/2014--Introduced.
Public Safety and Economic Security Communications Act of 2014 - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to require an intermediate provider that offers the capability to transmit certain voice communications and signaling information from one destination to another, and that charges a rate to any other entity (including an affiliated entity) for the transmission, to: (1) register with the Federal Communications Commission (FCC), and (2) comply with service quality standards to be established by the FCC.

Defines "intermediate provider" as any entity that: (1) carries or processes traffic that is generated from the placement of a call from a connection using a North American Numbering Plan resource or a call placed to a connection using such a numbering resource, and (2) does not itself originate or terminate such traffic in the context of the carriage or processing.

Prohibits certain long-distance voice service providers (including local exchange carriers, interexchange carriers, commercial mobile radio services, interconnected voice over Internet Protocol [VoIP] services, and certain non-interconnected VoIP services) from using an intermediate provider to transmit voice communications and signals unless the intermediate provider is so registered.

Directs the FCC, in promulgating rules for such standards, to: (1) ensure the integrity of the transmission of voice communications to all customers in the United States, (2) prevent unjust or unreasonable discrimination among areas of the United States in the delivery of such voice communications, and (3) make a registry of intermediate providers publicly available on the FCC website.</summary>
</bill>
