<bill session="113" type="h" number="5261" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CAUSA Initiatives Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Central American and USA Initiatives Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a North and Central American and Caribbean border security cooperation initiative, enhance the security of Mexico's southern border, improve United States short term detention standards, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400356"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Homeland Security, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-30">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-30">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-30">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-08-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border and Maritime Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Western Hemisphere.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA07" subcommittee="Western Hemisphere" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM11" subcommittee="Border and Maritime Security" name="House Homeland Security"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Central America"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Immigrant health and welfare"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Smuggling and trafficking"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/2014--Introduced.
Central American and USA Initiatives Act or the CAUSA Initiatives Act - Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to work with Canada, Mexico, and the countries of Central America to establish a program to:

 assess the needs of Central American countries to maintain the security of their international borders; determine the support needed by such countries from the United States, Canada, and Mexico to meet such needs; and assess the current structure for handling displaced minors and other vulnerable individuals in Central American countries and make recommendations to improve such structure. Directs the Secretary to work with:

 the Caribbean countries to establish a program to address maritime border security; and Mexico to establish a program to help secure Mexico's southern border from undocumented aliens, drugs, weapons, and other contraband. Directs the Secretary, through the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection, to:

 ensure that adequate facilities and sustaining needs (food, water, medical care, and sanitary facilities) are provided to an individual apprehended and detained by the Border Patrol as soon as practicable, ensure that an individual unlawfully present in the United States who is apprehended by a Border Patrol agent is promptly provided with information concerning such individual's rights, and maintain a database on individuals unlawfully present in the United States who are apprehended and detained by Border Patrol agents.</summary>
</bill>
