<bill session="113" type="h" number="4875" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Equalizing Transparency for Veterans Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to publish information on the provision of health care by the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400636"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412310" joined="2014-06-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR03" subcommittee="Health" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/17/2014--Introduced.
Equalizing Transparency for Veterans Act - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) to biennially publish information on the VA's provision of health care on a VA Internet database that is publicly available.

Includes among that information for each VA medical facility:

 quality measures regarding inpatient and outpatient care that the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) is required to make publicly available under the Medicare program; the average length of stay, opioid prescription rate, and suicide rate for patients discharged from the facility; and the average number of days a patient waited for an appointment or procedure at such facility. Includes in such information for each VA nursing home any quality measures the Secretary of HHS makes publicly available regarding Medicare nursing homes.

Directs the Secretary to establish a process to validate the published information.

Requires the Secretary to annually submit a plan to Congress to improve each VA medical facility that ranks within the bottom quartile on each quality measure used by the Secretary to rank such facilities.

Directs the Secretary to establish a toll-free telephone number for individuals to use to notify the Secretary of low-quality care being provided at a VA medical facility.</summary>
</bill>
