<bill session="113" type="h" number="5587" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Opioid Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reduce opioid misuse and abuse.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412257"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412263" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412524" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412562" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400352" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412219" joined="2014-09-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical ethics"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/18/2014--Introduced.
Opioid Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act of 2014 - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to award grants to states to develop a peer review process to identify and investigate questionable or inappropriate prescribing and dispensing patterns of drugs classified as schedule II or III under the Controlled Substances Act, which are drugs with an accepted medical use that have the potential to be abused and addictive.

Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary to establish grant programs to: (1) facilitate training to increase the capacity of health care providers to screen and treat patients to prevent drug abuse, and (2) develop continuing education criteria that allow health profession boards or state agencies to certify appropriate education for safe prescribing of schedule II or III drugs. Requires the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration to award grants to evaluate the prospect of state health professions boards expanding the authority of providers to prescribe drugs to treat drug abuse.

Requires the Attorney General to request that practitioners registered to dispense controlled substances screen patients for potential drug abuse before prescribing a schedule II or III drug.

Directs the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) to consider whether naloxone (a prescription drug used to rapidly reverse an overdose of heroin or other opioids, which are drugs with effects similar to opium) should be available without a prescription.

Requires the Secretary to use an interagency working group to encourage states and local governments to increase opportunities for disposal of opiates (drugs derived from opium) and to reduce opportunities for abuse of opiates.

Requires the Government Accountability Office (GAO) to review federal opioid abuse activities and make recommendations to reduce opioid abuse and overdoses.</summary>
</bill>
