<bill session="113" type="s" number="1262" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-11-19">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-11-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Conservation Corps Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to establish a veterans conservation corps, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300078"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2013-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2013-11-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2013-09-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-30">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 113-280.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-11-19" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3451"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Army Corps of Engineers"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="National and community service"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/27/2013--Introduced.
Veterans Conservation Corps Act of 2013 - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) to establish a veterans conservation corps to assist veterans in the transition from service in the Armed Forces to civilian life and to employ veterans: (1) in conservation, resource management, and historic preservation projects on public lands; (2) in maintenance and improvement projects for cemeteries under the jurisdiction of the National Cemetery Administration; and (3) as firefighters, law enforcement officers, and disaster relief personnel.

Requires priority to be given to the employment of veterans who served on active duty on or after September 11, 2001.

Requires, as part of the veterans conservation corps: (1) the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to award grants under the Federal Fire Prevention and Control Act of 1974 to hire veterans as firefighters; (2) the Attorney General to award grants under the public safety and community policing grant program (COPS ON THE BEAT grant program) under the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to hire veterans as law enforcement officers; and (3) the DHS Secretary to provide funds to increase participation by veterans in the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) Corps program.

Authorizes the VA Secretary to transfer amounts to carry out the corps to the Attorney General, the Chief of Engineers, and the Secretaries of Agriculture, Commerce, DHS, and Interior.

Directs the VA Secretary to establish a steering committee to establish selection criteria for, and provide advice to the VA Secretary on, the awarding of assistance under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
