<bill session="113" type="h" number="3705" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-12-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-12-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-12-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Excellence in Diagnostic Imaging Utilization Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to establish appropriateness requirements for certain advanced diagnostic imaging services, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412303"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400255" joined="2013-12-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-12-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-11">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-11">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/11/2013--Introduced.
Excellence in Diagnostic Imaging Utilization Act of 2013 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to establish appropriateness requirements for certain outpatient advanced diagnostic imaging services for which payment is made under the technical or professional component of the physicians' fee schedule or the prospective payment system for hospital outpatient department services.

Defines "applicable advanced diagnostic imaging services" as those for which defined appropriate use criteria (and related guidelines) have been: (1) developed or endorsed by national professional medical specialty societies, and (2) selected by the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) in consultation with such societies and other stakeholders.

Directs the Secretary to: (1) qualify imaging appropriateness registries developed and maintained by such societies, (2) publish a list of qualified suppliers of approved electronic clinical decision support tools, and (3) establish standards for the approval of such tools.

Directs the Secretary, for the purpose of making incentive payments for quality reporting, to treat an eligible advanced diagnostic imaging services professional as satisfactorily submitting data on quality measures if, instead of reporting measures under the established quality reporting system, the professional demonstrates compliance with the registry submission or consultation requirements of this Act for at least 90% of claims for applicable advanced diagnostic imaging services submitted in the year. Limits this treatment to eligible professionals who furnish the technical or professional component of applicable advanced diagnostic imaging services or who order such services.</summary>
</bill>
