<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H8EB1A2A233744B159E540E0E5FD3878E" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HR 5846 IH: Frank R. Wolf International Religious Freedom Act of 2014</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2014-12-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 5846</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20141210">December 10, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000522">Mr. Smith of New Jersey</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name> and <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998 to improve the ability of the United
			 States to protect religious freedom globally through enhanced diplomacy,
			 training, counterterrorism, and foreign assistance efforts, and through
			 stronger and more timely and flexible political responses to religious
			 freedom violations worldwide, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H40A40E854BBC4AE6AC60C4D9AAE38FA4" style="OLC">
		<section id="H7D83E508B80C442291D79EF99636CB91" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short Title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Frank R. Wolf International Religious Freedom Act of 2014</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="HD860E9A2A45C4C819D26F7B66044CEB2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings; policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2 of the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/6401">22 U.S.C. 6401</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
			<paragraph id="H9A6B4EEC86A04914948923301507C55C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text>
				<subparagraph id="H9ECB5D0F712E46C7965544A8FEA417F6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), in the fourth sentence, by inserting <quote>prohibitions on ritual animal slaughter, male infant circumcision, censorship of religious content,
			 or worship on the Internet,</quote> after <quote>confiscations of property,</quote>;</text>
				</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6F80BD2066A446948CCCD53BF13C16A5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by amending the second sentence to read as follows: <quote>In many countries, religious believers are forced to meet secretly, and religious leaders and
			 believers are targeted by national security forces, violent nonstate
			 actors, and hostile mobs.</quote>;</text>
				</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6C7CFE5D833A4E8B81815CFED9133454"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (7) as paragraph (9); and</text>
				</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H39A1CCAB7EC34FA4AED70796A289EC56"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (6) the following new paragraphs:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCA72006A51934643A8E00C17D0C1C3DE" style="OLC">
						<paragraph id="HA4EB098312B9423586861B67544FCF92"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is growing evidence that demonstrates a connection between the absence of religious freedom
			 and increased levels of persecution of religious minorities, religiously
			 motivated conflict, violent extremism, and terrorism, including the kind
			 of terrorism that has reached the United States.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="H2785CABB5BD1499BBAD65946EA1DA6CD"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is increasingly clear that understanding religion and the political and security implications of
			 religious motivation and conviction is critical to the success of United
			 States diplomacy and foreign policy initiatives as there are studies that
			 show—</text>
							<subparagraph id="H22D767199FCE43A792F776824F58296B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">75 percent of the world’s population lives in countries where the right to the freedom of religion
			 and belief is severely restricted, either by the government or violent
			 nonstate actors; and</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC42BC34C785E4991882E882DA23F1F6A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">84 percent of the world’s population identifies strongly with a specific religious group.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0AFB98ED3EBA4A5A9ABD71F0EAA7BF89"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC5B1BC7D054B479EBDA3148312D8AB59" style="OLC">
					<paragraph id="H98451A1D9F4E43189B24F83501613CFF"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Because the promotion of international religious freedom is a foreign policy strategy that protects
			 other, related human rights, advances democracy abroad, and is linked
			 directly to United States interests in stability, security, and
			 development globally, the promotion of international religious freedom
			 requires new and evolving policies, religion engagement strategies, and
			 diplomatic responses that are drawn from the expertise of the national
			 security agencies, the diplomatic services, Congress, and other
			 governmental agencies and nongovernmental organizations, and are
			 coordinated across and carried out by the entire range of Federal agencies
			 that are engaged with or conduct negotiations or United States Government
			 funded programs with governments or violent nonstate actors that engage in
			 or tolerate violations of religious freedom.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H46F796C3527041B69E1887CFD5939286"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3 of the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/6402">22 U.S.C. 6402</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
			<paragraph id="H9B8AD35C2695431382660DCB5CBE93E0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (12) to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H62AE7561929144AA9095BC077AF0A8D8" style="OLC">
					<paragraph id="HAFD96C3961DF4E63B64D87225A903B56"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Senior Director</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Senior Director</term> means the Senior Director for Global Religion Engagement and International Religious Freedom
			 Promotion described in section 101 of the National Security Act of 1947.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HA7C8FE8B58BC4700B3AE821A57DF5D11"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end, the following new paragraphs:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF651A47579884952A4DD4BCEF01CD957" style="OLC">
					<paragraph id="H58537721DB9C43BF93C5ED4435CB99DD"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Special Watch List</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Special Watch List</term> means the Special Watch List described in section 102(b)(1)(F)(iii).</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="HCDCD16DE23CF496A89CD3FBD81D39C73"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Violent nonstate actor</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>violent nonstate actor</term> means a nonsovereign entity or group that exercises significant political power or influence at a
			 national or international level and which, through violence or the threat
			 of violence, destabilizes existing government structures or gains defacto
			 or actual control over large territories within existing countries and
			 which engages in or tolerates violations of religious freedom.</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="HC56178949AD2469EAD46E2F715B47A89"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Institution of Higher Education</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given that term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (20 U.S.C.
			 1001)</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H9E6CD3492E7548C9BF69A3BC285A330D"><enum>4.</enum><header>Office on International Religious Freedom; Ambassador at Large for International Religious Freedom</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 101 of the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/6411">22 U.S.C. 6411</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
			<paragraph id="H9D36D101ADA3490E9759972EA7ABA005"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (a), by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>The Office shall be located in the Office of the Secretary of State.</quote>;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H7379C73E8C634748B777B703FFC8E9DB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by adding at the end the before the period the following: <quote>, and shall report directly to the Secretary of State.</quote>;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H16B77657E9C74C508144383007D3FE1B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text>
				<subparagraph id="H9AFA0EB155FA4C6B8BFF7F65DC9017C8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text>
					<clause id="H772425B426CE48638A2C29445997B7FF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>responsibility</quote> and inserting <quote>responsibilities</quote>;</text>
					</clause><clause id="HE8BF1BBE9D9E46DCBB73EBECFB51A38C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>shall be to advance</quote> and inserting the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H838365E3173441969ADD4C83D0503CEE" style="OLC"><text>shall be to—</text><subparagraph id="HB3E8683277AA47369D5CD45CC4DAD19C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">advance</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
					</clause><clause id="HE65BE508A25B4216B35C93E35D1C7DF5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), as so added, by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text>
					</clause><clause id="H8D0532FBBE214353B72E6DDEBB813E52"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H241C4EAC75F340378AA012C1B572E4E8" style="OLC">
							<subparagraph id="H922CECEF8EF74091826EBD11E9192EEE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">integrate United States international religious freedom policies and religious engagement
			 strategies into democracy, civil society, conflict prevention and
			 mitigation, and development efforts funded by the United States and into
			 the counterterrorism policies of Federal agencies, including the
			 Department of Defense, the Department of Homeland Security, the Department
			 of State, and the Department of the Treasury.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
					</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE9535D6A71E9459489AD412795F8C5AC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>a principal adviser</quote> and inserting <quote>the principal adviser</quote>;</text>
				</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC00022A82A340AE89E369B04211D446"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)—</text>
					<clause id="H2A0AD71EF50249F89DEBDEA1DA6BDD47"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text>
					</clause><clause id="HBC5FC6AF0FAB43BEBC4EDF8D4DFB8530"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text>
					</clause><clause id="H3DBE0C7E7A7244E799CF89FF11F987C5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF700EB455DF74C7588243A78A9EC8A86" style="OLC">
							<subparagraph id="H0B0630408C8B438ABF7E207064E80720"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">contacts with nongovernmental organizations that have an impact on the state of religious freedom
			 in their respective societies or regions, or internationally.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
					</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H24B9682BD6E941D59F5931273F0D8644"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (4) as paragraph (5); and</text>
				</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8A0BC1E5F4894D35864D3C0DCDFEDD1F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (3) the following new paragraph:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF24D4EFFB31745C5B7001EA43B3BA01E" style="OLC">
						<paragraph id="HA78BA7614ADB4849B3F09E0A2E2CBE7A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Coordination responsibilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In order to promote religious freedom as an interest of United States foreign policy, the
			 Ambassador at Large shall seek to coordinate religious freedom policies
			 and religious engagement strategies across all programs, projects, and
			 activities of the United States, including the programs, projects, and
			 activities of the Department of Defense, the Department of Homeland
			 Security, the Department of State, the Department of the Treasury, and the
			 United States Agency for International Development.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H271A3C52D5F645DEA313D182DEB614B5"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (d), by striking <quote>staff for the Office</quote> and all that follows through the period at the end and inserting <quote>individuals to fill at least 15 full-time equivalent staff positions, under the direct supervision
			 of the Ambassador at Large, including a senior advisor, for the Office,
			 for the conduct of investigations by the Office, and for necessary travel
			 to carry out the provisions of this section. The Secretary of State shall
			 also provide to the Ambassador at Large representation funds equal to the
			 amount of representation funds provided to other Ambassadors at Large in
			 the Department of State.</quote>.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HCE1F23C0E0A04E49ADCD3D6986059B9B"><enum>5.</enum><header>Annual Report on International Religious Freedom</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Paragraph (1) of section 102(b) of the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998 (22 U.S.C.
			 6412(b)) is amended—</text>
			<paragraph id="H21365241219A4260B495429FD8121F18"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text>
				<subparagraph id="H4EF35F8ED89148B8A9DE2C0A2CACB591"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in clause (iii), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text>
				</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD6CF124E153D458183CC2B54765A8988"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (iv), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text>
				</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9B28BEC5EF014C238D1D059A555D0756"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new clause:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2C71F97E315846F49791755E14047461" style="OLC">
						<clause id="H82E8437306E148AEA5DD74D56CDEB217"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any action taken by a government or other entity to censor religious content, communications, or
			 worship activities online, including descriptions of the targeted
			 religious group, the content, communication, or activities censored, the
			 means used, and government or other entity engaged in such online
			 censorship activities.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H951CDD17DE0A4D24B5E3A2DACB8B2FCB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), in the matter preceding clause (i)—</text>
				<subparagraph id="HB85FCED798BC48089949D9035BB27345"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>persecution of lawyers, politicians, or other human rights advocates seeking to defend targeted
			 religious groups or highlight religious freedom violations, prohibitions
			 on ritual animal slaughter or male infant circumcision,</quote> after <quote>entire religions,</quote>; and</text>
				</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3217DF16DDFA4898953EAFACA3306C2E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>policies that ban or restrict the public manifestation of religious belief and the peaceful
			 involvement of religious groups or their members in the political life of
			 each such foreign country,</quote> after <quote>such groups,</quote>;</text>
				</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2B85969C2EC84744922300050AD7B49B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C)—</text>
				<subparagraph id="HFE47285922284A8A9FF8D474FC0DDC6C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>A description</quote> and inserting <quote>A comprehensive description</quote>;</text>
				</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1E921062A31E44A8ADD5C20D91A71E51"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>policies in support</quote> and inserting <quote>religious engagement policies in support</quote>; and</text>
				</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFC02B7ADAD0B48ED84CB6ACC5CF1296E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end before the period the following: <quote>, and a unique, comprehensive, and country-specific analysis of the impact of actions by the United
			 States on the status of religious freedom in each such country.</quote>; and</text>
				</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3DF442C14EA1412E96FFBE35B4A503C3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subparagraph (F), by adding at the end the following new clause:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8798216FA0C243FCA9D70BC3890928BA" style="OLC">
					<clause id="H6B7E8650A9CF44ACA466F2325254C868"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Special Watch List</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A list, to be known as the <quote>Special Watch List</quote>, which shall identify any country or violent nonstate actor that has engaged in or tolerated
			 systematic, egregious, or ongoing violations of religious freedom during
			 the previous reporting year but which the Secretary determines does not
			 meet, at the time of the publication of the Annual Report, the criteria
			 for designation as a country of particular concern for religious freedom
			 under section 402(b)(1).</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H2E478BC5D9C04AA49EB832FD86395DEE"><enum>6.</enum><header>Training for Foreign Service officers; Report</header>
			<subsection id="H2B1DB35B9918476787BB2BAC451FF1EE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendment to Foreign Service Act of 1980</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 708 of the Foreign Service Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/4028">22 U.S.C. 4028</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
				<paragraph id="H4CCC9BF504F84ED4A45334F6E315CD59"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (b) and (c) as subsections (d) and (e), respectively;</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HD0478C5EAABA4B9BAECC2DB5989B0971"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (d), as redesignated, by striking <quote>The Secretary of State</quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Refugees.—</header-in-text>The Secretary of State</quote>;</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H382A5BAC03894074ACE5BEBE1E608821"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (e), as redesignated, by striking <quote>The Secretary of State</quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Child Soldiers</header-in-text>.—The Secretary of State</quote>;</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H5AEB899FD1E24F0ABDD5BFEC087E5BD1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by striking subsection (a) and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEF156D8EB8794678B5E01A4AE7A9BDF8" style="OLC">
						<subsection id="H6C9C7135FB52437894F326E897731863"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Development of Curriculum</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State, with the assistance of other relevant officials, including the Ambassador
			 at Large for International Religious Freedom appointed under section
			 101(b) of the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998, the Director of
			 the George P. Shultz National Foreign Affairs Training Center, and other
			 Federal officials as appropriate, and in consultation with the United
			 States Commission on International Religious Freedom established in
			 section 201(a) of the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998, shall
			 develop a curriculum for training United States Foreign Service officers
			 in the meaning and strategic value of religious freedom, how violations of
			 religious freedom harm fundamental United States interests, how the
			 advancement of religious freedom can advance such interests, how United
			 States international religious freedom policy should be carried out in
			 practice by United states diplomats and other Foreign Service officers,
			 and the relevance and relationship of religious freedom to United States
			 defense, diplomacy, development, and public affairs efforts.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="H8DCA24F2671E4483BA31307CBA19E91B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Training Program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than the date that is one year after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Frank R. Wolf International Religious Freedom Act of 2014</short-title>, the Director of the George P. Shultz National Foreign Affairs Training Center shall begin
			 mandatory training on religious freedom for all Foreign Service officers,
			 including all entry level officers and all outgoing deputy chiefs of
			 mission and ambassadors. Such training shall, at minimum, be a separate,
			 independent, and required segment of each of the following:</text>
							<paragraph id="HF1CEC2AA668E4EC8870816C03A62EEBA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The A–100 course attended by all Foreign Service officers.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="H180C7A05782A47C98D34A8B35819720E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The courses required of every Foreign Service officer prior to a posting outside the United States,
			 with segments tailored to the particular religious demography, religious
			 freedom conditions, and United States strategies for advancing religious
			 freedom, in each receiving country.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="HD10D9011038D4775BA42157048C411DF"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The courses required of all outgoing deputy chiefs of mission and ambassadors.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB814E8DBBE3B487A90E4E88070162EE8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Information Sharing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The curriculum and training materials developed pursuant to subsections (a) and (b) shall be shared
			 with the United States Armed Forces and intelligence community to provide
			 training and particularized instruction on United States religious freedom
			 policies, religious traditions, and religious and cultural issues for the
			 countries the Armed Forces and intelligence community are responsible.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H379AC943FF9F4EC587393CB2191B02FE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State, with
			 the assistance of the Ambassador at Large for International Religious
			 Freedom, and the Director of the George P. Shultz National Foreign Affairs
			 Training Center, shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the
			 House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the
			 Senate a report containing a comprehensive plan for undertaking training
			 for Foreign Service officers as required under section 708 of the Foreign
			 Services Act of 1980, as amended by subsection (a) of this section.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H1A5EEDCD08B5431C8847AC84ACEAC6CE"><enum>7.</enum><header>Prisoner lists and issue briefs on religious freedom concerns</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 108 of the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/6417">22 U.S.C. 6417</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
			<paragraph id="HED22C49D26A441AD81DA9B76C8BC6214"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text>
				<subparagraph id="HCF1F195E987B4A93B9D8EF69032494E3"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Sense of the Congress</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Increased Diplomatic Advocacy</header-in-text></quote>; and</text>
				</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC57A427A1E1C4E4D82AB71A4BD603EB5"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>it is the sense of the Congress that officials of the executive branch of Government should promote</quote> and inserting <quote>appropriate officials of the executive branch, including the Secretary of State, the Ambassador at
			 Large for Religious Freedom, and State Department officials from regional
			 bureaus, shall promote</quote>;</text>
				</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD1087334AFEC46B7ABEA4E03EE27113E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (c), by striking <quote>, as appropriate, provide</quote> and insert <quote>make available</quote>; and</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H1F5D6F0B6AA64CE49E4E5AFA432D12DB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB067BF79347F47F6BF6D0594E2910F4C" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H99E472DC1F644F0B872553954F6154DD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Victims List Maintained by the Commission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall compile, maintain, and make publicly available online and in official
			 publications, regularly updated lists of persons it determines are
			 imprisoned, detained, disappeared, placed under house arrest, tortured, or
			 subject to forced renunciations of faith by a foreign government that the
			 Commission recommends for designation as a country of particular concern
			 for religions freedom under section 402(b) or a violent nonstate actor and
			 include information on the conditions and circumstances of such
			 individuals. In compiling such lists, the Commission shall exercise
			 appropriate discretion, including consideration of the safety and security
			 of, and benefit to, the persons who may be included on the lists and their
			 families.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H3C6563DEA0784182985A9D84F6D53B6E"><enum>8.</enum><header>Duties of the Commission on International Religious Freedom</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subsection (a) of section 202 of the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/6432">22 U.S.C. 6432</external-xref>)
			 is amended—</text>
			<paragraph id="H5724FE6B944D4DAD921AD50A951CEF02"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>responsibility</quote> and inserting <quote>responsibilities</quote>;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H1036EAE6245749C8AA21A37AEB154E5B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H4C68AE7C30F042F9BD819134857624A1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HCB6F5BC689324110B5A2CCB81122EE37"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraphs:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5C23000CD3644AC995CA50CFA09C003A" style="OLC">
					<paragraph id="HE301513BCA244D2D8AB791E0754F2200"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by making annual recommendations on countries, and violent nonstate actors, as appropriate, which
			 commit particularly severe violations of religious freedom and issuing
			 reports on any other countries and violent nonstate actors that the
			 Commission believes to have engaged in or tolerated violations of
			 religious freedom; and</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1C909049225F466BAC7E80701ABB1A9E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>recommending specific policy responses or actions that may be taken under section 405(a), including
			 any commensurate actions that may be taken.</text>
					</paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HDE887F2D6F554201A004A53DEAFF7821"><enum>9.</enum><header>Report of the Commission on International Religious Freedom</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subsection (a) of section 205 of the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/6433">22 U.S.C. 6433</external-xref>)
			 is amended to read as follows:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4D93B1B9E67A4A80B10A31E74C0C1960" style="OLC">
				<subsection id="H9391E00D0765436BA10ED6848234905B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall—</text>
					<paragraph id="H0627D93F81B64DEBA4C229706390B018"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 180 days after the date of the submission of the report required of the Secretary of
			 State under section 102(b), submit an annual report to the President, the
			 Secretary of State, and the appropriate congressional committees setting
			 forth its recommendation for United States policy options based on
			 evaluations of country conditions under paragraphs (1) and (2) of section
			 202(a); and</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="H5F66E681B3864AB8B09A535BCB96A397"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit recommendations required under paragraphs (3) and (4) of section 202(a) sufficiently prior
			 to the annual designation of each country of particular concern for
			 religious freedom under section 402(b) to allow for presidential
			 consideration of such recommendations.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="H178A09F62D2D4DDE8BBB0268B47BB211"><enum>10.</enum><header>Senior Director for Global Religion Engagement and International Religious Freedom Promotion;
			 Interagency Policy Committees</header>
			<subsection id="H78567D1E1E744247A73668776F45E837"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendments to National Security Act of 1947</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 101 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3021">50 U.S.C. 3021</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
				<paragraph id="H158CEAB6EFE24C848F818D7EA1BA7666"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (k)—</text>
					<subparagraph id="H38E3B10A2FD945DDBD6F4D93D5119A89"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the first sentence,</text>
						<clause id="H11698284C1394D45B60D3C69E800D022"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>It is the sense of that there should be</quote> and inserting <quote>The President shall appoint</quote>; and</text>
						</clause><clause id="HDED624B21B6144B29D094ABA5B3FEDFF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Special Adviser to the President on International Religious Freedom</quote> and inserting <quote>Senior Director for Global Religion Engagement and International Religious Freedom Promotion</quote>; and</text>
						</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H41863F39CD8642ECAB001862A5BFE864"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking the second and third sentences and inserting the following: <quote>The Senior Director, shall develop and coordinate religious freedom policies and religion
			 engagement strategies throughout the Executive Branch, serve as a resource
			 for executive branch officials, compile and maintain information on the
			 facts and circumstances of violations of religious freedom, assist in
			 coordinating all programs, projects, and activities of the United States
			 to promote religious freedom and religious engagement outside the United
			 States, and make policy recommendations relevant to the programs,
			 projects, activities of the Department of Defense, the Department of
			 Homeland Security, the Department of State, the Department of the
			 Treasury, and the United States Agency for International Development, and
			 carry out all other applicable duties, responsibilities, and coordination
			 activities enumerated in the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998.
			 The Senior Director shall serve as liaison with the Ambassador at Large
			 for International Religious Freedom and the United States Commission on
			 International Religious Freedom described in the International Religious
			 Freedom Act of 1998, Congress, religious and nongovernmental
			 organizations, and, as appropriate, Cabinet-level agencies.</quote>; and</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H57713691790646F78FB8DC811AE1EA50"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end, the following new subsections:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4F1E756670E14E569A3077730CBB2210" style="OLC">
						<subsection id="HDE0DDD3520194FE8A65F217CA661F34E"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Interagency Policy Committee on Religious Freedom and Engagement</header>
							<paragraph id="H4FED7ADB06FB4B0180D5C74F55F0CD17"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established within the National Security Council a permanent interagency policy committee
			 to be known as the <quote>Interagency Policy Committee on Religious Freedom and Engagement</quote> (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>Committee</quote>).</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="H77B2FBB9A9A24F40BDD43362BD0B991B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Membership</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee shall be co-chaired by the Senior Director for Global Religion Engagement and
			 International Religious Freedom Promotion and the Ambassador at Large for
			 Religious Freedom described in section 101 of the International Religious
			 Freedom Act of 1998.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="H89A46A6BCFDB47689929B85B1DFD2968"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Functions</header><text>The Committee shall develop a religion engagement strategy globally and coordinate international
			 religious freedom policy across the Executive Branch.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD4852765FF7A4242B83DC506E32E0A77"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Interagency Policy Committee on Religion, Human rights, and National security</header>
							<paragraph id="H1242F9A7754F49D2B6F9B80AE59B958D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established within the National Security Council a permanent interagency policy committee
			 to be known as the <quote>Interagency Policy Committee on Religion, Human Rights, and National Security</quote> (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>Committee</quote>).</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="H1BFBC91364C1498CA2BFA9BF3999298A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Membership</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee shall be chaired by the Deputy National Security Advisor, the Assistant Secretary of
			 State for Democracy, Human Rights, and Labor, and the Ambassador at Large
			 for Religious Freedom described in section 101 of the International
			 Religious Freedom Act of 1998.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="H002206813AD04357A81C8E8810DC63D4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Functions</header><text>The Committee shall coordinate policy on the intersection of religion, human rights, and United
			 States interests in preventing terrorism, countering violent extremism,
			 and mitigating and preventing conflict.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8DDB317F25764122B2B2DEF53AB4100A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall promulgate
			 regulations to carry out subsections (k), (m), and (n) of section 101 of
			 the National Security Act of 1947 as amended by subsection (a) of this
			 section.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H91412C896A074308991CD6BEF4B1D6A6"><enum>11.</enum><header>Presidential actions in response to violations of religious freedom</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 401(b) of the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/6441">22 U.S.C. 6441(b)</external-xref>) is amended,</text>
			<paragraph id="H1D58C9EEF45D47B99851354218186A23"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>Special Adviser</quote> and inserting <quote>Senior Director</quote>; and</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H774522A918BD4B29A10FCE6EB0DE727C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (2) to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4C26CE805B8649AD9DDB935BA201BAFC" style="OLC">
					<paragraph id="H3F3F9774113641A380BE65F95F682F7A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deadline for Actions</header>
						<subparagraph id="H3A460F0B210A4860AE53302DA0857156"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), not later than 90 days after the date on which each of the
			 Annual Reports is submitted under section 102(b), the President shall take
			 1 or more of the actions referred to in section 405(a) or a commensurate
			 action with respect to each foreign country and violent nonstate actor
			 that has engaged in or tolerated violations of religious freedom at any
			 time since the previous such report was submitted.</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEF01B895F1A54BBFAF3BEE49C0F19FE2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Additional Prerequisite</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may not take any of the actions described in paragraphs (9) through (15) of section
			 405(a) or a commensurate action with respect to a foreign country or
			 violent nonstate actor until the President certifies that the requirements
			 under sections 403 and 404 have been satisfied with respect so such
			 country or actor.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HAF57ED437A554B46829563BE96C69285"><enum>12.</enum><header>Presidential actions in response to particularly severe violations of religious freedom</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 402 of the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/6442">22 U.S.C. 6442</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
			<paragraph id="H97DFF2EA1258477DA8B90E6F8EF3B78B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text>
				<subparagraph id="H1079D4EED5FF41BC9EC8F76B27E4328A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text>
					<clause id="H1E6C2FE15B604F4E968F98270EB26180"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by amending subparagraph (A) to read as follows:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8656FC5079494DDBAAA433BCCC2B5BEB" style="OLC">
							<subparagraph id="H77B347A0AD2F4ED299957AE78196FBD9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date on which each Annual Report is submitted under section
			 102(b), the President shall—</text>
								<clause id="HE16F8D09342D4A79A083A80B5EA68A78"><enum>(i)</enum><text>review the status of religious freedom in each foreign country to determine whether the government
			 of that country has engaged in or tolerated particularly severe violations
			 of religious freedom in each such country during the preceding 12 months
			 or longer; and</text>
								</clause><clause id="H157364CB9AEF48E3B42F1A10B6D2E8EA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>designate each country the government of which has engaged in or tolerated violations described in
			 clause (i) as a country of particular concern for religious freedom under
			 section 402(b).</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
					</clause><clause id="H66DAB339B2C04A619321FDAB2C696EB8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>prior to September 1 of the respective year</quote> and inserting <quote>before the date on which each Annual Report is submitted under section 102(b)</quote>;</text>
					</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC5E3F83E991C4D6B948E2CDE1C1747BA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (3) to read as follows:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9DC8CA5A0ADC446AB738535E338B6292" style="OLC">
						<paragraph id="H766B7414F0F64C8EBAF02C8EEE86CC7C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Congressional notification</header>
							<subparagraph id="H9B005A49B9B14653B300305E4A715115"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whenever the President designates a country as a country of particular concern for religious
			 freedom under paragraph (1)(A), the President shall, not later than 120
			 days after the designation is made, transmit to the appropriate
			 congressional committees—</text>
								<clause id="HEB7270AA8A2A4C31B128A1F750412730"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the designation of the country, signed by the President;</text>
								</clause><clause id="H2AED1A5F177E4AC498AAE3F4089979A4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the identification, if any, of responsible parties determined under paragraph (2); and</text>
								</clause><clause id="HF91A06D1680B4D5BB509C35F3E150872"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the actions taken under subsection (c), the purposes of the actions taken, and the
			 effectiveness of the actions taken.</text>
								</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H992B332A0B2D4CA993C5DFA1FA4976F6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Removal of Designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A country that is designated as a country of particular concern for religious freedom under
			 paragraph (1)(A) shall retain such designation until the President
			 determines and reports to the appropriate congressional committees that
			 the country should no longer be so designated.</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H32F8D279A70540CAB57A63E039F8DBEF"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Explanation for Nondesignation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the President does not designate a country as a country of particular concern for religious
			 freedom under paragraph (1)(A) after the Commission has recommended such
			 designation, the President shall provide an explanation for the
			 nondesignation to the appropriate congressional committees.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE4BFB394AFBC4E0F9053F9A5884B8A9A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end, the following new paragraph:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7BCF09C1F84A49F58D30320A92C1929F" style="OLC">
						<paragraph id="H5CBAD1F79FBA4E65831CED465965A3F5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Treatment of countries on Special Watch List</header>
							<subparagraph id="H303A0108791A4052A5A1DB1B511EF08E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall designate as a country of particular concern for religious freedom under
			 paragraph (1)(A) any country that appears on the Special Watch List—</text>
								<clause id="H5D346CBD50AD43B8BA29362BA2829D77"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in more than 2 consecutive Annual Reports;</text>
								</clause><clause id="HC3C2C02B2E434A6CBA3E09A1008B31AF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in any 4 Annual Reports;</text>
								</clause><clause id="HB93A49831CE14FD9B1B8CFC14009CCAD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in more than 1 Annual Report after the expiration of a waiver issued under subparagraph (B); and</text>
								</clause><clause id="H3C6C1F162CE14696BFAD38B6F58D5D98"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>in more than 1 Annual Report if the President has previously designated such country as a country
			 of particular concern for religious freedom under paragraph (1)(A).</text>
								</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F57EAA7625D49AF84705529B5EA48E3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exercise of Waiver Authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may waive the application of clauses (i) or (ii) of subparagraph (A) with respect to
			 a country for up to 2 years if the President certifies to the appropriate
			 committees of Congress that—</text>
								<clause id="HD0E14DF47C6845B088ECCB8436E2CFC2"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the country has entered into an agreement with the United States to carry out specific and credible
			 actions to improve religious freedom conditions and end religious freedom
			 violations;</text>
								</clause><clause id="H72943E45D64B4E41A75D5D72334632AC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the country has entered into an agreement with the United Nations, the European Union, or other
			 ally of the United States, to carry out specific and credible actions to
			 improve religious freedom conditions and end religious freedom violations;
			 or</text>
								</clause><clause id="H92D7882DE9B44B03B15AC860D4655DDE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">waiver is in the national security interests of the United States.</text>
								</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H96D491E9EDBB43529C878894C1A2BA72"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Effect on Designation as Country of Particular Concern</header><text>The presence or absence of a country from the Special Watch List in any given year shall not
			 preclude the designation of such country as a country of particular
			 concern for religious freedom under paragraph (1)(A) in any such year.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8085C52F0EF842C4802C75EA147AFC54"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(5), in the second sentence, by inserting <quote>and include a description of the impact of the designation of such sanction or sanctions that exist
			 in each country</quote> after <quote>determines satisfy the requirements of this subsection</quote>.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H582D8D56CD664145A6BFD19DADE37EA5"><enum>13.</enum><header>Consultations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subsection (a) of section 403 of the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/6443">22 U.S.C. 6443</external-xref>)
			 is amended by striking <quote>As soon as practicable</quote> and inserting <quote>Not later than 90 days</quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="H904111B406F84FB29BDFBB3B8FFEBA95"><enum>14.</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subsection (a) of section 404 of the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/6444">22 U.S.C. 6444</external-xref>)
			 is amended—</text>
			<paragraph id="H74102140121F4EFE9B166D20EE6CB199"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>decides to take action under section 401</quote> and inserting <quote>takes action under section 401</quote>;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HA0B38D8D8AF34431A9EEBDA6A10270C0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>decides to take action under paragraphs</quote> and inserting <quote>takes the required action under paragraphs</quote>; and</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HD16A4C01CDD84CCDB55CD7ADE1FCBFF7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)(A)—</text>
				<subparagraph id="H581817B1DB9C4B99B6870783F87AF0E3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding clause (i), by striking <quote>Special Adviser</quote> and inserting <quote>Senior Director</quote>;</text>
				</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2ACB2AD0E56742518ECAD95838A676A6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text>
				</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H15EFA20711994FAFADB358BEDE466C1C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in clause (iii), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text>
				</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCA5BA7619901413DBB5705A3154CD014"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new clause:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6A5BB121FC194BC4B3AAB8B9436ADB39" style="OLC">
						<clause id="H6D9445C5F1DC4AE0A85C0997CB31E5E0"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the impact on other policy tools, and a description of policy tools being applied in the country,
			 including programs that target democratic stability, economic growth, and
			 counterterrorism.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="HE684F5C6E22249C38B5470FA9A32469A"><enum>15.</enum><header>Presidential waiver</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 407 of the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/6447">22 U.S.C. 6447</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
			<paragraph id="H08BB2D0F57B44AEB8BD698D2D4DD0D18"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by inserting <quote>, for a 180-day period beginning on the date of the initial designation,</quote> after <quote>may waive</quote>; and</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H3B9788F677A74412901724C8045E6A3E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H093FA42F6D024516B333BEE2638C9188" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="HB197FBA56AFC4EB68111F6B3148CDCF5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that ongoing and persistent waivers for any country designated as a
			 country of particular concern for religious freedom under section 402(b)
			 for engaging in particularly severe violations of religious freedom do not
			 fulfill the purposes of this Act, and, given that promotion of religious
			 freedom is a compelling United States foreign policy priority, the
			 President, the Secretary of State, and other executive branch officials,
			 in consultation with Congress, should seek to find ways to address
			 existing violations, on a country-by-country basis, through the actions
			 specified in section 405 or other commensurate actions, possibly including
			 through the actions described in section 605, or by some other action that
			 addresses the specific religious freedom violations of each country
			 designated.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H1DF45214D7CF43D8BE90DFA84398F6FB"><enum>16.</enum><header>Termination of presidential actions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 409 of the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/6449">22 U.S.C. 6449</external-xref>) is amended to read
			 as follows:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H22FB737F985C45EFA72829E83968331F" style="OLC">
				<section id="H620B46086FA7418BA5C69514931932C5"><enum>409.</enum><header>Termination of presidential actions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Any Presidential action taken under this Act with respect to a foreign country shall terminate
			 after a determination by the President, in consultation with the
			 Commission, and written certification to Congress that the foreign
			 government has ceased or taken substantial and verifiable steps to cease
			 the particularly severe violations of religious freedom</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="H02F9567137AC422B86C44CCC5BB48D5A"><enum>17.</enum><header>Country of particular concern designation for violent nonstate actors</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title IV of the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/6441">22 U.S.C. 6441 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by
			 inserting after section 405 the following new section:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2DF5E6F3A4C24833898077BDA89E4094" style="OLC">
				<section id="H19F8A7423E914BDA88652C9F164107E5"><enum>405A.</enum><header>Sense of Congress regarding country of particular concern designation for violent nonstate actors</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that the country of particular concern for religious freedom
			 designation described in section 402(b) and the Presidential actions
			 described in 405 should be applicable to violent nonstate actors. The
			 President should include, in the report to Congress required by section
			 404, any reasons why such violent nonstate actors were not so designated
			 (if the Council recommended doing so) and whether any presidential actions
			 described in section 405 were taken against such violent nonstate actors</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="HF078D1CF65024D389C21D1E9F01CD6A5"><enum>18.</enum><header>Assistance for promoting religious freedom</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 501 of the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998 is amended by adding at the end the
			 following new subsections:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H73D013DD962A4FB481D8E10EC07DFC95" style="OLC">
				<subsection id="HC7F039244B1448C49B411824D74BF4A8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Availability of Amounts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the amounts made available for fiscal years 2016 through 2021 for the Human Rights and Democracy
			 Fund established under section 664 of the Freedom Investment Act of 2002
			 (subtitle E of title VI of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/107/228">Public Law 107–228</external-xref>), the Secretary of State
			 shall provide to the Office—</text>
					<paragraph id="H0F88CC4E7E574D47B7F863484D71FF92"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not less than 5 percent of such amounts for each such fiscal year for the promotion of
			 international religious freedom through groups that are able to develop
			 legal protections or promote cultural and societal understanding of
			 international norms of religious freedom and groups that seek to address
			 and mitigate religiously motivated and sectarian violence; and</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="HF26EC296FA574148AA56FB2B0A516DCA"><enum></enum><text>not less than 1 percent of such amounts for each such fiscal year for the Religious Freedom Defense
			 Fund established under subsection (d).</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H880E958439D6424BB0D5DB2B33D3A965"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Religious Freedom Defense Fund</header>
					<paragraph id="HDB6079EDC13B4243AE16A20FA9D856F2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established in the Department of State a fund to be known as the <quote>Religious Freedom Defense Fund</quote> (referred to in this subsection as the <quote>Fund</quote>) which shall be administered by the Ambassador at Large.</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="H66451792B0754E8AB420F11BBF663DC0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Amounts</header><text>The Fund shall consist of amounts made available under subsection (c)(2).</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="HF220F7A076C6429CB5DA54823C7C772C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of Fund</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Ambassador at Large shall use amounts in the Fund to issue grants for the following:</text>
						<subparagraph id="H528044C5F59E464FB65B99E6E5F3B4F0"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Victims of religious freedom abuses and their families to cover legal and other expenses that may
			 arise from detention, imprisonment, torture, fines, and other
			 restrictions.</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0EEF3DC56C7642528F042CB644C3D25A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Projects to help create and support a new generation of defenders of religious freedom, including
			 legal and political advocates, and civil society projects which seek to
			 create advocacy networks, train and educate new religious freedom
			 defenders, and build the capacity of religious communities and rights
			 defenders to protect against religious freedom violations, sectarian
			 violence, or legal or other restrictions of the right to the freedom of
			 religion and belief.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6288608B4C5C4028BAB90FD92EF0233F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Preference</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In issuing grants under paragraph (3), the Ambassador at Large shall, as appropriate, give
			 preference to projects targeting religious freedom violations in countries
			 designated as countries of particular concern for religious freedom under
			 section 402(b) and those included on the Special Watch List.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF7FBBD71682140B291281940A564D106"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Ambassador at Large should consult, in developing priorities and policies for disbursing the
			 funds referred to in subsection (c), including grant policies and the
			 identification of potential grantees, with other Federal agencies,
			 including the Commission, and the International Republican Institute, the
			 National Democratic Institute, the National Endowment for Democracy and,
			 as appropriate, other nongovernmental organizations.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="H940441230CDA4017AAC5DF75D61E0BFC"><enum>19.</enum><header>Actions against persons responsible for committing particularly severe violations of international
			 religious freedom</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title VI of the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/6471">22 U.S.C. 6471 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
			<paragraph id="H3ABDFDFC16F049089F538E16D1133ABA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating section 605 as section 606; and</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HF7AB4A96B8BD4666B9A1DF71BDEA58B0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after section 604 the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBFCB9AE9713140478567D893C23AFD37" style="OLC">
					<section id="H272CE1C14471430881CE380D5FE45ED9"><enum>605.</enum><header>Actions against persons responsible for committing particularly severe violations of international
			 religious freedom</header>
						<subsection id="H9D58B71651524B598FD51801278D5E08"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority To sanction persons responsible for committing or ordering particularly severe violations
			 of international religious freedom</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 202 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref>),
			 the President may exercise the authority specified in section 203 of such
			 Act with respect to—</text>
							<paragraph id="H798047D478CA411BA94CC185EF7AB9A7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any person that the President determines plays a role in committing, ordering, or materially
			 supporting particularly severe violations of religious freedom; or</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="H8E4E29C4A84E4B7D83D43CEC29598E71"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any person that the President determines to be providing material or other assistance supporting
			 violent religious extremism.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H78380F2C020347FEBE77B2E7B7256B26"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report to Congress on identification and sanction of persons responsible for particularly severe
			 violations of international religious freedom</header>
							<paragraph id="HE8AC5B90D8AD4650818B30A2C33F2227"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon exercising the authority described in subsection (a) with respect to a person, the President
			 shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report—</text>
								<subparagraph id="HAE45D49C7C0E4F7EBE408DBB40A074B1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identifying the persons that the President determines to be subject to action under subsection (a)
			 and the basis for such determination; and</text>
								</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E212AB7A4F94A86AF75E0D0BDA92BAD"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">describing the actions carried out against such persons pursuant to subsection (a).</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0571D81B581A4C48A8E5646FAD90C1A7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report on Removal of Sanctions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon suspending or terminating any action imposed on a person under the authority of subsection
			 (a), the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional
			 committees written notification of such suspension or termination.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="H1532E435B89B4C3387F6BE79CB7B8B2A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Submission of Classified Information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Reports submitted under this subsection shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may contain a
			 classified annex.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H23A87187760A4BB3B42A1395DF021DF4"><enum>20.</enum><header>Miscellaneous Provisions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title VII of the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/6481">22 U.S.C. 6481 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by
			 adding at the end the following new sections:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7DD353A291474589A3CE5958D0788DB4" style="OLC">
				<section id="H3EE28C21A31A4A16A61A6C2E5ED9F9AF"><enum>702.</enum><header>Codes of conduct for United States institutions of higher education outside the United States</header>
					<subsection id="H1BE8B378A15047E282647D03ABBFB247"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Finding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress recognizes the enduring importance of United States institutions of higher education
			 worldwide both for their potential for shaping positive leadership and new
			 educational models in host countries and for their emphasis on teaching
			 universally recognized rights of free inquiry and academic freedom.</text>
					</subsection><subsection id="H7154A200091F4DDDB21FE9BD945FDDB3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that United States institutions of higher education operating campuses
			 outside the United States or establishing any educational entities with
			 foreign governments, particularly with or in countries the governments of
			 which engage in or tolerate severe violations of religious freedom as
			 identified in the Annual Report and the annual report of the
			 Congressional-Executive Commission on China, should adopt a code of
			 conduct—</text>
						<paragraph id="H26CEE4FFCDC241369D77B849CAD82FBB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">upholding the right of freedom of religion of their employees and students, including the right to
			 manifest that religion peacefully as protected in international law;</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="H95B09619C14846219630ABE909466EAE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensuring that the religious views and peaceful practice of belief in no way affect, or be allowed
			 to affect, the status of a worker’s or faculty member’s employment or a
			 student’s enrollment; and</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="HEA933B39BE1D407A8AD3F047AF22C7B9"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">affirming that all negotiations, contracts, or memoranda of understanding engaged in or constructed
			 with a foreign government to establish any educational entity, shall be
			 open, transparent, and made available for public inspection before
			 conclusion and that any such agreement shall affirm, at all times,
			 academic freedom and universal rights to the freedoms of religion, speech,
			 assembly, and association.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HCB5A4218D6994551932FD1D4579E3FB5"><enum>703.</enum><header>Sense of Congress regarding national security strategy to promote religious freedom through United
			 States foreign policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text>
					<paragraph id="HACEC0D29EA51446CACEEF27A27D2377A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the annual national security strategy report of the President required by section 108 of the
			 National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3043">50 U.S.C. 3043</external-xref>) should promote
			 international religious freedom as a foreign policy and national security
			 priority and should articulate that promotion of the right to freedom of
			 religion or belief is a strategy that protects other, related human
			 rights, and advances democracy outside the United States, and make clear
			 its importance to United States foreign policy goals of stability,
			 security, development, and diplomacy;</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="H02C1DDED68A2465183CD99353B04BEB0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the national security strategy report should be a guide for the strategies and activities of
			 relevant Federal agencies and inform the Department of Defense quadrennial
			 defense review under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/118">section 118</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, and the
			 Department of State Quadrennial Diplomacy and Development Review; and</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="H99E1F71850AA488D86115A048A01E625"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in order to support the development of a national security strategy that emphasizes the challenges
			 of integrating religious freedom into United States foreign policy at all
			 levels, the President should consider—</text>
						<subparagraph id="H6283FDD63BBA4D87BC40FA4615F04A45"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">adopting a whole-of-government approach to promote international religious freedom by creating
			 senior policy positions and committees at the National Security Council,
			 chaired by the Senior Directors of the National Security Council and the
			 Ambassador at Large, and implemented through specific policy directives
			 that guide the actions of other Federal agencies; and</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H93124D276B064B09A3337BCC3E375384"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">requesting a national intelligence estimate on international religious freedom by the National
			 Intelligence Council or any other intelligence agency as appropriate,
			 which that analyzes conditions and trends of international religious
			 freedom and identifies potential national security risks related to the
			 absence of religious freedom, including threats to stability from
			 authoritarian governments, terrorism, violent religious extremism,
			 sectarian violence, and laws that restrict religious freedom.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H59BF513194C3490889F42EC1B88BC05B"><enum>704.</enum><header>Report on religious freedom conditions in Nigeria, Pakistan, and Vietnam</header>
					<subsection id="HC7542C3A7E4F4CC89FFFC355ABB71353"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of <short-title>Frank R. Wolf International Religious Freedom Act of 2014</short-title>, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the appropriate congressional
			 committees a report on whether religious freedom conditions are such that
			 the countries of Nigeria, Pakistan, and Vietnam meet the criteria for
			 designation as countries of particular concern for religious freedom under
			 section 402(b).</text>
					</subsection><subsection id="H47393783BDF744158AAFD6D39E6D74AC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General shall consult with the appropriate executive branch officials, appropriate
			 congressional committees, and governmental and nongovernmental
			 organizations for the purposes of preparing the report required by
			 subsection (a).</text>
					</subsection><subsection id="H7461B6B7B23B4CBFB70DF9E4D7D6F87B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Matters To be included</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required by subsection (a) shall include the following:</text>
						<paragraph id="HE2F17E50CA564A5F9C34B37DFC770E8E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A multiyear comparison of country reports on Nigeria, Pakistan, and Vietnam in the Annual Country
			 Reports on Human Rights Practices, the Annual Reports described in section
			 102(b), and the annual reports of the Commission.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="H995F38D06C4140E0AA1881D998A63EA3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A comparison of reports and publications on religious freedom conditions in Nigeria, Pakistan, and
			 Vietnam issued by foreign governments, nongovernmental organizations, and
			 academic entities, to the findings of the reports issued by the United
			 States.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="H15EAD4577558470F94727D1A9EA067E6"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Discussions with current and former United States officials, including Members of Congress,
			 Commissioners, and staff of the Commission, about religious freedom
			 conditions in Nigeria, Pakistan, and Vietnam, the requirements of this
			 Act, and United States national interests in such countries.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="H93BAD21136264A9995A3D3C68FD956B3"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Discussions with current and former United Nations Special Rapporteurs on Religion and Belief and
			 their staffs, about religious freedom conditions in Nigeria, Pakistan, and
			 Vietnam.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="H1536872A251648799B1AD909CF96078D"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Discussions with academic and other experts, including representatives of religions and ethnic
			 minority groups, about religious freedom conditions in Nigeria, Pakistan,
			 and Vietnam, the effect of United States advocacy for religious freedom in
			 such countries, and United States national interests in such countries.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="HD3FEBA7DA7E9456BA5034532CC6572D4"><enum>21.</enum><header>Clerical Amendments</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The table of contents of the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/6401">22 U.S.C. 6401</external-xref> note) is
			 amended—</text>
			<paragraph id="HDF46C5EEF3EB4D7D9660B5A80E53EF57"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by inserting after the item relating to section 405 the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2FD4C962C28549BF8C844F900FAD3F6F" style="OLC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 405A. Sense of Congress regarding country of particular concern designation for violent
			 nonstate actors.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H105C9EE89F07421EB57AC2C6CF24A106"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the item relating to section 605 and inserting the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF993AE597AD1491698BCA23D46FE95F4" style="OLC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 606. Studies on the effect of expedited removal provisions on asylum claims.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HC5EBCBFC80DF46C7B9737A37A3714DFB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after the item relating to section 604 the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2D6923716CD8421F867A62C977775447" style="OLC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 605. Actions against persons responsible for committing particularly severe violations of
			 international religious freedom.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				<continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">and</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="H838BACCE9F3B49F4AE2E4E5B11722B12"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3CC92170E53842A49C121B5C11966BC5" style="OLC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 702. Codes of conduct for United States institutions of higher education operating outside the
			 United States.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 703. Sense of Congress regarding national security strategy to promote religious freedom
			 through United States foreign policy.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 704. Report on religious freedom conditions in Nigeria, Pakistan, and Vietnam.</toc-entry>
					</toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body>
</bill>


