<bill session="113" type="s" number="2248" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-04-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-04-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Expand School Meals Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act and the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 to increase the number of children eligible for free school meals, with a phased-in transition period, with an offset.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412378"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2014-04-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Competition and antitrust"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Life, casualty, property insurance"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/10/2014--Introduced.
Expand School Meals Act of 2014 - Amends the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act and the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 to require the Secretary of Agriculture to gradually expand eligibility for free meals under the school lunch and breakfast programs to children whose family income falls at or below 185% of the federal poverty guidelines. (This makes children who are currently eligible for reduced price meals eligible for free meals.)

Requires the Secretary to: (1) begin this expansion in the school year beginning July 1, 2014, in states that have enacted a law under which school food authorities provide free breakfasts or lunches in lieu of reduced price breakfasts or lunches in schools statewide; and (2) continue such expansion in up to five additional states in each subsequent school through the school year beginning on July 1, 2019. Makes the new income eligibility guidelines effective on such date.

Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) deny a tax deduction for any amount paid or incurred for punitive damages in connection with any judgment in, or settlement of, any action; and (2) include in gross income any amount paid as insurance or otherwise due to liability for punitive damages.</summary>
</bill>
