<bill session="113" type="s" number="2041" updated="2015-09-01T17:50:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-11">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-06-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-02-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">May 31, 1918 Act Repeal Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">May 31, 1918 Act Repeal Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to repeal the Act of May 31, 1918, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300030"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412322" joined="2014-02-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-02-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-07">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 113-509.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-06-11" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-08-26">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Reported by Senator Tester under authority of the order of the Senate of 08/05/2014 with amendments. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-08-26" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="539">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 539.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-11-13">
      <text>By Senator Tester from Committee on Indian Affairs filed written report. Report No. 113-271.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="5050"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/26/2014--Reported to Senate amended.
May 31, 1918 Act Repeal Act - Repeals the Act of May 31, 1918 (authorized the Secretary of the Interior to set aside and reserve a tract of land within the Fort Hall Indian Reservation, Idaho, for town-site purposes).

Gives the Shoshone-Bannock Tribes of the Fort Hall Indian Reservation the exclusive right of first refusal to purchase at fair market value any land within the Fort Hall Townsite and offered for sale.

Directs the United States to hold in trust for the benefit of the Tribes or a member of the Tribes: (1) any land they owned or acquired within the Townsite before this Act's enactment, and (2) any land they owned or acquired within the Townsite on or after this Act's enactment.

Declares that, nothing in this Act affects any valid right to any land set aside or set apart under the 1918 Act.</summary>
</bill>
