<bill session="113" type="h" number="3606" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-29">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-05-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-11-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Emigrant Wilderness Historical Use Preservation Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Emigrant Wilderness Historical Use Preservation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To permit certain activities to be conducted on Federal land within the Emigrant Wilderness of Stanislaus National Forest in the State of California at the level at which such activities were conducted on such land before the wilderness designation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412295"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412403" joined="2013-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400297" joined="2013-11-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412581" joined="2013-11-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-11-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-06">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-29">
      <text>Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-29">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-05-29" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-09-15T16:37:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 113-595.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-09-15T16:37:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="442">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 442.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII10" subcommittee="Public Lands and Environmental Regulation" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/21/2013--Introduced.
Emigrant Wilderness Historical Use Preservation Act of 2013 - Declares that this Act modifies and supplements federal law applicable to the Emigrant Wilderness of the Stanislaus National Forest in California.

Directs the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) to ensure that, within the Emigrant Wilderness, the level of use, allotted user days, and activities by commercial outfitters and guides shall not rise above or be restricted below the historical level of use, allotted user days, and activities by commercial outfitters and guides within that area that existed as of the original designation of the Wilderness on January 3, 1975.

Prohibits any increase or reduction in the level of commercial pack and saddle stock use from the highest level of such use in the preceding 10 years.

Allows the historical use of trails, roads, paths, campsites, meadows, and cross-country areas in the Wilderness by recreational and commercial pack and saddle stock to continue.

States that the use of drift fences that are in existence or were previously in existence at the time of the Wilderness' designation shall be allowed and maintained.</summary>
</bill>
