<bill session="113" type="s" number="2503" updated="2015-09-01T17:51:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bill Williams River Water Rights Settlement Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of the Interior to enter into the Big Sandy River-Planet Ranch Water Rights Settlement Agreement and the Hualapai Tribe Bill Williams River Water Rights Settlement Agreement, to provide for the lease of certain land located within Planet Ranch on the Bill Williams River in the State of Arizona to benefit the Lower Colorado River Multi-Species Conservation Program, and to provide for the settlement of specific water rights claims in the Bill Williams River watershed in the State of Arizona.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400134"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="2014-06-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-19">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3864"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-09">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 113-419.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="4924"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/19/2014--Introduced.
Bill Williams River Water Rights Settlement Act of 2014 - Authorizes, ratifies, and confirms the Big Sandy River-Planet Ranch Water Rights Settlement Agreement between the Hualapai Tribe, the Department of of the Interior, the Arizona Game and Fish Commission, the Arizona Department of Water Resources, and the Freeport Minerals Corporation.

 Authorizes, ratifies, and confirms the Hualapai Tribe Bill Williams River Water Rights Settlement Agreement between the Tribe, the United States as trustee for the Tribe, and Freeport Minerals Corporation.

Directs the Secretary of Interior to execute both agreements.

 Sets forth provisions regarding the waiver, release, and retention of specified water rights claims.</summary>
</bill>
