<bill session="113" type="h" number="5290" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">COMMUTE Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Creating Opportunities for Military Members to Use Transportation Efficiently Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a Military Community Infrastructure Program to provide grants for transportation infrastructure improvements in military communities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412584"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2014-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412583" joined="2014-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Pedestrians and bicycling"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Regional and metropolitan planning"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/2014--Introduced.
Creating Opportunities for Military Members to Use Transportation Efficiently Act of 2014 or the COMMUTE Act of 2014 - Directs the Secretary of Defense, acting through the Director of the Office of Economic Adjustment, to establish a Military Community Infrastructure Program to provide grants to a state or political subdivision, a public transportation owner or operator, a local governmental authority, a metropolitan planning organization (MPO), or a regional transportation planning organization for transportation infrastructure improvement projects in military communities.

Directs the Secretary to conduct a traffic impact study for any urbanized area that expects a significant increase in traffic due to a military installation within or abutting such area.</summary>
</bill>
