<bill session="113" type="s" number="2485" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-17">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-09-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Northwest Atlantic Fisheries Convention Amendments Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Northwest Atlantic Fisheries Convention Amendments Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to implement the Amendment to the Convention on Future Multilateral Cooperation in the Northwest Atlantic Fisheries, as adopted at Lisbon on September 28, 2007.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400253"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-09-17" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-12-08">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Rockefeller without amendment. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-12-08" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="623">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 623.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-12-12">
      <text>By Senator Rockefeller from Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation filed written report. Report No. 113-316.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Atlantic Ocean"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/17/2014--Introduced.
Northwest Atlantic Fisheries Convention Amendments Act - Reauthorizes and amends the Northwest Atlantic Fisheries Convention Act of 1995, which provides for: (1) the implementation of the Convention on Future Multilateral Cooperation in the Northwest Atlantic Fisheries, done in Ottawa on October 24, 1978 (1978 Convention); and (2) the management and conservation of fish in the Conservation area (specified waters in the Northwest Atlantic Ocean).

 Provides for the implementation of the Convention on Cooperation in the Northwest Atlantic Fisheries, as adopted in Lisbon on September 28, 2007, which amends the 1978 Convention.

Applies this Act to all fish, mollusks, and crustaceans within the Convention, excluding: (1) sedentary species over which coastal states may exercise sovereign rights consistent with the United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea of 10 December 1982 (1982 Convention), and (2) anadromous and catadromous stocks and highly migratory species managed under other international treaties and listed in the 1982 Convention.

Applies this Act to vessels engaged in fishing activities, including fish harvesting vessels, fish processing vessels, vessels engaged in transshipment of fishery resources, and vessels engaged in experimental or exploratory fishing activities.

 Repeals provisions requiring the Secretary of Commerce to establish a new quota allocation practice.</summary>
</bill>
