<bill session="113" type="s" number="1277" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Combating Prescription Drug Abuse Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a commission for the purpose of coordinating efforts to reduce prescription drug abuse, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300011"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2014-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412582" joined="2014-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412542" joined="2013-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5706"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/10/2013--Introduced.
Combating Prescription Drug Abuse Act - Establishes the Combating Prescription Drug Abuse Commission, whose duties shall be to: (1) review and report to Congress on federal initiatives regarding efforts to prevent and reduce prescription drug abuse, (2) identify gaps and opportunities regarding the safe use of prescription drugs with the potential for diversion and abuse, and (3) make recommendations on specific ways to reduce diversion and abuse of prescription drugs.

Requires the report to describe Commission efforts to prevent or reduce drug diversion and abuse to ensure that patients continue to have access to medications and include specific recommendations for the Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA), the Food and Drug Administration (FDA), and other federal and state agencies concerning prescription drug monitoring and abuse.</summary>
</bill>
