<bill session="113" type="hj" number="125" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Authorization for Use of Military Force Against ISIL Resolution</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the use of United States Armed Forces against the terrorist organization Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant ("ISIL").</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400361"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400232" joined="2014-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2014-09-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/16/2014--Introduced.
Authorization for Use of Military Force Against ISIL Resolution - Authorizes the President to use the U.S. Armed Forces against the Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant (ISIL) in the territory of the Republic of Iraq and the Syrian Arab Republic. States that such territorial limitation shall not apply to U.S. Armed Forces training indigenous Syrian or regional military forces for the purpose of combating ISIL.

 States that:

 such authority does not authorize the deployment of ground forces in a combat role; "ground forces in a combat role" do not include special operations forces or other forces that may be deployed in a training, advisory, or intelligence capacity; and such authority shall terminate 18 months after enactment of this resolution. Declares that this Act is intended to constitute specific statutory authorization pursuant to the War Powers Resolution.

Directs the President to report to Congress at least once every 60 days on matters relevant to this joint resolution, including actions taken pursuant to the exercise of authority granted by this resolution and the status of planning for efforts that are expected to be required over the next 60 days.

Repeals the Authorization for Use of Military Force Against Iraq Resolution of 2002. Repeals, effective 18 months after enactment of this resolution, the Authorization for Use of Military Force.</summary>
</bill>
