<bill session="113" type="h" number="5893" updated="2015-09-01T17:50:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2015-01-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-01-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-01-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ansel Adams Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To restore the First Amendment Rights of Photographers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410396"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-01-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committees on Natural Resources, Agriculture, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-02">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-02">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-02">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-02">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="First Amendment rights"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="General public lands matters"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Life, casualty, property insurance"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Photography and imaging"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/2/2015--Introduced.
Ansel Adams Act - Declares that it is contrary to U.S. public policy to prohibit or restrict photography in public spaces, whether for private, news media, or commercial use.

Requires a federal agency, should it seek to restrict photography of its installations or personnel, to obtain a court order that outlines the national security or other reasons for the restriction. Instructs that such court order shall allow restrictions of such photography when it may lead to the endangerment of public safety or national security.

Prohibits any federal government agency from requiring fees, permits, or insurance as a condition to take still or moving images on federal lands, National Parks and Forests, and public spaces, whether for private, media, or commercial use.

Prohibits federal law enforcement officers or private contractors from seizing any photographic equipment or their contents or memory cards or film nor from ordering a photographer to erase the contents of a camera or memory card or film.</summary>
</bill>
