<bill session="113" type="hc" number="105" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-25T12:44:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-07-25T12:44:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Directing the President, pursuant to section 5(c) of the War Powers Resolution, to remove United States Armed Forces, other than Armed Forces required to protect United States diplomatic facilities and personnel, from Iraq.</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by house">Prohibiting the President from deploying or maintaining United States Armed Forces in a sustained combat role in Iraq without specific, subsequent statutory authorization.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400263"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2014-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="2014-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2014-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2014-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2014-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2014-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2014-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2014-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412315" joined="2014-07-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6127"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-23T15:47:00-04:00">
      <text>ORDER OF BUSINESS - Mr. Nugent asked unanimous consent that it be in order at any time to consider H.Con.Res. 105 in the House, if called up by the Chair of the Committee on Foreign Affairs or his designee; that the amendment printed in the portion of the Congressional Record designated for that purpose in clause 8 of rule XVIII and numbered 1 be considered as adopted; that the concurrent resolution, as amended, be considered as read; and that the previous question be considered as ordered on the concurrent resolution, as amended, to adoption without intervening motion or demand for division of the question except one hour of debate equally divided and controlled by Mr. Royce of California and Mr. McGovern of Massachusetts or their respective designees. Agreed to without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6695" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-25T10:18:00-04:00">
      <text>Consideration initiated pursuant to a previous order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-25T10:18:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered pursuant to a previous order.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6819-6825" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-25T10:18:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House of Wednesday, July 23, 2014, the amendment numbered 1 printed in the Congressional Record is considered adopted. The House proceeded with one hour debate on H.Con.Res. 105.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-25T11:04:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to a previous  order of the House.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6825"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-25T11:04:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H.Con.Res. 105, the Chair put the question on the adoption of the resolution, as amended, and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. McGovern demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question on adoption of the resolution, as amended, until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-25T12:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6833-6834" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="452" datetime="2014-07-25T12:44:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 370 - 40 (Roll no. 452).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6819" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-07-25T12:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-25T12:45:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-28">
      <text>Received in the Senate and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/25/2014--Passed House amended.
Prohibits the President from deploying or maintaining U.S. Armed Forces in a sustained combat role in Iraq without specific statutory authorization enacted after the adoption of this concurrent resolution.

States that nothing in this concurrent resolution supersedes the requirements of the War Powers Resolution.</summary>
</bill>
