<bill session="113" type="h" number="3549" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-11-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-11-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-11-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Adoption Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To promote permanent families for children, privacy and safety for unwed mothers, responsible fatherhood, and security for adoptive parents by establishing a National Responsible Father Registry and encouraging States to enter into agreements to contribute the information contained in the State's Responsible Father Registry to the National Responsible Father Registry, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412444"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400029" joined="2014-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400046" joined="2014-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412539" joined="2014-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412258" joined="2013-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412457" joined="2014-01-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400141" joined="2014-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412557" joined="2013-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400630" joined="2014-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412445" joined="2013-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412292" joined="2014-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412310" joined="2014-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="410396" joined="2014-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400400" joined="2013-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412213" joined="2013-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412255" joined="2013-12-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-11-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2439"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1203"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Marriage and family status"/>
    <term name="Separation, divorce, custody, support"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/20/2013--Introduced.
Protecting Adoption Act - Amends part B (Child and Family Services) of title IV of the Social Security Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish and maintain an automated National Responsible Father Registry.

Requires the Registry to: (1) contain specified kinds of information sufficient to identify a possible father, and (2) provide a mechanism for men to register such identifying information directly with the Registry.

Limits access to Registry information to eligible parties, including: (1) public and licensed private adoption or child placement agencies, (2) licensed attorneys representing a party in a planned or pending adoption or in the termination of rights of one or more possible fathers, (3) state agencies or entities responsible for the placement of children, and (4) state courts.

Directs the Secretary to establish a nationwide campaign designed to inform possible fathers, unwed mothers, possible adoptive parents, and eligible parties of the National Registry, the advantages of possible fathers registering either in the National Registry or State Responsible Father Registries, or both, the rights and responsibilities of such parties with regard to a proceeding, and the role of such Registries in a proceeding.

Directs the Secretary to use all reasonable efforts to encourage states to enter into agreements to establish automated State Responsible Father Registries and centers that make registration forms easily accessible to possible fathers.

Authorizes the Secretary to make a grant to a state to establish a State Registry or modify an existing one to meet the requirements of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
