<bill session="113" type="h" number="5560" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Helping College Students Cross the Finish Line Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to establish a grant program for undergraduate students with financial need to assist such students in completing degrees at institutions of higher education.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412208"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Training" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Financial literacy"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/18/2014--Introduced.
Helping College Students Cross the Finish Line Act - Amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require the Secretary of Education to award grants to institutions of higher education (IHEs) to establish a financial assistance program that awards funds to at least 100 of the IHE's undergraduate or vocational students each academic year who:

 are enrolled on at least a half-time basis; are academically able to complete the degree or certificate program in which they are enrolled within an academic year; are in good academic standing; if they previously received such an award, maintained good academic standing during the academic period for which they received such award; are unable to fully pay an outstanding tuition payment that is due; and without financial assistance, will discontinue the degree or certificate program in which they are enrolled. Caps the amount of such award. Prohibits a student from receiving an award for more than two semesters or the equivalent of two semesters.

Requires the IHEs to provide each student who receives an award that does not fully cover the amount due on the student's outstanding tuition with information on the financial assistance available from any other source.

Directs the Secretary to create, and each student that receives an award to complete, an online financial literacy survey that includes matters relating to budgeting and saving, student loan debt, and career planning.</summary>
</bill>
