<bill session="113" type="h" number="5500" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protect Veterans Employment and Training Services Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to protect employment and training services for veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400646"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412555" joined="2014-11-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR10" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="s" number="2834"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/17/2014--Introduced.
Protect Veterans Employment and Training Services Act of 2014 - Amends the disabled veterans' outreach program to authorize the Secretary of Labor to establish an order of priority for furnishing program services if state disabled veterans' outreach program specialists are unable to assist every eligible veteran seeking assistance.

Requires that priority order to be consistent with the program's purposes and the existing priority order of special disabled veterans, other disabled veterans, and other eligible veterans.

Allows a state disabled veterans' outreach program specialist to perform an initial intake and assessment of each veteran who seeks program services.

Authorizes local veterans' employment representatives to provide employment, training, and placement services directly to eligible veterans and eligible persons.

Requires those representatives to spend a majority of their time carrying out their principal duties of: (1) conducting outreach to local employers to assist veterans in gaining employment; and (2) facilitating the provision of state employment, training, and placement services to veterans.

Prohibits the Secretary from imposing restrictions on the duties that a state disabled veterans' outreach program specialist or a local veterans' employment representative may perform or the individuals they may assist other than those set forth in the law providing veterans with job counseling, training, and placement services.</summary>
</bill>
