<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 S3006 IS: To require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to use existing authorities to furnish health care at non-Department of Veterans Affairs facilities to veterans who live more than 40 miles driving distance from the closest medical facility of the Department that furnishes the care sought by the veteran.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2014-12-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 3006</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20141211">December 11, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S347">Mr. Moran</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to use existing authorities to furnish health care at
			 non-Department of Veterans Affairs facilities to veterans who live more
			 than 40 miles driving distance from the closest medical facility of the
			 Department that
			 furnishes the care sought by the veteran.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body><section id="id499B7DA77AF04C348680482762FB0D95" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Use of existing Department of Veterans Affairs authorities to furnish health care to certain
			 veterans who have geographic inaccessibility to care</header><subsection id="id5873B773E0C64489B917175ED0CE491E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall use the authorities specified in subsection (b) to furnish
			 hospital care and medical services at non-Department of Veterans Affairs
			 facilities to veterans who  reside more than 40 miles driving distance
			 from the closest
			 medical facility of the Department to the residence of the veteran that
			 furnishes the hospital care or medical services that are sought by the
			 veteran, including a community-based outpatient clinic.</text></subsection><subsection id="id37E51FD8DF134AC9BC05E16DCA7F9153"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The authorities specified in this subsection are the following:</text><paragraph id="idb6330fe721b7470f99bedf0cfe22f087"><enum>(1)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/1703">Section 1703</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, relating to contracts for the furnishing of hospital
			 care and medical services through non-Department facilities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idAA4127FB5466439390664097132B3F78"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 101 of the Veterans Access, Choice, and Accountability Act of
			 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/146">Public Law 113–146</external-xref>; 128 Stat. 175), relating to the furnishing of
			 hospital care and medical services to veterans through non-Department
			 entities if the veteran is unable to schedule an appointment for the
			 receipt of such care or services within the wait-time goals of the
			 Veterans Health Administration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5A9AD1A4705145878AC9ADF98224E455"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any other authority under the laws administered by the Secretary relating to the furnishing of
			 hospital care and medical services at non-Department facilities.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idA900A9F2BF1A41CB8BA98DE65851CB94"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Hospital care and medical services</header><text>In this section, the terms <term>hospital care</term> and <term>medical services</term> have the meanings given such terms in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/1701">section 1701</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


