<bill session="113" type="h" number="3358" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-10-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-10-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fairness for Individuals Using Exchange Websites Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for an exemption from the individual mandate under the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act for individuals residing in States in which the Exchange Websites are not fully functional, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412540"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400029" joined="2013-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400071" joined="2013-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412426" joined="2013-11-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-28">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-28">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/28/2013--Introduced.
Fairness for Individuals Using Exchange Websites Act of 2013 - Requires the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to certify the website of a health care exchange once it is determined, based upon criteria specified by the Comptroller General (GAO) after enactment of this Act, to be fully functional for the purpose of enrollment in qualified health plans.

Amends the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to require an exchange for which the website is certified under this Act after December 31, 2013, to provide a special enrollment period of at least three months after the date of certification. Amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to the penalty for failure to maintain minimum essential coverage, to exempt: (1) individuals residing in states for which an exchange is uncertified, and (2) individuals residing in states with websites certified after December 31, 2013, for months during the special enrollment period.</summary>
</bill>
