<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HDA4B94F2A8DD44C2A9E9694A3C102555" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HR 3882 IH: National Security Agency Accountability Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2014-01-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress>113th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>H. R. 3882</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20140115">January 15, 2014</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001083">Mr. Carney</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the <committee-name committee-id="">Select Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select)</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Comptroller General to produce annual reports on programs under the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1DB189F8F1AE4C3DB2120129B0A96016" style="OLC"><section id="HF8E47D8EC97942B6ADA217F4074B3024" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Security Agency Accountability Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H8E47455276B146EC98248C1857FE0A0A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Annual report by the Comptroller General on programs under the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978</header><subsection id="HFCA2CC90A05648E3A798EB09465D11A0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title VI of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1871">50 U.S.C. 1871 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC5C22754E8474F978AEEE6C7FE7B85B9" style="OLC"><section id="H07323C059762458C9146EBAA44B9DAAB"><enum>602.</enum><header>Annual report by the Comptroller General</header><subsection id="H2CD563AE53A64C379370429E58AFC6A0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States shall annually submit to the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Select Committee on Intelligence and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate a report on the effectiveness of the programs and activities carried out under this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H610C036C6F384A6AA5A0D292314A5B74"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each report under subsection (a) shall include—</text><paragraph id="H574F3EB67A364FB4BD3C11E441473BC7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an analysis of the restrictions placed on access to information obtained under this Act;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2771E8903D70474BB946464460AA719A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the number of incidents of non-compliance with this Act or any rule, regulation, policy, or procedure to carry out this Act;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD2574A6C199541B3B263C9B5823703E7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a description of actions taken in response to incidents of non-compliance described in paragraph (2);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF9F318CB7BBE468A94823EE29A36989D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a description of the minimization procedures used to carry out each provision of this Act;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5C547242C9BC4E34946BE09A8690F2FB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>a description of how such minimization procedures are verified to be in use and effective;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1C55B05F6CC547B3A5B3BB3C2A5D536A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the number of applications made under each appropriate provision of this Act, the number of such applications approved by a court, and the number of times such applications resulted in an oral argument before the court;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB3788D0B0D5C44C6B6284029F756659E"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the number of times employees of or contractors to the National Security Agency search information acquired under this Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE6ED11B5CDEA41209C381EA08671046A"><enum>(8)</enum><text>any other information the Comptroller General considers appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA2F1BB3633954D9DA131E6C3F73E20C4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Public disclosure</header><text>At the time of submission of each report required under subsection (a), the Comptroller General shall make publicly available an unclassified summary of such report.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HF136641D57264404B85B61B9F3D61314"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents amendment</header><text>The table of contents in the first section of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 601 the following new item:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0F91A02A917844B59D73FEDC48C7B6ED" style="OLC"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 602. Annual report by the Comptroller General.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


