<bill session="113" type="s" number="2961" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-11-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-11-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-11-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Office of Planning for Future Intercity Transportation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Office of Planning for Future Intercity Transportation within the Office of the Secretary of Transportation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412326"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-11-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/20/2014--Introduced.
Office of Planning for Future Intercity Transportation Act - Directs the Secretary of Transportation (DOT) to establish within the Office of the Secretary the Office of Planning for Future Intercity Transportation (Office), headed by the Assistant Secretary for Intercity Transportation Planning.

Requires the Office to be composed of:

 the Office of High-Speed Rail Policy, the Office of High-Speed Planning, and the Office of High-Speed Rail Operations and Safety. Requires the Assistant Secretary to oversee the planning, development, construction, financing, funding, and operation of high-speed rail in selected corridors throughout the United States.

Directs the Secretary to report to Congress the results of a feasibility study that identifies and prioritizes corridors that offer the best opportunity to provide point-to-point high-speed intercity passenger rail service.</summary>
</bill>
