<bill session="113" type="s" number="2887" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Accessible Transportation for All Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to expand access to transportation services for individuals with disabilities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300051"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5790"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5790-5792" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/18/2014--Introduced.
Accessible Transportation for All Act - Requires owners or operators of a for-hire transportation company, taxi service, or transportation network company to provide accessible vehicles for hire by disabled individuals in need of transportation services.

Prohibits discrimination against disabled individuals in the provision of for-hire transportation services.

Requires the Administrator of the Federal Transit Administration (FTA) to organize a national competition for U.S. automobile manufacturers to design one or more model accessible taxi vehicles and model accessible passenger cars.

Establishes in the FTA an Accessible Taxi and For-Hire Transportation Board.

Requires states to develop a strategic plan to increase the availability of accessible taxi vehicles, accessible vehicles for hire, and other accessible for-hire transportation options for people with disabilities.

Directs the Administrator, in collaboration with the U.S. Access Board, to promulgate accessibility and service standards for accessible taxi vehicles and accessible vehicles for hire to ensure that they are fully accessible to, and usable by, passengers with disabilities.

Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a tax credit for expenditures incurred by a small business that is a qualified taxi company in purchasing or adapting a vehicle for use as an accessible taxi vehicle.</summary>
</bill>
