<bill session="113" type="h" number="5183" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Value Based Insurance Design for Better Care Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">VBID for Better Care Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a demonstration program requiring the utilization of Value-Based Insurance Design to demonstrate that reducing the copayments or coinsurance charged to Medicare beneficiaries for selected high-value prescription medications and clinical services can increase their utilization and ultimately improve clinical outcomes and lower health care expenditures.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412478"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2014-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412462" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412202" joined="2014-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412428" joined="2014-09-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-23">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-23">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="s" number="2783"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/23/2014--Introduced.
Value Based Insurance Design for Better Care Act of 2014 or the VBID for Better Care Act of 2014 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish a three-year demonstration program to test the use of value-based insurance design methodologies under the eligible Medicare plans offered by Medicare Advantage organizations under part C (Medicare+Choice) of title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act.

Defines "value-based insurance design methodology" as one for identifying specific prescription medications, and clinical services reimbursable under Medicare, for which copayments, coinsurance, or both should be reduced or eliminated because of the high-value and effectiveness of these medications and services for specific chronic clinical conditions (as approved by the Secretary).

Directs the Secretary to expand the demonstration program to implement, on a permanent basis, those components beneficial to Medicare beneficiaries and the Medicare program, unless a required evaluation of the program states that it: (1) increases expenditures under Medicare with respect to participating beneficiaries, or (2) decreases the quality of health care services furnished to such beneficiaries.</summary>
</bill>
