<bill session="113" type="h" number="5193" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans' Credit Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to conduct outreach to veterans regarding the effect of delayed payments by the Veterans Integrated Service Networks and to direct the Secretary to submit to Congress an annual report regarding such delayed payments.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400636"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412269" joined="2014-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412271" joined="2014-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412599" joined="2014-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412432" joined="2014-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412261" joined="2014-07-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-08-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR03" subcommittee="Health" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2654"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/24/2014--Introduced.
Veterans' Credit Protection Act - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) to: (1) conduct outreach to inform veterans of how to resolve credit issues caused by a delayed payment (i.e., a proper invoice that is not paid by the Secretary until after the required payment date); and (2) establish a toll-free telephone number for veterans to report such issues to the Veterans Integrated Service Networks.

Requires the Secretary to report annually on the effectiveness of each Network in providing timely payment of proper invoices during both the preceding five-year period and the preceding one-year period. Requires such report to include:

 the number of veterans who contacted the Secretary regarding delayed payments that could negatively affect their credit; the total amount of interest penalties paid by the Secretary by reason of delayed payments; the number of proper invoices submitted, the amount owed for and the payment status of such invoices, and the periods that elapsed before such invoices were paid; any comments regarding delayed payments made by medical providers; identification of the Networks with the least and most delayed payments; and a description of the best practices to provide timely payment of a proper invoice, including a plan for under-performing Networks to improve. Directs the Comptroller General (GAO) to conduct a study that compares the effectiveness of Networks in providing timely payment of proper invoices.</summary>
</bill>
