<bill session="113" type="s" number="1660" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-11-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-11-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-11-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SPORT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sportsmen's and Public Outdoor Recreation Traditions Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to protect and enhance opportunities for recreational hunting, fishing, and shooting, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412324"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2013-11-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412281" joined="2013-11-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300080" joined="2013-11-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2013-11-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="2013-11-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412321" joined="2013-11-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-11-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="263"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1206"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2463"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3590"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3590"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3962"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="51"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="170"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="738"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1212"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1335"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1505"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1634"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1996"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2363"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Agricultural practices and innovations"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Art, artists, authorship"/>
    <term name="Birds"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Farmland"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Hunting and fishing"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Mammals"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Pest management"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Television and film"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/6/2013--Introduced.
Sportsmen's and Public Outdoor Recreation Traditions Act or the SPORT Act - Title I: Regulatory Reforms - Amends the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 to exempt from sequestration the following budget accounts: Federal Aid in Wildlife Restoration, Sport Fish Restoration, and Wildlife Restoration.

Amends the Toxic Substances Control Act (TSCA) to exclude from the definition of "chemical substance" for purposes of such Act: (1) any component of any pistol, revolver, firearm, shell, or cartridge the sale of which is subject to federal excise tax, including shot, bullets and other projectiles, propellants, and primers; and (2) any sport fishing equipment the sale of which is subject to federal excise tax and sport fishing equipment components.

Grants the Secretary of the Interior permanent authority to authorize any state to issue electronic duck stamps.

Sets forth state electronic duck stamp application requirements.

Allows the Secretary to determine the number of new states permitted per year to participate in the electronic duck stamp program.

Instructs the Secretary to require electronic stamp revenue and customer information collected by each state to be transmitted in accordance with a written agreement between the Secretary and the state.

Amends the Marine Mammal Protection Act of 1972 to direct the Secretary of the Interior to issue a permit for the importation of any polar bear part (other than an internal organ) from a polar bear taken in a sport hunt in Canada to any person who submits proof that the polar bear was legally harvested before May 15, 2008 (currently by February 18, 1997), when polar bears were listed as a threatened species by the Department of the Interior.

Amends the Pittman-Robertson Wildlife Restoration Act to: (1) authorize a state to pay up to 90% of the costs of acquiring land for, expanding, or constructing a public target range; (2) authorize a state to elect to allocate 10% of a specified amount apportioned to it from the federal aid to wildlife restoration fund for such costs; (3) limit the federal share of such costs under such Act to 90%; and (4) require amounts provided for such costs under such Act to remain available for expenditure and obligation for five fiscal years.

Shields the United States from any civil action or claim for money damages for injury to or loss of property, personal injury, or death caused by an activity occurring at a public target range that is funded by the federal government pursuant to such Act or located on federal land, except to the extent provided under the Federal Tort Claims Act with respect to the exercise or performance of a discretionary function.

Urges the Chief of the Forest Service and the Director of BLM to cooperate with state and local authorities and other entities to carry out waste removal and other activities on any federal land used as a public target range to encourage its continued use for target practice or marksmanship training.

Amends the Migratory Bird Treaty Act to permit the taking of any migratory game bird, including waterfowl, coots, and cranes, on or over land that: (1) is not a baited area; and (2) contains a standing crop (including an aquatic crop), standing, flooded, or manipulated natural vegetation, flooded harvested cropland, or an area on which seed or grain has been scattered solely as the result of a normal agricultural practice.

Requires the Secretary and the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA), for any film crew of five persons or fewer, to require a permit and assess an annual fee of $200 for commercial filming activities or similar projects on federal land and waterways administered by the Secretary. Makes such a permit valid for such activities or projects that occur in areas designated for public use during public hours on all federal land and waterways administered by the Secretary for a one-year period. Allows an applicable land management agency to deny access to a film crew if: (1) there is a likelihood of resource damage that cannot be mitigated, (2) there would be an unreasonable disruption of the public use and enjoyment of the site, (3) the activity poses public health or safety risks, and (4) the filming includes the use of models or props that are not part of the land's natural or cultural resources or administrative facilities.

Title II: Improving Access - Amends the Land and Water Conservation Fund Act of 1965 to direct the Secretary and the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) to ensure, from amounts requested for the Land and Water Conservation Fund per fiscal year, that not less than the greater of 1.5% of the requested amounts or $10 million be made available for certain projects identified on an annual priority list to be developed pursuant to this Act.

Requires projects identified on such a list to secure, through rights-of-way or the acquisition of lands or interests from willing sellers, recreational public access to existing federal public lands that have significantly restricted access to hunting, fishing, and other recreational purposes.

Amends the Federal Land Transaction Facilitation Act (FLTFA) to revoke provisions that terminate: (1) the authority provided under such Act, and (2) the Federal Land Disposal Account. Makes the FLTFA inapplicable to land eligible for sale under specified public land laws. Requires a federal public land management official, in cooperation with the respective state and fish and wildlife agency, to exercise the authority of the official under law, including regarding land use planning, to facilitate the use of, and access to, federal public land for hunting, recreational fishing, and recreational shooting, except as described in this Act. Requires the heads of federal public land management agencies to exercise their discretion in a manner that supports and facilitates hunting, recreational fishing, and recreational shooting opportunities, to the extent authorized under applicable law.

Requires that Bureau of Land Management (BLM) and Forest Service land, excluding land on the Outer Continental Shelf, be open to hunting, recreational fishing, or recreational shooting unless the managing agency acts to close lands to such activity. Permits closures or restrictions on such land for purposes including resource conservation, public safety, energy or mineral production, energy generation or transmission infrastructure, water supply facilities, national security, or compliance with other law.

Allows agencies to: (1) lease or permit use of federal public land for recreational shooting ranges, and (2) designate specific land for recreational shooting activities. Excepts from such use or designation land including a component of the National Wilderness Preservation System, land designated as a wilderness study area or administratively classified as wilderness eligible or suitable, and primitive or semiprimitive areas.

Requires annual reports on closures of federal public lands to hunting, recreational fishing, or recreational shooting. Sets forth requirements for specified closures or significant restrictions involving 1280 or more contiguous acres of federal public land or water to hunting or recreational fishing or related activities.

Instructs federal public land agencies to consult with the advisory councils specified in Executive Orders 12962 (relating to recreational fisheries) and 13443 (relating to the facilitation of hunting heritage and wildlife conservation) in carrying out this Act.

Requires each head of a federal public land management agency (the National Park Service, the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, the U.S. Forest Service, and the Bureau of Land Management [BLM]), to annually make available to the public on its website a report that includes: (1) a list of the land more than 640 acres in size under its jurisdiction on which the public is allowed to hunt, fish, or use such land for other recreational purposes and to which there is no public access or egress or to which such access or egress to the land's legal boundaries is significantly restricted; (2) a list of locations and acreage on such land that the agency head determines have significant potential for use for hunting, fishing, and other recreational purposes; and (3) a plan to provide such access and egress that is consistent with the travel management plan in effect.

Requires each agency head to make available to the public on the agency's website, and thereafter revise, a list of roads or trails that provide the primary public access and egress to the legal boundaries of contiguous parcels of land equal to more than 640 acres in size under the agency's jurisdiction on which the public is allowed to hunt, fish, or use such lands for other recreational purposes.

Title III: Habitat Conservation - Amends the North American Wetlands Conservation Act to extend through FY2017 the authorization of appropriations for allocations to carry out approved wetlands conservation projects.

Reauthorizes and revises the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation Establishment Act. Requires the Secretary of the Interior to appoint 28 directors (currently, 23) who are knowledgeable and experienced in matters relating to conservation of fish, wildlife, or other natural resources and represent a balance of expertise in ocean, coastal, freshwater, and terrestrial resource conservation. Removes limitations on the appointment of such Foundation's officers and employees. Requires the Foundation's Executive Director to be appointed by and serve at the direction of the Board as the chief executive officer and to be knowledgeable and experienced in matters relating to fish and wildlife conservation.

Gives the Foundation the power to receive and administer restitution and community service payments, amounts for mitigation of impacts to natural resources, and other amounts arising from legal, regulatory, or administrative proceedings, subject to the condition that the amounts are received or administered for purposes that further the conservation and management of fish, wildlife, plants, and other natural resources.

Repeals provisions authorizing the Foundation to establish a national whale conservation endowment fund.

Authorizes appropriations for the Foundation for FY2014-FY2019.

Authorizes the Foundation to: (1) assess and collect fees for the management of amounts received from federal agencies; and (2) use such federal funds for matching contributions made by private persons, state and local agencies, and other entities (current law requires such use).

Amends the Multinational Species Conservation Funds Semipostal Stamp Act of 2010 to require the Multinational Species Conservation Funds Semipostal Stamp to be made available to the public for an additional four years.

Amends the Partners for Fish and Wildlife Act to extend through FY2018 the authorization of appropriations to carry out such Act.</summary>
</bill>
