<bill session="113" type="h" number="5125" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Wi-Fi Innovation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To promote unlicensed spectrum use in the 5 GHz band, to maximize the use of the band for shared purposes in order to bolster innovation and economic development, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412256"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="2014-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400196" joined="2014-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400663" joined="2014-07-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF16" subcommittee="Communications and Technology" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2505"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission (FCC)"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/16/2014--Introduced.
Wi-Fi Innovation Act - Requires the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to provide additional unlicensed spectrum in the 5850-5925 megahertz band under technical rules suitable for the widespread commercial development of unlicensed operations.

Provides for such technical rules to permit outdoor unlicensed operations without requiring devices to dynamically detect signals from other systems.

Directs the FCC's Office of Engineering and Technology to seek public comments on proposals for interference-mitigation techniques and potential rechannelization that would accommodate both incumbent licensees and widespread commercial unlicensed operations in such band.

Sets forth a process for the FCC to test mitigation measures and methods of sharing spectrum with unlicensed devices within such band in a manner that would not cause harmful interference to incumbent licensees.

Directs the FCC, if it determines that existing licensees would not be harmed by interference, to modify regulations to adopt technical rules for widespread commercial deployment of unlicensed operations for such band. Prohibits modification of such regulations if the FCC determines that mitigation, rechannelization, or sharing would not prevent harmful interference. Requires the FCC to notify Congress, the Department of Transportation (DOT), and the National Telecommunications and Information Administration (NTIA) of a harmful interference determination.

Requires the FCC to modify regulations relating to Intelligent Transportation Systems radio service and dedicated short-range communications service on-board units if such modification would maximize utility of such band while protecting existing licensees.

Directs the FCC to make recommendations to Congress regarding the availability of broadband Internet access using unlicensed spectrum and wireless networks in low income neighborhoods.</summary>
</bill>
