<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public">
  <metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 S2915 IS: To designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 4000 Leap Road in Hilliard, Ohio, as the “Master Sergeant Shawn T. Hannon, Master Sergeant Jeffrey J. Rieck and Veterans Memorial Post Office Building”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-11-12</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
    <congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session>2d Session</session>
    <legis-num>S. 2915</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
    <action>
      <action-date date="20141112">November 12, 2014</action-date>
      <action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S349">Mr. Portman</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S307">Mr. Brown</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
    <official-title>To designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 4000 Leap Road in
			 Hilliard, Ohio, as the <quote>Master Sergeant Shawn T. Hannon, Master Sergeant Jeffrey J. Rieck and Veterans Memorial Post Office
			 Building</quote>.</official-title>
  </form>
  <legis-body style="OLC">
    <section id="HFF425416E06E448CA9CC7C706AF0E6D9" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Master Sergeant Shawn T. Hannon, Master Sergeant Jeffrey J. Rieck and Veterans Memorial Post Office
			 Building</header>
      <subsection id="H2F3ED64A356D4B079523DAF1119DE1FE">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Designation</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The facility of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1800" entity-type="federal-body">United States Postal Service</cato:entity-ref> located at 4000 Leap Road in Hilliard, Ohio, shall
			 be known and designated as the <quote>Master Sergeant Shawn T. Hannon, Master Sergeant Jeffrey J. Rieck and Veterans Memorial Post Office
			 Building</quote>.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H7B0D9BB2D63B407EA367993355F9C1D4">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>References</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any reference in a law, map, regulation, document, paper, or other record of the United States to
			 the facility referred to in subsection (a) shall be deemed to be a
			 reference to the <quote>Master Sergeant Shawn T. Hannon, Master Sergeant Jeffrey J. Rieck and Veterans Memorial Post Office
			 Building</quote>.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>