<bill session="113" type="sr" number="319" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-01-07">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-01-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-12-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution expressing support for the Ukrainian people in light of President Yanukovych's decision not to sign an Association Agreement with the European Union.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412194"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2013-12-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2013-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412573" joined="2013-12-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2013-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412496" joined="2013-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2013-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2013-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412322" joined="2013-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412491" joined="2013-12-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2013-12-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-12-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8776" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-12-18" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-12-18">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Menendez without amendment and with a preamble. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-12-18" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="274">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 274.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2014-01-07" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>Resolution agreed to in Senate without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S82-83" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S83" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="European Union"/>
    <term name="Foreign property"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Ukraine"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/7/2014--Passed Senate without amendment.
Supports the sovereign right of the people of Ukraine to chart an independent and democratic future for their country.

Urges U.S. and European leaders to work together to support a peaceful and democratic resolution to the current crisis that moves Ukraine toward a future in the Euro-Atlantic community and a long-term solution to Ukraine's economic crisis.

Encourages demonstrators and members of the opposition and civil society in Ukraine to avoid violence and engage in a dialogue of national reconciliation.

Urges all political parties to refrain from hate speech or actions of an anti-Semitic or other character which further divide the Ukrainian people.

Calls on the government of Ukraine to respect the internationally recognized human rights of the Ukrainian people, especially the freedoms of speech and assembly.

Condemns the decision by Ukrainian authorities to use violence against peaceful demonstrators and calls for those responsible to be brought to justice and all detained nonviolent demonstrators to be released.

States that, in the event of further state violence against peaceful protestors, the President and Congress should consider whether to apply targeted sanctions, including visa bans and asset freezes, against individuals responsible for ordering or carrying out the violence.</summary>
</bill>
