<bill session="113" type="h" number="4062" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-02-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-02-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-02-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Homeowner Tax Fairness Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to extend the income exclusion for discharge of qualified principal residence indebtedness, to provide exclusions from income for certain payments under the National Mortgage Settlement, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400262"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2014-03-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-02-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E216"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/14/2014--Introduced.
Homeowner Tax Fairness Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) extend through 2016 the exclusion from gross income of income attributable to the discharge of indebtedness on a principal residence, (2) extend through 2015 the tax deduction for mortgage insurance premiums, (3) exclude from gross income any National Mortgage Settlement amount, and (4) deny a tax deduction for any National Mortgage Settlement amount that was paid in exchange for a full release of the potential civil claims of the United States under the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act. .

Defines "National Mortgage Settlement amount" as any amount received pursuant to the settlement in a legal action against Bank of America Corporation filed in U.S. District Court on March 12, 2012, which is: (1) a payment for transitional assistance; (2) a payment from the Borrower Payment Fund under the National Mortgage Settlement to a borrower whose home was finally sold or taken in foreclosure after December 31, 2007, and before January 1, 2014; or (3) a payment received as a result of a foreclosure or excess charge of interest that the Department of Justice (DOJ) has determined was not in compliance with the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act.</summary>
</bill>
