<bill session="113" type="h" number="4802" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-22T16:29:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-07-22T16:29:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Airport Security Enhancement Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Gerardo Hernandez Airport Security Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Gerardo Hernandez Airport Security Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve intergovernmental planning for and communication during security incidents at domestic airports, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412550"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400654" joined="2014-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412432" joined="2014-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="2014-06-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11">
      <text>Subcommittee on Transportation Security Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-06-11" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-07-03T13:37:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Homeland Security. H. Rept. 113-512.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-07-03T13:37:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="384">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 384.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-07-22T16:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hudson moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-22T16:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6606-6609" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-22T16:20:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4802.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2014-07-22T16:29:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6607" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-07-22T16:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-23">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSHM07" subcommittee="Transportation Security" name="House Homeland Security"/>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/22/2014--Passed House amended.
Gerardo Hernandez Airport Security Act of 2014 - (Sec. 3) Directs the Assistant Secretary of Homeland Security (Transportation Security) of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to: (1) conduct outreach to all U.S. airports at which the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) performs, or oversees the implementation and performance of, security measures; and (2) give necessary technical assistance to verify that such airports have in place individualized working plans for responding to security incidents inside the airport perimeter, including active shooters, acts of terrorism, and incidents that target passenger-screening checkpoints.

Requires the Assistant Secretary to report to Congress on the outreach findings, including an analysis of the level of preparedness such airports have to respond to such incidents.

 (Sec. 4) Requires the Assistant Secretary to: (1) identify best practices that exist across airports for security incident planning, management, and training; and (2) establish a mechanism through which to share those best practices with other airport operators nationwide.

(Sec. 5) Requires the Assistant Secretary also to: (1) certify annually to specified congressional committees that all screening personnel have participated in practical training exercises for active shooter scenarios, and (2) analyze for those same committees how TSA can use cost savings achieved through efficiencies to increase over the next five fiscal years the funding available for checkpoint screening law enforcement support reimbursable agreements.

(Sec. 7) Declares that no additional appropriations are authorized to carry out this Act. Requires this Act to be carried out using amounts otherwise available.

(Sec. 8) Requires the Assistant Secretary to review the interoperable communications capabilities of law enforcement, fire, and medical personnel responsible for responding to security incidents at all U.S. airports at which the TSA performs, or oversees the implementation and performance of, security measures.</summary>
</bill>
