<bill session="113" type="s" number="1750" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-11-13">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-11-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-11-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Public Access to Public Land Guarantee Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Public Access to Public Land Guarantee Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture to enter into agreements with States and political subdivisions of States providing for the continued operation, in whole or in part, of public land, units of the National Park System, units of the National Wildlife Refuge System, and units of the National Forest System in the State during any period in which the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture is unable to maintain normal level of operations at the units due to a lapse in appropriations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400134"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="2013-11-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412495" joined="2013-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="2013-11-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-11-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-23">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-11-13" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-12-10">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Landrieu without amendment. With written report No. 113-295.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-12-10" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="635">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 635.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="National Parks" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3661"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/20/2013--Introduced.
Public Access to Public Land Guarantee Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA), with respect to land under their respective jurisdictions, pursuant to a state or local government offer, to enter into an agreement under which the United States may accept funds from the state or local government to reopen any unit of the National Park System, the National Wildlife Refuge System, or the National Forest System within the state or local government during any period in which there is a lapse in appropriations for that unit.

Makes such authority effective only during a period in which the Secretary is unable to operate and manage covered units at normal levels.

Requires the appropriate Secretary to refund to the state or local government all amounts it provided to the United States under such an agreement: (1) upon enactment of an Act retroactively appropriating amounts sufficient to maintain normal operating levels at the reopened covered unit, or (2) on the date on which the state or local government establishes that the Secretary collected entrance or user fees for the covered units during the period in which the agreement was in effect.

Allows the appropriate Secretary, if such refund requirements are not met, to reimburse the state or local government voluntarily for any amounts it provided to the United States under such an agreement.</summary>
</bill>
