<bill session="113" type="h" number="5011" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Making Every Representative's Integrity Transparent Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">MERIT Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to prohibit authorized committees of candidates for election for Federal office and leadership PACs from employing immediate family members of the candidates, to amend such Act to limit the rate of interest an authorized committee of a candidate may pay on loans made to the committee by the candidate, to amend such Act to apply the prohibition against the conversion of contributions to personal use to contributions to political committees, to amend the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 to require registered lobbyists to identify relatives who are covered officials and disclose lobbying contacts with relatives, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412259"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412537" joined="2014-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412535" joined="2014-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412509" joined="2014-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-26">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-26">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU10" subcommittee="Constitution and Civil Justice" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3356"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/26/2014--Introduced.
Making Every Representative's Integrity Transparent Act of 2014 or the MERIT Act - Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to prohibit a candidate's authorized committee from employing any of the candidate's relatives in a paid position.

Prohibits a leadership political action committee (PAC) from employing in a paid position any relative of the candidate or any individual holding federal office who establishes, finances, maintains, or controls the leadership PAC.

Limits the interest rate an authorized committee may pay on a loan accepted from the candidate to an annual rate no higher than the prime rate plus 2%.

Revises political committee disclosure requirements about:

 loans made by candidates, expenditures to relatives of candidates for operating expenses, and disbursements received by a candidate's relative or a business organization one of whose officers or dicrectors is a relative of the candidate. Applies the prohibition against the conversion to personal use of contributions accepted by candidates also to contributions accepted by political committees.

Allows the use of contributions accepted by political committees for authorized expenditures in connection with political activities.

Amends the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 to: (1) require lobbying registrations to contain, for each employee of the registrant who has acted or who the registrant expects to act as a lobbyist on behalf of the client, the name of each relative of the employee who serves currently or who has served previously as a covered executive or legislative branch official, including the Congressional Bioguide Identifier of any covered official who is or was a Member of Congress; (2) require updates to registrations for employees who become relatives of covered officials, and (3) include lobbying contacts with relatives who are covered officials in quarterly reports on lobbying activities.</summary>
</bill>
