<bill session="113" type="h" number="4905" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Global Development Lab Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish in the United States Agency for International Development an entity to be known as the United States Global Development Lab, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412576"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412470" joined="2014-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400654" joined="2014-06-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-19">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-19">
      <text>Referred to House Science, Space, and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Research and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY15" subcommittee="Research and Technology" name="House Science, Space, and Technology"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="s" number="2502"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/19/2014--Introduced.
Global Development Lab Act of 2014 - Establishes in the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) the United States Global Development Lab whose responsibilities should include:

 increasing the application of science, technology, innovation and partnerships to develop and scale solutions to end extreme poverty; discovering, testing, and scaling development innovations to increase cost effectiveness and support U.S. foreign policy and development goals; leveraging the expertise and resources of businesses, nongovernmental organizations, science and research organizations, and universities to increase program impact; utilizing innovation-driven competitions to expand solutions to development challenges; and supporting USAID Missions and Bureaus in applying science, technology, innovation, and partnership approaches to decision making, procurement, and program design.</summary>
</bill>
