<bill session="113" type="sr" number="412" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-10">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-07-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution reaffirming the strong support of the United States Government for freedom of navigation and other internationally lawful uses of sea and airspace in the Asia-Pacific region, and for the peaceful diplomatic resolution of outstanding territorial and maritime claims and disputes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400272"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2014-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2014-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2014-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2014-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="2014-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412322" joined="2014-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412491" joined="2014-04-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2198-2199" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-05-20" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-05-20">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Menendez with amendments and with an amended preamble. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-05-20" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="380">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 380.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-07-10">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4436-4442" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-10">
      <text>The committee reported amendments were agreed to by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-10">
      <text>The committee reported amendment to the preamble was agreed to by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4436-4438" label="text as reported in Senate"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2014-07-10" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>Resolution agreed to in Senate with amendments and an amended preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4440-4442" label="text"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hr" number="704"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Japan"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Pacific Ocean"/>
    <term name="South Korea"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s3553"/>
    <amendment number="s3554"/>
    <amendment number="s3555"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>7/10/2014--Passed Senate amended.
States that the Senate: (1) condemns coercive actions or the use of force to impede freedom of operations in international airspace to alter the status quo or to destabilize the Asia-Pacific region; (2) urges China to refrain from implementing the declared East China Sea Air Defense Identification Zone and to refrain from taking similar provocative actions elsewhere in the Asia-Pacific region; (3) commends Japan and the Republic of Korea for their restraint; and (4) calls on China to withdraw its Hai Yang Shi You (HD-981) drilling rig and associated maritime forces from their current positions, refrain from maritime maneuvers contrary to the Convention on the International Regulations for Preventing Collisions at Sea, and return to the status quo as it existed before May 1, 2014.

Sets forth U.S. policy regarding: (1) supporting allies and partners in the Asia-Pacific region; (2) opposing claims that impinge on the rights, freedoms, and lawful use of the sea; (3) managing disputes without intimidation or force; (4) supporting development of regional institutions to build cooperation and reinforce the role of international law; and (5) assuring continuity of operations by the United States in the Asia-Pacific region.

States that nothing in this resolution shall be construed as a declaration of war or authorization to use force.</summary>
</bill>
