<bill session="113" type="h" number="3170" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-09-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-09-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-09-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Health Care Regulator Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide that the only health plans that the Federal Government may make available to Federal employees responsible for the administration of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act are those created under such Act or offered through a health insurance exchange, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412309"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400032" joined="2013-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412480" joined="2013-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412463" joined="2013-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400651" joined="2013-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412434" joined="2013-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412429" joined="2013-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400279" joined="2013-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412310" joined="2013-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412311" joined="2013-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400606" joined="2013-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412213" joined="2013-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412574" joined="2013-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412410" joined="2013-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400627" joined="2013-10-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-09-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, House Administration, and Appropriations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-23">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-23">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-23">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-23">
      <text>Referred to House Appropriations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Internal Revenue Service (IRS)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/23/2013--Introduced.
Health Care Regulator Accountability Act - Amends the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (PPACA) to prohibit the federal government from making any health care plan available to Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), Internal Revenue Service (IRS), or any other federal executive agency employees responsible for the administration of the Act except a health plan created under it or offered through an American Health Benefit Exchange.

Prohibits the Secretary of HHS, the IRS Director, and the head of any other agency involved in promulgating rules or regulations to carry out or to enforce PPACA, or any amendments made by it, from obligating or expending, in any fiscal year, more than 90% of the funds made available for the salaries and expenses of their offices unless those regulations are promulgated and take effect before the fiscal year's close. Requires rescission of any amounts which remain precluded from obligation or expenditure on that last day of the fiscal year.</summary>
</bill>
