<bill session="113" type="h" number="4825" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Presidential Make it in America Awards Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish presidential awards to recognize organizations that have made extraordinary efforts to create jobs and strengthen the economy of the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="408211"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF17" subcommittee="Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/10/2014--Introduced.
Presidential Make it in America Awards Act of 2014 - Establishes the following presidential awards:

 the Presidential Reshoring Award, for the best example of a U.S. company that returns manufacturing jobs and operations from overseas to the United States; the Presidential Invest in America Award, for the best example of a U.S. company that invests in significant new domestic manufacturing jobs and operations, and the Presidential Foreign Direct Investment Award, for the best example of a foreign company that invests in U.S. manufacturing jobs and operations. Authorizes the awards, subject to modification, in the categories of: (1) small business, (2) company or its subsidiary, (3) company which primarily provides services, (4) health care provider, (5) education provider, and (6) nonprofit organization.

Limits the awards to one of each in any year to a qualified organization in each eligible category.

Requires the Secretary of Commerce to publish on the departmental website information on the successful strategies and programs of organizations that receive these awards.</summary>
</bill>
