<bill session="113" type="h" number="5113" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Seniors' Medicare Choices from Obamacare Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to end the increased Federal funding for Medicaid expansion with respect to inmates' hospital care under the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act, to apply the savings towards a 2015 Medicare Advantage stabilization program to help protect seniors' choices, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412271"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400032" joined="2014-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400165" joined="2014-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412465" joined="2014-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412510" joined="2014-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412191" joined="2014-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412409" joined="2014-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412570" joined="2014-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-15">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-15">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/15/2014--Introduced.
Protecting Seniors' Medicare Choices from Obamacare Act of 2014 - Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to eliminate the increased Medicaid federal medical assistance percentage (FMAP, or federal matching amount) for prisoners with respect to their hospital care under the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act.

Amends SSA title XVIII (Medicare) part C (Medicare+Choice) to establish a Medicare Advantage (MA) stabilization program under which the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) shall distribute a stabilization funding amount to each eligible MA plan for plan year 2015 to address any beneficiary plan inadequacies.</summary>
</bill>
