<bill session="113" type="sr" number="523" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate on the importance of the United States-India strategic partnership and the continued deepening of bilateral ties with India.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412321"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2014-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412582" joined="2014-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412322" joined="2014-07-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4910-4911" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="India"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements and negotiations"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/24/2014--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of the Senate that:

 Prime Minister Narenda Modi of India should address Congress at the earliest opportunity; the U.S. government should hold a strategic dialogue in New Delhi that lays out clear objectives for the U.S.-India relationship; the United States nominate and confirm an Ambassador to India as soon as possible; the United States and India should continue to expand economic engagement, including finalizing a bilateral investment treaty and reviving the Trade Policy Forum; India should continue its economic liberalization reforms, including discussions with other Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) forum nations about Indian membership in APEC; the United States and India should expand energy, defense, and security cooperation; and India should modify its offset regime so funds can flow to a second tier of Indian priorities such as education, skills development, or manufacturing.</summary>
</bill>
