<bill session="113" type="h" number="3643" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-12-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-12-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-12-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Undetectable Firearms Modernization Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reauthorize the Undetectable Firearms Act of 1988 for 10 years and to close a loophole in the Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400195"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2013-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412524" joined="2013-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412282" joined="2014-01-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400219" joined="2013-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400230" joined="2013-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400407" joined="2014-02-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-12-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3626"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/3/2013--Introduced.
Undetectable Firearms Modernization Act of 2013 - Amends the Undetectable Firearms Act of 1988 to extend such Act for 10 years.

Revises what are prohibited firearms to include any firearm: (1) that, after removal of all parts other than major components (currently, of grips, stocks, and magazines), is not as detectable by walk-through metal detectors as the Security Exemplar; or (2) any major component of which, if subjected to inspection by the types of detection devices (currently, x-ray machines) commonly used at airports for security screening, would not generate an image that accurately depicts the shape of the component.

Modifies the definition of: (1) "major component" to include the barrel of a firearm only in the case of a rifle or shotgun; and (2) "Security Exemplar" to repeal the requirement that it be fabricated within 12 months after enactment of such Act.

Exempts from undetectable firearms provisions: (1) a prototype firearm for detectability testing; (2) any firearm received by, in the possession of, or under the control of the United States; or (3) the manufacture, importation, possession, transfer, receipt, shipment, or delivery of a firearm by a licensed manufacturer or licensed importer pursuant to an existing contract with the United States. (Replaces the exemption of any firearm that has been certified by the Secretary of Defense [DOD] or the Director of Central Intelligence [CIA] as necessary for military or intelligence applications or that is manufactured and sold exclusively to U.S. military or intelligence agencies.)</summary>
</bill>
