<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>112 S1930 IS: Uphold Our Promise to Veterans Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2014-01-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>113th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 1930</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20140115">January 15, 2014</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S348">Mr. Paul</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To repeal the annual adjustment of retired pay and retainer pay amounts for retired members of the Armed Forces under age 62, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HFEB4F688605E4B74AF174F8B6E3B45E6" style="OLC"><section id="HD82DC708192A49A98186937D5392F5F0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Uphold Our Promise to Veterans Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H942FE59C7C3147EBA2ABE159B23CFC33" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Repeal of annual adjustment of retired pay and retainer pay amounts for retired members of the Armed Forces under age 62</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 403 of the Bipartisan Budget Act of 2013 is hereby repealed.</text></section><section id="HA55F17F5BED44FCE839D4DD0C4A003BC"><enum>3.</enum><header>Limitations on foreign assistance</header><subsection id="id98f9d226256f472cb70ba35d86cbf4cc"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Foreign assistance to the Government of Egypt</header><paragraph id="id0440858d783242c2a0f63769d22f3140"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Restrictions on assistance under Section 7008</header><text>In accordance with section 7008 of the Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Act, 2012 (division I of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/74">Public Law 112–74</external-xref>; 125 Stat. 1195), the United States Government, including the Department of State, shall refrain from providing to the Government of Egypt the assistance restricted under such section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idde8abb3d2f6446fea412af4ad830d084"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional restrictions</header><text>In addition to the restrictions referred to in paragraph (1), the following restrictions shall be in effect with respect to United States assistance to the Government of Egypt:</text><subparagraph id="idd50ee4468a2a48b49cd9665d731b3aaa"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Deliveries of defense articles currently slated for transfer to Egyptian Ministry of Defense (MOD) and Ministry of Interior (MOI) shall be suspended until the President certifies to Congress that democratic national elections have taken place in Egypt followed by a peaceful transfer of power.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida8cdf7ae4c394bc7819094ac610c0eec"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Provision of defense services to Egyptian MOD and MOI shall be halted immediately until the President certifies to Congress that democratic national elections have taken place in Egypt followed by a peaceful transfer of power.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id58e2ab3c3e6549369e4c2d50d2d0c62c"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Processing of draft Letters of Offer and Acceptance (LOAs) for future arms sales to Egyptian MOD and MOI entities shall be halted until the President certifies to Congress that democratic national elections have taken place in Egypt followed by a peaceful transfer of power.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id39c25ad1e9514439b291e579127cdc4c"><enum>(D)</enum><text>All costs associated with the delays in deliveries and provision of services required under subparagraphs (A) through (C) shall be borne by the Government of Egypt.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idfbc1fe3ca3a24b04b9d221b8e7964305"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Other Limitations on foreign assistance</header><paragraph id="id992eacc0365a4e52bdd8b7dedbe62d9f"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>No amounts may be obligated or expended to provide any direct United States assistance, loan guarantee, or debt relief to a Government described under paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida6eab086f7b641f5bd98f6fe745ef574"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered governments</header><text>The Governments referred to in paragraph (1) are as follows:</text><subparagraph id="id8cf5f07978734edf8f90aa464eced26a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Government of Libya.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0fe9e2e0259944c48e028507319d3a81"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Government of Pakistan.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9ff29cf9736a435b828c39053961174e"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Government of a host country of a United States diplomatic facility on the list submitted to Congress pursuant to paragraph (3).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8ec4767bdf544b208c73c67015df5180"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Determination by Secretary</header><text>The Secretary of State shall submit to Congress a list of all United States diplomatic facilities attacked, trespassed upon, breached, or attempted to be attacked, trespassed upon, or breached on or after September 1, 2012, not later than 5 days after the date of enactment of this Act and not later than 5 days after any subsequent attack, trespass, breach, or attempt.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4e17a3ee872d4480aa21909d95614d0c"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Certification</header><text>Beginning 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President may certify to Congress that—</text><subparagraph id="id3e977562dd8d4cb38cbb508cd6373130"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a Government described under paragraph (2)—</text><clause id="idf68bef1b98684e978699dde2d539eee1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is cooperating or has cooperated fully with investigations into an attack, trespass, breach, or attempted attack, trespass, or breach;</text></clause><clause id="idad39af9534234d8bb6276570fa9de936"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has arrested or facilitated the arrest of, and if requested has permitted extradition of, all identifiable persons in such country associated with organizing, planning, or participating in the attack, trespass, breach, or attempted attack, trespass, or breach;</text></clause><clause id="idd97a590b022f4c229f17fb298654be07"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is facilitating or has facilitated any security improvements at United States diplomatic facilities, as requested by the United States Government; and</text></clause><clause id="idd1e39945e89a418bae27756669f81ed1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>is taking or has taken sufficient steps to strengthen and improve reliability of local security in order to prevent any future attack, trespass, or breach; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb7ad0d4c08b044829f4486cac2d4b722"><enum>(B)</enum><text>all identifiable persons associated with organizing, planning, or participating in the attack, trespass, breach, or attempted attack, trespass, or breach—</text><clause id="ida3d76d746d964149a7ce16068060f026"><enum>(i)</enum><text>have been identified by the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Bureau of Diplomatic Security, or other United States law enforcement entity; and</text></clause><clause id="id287f56771a3e4e85baed1c114ea854f9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>are in United States custody.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id75c398ec7a474c71924b0e41dffa6a07"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Request to suspend prohibition on foreign assistance</header><text>Upon submitting a certification under paragraph (4) with respect to a Government described under paragraph (2), the President may submit a request to Congress to suspend the prohibition on foreign assistance to the Government.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7EB0C89ECDD24E559284B6612C2D119B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section takes effect on the date of the enactment of this Act and applies with respect to funds made available to any Federal department or agency beginning with fiscal year 2015.</text></subsection></section><section id="HC09CB126AB904AFA81ADD652A9636034"><enum>4.</enum><header>Authorization to sell land</header><subsection id="H9B450C2923C64559B88BCB2F71428E6F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text>For each of fiscal years 2014 through 2024 or when the authority under this section is terminated in accordance with subsection (d), whichever occurs first, subject to valid existing rights, the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture, as the case may be, shall offer for competitive sale by auction all right, title, and interest, to the extent provided in subsection (b)(2), in and to the following:</text><paragraph id="HF609D98657EA4B02BCAFD7490B9C3E5A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Eight percent of the Federal land managed by the Bureau of Land Management.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H314D24981D8B471BADE5D040C358466B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Eight percent of the National Forest System land.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7652C735CEB14CC3A2E3AB864A1D621E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Terms and conditions</header><paragraph id="H1F2DB2F3D3574D6785429680205FAD67"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Configuration of land</header><text>The Secretary concerned shall configure the land to be sold to maximize marketability or achieve management objectives, and may prescribe such terms and conditions on the land sales authorized by this Act as the Secretary deems in the public interest.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H937DEB8327AB453993B2711F16E5D8B6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Mineral rights</header><text>For each fiscal year, the Secretary concerned may include in the sale of land under subsection (a) the mineral rights to such land for not more than 50 percent of the total acreage sold under subsection (a) by that Secretary, if the Secretary determines that such inclusion is likely to maximize marketability.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEF974FCDB2F24B12A6A5B04B915662DF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Proceeds from the sale of land</header><text>All proceeds from the sale of land under this section shall be deposited into the Treasury and applied—</text><paragraph id="H59274F53440B490996814BED1EA1BE18"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to reduce the annual Federal budget deficit for the fiscal year in which the sums are received, except as provided in paragraph (2); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H88E8FD5A84E9463B94368BC37CF26DF7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if there is no annual Federal budget deficit for the fiscal year in which the sums are received, to reduce the outstanding Federal debt.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE626D392005E4A7998DF0DE0AED6B503"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Termination of authority</header><text>The authority under this section shall terminate when the proceeds deposited into the Treasury under subsection (c) equal $3,500,000 or at the end of fiscal year 2024, whichever occurs first.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


