<bill session="113" type="hr" number="590" updated="2015-09-01T10:18:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-21T18:00:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-05-21T18:00:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for further consideration of the bill (H.R. 4435) to authorize appropriations for fiscal year 2015 for military activities of the Department of Defense and for military construction, to prescribe military personnel strengths for such fiscal year, and for other purposes; and providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3361) to reform the authorities of the Federal Government to require the production of certain business records, conduct electronic surveillance, use pen registers and trap and trace devices, and use other forms of information gathering for foreign intelligence, counterterrorism, and criminal purposes, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412409"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <calendar datetime="2014-05-21T01:44:00-04:00" state="REPORTED" calendar="House" number="109">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 109.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21T01:44:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 113-460, by Mr. Nugent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21T01:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides further consideration of H.R. 4435. No amendment shall be in order except those printed in part A of the report. At the conclusion of consideration for amendment, the Committee shall rise and report the bill to the House with such further amendments as may have been adopted. The previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motion except one motion to recommit with or without instructions. The rule also provides for consideration of H.R. 3361. All points of order against consideration are waived. The bill, as amended by part B of the report</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21T13:53:00-04:00">
      <text>By direction of the Committee on Rules, Mr. Nugent called up H. Res. 590 for its immediate consideration.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4699-4706" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21T14:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. McGovern raised a point of order against consideration of H. Res. 590 and the Chair recognized Mr. McGovern and Mr. Nugent for up to 10 minutes each on the point of order. After debate, the Chair will put the question of consideration on the resolution as the statutory means of disposing of the point of order in the following form: "Will the House now consider the resolution?".</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4701" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21T14:23:00-04:00">
      <text>On question of consideration of the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4703" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21T14:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4703-4712" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21T14:23:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 590.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21T15:13:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resumed debate on H. Res. 590.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21T15:55:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4712" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21T15:55:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H. Res. 590, the Chair put the question on adoption of the resolution and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Polis demanded the yeas and nays, and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the resolution until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21T17:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4714-4715" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="228" datetime="2014-05-21T18:00:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 231 - 190 (Roll no. 228).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4699" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21T18:00:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="113" type="h" number="3361"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4435"/>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="113" type="h" number="4435"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/21/2014--Reported to House without amendment.
Sets forth the rules for consideration of H.R. 4435 (Howard P. "Buck" McKeon National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2015) and H.R. 3361 (USA FREEDOM Act).</summary>
</bill>
