<bill session="113" type="h" number="4396" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-04-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-04-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Religious Liberty Protection Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit the Secretary of Health and Human Services from implementing certain rules relating to the health insurance coverage of sterilization and contraceptives approved by the Food and Drug Administration.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412292"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412547" joined="2014-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412252" joined="2014-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412444" joined="2014-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412460" joined="2014-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412445" joined="2014-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400654" joined="2014-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412302" joined="2014-05-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Family planning and birth control"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/3/2014--Introduced.
Religious Liberty Protection Act of 2014 - Prohibits the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) from implementing or enforcing any provision of the final rule published on July 2, 2013, related to the coverage of preventive health services under the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (PPACA) or any amendment to such rule or subsequent rule insofar as such provision, amendment, or subsequent rule requires any individual or entity to provide coverage of sterilization or contraceptive services to which the individual or entity is opposed on the basis of religious belief.

Amends PPACA to declare that a health plan shall not be considered to have failed to provide essential health benefits, to fail to be a qualified health plan, or to fail to fulfill any other requirements on the basis that the plan does not provide or pay for coverage of sterilization or contraceptive services because: (1) providing or paying for such coverage is contrary to the religious or moral beliefs of the sponsor, issuer, or other entity offering the plan; or (2) such coverage, in the case of individual coverage, is contrary to the religious or moral beliefs of the purchaser or beneficiary of the coverage.</summary>
</bill>
