<bill session="113" type="s" number="2554" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-26">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-06-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Keystone XL Pipeline Approval Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Keystone XL Pipeline Approval Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">An original bill to approve the Keystone XL Pipeline.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300063"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-26">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Landrieu. With written report No. 113-200.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-06-26" state="REPORTED" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="446">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 446.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-10-01">
      <text>Star Print ordered on report 113-200.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="5682"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="5682"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2280"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2314"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Federal appellate courts"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Nebraska"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/26/2014--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Keystone XL Pipeline Approval Act - Authorizes TransCanada Keystone Pipeline, L.P. to construct, connect, operate, and maintain the pipeline and cross-border facilities specified in an application filed by TransCanada Corporation to the Department of State on May 4, 2012.

Deems the Final Supplemental Environmental Impact Statement regarding the pipeline issued by the Secretary of State in January 2014 to fully satisfy the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 and any law that requires federal agency consultation or review, including the Endangered Species Act of 1973.

Declares any applicable federal permit or authorization issued before enactment of this Act to remain in effect.

Grants the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit, subject to review in the Supreme Court of the United States, original and exclusive jurisdiction over any civil action for the review of any order or action of a federal agency regarding the pipeline and cross-border facilities, and the related facilities in the United States, approved by this Act (including any order granting a permit or right-of-way, or any other agency action taken to construct or complete the project).

Declares that this Act does not alter any federal, state, or local process or condition in effect on the date of enactment of this Act that is necessary to secure access from an owner of private property to construct the pipeline and cross-border facilities.</summary>
</bill>
