<bill session="113" type="s" number="2417" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Close the Revolving Door Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide greater controls and restriction on revolving door lobbying.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412330"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2014-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2014-06-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers and employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/3/2014--Introduced.
Close the Revolving Door Act of 2014 - Amends the federal criminal code to impose a lifetime ban on any former Senator, Member of the House of Representatives, or elected officer of the Senate or House of Representatives lobbying any current Member, officer, or employee of Congress or any employee of any other legislative office (currently, the ban is for two years after a Senator leaves office and one year after a Member of the House of Representatives leaves office). Extends such ban from one to six years for officers and employees of the Senate, personal staff of Members, committee staff, leadership staff, and other legislative offices.

Prohibits for a six-year period the hiring of a registered lobbyist or agent of a foreign principal by a Member of Congress or a congressional committee with whom the lobbyist or agent has had a substantial lobbying contact.

Amends the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 to: (1) direct the Secretary of the Senate and the Clerk of the House of Representatives to maintain a joint lobbyist disclosure Internet database for information required to be publicly disclosed by such Act, (2) require a substantial lobbying entity to file with Congress a list of any employees who provide paid consulting services and who are former Members of Congress or highly-paid congressional staffers, and (3) increase the civil penalty for violations of the disclosure or reporting provisions of such Act.</summary>
</bill>
