<bill session="113" type="s" number="2865" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Voter Registration Modernization Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 to provide for voter registration through the Internet, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412223"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2014-09-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="12"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="123"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/18/2014--Introduced.
Voter Registration Modernization Act - Amends the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 (NVRA) to require each state to make available official public websites for online voter registration.

Directs the appropriate state or local election official to ensure that information on the computerized statewide voter registration list may be updated through the official public website.

Directs the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) to study best practices for implementing the requirements for Internet registration and the online updating of voter registration information.

Authorizes the provision of election information by electronic mail to individuals registered to vote who have requested to receive it.

Directs the Election Assistance Commission (EAC) to make an implementation payment each year to enable each state to meet the requirements of this Act and to carry out activities to improve the administration of federal elections.</summary>
</bill>
