<bill session="113" type="s" number="1678" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-11-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-11-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-11-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Public-Private Employee Retirement Parity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend subchapter II of chapter 84 of title 5, United States Code, to prohibit coverage for annuity purposes for new Federal employees, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400054"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2013-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2013-11-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-11-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/12/2013--Introduced.
Public-Private Employee Retirement Parity Act - Excludes as creditable service under the Federal Employees Retirement System (FERS) any service performed by an federal employee or Member of Congress (including military service) after the date that is six months after enactment of this Act, if that individual did not perform any period of creditable service (including military service) before such date. Prohibits an employing agency from making any deduction or withholding from the basic pay of, or any contribution for, any employee or Member for such excluded service.

Modifies the reporting requirements of the Board of Actuaries of the Civil Service Retirement System (CSRS) to require: (1) its annual reports on the actuarial status of CSRS and FERS submitted after the enactment of this Act to be made available online, and (2) all previous reports prepared on or after June 6, 1986, to be made available online.</summary>
</bill>
