<bill session="113" type="s" number="1752" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-11-21">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-11-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-11-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Military Justice Improvement Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reform procedures for determinations to proceed to trial by court-martial for certain offenses under the Uniform Code of Military Justice, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412223"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-11-20">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-11-21" state="REPORTED" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="251">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 251.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-03-06">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1335-1349" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-06">
      <text>Cloture motion on the measure presented in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1336" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S1336" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-06">
      <text>Cloture on the measure not invoked in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 55 - 45. Record Vote Number: 59.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1349" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-06">
      <text>Returned to the Calendar. Calendar No. 251.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1349" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="967"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2970"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2992"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Military command and structure"/>
    <term name="Military law"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/20/2013--Introduced.
Military Justice Improvement Act of 2013 - Amends the Uniform Code of Military Justice (UCMJ) to direct the Secretaries of Defense (DOD) and Homeland Security (DHS) to require the Secretaries of the military departments to modify the process for determining whether to try by court-martial a member accused of: (1) certain UCMJ offenses for which the maximum punishment includes confinement for more than one year; or (2) a conspiracy, solicitation, or attempt to commit such offenses.

Requires courts-martial determinations for such offenses to be made by a commissioned officer available for detail as trial counsel who is outside the chain of command of the member subject to the charges. (Currently, courts-martial decisions are made by commanding officers of accused members.)

Excludes from the revised procedures that require counsel outside the chain of command to make such courts-martial determinations certain UCMJ offenses relating specifically to military service, including absence without leave, insubordination, and aiding the enemy.

Prohibits an outside counsel's determination not to proceed to trial by general or special court-martial from altering the authority of commanding officers to: (1) refer noncapital offenses to summary courts-martial with limits on the punishments that may be imposed; or (2) impose non-judicial admonitions, reprimands, or disciplinary punishment for minor offenses.

Requires military chiefs of staff to establish offices to convene general and special courts-martial. Prohibits officers in the chain of command of an accused or a victim from detailing members to serve on a resulting trial by court-martial.</summary>
</bill>
