<bill session="113" type="h" number="3029" updated="2015-09-01T10:19:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">College Savings Enhancement Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Securities and Exchange Commission to revise certain rules relating to the status of qualified prepaid tuition programs under the securities laws.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412484"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412544" joined="2013-08-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-08-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/2/2013--Introduced.
College Savings Enhancement Act of 2013 - Directs the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to revise specified regulations so as to include: (1) qualified prepaid tuition programs under the definition of a qualified institutional buyer (with respect to private resales of securities to institutions), and (2) as accredited investors any qualified prepaid tuition programs whose total assets exceed $5 million (with respect to Regulation D, governing the limited offer and sale of securities without registration under the Securities Act of 1933).

Defines, for purposes of such revisions, a "qualified prepaid tuition program" as a qualified tuition program (under which a person may purchase tuition credits or certificates on behalf of a designated beneficiary which entitle the beneficiary to the waiver or payment of the beneficiary's qualified higher education expenses), which is established and maintained by a state or state agency or instrumentality that satisfies certain other requirements of the Internal Revenue Code.</summary>
</bill>
