<bill session="113" type="h" number="2599" updated="2015-09-01T10:19:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">JUSTICE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Justice for the Unprotected against Sexually Transmitted Infections among the Confined and Exposed Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reduce the spread of sexually transmitted infections in correctional facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400237"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412221" joined="2013-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2013-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2013-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="2013-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2013-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2013-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400366" joined="2013-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400422" joined="2013-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412412" joined="2013-06-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-28">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-28">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-28">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="HIV/AIDS"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Homelessness and emergency shelter"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Sex and reproductive health"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Sexually transmitted diseases"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/28/2013--Introduced.
Justice for the Unprotected against Sexually Transmitted Infections among the Confined and Exposed Act or the JUSTICE Act - Requires the Attorney General to direct the Bureau of Prisons to allow community organizations to distribute sexual barrier protection devices and engage in sexually transmitted infection (STI) counseling and prevention education in federal correctional facilities.

Expresses the sense of Congress that states should permit the legal distribution of sexual barrier protection devices in state correctional facilities to reduce the prevalence and spread of STIs in those facilities.

Amends the Social Security Act to require the automatic enrollment or reinstatement of enrollment of an eligible individual in a state's Medicaid plan (with the individual's affirmative consent) upon such individual's release from incarceration. Defines an "eligible individual" as an inmate who was enrolled before being incarcerated or who is diagnosed with human immunodeficiency virus. Provides for a one-year increase in federal matching payments to states that agree to provide for such enrollment.

Directs the Attorney General and the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to conduct an annual survey of all federal and state correctional facilities and immigration detention facilities regarding: (1) STI prevention education and training offered to inmates and staff; (2) inmate access to sexual barrier protection devices; (3) the incidence of sexual violence committed by inmates and staff; (4) required inmate participation in counseling, treatment, and supportive services related to STIs; (5) facility testing of inmates for STIs; (6) pre-release referral to STI-related services; and (7) Medicaid reinstatement assistance upon release.

Requires the Attorney General to develop and implement a five-year strategy that includes specified components to reduce the prevalence and spread of STIs in federal and state correctional facilities.

Amends the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act to include as a homeless person for purposes of eligibility for housing assistance under such Act an individual who: (1) is being released from any prison or other correctional facility, and (2) has been diagnosed with any STI.</summary>
</bill>
