<bill session="113" type="s" number="1628" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-10-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-10-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fallen Wildland Firefighters Fair Compensation Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide Federal death and disability benefits for contractors who serve as firefighters of the Forest Service, Department of the Interior agencies, or any State or local entity.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412325"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2014-09-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/31/2013--Introduced.
Fallen Wildland Firefighters Fair Compensation Act of 2013 - Amends the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 to make eligible for death or disability benefits an individual who: (1) serves the Forest Service, any agency of the Department of the Interior, or any state or local firefighting entity as a contractor or subcontractor, in an official capacity, with or without compensation; (2) performs under an exclusive use, call when needed, or equipment rental agreement with such agency or entity; and (3) directly performs fire suppression activities as a member of an aerial or ground-based firefighting crew or equipment operator in the direct fire suppression, or en route to or return from such direct fire suppression activity.

Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to include such an individual within the definition of "public safety officer" for purposes of death benefits eligibility provisions.</summary>
</bill>
