<bill session="113" type="s" number="2866" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">In-Home CARE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">In-Home Caregiver Assessment Resources and Education Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize grants for the support of caregivers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412598"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="5633"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Adult day care"/>
    <term name="Allied health services"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/18/2014--Introduced.
In-Home Caregiver Assessment Resources and Education Act or the In-Home CARE Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Administration for Community Living to award grants to carry out home visiting programs for unpaid caregivers.

Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to coordinate with the National Family Caregiver Support Program, Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS), and others on this grant program.

Requires grantees to provide:

 caregiver education and training regarding medication management, food preparation, falls prevention and other subjects; services or referrals for services related to home care, such as transportation, home modification, or respite care; and an assessment and referral for physical and mental health services for the caregiver or person receiving care from the caregiver.</summary>
</bill>
