<bill session="113" type="s" number="1611" updated="2015-09-01T17:50:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-18">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Data Center Consolidation Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Federal Data Center Consolidation Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Federal Data Center Consolidation Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require certain agencies to conduct assessments of data centers and develop data center consolidation and optimization plans.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412330"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412493" joined="2013-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300019" joined="2014-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2013-10-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-11-06" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-05-06">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Carper with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 113-157.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-05-06" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="372">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 372.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5863-5865" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18">
      <text>The committee substitute as amended agreed to by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5863-5864" label="text of committee substitute as amended"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2014-09-18" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5864-5865" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-09-19">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-19T12:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-19">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-19">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1232"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3979"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s3929"/>
    <amendment number="s3930"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>9/18/2014--Passed Senate amended.
Federal Data Center Consolidation Act of 2013 - Requires the heads of specified federal agencies, assisted by their chief information officers, to submit to the Administrator for the Office of E-Government and Information Technology of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) each fiscal year: (1) a comprehensive inventory of data centers owned, operated, or maintained by each such agency; and (2) a multi-year strategy to achieve the consolidation and optimization of such data centers that includes performance metrics, a timeline for agency activities to be completed under the OMB Federal Data Center Consolidation Initiative (FDCCI), and year-by-year calculations of investments and cost savings.

Provides that for any year that the Department of Defense (DOD) is required to submit a performance plan for the reduction of resources required for data servers and centers, DOD: (1) may submit to the Administrator, in lieu of the multi-year strategy, the defense-wide plan and report on cost savings required by the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2012; and (2) shall submit the comprehensive inventory required by this Act unless the defense-wide plan contains a comparable comprehensive inventory.

Requires the Administrator to: (1)&#160;establish deadlines for annual reporting and requirements such agencies must meet to be considered in compliance with this Act, (2)&#160;develop and make publicly available a goal for the amount of planned cost savings and optimization improvements achieved through the FDCCI during a specified period, (3) aggregate the reported cost savings of each agency and optimization improvements achieved to date through the FDCCI and compare such savings to the projected cost savings and optimization improvements achieved through the FDCCI, and (4) report to Congress. Directs the Comptroller General (GAO) to review and verify the quality and completeness of the asset inventory and strategy of each agency and report to Congress.

Requires such agencies to implement&#160;their data center consolidation and optimization strategies consistent with federal guidelines on cloud computing security, including: (1) applicable provisions in the Federal Risk and Authorization Management Program (FedRAMP), and (2) guidance published by the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST).&#160;

Authorizes the Director of National Intelligence (DNI) and the Secretary of Defense to waive the applicability of any provision of this Act to any national security system if such waiver is in the interest of national security. Requires the Director or the Secretary to submit to specified congressional committees a statement describing the waiver and the reasons for it.

Repeals this Act effective on October 1, 2018.</summary>
</bill>
