<bill session="113" type="h" number="5021" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-08-08">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-08-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Highway and Transportation Funding Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Highway and Transportation Funding Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Highway and Transportation Funding Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Highway and Transportation Funding Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide an extension of Federal-aid highway, highway safety, motor carrier safety, transit, and other programs funded out of the Highway Trust Fund, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400058"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="409888" joined="2014-07-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, Science, Space, and Technology, Energy and Commerce, Education and the Workforce, and Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-08">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-08">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-08">
      <text>Referred to House Science, Space, and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-08">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-08">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-08">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-10">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-07-10" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-07-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-14T19:19:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Ways and Means. H. Rept. 113-520, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-14T19:19:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 669 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 5021 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-15T14:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 669 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-15T15:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 669.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6245-6261" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-15T15:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 5021 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-15T15:10:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 5021.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-15T16:14:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6258" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-15T16:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Blumenauer moved to recommit with instructions to the Committee on Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6258-6261" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6258-6259" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-15T16:17:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the motion to recommit with instructions, pending the reservation of a point of order. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to add a section to the bill that changes the end date of the extension to December 31, 2014. The amendment also makes sundry changes to the bill. Subsequently, the reservation of a point of order was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-15T16:25:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6260" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-15T16:53:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 193 - 227 (Roll no. 413).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6260-6261" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="414" datetime="2014-07-15T17:00:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 367 - 55 (Roll no. 414).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6246-6249" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-07-15T17:00:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-15">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-07-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="468">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 468.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-07-29">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5021-5039" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote2" roll="248" datetime="2014-07-29" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_BACK:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate, pursuant to the order of 7/23/2014, having achieved 60 votes in the affirmative, with an amendment by Yea-Nay Vote. 79 - 18. Record Vote Number: 248.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-07-30">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-30T23:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 696 Reported to House. The rule makes in order one hour of debate each for H.R. 5230 and H.R. 5272. The rule also makes in order for one hour debate on a motion that the House disagree to the Senate amendment to H.R. 5021. Any motion pursuant to clause 4 of rule XXII relating to H.R. 5021 may be offered only by the Majority Leader or his designee. It shall be in order at any time on the legislative day of July 31, 2014 for the Speaker to entertain motions to suspend the rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31T11:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 696 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31T13:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Shuster moved that the House disagree to the Senate amendment.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7169-7176" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31T13:25:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 696, the House proceeded with one hour of debate on the Shuster motion that the House disagree to the Senate amendment to H.R. 5021.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31T13:55:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7176" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31T14:25:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House disagree to the Senate amendment Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 272 - 150 (Roll no. 473).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31T14:25:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31">
      <text>Message on House action received in Senate and at desk: House disagrees to Senate amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31">
      <text>Senate receded from its amendment to the measure by Yea-Nay Vote. 81 - 13. Record Vote Number: 255.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5209" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-08-01">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2014-08-01">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2014-08-08" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="113-159" type="public" datetime="2014-08-08">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 113-159.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW12" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF17" subcommittee="Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII22" subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hc" number="108"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hc" number="108"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="113" type="hr" number="669"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="113" type="hr" number="696"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Customs enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Motor carriers"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Urban and suburban affairs and development"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h1070"/>
    <amendment number="s3564"/>
    <amendment number="s3565"/>
    <amendment number="s3566"/>
    <amendment number="s3574"/>
    <amendment number="s3582"/>
    <amendment number="s3583"/>
    <amendment number="s3584"/>
    <amendment number="s3585"/>
    <amendment number="s3613"/>
    <amendment number="s3702"/>
    <amendment number="s3705"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>8/8/2014--Public Law.
Highway and Transportation Funding Act of 2014 - Title I: Surface Transportation Program Extension - Subtitle A: Federal-Aid Highways - (Sec. 1001) Continues from October 1, 2014, through May 31, 2015, and authorizes appropriations through that period for, specified federal-aid highway programs under:

 the Moving Ahead for Progress in the 21st Century Act (MAP-21), the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (SAFETEA-LU) Technical Corrections Act of 2008, SAFETEA-LU, the Transportation Equity Act for the 21st Century (TEA-21), the National Highway System Designation Act of 1995, the Intermodal Surface Transportation Efficiency Act of 1991 (ISTEA), and other specified law. Subjects funding for such programs generally to the same manner of distribution, administration, limitation, and availability for obligation, but at a specified pro rata of the total amount, as funds authorized for appropriation out of the Highway Trust Fund (HTF) for such programs and activities for FY2014.

Amends the Moving Ahead for Progress in the 21st Century Act (MAP-21) to authorize appropriations out of the general fund of the Treasury for the Tribal High Priority Projects program for the same period.

Prescribes an obligation ceiling of $26,800,569,863 for federal-aid highway and highway safety construction programs for the same period.

(Sec. 1002) Authorizes appropriations from the HTF (other than the Mass Transit Account) for administrative expenses of the federal-aid highway program for the same period.

Subtitle B: Extension of Highway Safety Programs - (Sec. 1101) Amends MAP-21 to extend for the same period the authorization of appropriations for National Highway Traffic Safety Administration (NHTSA) safety programs, including: (1) highway safety research and development, (2) national priority safety programs, (3) the National Driver Register, (4) the High Visibility Enforcement Program, and (5) NHTSA administrative expenses.

 Amends SAFETEA-LU to extend for the same period high-visibility traffic safety law enforcement campaigns under the High Visibility Enforcement Program.

Sets aside a specified amount of the total apportionment to states for highway safety programs for a cooperative program to research and evaluate priority highway safety countermeasures for the same period.

(Sec. 1102) Extends for the same period the authorization of appropriations for Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration (FMCSA) programs, including: (1) motor carrier safety grants, (2) FMCSA administrative expenses, (3) commercial driver's license program improvement grants, (4) border enforcement grants, (5) performance and registration information system management grants, (6) commercial vehicle information systems and networks deployment grants, (7) safety data improvement grants, (8) a set-aside for high priority activities that improve commercial motor vehicle safety and compliance with commercial motor vehicle safety regulations, (9) a set-aside for new entrant motor carrier audit grants, (10) FMCSA outreach and education, and (11) the commercial motor vehicle operators grant program.

(Sec. 1103) Amends the Dingell-Johnson Sport Fish Restoration Act to continue, for the same period, the authorized distribution of funds for coastal wetlands, recreational boating safety, projects under the Clean Vessel Act of 19921, boating infrastructure projects, and the National Outreach and Communications Program.

Subtitle C: Public Transportation Programs - (Sec. 1201) Extends for the same period the apportionment of nonurbanized (rural) area formula grants for competitive grants and formula grants for public transportation on Indian reservations.

(Sec. 1202) Extends the apportionment of urbanized area formula grants for passenger ferry projects for the same period.

(Sec. 1203) Extends for the same period the authorization of appropriations from the HTF Mass Transit Account for: (1) formula grants for public transportation, including allocations for specified projects; (2) research, development demonstration, and deployment projects; (3) the transit cooperative research program; (4) technical assistance and standards development grants; (5) human resources and training grants; (6) capital investment grants; and (7) administrative expenses.

(Sec. 1204) Allocates, for the same period, certain amounts to states and territories for formula bus and bus facilities grants.

Subtitle D: Hazardous Materials - (Sec. 1301) Authorizes appropriations for the same period for hazardous materials (hazmat) transportation safety projects.

Authorizes the Secretary of Transportation (DOT) to make certain expenditures, including an amount for hazmat training grants, from the Hazardous Materials Emergency Preparedness Fund for the same period.

Title II: Revenue Provisions - (Sec. 2001) Amends the Internal Revenue Code to extend through May 31, 2015, the authority for expenditures from: (1) the HTF Highway and Mass Transit Accounts, (2) the Sport Fish Restoration and Boating Trust Fund, and (3) the Leaking Underground Storage Tank Trust Fund.

(Sec. 2002) Makes appropriations out of the Treasury to the HTF Highway and Mass Transit Accounts.

Makes appropriations out of the Leaking Underground Storage Tank Trust Fund and transfers them to the HTF Highway Account.

(Sec. 2003) Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) and the Internal Revenue Code to revise the applicable percentages for determining minimum funding standards for single-employer defined benefit pension plans (funding stabilization). Exempts plans providing accelerated benefit distributions from the application of such standards.

(Sec. 2004) Amends the Consolidated Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1985 to extend, through September 30, 2024, certain customs user fees for the processing of merchandise entered or released into the United States.

Title III: Treatment For PAYGO Purposes - (Sec. 3001) Declares that the budgetary effects of this Act and its amendments shall not be entered on the PAYGO scorecards of either the House of Representatives or of the Senate.</summary>
</bill>
