<bill session="113" type="h" number="5490" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Wall Street Accountability through Sustainable Funding Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Commodity Futures Trading Commission to impose fees and assessments to recover the cost of appropriations to the Commission.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400103"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412193" joined="2014-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412239" joined="2014-09-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on General Farm Commodities and Risk Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG16" subcommittee="General Farm Commodities and Risk Management" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Commodities markets"/>
    <term name="Commodity Futures Trading Commission"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/16/2014--Introduced.
Wall Street Accountability Through Sustainable Funding Act - Amends the Commodity Exchange Act to require the Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC) to impose fees to recover the cost of the appropriation to the CFTC for the fiscal year.

Requires the fees to be imposed on each agreement, contract, or transaction that is a contract of sale of a commodity for future delivery, an option, or a swap.

Permits the CFTC to exempt contracts, agreements, or transactions from the fee if the exemption is consistent with: (1) the public interest; (2) the equal treatment of contract markets, derivatives clearing organizations, and market participants; and (3) the operation of a nationwide market system.

Establishes the Commodity Futures Trading Commission Reserve Fund in the Treasury and requires the CFTC to impose and collect an additional fee to be deposited into the Fund. Permits the CFTC to obligate amounts in the Fund for long-term investments in information technology and unexpected expenses. Limits the balance in the Fund to $50 million.</summary>
</bill>
