<bill session="113" type="s" number="2529" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National All Schedules Prescription Electronic Reporting Reauthorization Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend and reauthorize the controlled substance monitoring program under section 399O of the Public Health Service Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412323"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2014-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2014-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2014-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2014-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412391" joined="2014-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2014-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2014-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300088" joined="2014-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400408" joined="2014-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412542" joined="2014-09-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3528"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/25/2014--Introduced.
National All Schedules Prescription Electronic Reporting Reauthorization Act of 2014 - Amends the National All Schedules Prescription Electronic Reporting Act of 2005 to include as a purpose of such Act to foster the establishment of state-administered controlled substance monitoring systems in order to ensure that appropriate law enforcement, regulatory, and state professional licensing authorities have access to prescription history information for the purposes of investigating drug diversion and prescribing and dispensing practices of errant prescribers or pharmacists.

 Amends the Public Health Service Act to revise and update the controlled substance monitoring program, including to:

 allow grants to be used to maintain and operate existing state controlled substance monitoring programs, require submission by a state of a plan to apply the latest advances in health information technology to incorporate prescription drug monitoring program data directly into the workflow of prescribers and dispensers, require timelines and descriptions for implementation of interoperability for purposes of information sharing with a bordering state that already operates a monitoring program, require health information interoperability standards to be consistent with at least one health information technology system, require the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to redistribute any funds that are returned among the remaining grantees, require a state to provide the Secretary with aggregate data and other information to enable the Secretary to evaluate the success of the state's program and to submit a progress report to Congress, and expand the program to include any commonwealth or territory of the United States. Authorizes the Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA) or a state Medicaid program or health department receiving nonidentifiable information from a controlled substance monitoring database to make such information available to other entities for research purposes.

Requires a state receiving a grant to: (1) facilitate prescriber and dispenser use of the state's controlled substance monitoring system, and (2) educate prescribers and dispensers on the benefits of the system both to them and society.

 Removes the preferences for grants related to drug abuse for states with approved applications to implement controlled substances monitoring programs.

Revises requirements for studies on progress to include assessment of the effects upon linkages to substance abuse disorder services and interoperability with health information technology systems.</summary>
</bill>
