<bill session="113" type="h" number="4401" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-04-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-04-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Social Security Temporary Emergency Payee Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title II of the Social Security Act to provide for the immediate designation of substitute representative payees, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412315"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412501" joined="2014-04-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/4/2014--Introduced.
Social Security Temporary Emergency Payee Act - Amends title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability) (OASDI) of the Social Security Act to require the Commissioner of Social Security, if the Commissioner or a court of competent jurisdiction determines that the representative payee for an individual has died, has misused any individual's benefit, or has otherwise become unable or unwilling to continue as a representative payee, to: (1) revoke immediately certification for payment of the individual's benefits to such representative payee; (2) certify payment of such benefits, on a permanent or temporary basis, to a qualified organization to serve as a substitute representative payee; or (3) certify payments of such benefits to the individual directly if it would serve the individual's interests.

Prohibits the deferral of benefits payments directly to an individual during the selection of a substitute representative payee in any case in which a representative payee has previously been designated for the individual.</summary>
</bill>
