<bill session="113" type="h" number="5473" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">James Boulet National Language Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 4, United States Code, to declare English as the official language of the Government of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410396"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2014-11-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-15">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-15">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-10-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-10-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU10" subcommittee="Constitution and Civil Justice" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Border Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Citizenship and naturalization"/>
    <term name="Foreign language and bilingual programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Voting rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/15/2014--Introduced.
James Boulet National Language Act of 2014 - Amends federal law to: (1) make English the official language of the United States, (2) require that official U.S. government functions be conducted in English, and (3) require the U.S. government to preserve and enhance the role of English as the official language of the United States.

Declares that, unless specifically stated in applicable law, no person has a right, entitlement, or claim to have the U.S. government or any of its officials or representatives act, communicate, perform or provide services, or materials in any language other than English.

Makes exceptions to these requirements the use of a language other than English for: (1) religious purposes, (2) language training for international communication, or (3) school programs designed to encourage students to learn foreign languages.

Amends the the Voting Rights Act of 1965 to repeal bilingual voting and related voting qualification requirements.

Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to require that all public naturalization ceremonies in which the oath of allegiance is administered be conducted solely in the English language.</summary>
</bill>
