<bill session="113" type="h" number="5596" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fairness in Student Loan Repayment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide borrowers of Federal Family Education Loans with the repayment terms available to borrowers of Federal Direct Loans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412530"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412527" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412506" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400606" joined="2014-09-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Training" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/18/2014--Introduced.
Fairness in Student Loan Repayment Act - Amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require the Secretary of Education to make available to borrowers of Federal Family Education Loans (FFELs) the following loan repayment options and benefits that are made available to borrowers of William D. Ford Federal Direct Loans (DLs):

 standard repayment plans, graduated repayment plans, extended repayment plans, income contingent repayment plans, income-based repayment plans, or alternative repayment plans that the Secretary deems appropriate; the loan deferments that are made available to certain borrowers who are still in school, unemployed, performing specified military service, or facing an economic hardship; payments of interest on behalf of military personnel; the repayment plan for public service employees; and the non-accrual of interest on the loans of active duty military personnel. Directs the Secretary to pay to FFEL holders the principal, interest, or special allowance payments needed to apply these options and benefits to FFEL borrowers.</summary>
</bill>
