<bill session="113" type="h" number="4965" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pre-K for USA Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to award grants to improve childhood care and education for local governments and local educational agencies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412576"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400130" joined="2014-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412530" joined="2014-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412585" joined="2014-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412579" joined="2014-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412412" joined="2014-12-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5736"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/25/2014--Introduced.
Pre-K for USA Act - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to direct the Secretary of Education and the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), acting jointly in accordance with an interagency agreement, to award competitive grants to local educational agencies or local governmental entities to develop, enhance, or expand high-quality preschool programs.

Requires each of those programs to include structural elements that are evidence-based and nationally recognized as important for ensuring program quality, including, at a minimum:

 high staff qualifications, including having a teacher with a bachelor's degree in early childhood education or in any field with a state-approved alternate pathway to teaching preschool children and having teaching assistants with appropriate credentials; high-quality professional development for all staff; at least 1 staff member for every 10 children; a class size that does not exceed 20 children; a full-day program; the full inclusion of disabled children; developmentally appropriate curricula and learning environments, that are aligned with state early learning and development standards, for at least the year preceding kindergarten; individualized accommodations and supports so that all children can participate fully in learning activities; instructional staff salaries that are comparable to the salaries of kindergarten through grade 12 teaching staff; program evaluation to ensure continuous improvement; onsite or accessible comprehensive services for children; and health and safety standards.</summary>
</bill>
