<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Enrolled-Bill" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB2097CBA858C4EB0A9DC4F35DB1020A2" public-private="public" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title> HR 2391 ENR: To designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 5323 Highway N in Cottleville, Missouri as the Lance Corporal Phillip Vinnedge Post Office.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>One Hundred Thirteenth Congress of the United States of America</congress> <session>At the Second Session</session><enrolled-dateline>Begun and held at the City of Washington on Friday, the third day of January, two thousand and fourteen</enrolled-dateline> 
<legis-num>H. R. 2391</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no"></current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 5323 Highway N in Cottleville, Missouri as the <term>Lance Corporal Phillip Vinnedge Post Office</term>.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H16C8ED222FC54DDDA61AFD959F60BB96" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA1765D1F7EFD49D5866DA0CD36DD1ECA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Lance Corporal Phillip D. Vinnedge Post Office</header> 
<subsection id="H8280619E9862491EABDDCD0DC90B441E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>The facility of the United States Postal Service located at 5323 Highway N in Cottleville, Missouri, shall be known and designated as the <term>Lance Corporal Phillip Vinnedge Post Office</term>.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H0DD7564766854EA3A516C0D286ACAEA1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>References</header><text>Any references in a law, map, regulation, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the facility referred to in subsection (a) shall be deemed to be a reference to the <term>Lance Corporal Phillip Vinnedge Post Office</term>.</text> </subsection></section> 
</legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><role>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</role></attestation-group><attestation-group><role>Vice President of the United States and President of the Senate.</role></attestation-group></attestation>
</bill> 


