<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="A1" public-print="no" public-private="public" stage-count="1" star-print="no-star-print"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 S812 ES: To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to take actions to implement the Agreement between the United States of America and the United Mexican States Concerning Transboundary Hydrocarbon Reservoirs in the Gulf of Mexico.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form display="yes">
<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">S. 812</legis-num><current-chamber display="no">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><legis-type display="yes">AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to take
		  actions to implement the Agreement between the United States of America and the
		  United Mexican States Concerning Transboundary Hydrocarbon Reservoirs in the
		  Gulf of Mexico.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" style="OLC"><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Agreement between the United
			 States of America and the United Mexican States Concerning Transboundary
			 Hydrocarbon Reservoirs in the Gulf of Mexico</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of the Interior is authorized
			 to take actions necessary to implement the terms of the Agreement between the
			 United States of America and the United Mexican States Concerning Transboundary
			 Hydrocarbon Reservoirs in the Gulf of Mexico, which is hereby approved,
			 including—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id59B5DD523A5A4493BAF699B2449A215A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to approve unitization agreements and
			 related arrangements for the exploration of, and development or production of
			 oil or gas from, transboundary reservoirs and geological structures;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9004AC6FFB0049CCACB2AFD75E4FF17A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to disclose as necessary under the
			 Agreement information related to the exploration, development, and production
			 of a transboundary reservoir or geological structure that may be considered
			 confidential, privileged, or proprietary information under law; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id514EA51D0BFD4E5EB0F3BBB3383CE732"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to accept and take action not inconsistent
			 with an expert determination under the Agreement.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date chamber="Senate" date="20131012">Passed the Senate October 12, 2013.</attestation-date><attestor display="no"></attestor><role>Secretary</role></attestation-group></attestation><endorsement display="yes"></endorsement></bill>


