<bill session="113" type="s" number="2351" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-05-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Notice for Organizations That Include Charities is Essential (NOTICE) Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide notice to charities and other nonprofit organizations before their tax-exempt status is automatically revoked.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402675"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/15/2014--Introduced.
Notice for Organizations That Include Charities is Essential (NOTICE) Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to require the Secretary of the Treasury to notify any tax-exempt organization, not later than 300 days after such an organization fails to file its annual tax return or other required information for two consecutive years, that: (1) the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) has no record of its return or&#160;information&#160;for two consecutive years, and (2) a penalty will occur if the organization fails to file&#160;its&#160;return or&#160;information by the next filing deadline.&#160;Allows the reinstatement of the tax-exempt status of such an organization without the requirement of an application if: (1) the organization demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Secretary that it did not receive the notice required by this Act, and (2) it files an annual return or required&#160;information for the current year.</summary>
</bill>
