<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="H52A2BCAFADCC4A6ABD2CEA6A36F5A279" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Reported-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HRES 644 RH: Condemning and disapproving of the Obama administration’s failure to comply with the lawful statutory requirement to notify Congress before releasing individuals detained at United States Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba, and expressing national security concerns over the release of five Taliban leaders and the repercussions of negotiating with terrorists.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2014-07-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code> 
<calendar display="yes">House Calendar No. 133</calendar> 
<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress> 
<session display="yes">2d Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. RES. 644</legis-num> 
<associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 113–569]</associated-doc> 
<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action display="yes"> 
<action-date date="20140625">June 25, 2014</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000589">Mr. Rigell</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000587">Mr. Ribble</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001252">Mr. Barrow of Georgia</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000011">Mr. Rahall</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00" added-display-style="italic" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<action>
<action-date date="20140731">July 31, 2014</action-date>
<action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="S001189">Mr. Austin Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001188">Mr. Stutzman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001052">Mr. Harris</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000549">Mr. Gerlach</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000804">Mr. Wittman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001060">Mr. Hurt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001192">Mr. Stewart</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000597">Mr. Rice of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000616">Mr. DesJarlais</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000238">Mr. Thornberry</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000567">Mr. Lance</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000583">Mr. Smith of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001048">Mr. Hunter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000289">Mr. Goodlatte</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000588">Mr. Pearce</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000508">Mr. McKeon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000567">Mr. Griffin of Arkansas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000813">Mrs. Walorski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000266">Mr. Chabot</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000575">Mr. Lankford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001094">Mr. Cook</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001092">Mr. Collins of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000018">Mr. Salmon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000065">Mr. Yoho</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001186">Mr. Southerland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001095">Mr. Cotton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000672">Mr. Wolf</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000445">Mr. Forbes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000605">Mr. Perry</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001187">Mr. Stivers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000592">Mr. Rokita</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001172">Mr. Smith of Nebraska</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000576">Mr. Long</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001289">Mr. Byrne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001189">Mr. Messer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000591">Mr. Price of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000582">Mr. Roe of Tennessee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000244">Mr. Sensenbrenner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000220">Mr. Kingston</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000810">Mr. Woodall</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001062">Mr. Conaway</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000601">Mr. Palazzo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001260">Mr. Buchanan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000619">Mr. Rodney Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000451">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000612">Mr. Denham</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001274">Mr. Brooks of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000463">Mr. Turner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000552">Mr. Gohmert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001053">Mr. Cole</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001179">Mr. Schock</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000568">Mr. Griffith of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000185">Mr. Nugent</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001243">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001154">Mr. Shuster</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001179">Mr. Marino</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001256">Mrs. Bachmann</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001053">Mrs. Hartzler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001051">Mr. Carter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000184">Mrs. Noem</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000809">Mr. Womack</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001182">Mr. Mulvaney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001059">Mr. Hultgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000291">Mrs. Ellmers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001180">Mr. McKinley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001144">Mr. Miller of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000456">Mr. Fleming</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001273">Mrs. Black</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000602">Mr. Pompeo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000363">Mr. Kline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000621">Mr. DeSantis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000255">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001087">Mr. Crawford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001036">Mr. Hensarling</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000556">Mr. Coble</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000059">Mr. Calvert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000186">Mr. Nunnelee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000815">Mr. Wenstrup</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001280">Mr. Bentivolio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001269">Mr. Barletta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000554">Mr. LoBiondo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000566">Mr. Latta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000055">Mr. Aderholt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000812">Mrs. Wagner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001064">Mr. Campbell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000174">Mr. Sam Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001096">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor></action-desc>
</action>
<action> 
<action-date date="20140731">July 31, 2014</action-date> 
<action-desc>Reported with amendments, referred to the House Calendar, and ordered to be printed</action-desc> 
<action-instruction>Strike out the preamble and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction> 
<action-instruction>Strike out all after the resolving clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction> 
</action> 
<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">Condemning and disapproving of the Obama administration’s failure to comply with the lawful statutory requirement to notify Congress before releasing individuals detained at United States Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba, and expressing national security concerns over the release of five Taliban leaders and the repercussions of negotiating with terrorists.</official-title> 
</form> 
<preamble reported-display-style="strikethrough" changed="deleted" committee-id="HAS00"> 
<whereas><text>Whereas section 1035 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/66">Public Law 113–66</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/801">10 U.S.C. 801</external-xref> note) clearly requires the Secretary of Defense to notify the appropriate committees of Congress at least 30 days before the transfer or release of an individual detained at United States Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba;</text> </whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, on May 31, 2014, the Department of Defense executed the release of five senior Taliban detainees held at United States Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba;</text> </whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the five released Taliban detainees are all senior Taliban leaders: Abdul Haq Wasiq was the Taliban Deputy Minister of Intelligence, Mullah Norullah Noori was the Taliban military commander at Mazar-e-Sharif, Mullah Mohammad Fazl was the Taliban Deputy Minister of Defense, Khairullah Said Wai Khairkwa was the Taliban Minister of Interior, and Mohammad Nabi Omari was the Taliban commander of secret police;</text> </whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas these five senior Taliban leaders have associations with al-Qaeda or have engaged in hostilities against the United States or its coalition partners;</text> </whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas these five senior Taliban detainees held leadership positions within the Taliban when it provided safehaven for al-Qaeda to conduct planning, training, and operations for the September 11, 2001, attacks;</text> </whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the President has stated that there is <quote>absolutely</quote> a possibility of the released detainees returning to activities that are detrimental to the United States, and, according to media reports, United states intelligence officials told members of the Senate that four of the five detainees are expected to return to the battlefield;</text> </whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Secretary Hagel stated before the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives on June 11, 2014, that the threat, <quote>should these five detainees return and reintegrate with the Taliban, their focus would almost certainly be on Taliban efforts inside Afghanistan,</quote> where the United States and coalition partners will retain military and civilian personnel;</text> </whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas in 2010, after an extensive evaluation meant to identify detainees who could be transferred out of the detention facility at United States Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba, the Obama administration determined that these five should remain in United States detention because they were <quote>too dangerous to transfer</quote> because each <quote>poses a high level of threat that cannot be mitigated sufficiently except through continued detention</quote>;</text> </whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Obama administration negotiated, through intermediaries in the Government of Qatar, with the Taliban, with whom the United States remains engaged in active combat, and with the Haqqani Network, which the State Department has designated as foreign terrorist organization, and who had held Sergeant Bowe Bergdahl captive;</text> </whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas congressional notification was not received until June 2, 2014, three days after such individuals were released, and 33 days after the date on which such notification was required by law;</text> </whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Obama administration admits that it made no effort to comply with the 30-day notification requirement;</text> </whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Obama administration officials acknowledge that approximately 80 or 90 employees within the administration were knowledgeable of the transfer of the five Taliban detainees prior to their release;</text> </whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Obama administration has offered differing, unconvincing, and conflicting explanations of why it failed to comply with the 30-day notification requirement and has described the failure to notify Congress as an <quote>oversight</quote>;</text> </whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas article II, section 3 of the Constitution states that the President <quote>shall take care that the laws be faithfully executed</quote>;</text> </whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, on January 15, 2009, the Office of Legal Counsel in the Department of Justice acknowledged that Congress possesses under article I of the Constitution <quote>significant war powers</quote>, including legislative authority concerning the detention and release of enemy combatants;</text> </whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Obama administration has complied with section 1035 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/66">Public Law 113–66</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/801">10 U.S.C. 801</external-xref> note) and section 8111 of the Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/76">Public Law 113–76</external-xref>) in all previous detainee transfers from United States Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba, since the date of the enactment of each such Act; and</text> </whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the leadership and the leaders of the national security committees of the Senate and House of Representatives are on record, specifically in 2011, as opposing the transfer of detainees in exchange for a prisoner of war: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble> 
<preamble reported-display-style="italic" changed="added" committee-id="HAS00"> 
<whereas><text>Whereas section 1035 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/66">Public Law 113–66</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/801">10 U.S.C. 801</external-xref> note) requires the Secretary of Defense to notify the appropriate committees of Congress not later than 30 days before the transfer or release of any individual detained at United States Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba (hereinafter referred to as <quote>GTMO</quote>);</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas on May 31, 2014, the Department of Defense transferred five Taliban detainees held at GTMO to the State of Qatar;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas according to declassified United States government documents, the five detainees were all senior Taliban leaders: Abdul Haq Wasiq was the Taliban Deputy Minister of Intelligence, Mullah Norullah Noori was the Taliban military commander at Mazar-e-Sharif, Mullah Mohammad Fazl was the Taliban Deputy Minister of Defense, Khairullah Said Wai Khairkwa was the Taliban Minister of Interior, and Mohammad Nabi Omari was the Taliban communications chief and border chief;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas these five senior Taliban leaders have had associations with al-Qaeda or have engaged in hostilities against the United States or its coalition partners;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas these five senior Taliban detainees held leadership positions within the Taliban in Afghanistan when it provided safehaven for al-Qaeda to conduct planning, training, and operations for the September 11, 2001, attacks;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas in 2010, after an extensive evaluation meant to identify detainees who could be transferred out of the detention facility at GTMO, the Obama administration determined that these five should remain in United States detention because they were <quote>too dangerous to transfer</quote> because each <quote>poses a high level of threat that cannot be mitigated sufficiently except through continued detention</quote>;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the President has stated that there is <quote>absolutely</quote> the <quote>possibility of some</quote> of these former Taliban detainees <quote>trying to return to activities that are detrimental to</quote> the United States;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas other former GTMO detainees that were transferred have become leaders of al-Qaeda affiliates actively plotting against the United States and are <quote>involved in terrorist or insurgent activities</quote>;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Secretary of Defense Chuck Hagel testified before the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives that, pursuant to an agreement with Qatar, the five former detainees transferred in May would not be allowed to leave Qatar for one year, but after that date there would be no restrictions on the movement of the former detainees;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas notwithstanding the fact that Qatar is an important regional ally, after another GTMO detainee was transferred to Qatar in 2008, Qatar apparently had difficulty implementing the assurances Qatar gave the United States in connection with that detainee’s transfer;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas senior officials in the Obama administration negotiated, through intermediaries in the government of Qatar, with the Taliban, and with the Haqqani Network, which the Department of State has designated as a foreign terrorist organization, and which held Sergeant Bowe Bergdahl captive;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Secretary Hagel testified to the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives that negotiations for the transfer of the five Taliban detainees in exchange for Sergeant Bergdahl began in January 2014;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the General Counsel of the Department of Defense signed a memorandum of understanding with the Attorney General of the State of Qatar on May 12, 2014, regarding the security conditions for transfer of these five Taliban detainees;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas in addition to an unknown number of officials of Qatar, senior Obama administration officials acknowledge that approximately 80 or 90 individuals within the Obama administration were knowledgeable of the planned transfer of the five Taliban detainees prior to their transfer;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Congress was not notified of the transfer until June 2, 2014, three days after such individuals were transferred, and 33 days after the date on which such notification was required by section 1035 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/66">Public Law 113–66</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/801">10 U.S.C. 801</external-xref> note) and section 8111 of the Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/76">Public Law 113–76</external-xref>);</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the President and other senior Obama administration officials, did not comply with the 30-day notification requirement;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas article II, section 3 of the Constitution stipulates that the President <quote>shall take care that the laws be faithfully executed</quote>;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas on January 15, 2009, the Office of Legal Counsel in the Department of Justice acknowledged that, under article I of the Constitution, Congress possesses legislative authority concerning the detention and release of enemy combatants;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Obama administration has complied with the law in all other detainee transfers from GTMO since the date of the enactment of prevailing law; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas in 2011, after leaders of the Senate and House of Representatives expressed their bipartisan opposition to the prospective transfer of these Taliban detainees from GTMO, senior Obama administration officials assured these Senators and Members of Congress that there would be no exchange of Taliban detainees for Sergeant Bergdahl, and that any transfer of Taliban detainees that might otherwise occur would be part of a reconciliation effort with the Taliban and the Government of Afghanistan and that such a transfer would only take place in consultation with Congress pursuant to law: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble> 
<resolution-body id="H3AA91E4BDBA04A6593286CF0438CB417" style="traditional"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HEB1B8AB177144492BEA18DC55143320A" section-type="undesignated-section" reported-display-style="strikethrough" changed="deleted" committee-id="HAS00"><enum></enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="H00C50D9AF60243C5B528833B3ACF40C5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>condemns and disapproves of the failure of the Obama administration to comply with the lawful 30-day statutory reporting requirement in executing the release of five senior members of the Taliban from detention at United States Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba;</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD6EF46C4D85643D0A1F56387E5D084D9"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expresses grave concern over national security implications that may arise due to the release of Taliban officials, including the national security threat to the people and Armed Forces of the United States and complications of the current efforts of the United States to combat terrorism worldwide;</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HED7A13588CBE4ED68A6560E9CC8FEBCD"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expresses grave concern over the repercussions of negotiating with terrorists, and the risk that such negotiations with terrorists may further encourage hostilities and the abduction of Americans as a means of further prisoner exchanges;</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB58A60605BDF4AFBB6943BF87B498DDF"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">stipulates that further violations of the law set forth in section 1035 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/66">Public Law 113–66</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/801">10 U.S.C. 801</external-xref> note) and section 8111 of the Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/76">Public Law 113–76</external-xref>) are unacceptable;</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9508D969A99C447EB960D690EF7033AE"><enum>(5)</enum><text>declares grave misgivings about the prospect of any other similar transfers from United States Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba, even if undertaken pursuant to statutory requirements; and</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA7E98A7AFBBF4AD8BAE60A9F20FA80B8"><enum>(6)</enum><text>expresses that the Obama administration’s release of the five detainees has burdened unnecessarily the trust and confidence in the administration’s commitment and ability to constructively engage and work with the legislative branch, and therefore works against what is in the best interest of the people of the United States.</text> </paragraph></section> 
<section id="H53FAEC72D76B4578BADE6AF82FF05176" section-type="undesignated-section" reported-display-style="italic" changed="added" committee-id="HAS00"><enum></enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="H8841AD219C194F3FB55B9DA34F9A42FF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>condemns and disapproves of the failure of the Obama administration to comply with the lawful 30-day statutory reporting requirement in executing the transfer of five senior members of the Taliban from detention at United States Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9F9C8D198DCC45C98861281F195A6EEC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>expresses grave concern about the national security risks associated with the transfer of five senior Taliban leaders, including the national security threat to the American people and the Armed Forces of the United States;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6E086AC7EDB643688DC7C951E0A767AA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>expresses grave concern over the repercussions of negotiating with terrorists, even when conducted through intermediaries, and the risk that such negotiations with terrorists may further encourage hostilities and the abduction of Americans;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H58297BAE5F8F48F888942673DCBCE128"><enum>(4)</enum><text>stipulates that further violations of the law set forth in section 1035 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/66">Public Law 113–66</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/801">10 U.S.C. 801</external-xref> note) and section 8111 of the Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/76">Public Law 113–76</external-xref>) are unacceptable;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H38E7A68C06894E14A820A2FBC14254FA"><enum>(5)</enum><text>expresses that these actions have burdened unnecessarily the trust and confidence in the commitment and ability of the Obama administration to constructively engage and work with Congress; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H50B31013B655429883727267D4A3B209"><enum>(6)</enum><text>expresses relief that Sergeant Bergdahl has returned safely to the United States.</text></paragraph> </section> 
</resolution-body><official-title-amendment>Amend the title so as to read: <quote>Resolution condemning and disapproving of the failure of the Obama administration to comply with the lawful statutory requirement to notify Congress before transferring individuals detained at United States Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba, and expressing concern about the national security risks over the transfer of five Taliban leaders and the repercussions of negotiating with terrorists.</quote>.</official-title-amendment> 
<endorsement display="yes"> 
<action-date date="20140731">July 31, 2014</action-date> 
<action-desc>Reported with amendments, referred to the House Calendar, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement> 
</resolution> 


