<bill session="113" type="h" number="4688" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Gold Star Families Equality Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 10, United States Code, to provide appropriate recognition for the survivors of members of the Armed Forces who die while serving on certain active or reserve duty, to expand the availability of the Gold Star Installation Access Card for survivors of deceased members of the Armed Forces, and to extend commissary store and exchange store and other MWR retail facility benefits to the parents of such members.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412435"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="National symbols"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/20/2014--Introduced.
Gold Star Families Equality Act - Requires a lapel button to be designed to identify widows, parents, and next of kin of members of the Armed Forces who die, under circumstances not already prescribed for under existing eligibility standards for a gold star lapel button, while serving on active duty or while assigned to a reserve component in a drill status.

Makes such next of kin button available retroactively to survivors of members of the Armed Forces who have died since September 10, 2001.

Directs the Secretary of each military department and the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating to provide for the issuance of a Gold Star Installation Access Card to family members with gold or next of kin buttons to expedite their ability to gain unescorted access to military installations for the purpose of obtaining on-base services and benefits.

Requires regulations to be prescribed to permit parents (including stepparents, parents though adoption, or foster parents who stood in loco parentis) with such buttons to use commissary stores and other military retail facilities on the same basis as surviving spouses or children.</summary>
</bill>
