<bill session="113" type="s" number="2352" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-05-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Russian Weapons Embargo Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to re-impose sanctions on Russian arms exporter Rosoboronexport.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402675"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2014-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2014-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2014-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400222" joined="2014-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="2014-05-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-28">
      <text>Senate Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="Ukraine"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/15/2014--Introduced.
Russian Weapons Embargo Act of 2014 - Prohibits the head of any executive agency from entering into a contract, subcontract, memorandum of understanding, or cooperative agreement with, or make a grant to, or provide a loan or loan agreement to Rosoboronexport, any subsidiary or affiliate of it, or any entity that has a business relationship with Rosoboronexport regarding the design, manufacture, or sale of military equipment.

Requires the head of each executive agency to terminate any such arrangement.

Authorizes the President to waive such prohibition if : (1) Rosoboronexport has ceased the transfer of military equipment to, and the maintenance of existing military equipment for, the government of Syria; (2) the armed forces of the Russian Federation have withdrawn from Crimea (other than forces present on certain military bases); and (3) agents of the Russian Federation are not taking measures to destabilize the control of the government of Ukraine over eastern Ukraine.

Authorizes the President to reprogram Economic Support Fund assistance or security assistance for the government of any country that enters into a contract, memorandum of understanding, or cooperative agreement with, or makes a grant or loan to Rosoboronexport or any subsidiary or affiliate of it in an amount up to or equal to the total amount of each such arrangement.</summary>
</bill>
