<bill session="113" type="h" number="5169" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-16T20:37:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-09-16T20:37:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Senior Executive Service Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Senior Executive Service Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 5, United States Code, to enhance accountability within the Senior Executive Service, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412213"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400068" joined="2014-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400196" joined="2014-07-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-24">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-07-24" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-09-16T19:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform. H. Rept. 113-603.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-09-16T19:48:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="448">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 448.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-09-16T20:12:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Meadows moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-16T20:12:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7591-7594" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-16T20:12:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5169.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2014-09-16T20:37:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7591" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-09-16T20:37:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-17">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Employee leave"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/16/2014--Passed House amended.
Senior Executive Service Accountability Act - (Sec. 2) Requires each federal agency to include in its biennial report to the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) for a specific number of Senior Executive Service (SES) positions a justification for each position (by title and organizational location) and the specific result expected from each such position, including the impact of such result on the agency mission.

(Sec. 3) Extends from one year to two years the probationary period for SES employees.

(Sec. 4) Eliminates the authority for allowing an individual removed from the SES for a less than fully successful executive performance to retain an SES pay grade level if appointed to a civil service position.

(Sec. 5) Requires a written description of employee performance requirements to be provided to SES employees not later than 30 calendar days before each rating period.

(Sec. 6) Makes SES employees subject to the same 14-day (or less) suspension period, without duties and pay, as is applicable to other federal employees. Expands the grounds for suspension or termination of an SES employee to include such cause as would promote the efficiency of the SES.

Requires: (1) a written decision of an adverse action to be rendered not later than 30 days after the employee's answer to such action is received, and (2) any SES employee who is terminated from service to repay any salary received and forfeit any annual leave accumulated during the period of any adverse action leading to termination.</summary>
</bill>
