<bill session="113" type="s" number="2759" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-12-18">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-12-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to release the City of St. Clair, Missouri, from all restrictions, conditions, and limitations on the use, encumbrance, conveyance, and closure of the St. Clair Regional Airport.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412243"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2014-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-09-17" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-12-01">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Rockefeller without amendment. With written report No. 113-282.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-12-01" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="609">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 609.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2014-12-03" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6304-6305" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S6305" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-12-04T12:25:00-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-04">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-09T14:50:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Gibbs moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-09T14:50:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8897-8898" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-09T14:50:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 2759.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote2" datetime="2014-12-09T14:56:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8897" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-12-09T14:56:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2014-12-12">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2014-12-18" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="113-285" type="public" datetime="2014-12-18">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 113-285.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Missouri"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/18/2014--Public Law.
Directs the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) to release the city of St. Clair, Missouri, from all restrictions on the use, encumbrance, conveyance, and closure of the St. Clair Regional Airport.

Prohibits such release from being executed before the city transfers to the Missouri Department of Transportation: (1) specified amounts to be used for capital improvements for airport development consistent with such Department's obligations under the FAA's state block grant program; and (2) for no consideration, all airport and aviation-related equipment of the Airport owned by the city and determined to be salvageable.

Describes such specified amounts as: (1) the fair market value for the highest and best use of the Airport property; (2) the unamortized portion of any federal development grants other than land paid to the city for use at the airport, which may be paid with, and shall be an allowable use of, airport revenue; and (3) the airport revenues remaining in the Airport's account and otherwise due to or received by the city.

Directs the FAA to remove the runway end indicator lighting system at the Airport.</summary>
</bill>
