<bill session="113" type="s" number="2682" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Made in the U.S.A. Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require certain Federal agencies to use iron, steel, wood products, cement and manufactured goods produced in the United States in public construction projects, to permanently extend the Build America Bonds program, to ensure that transportation and infrastructure projects carried out using Federal financial assistance are constructed with steel, iron, and manufactured goods that are produced in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300080"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412602" joined="2014-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="949"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Buy American requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="National Railroad Passenger Corporation (Amtrak)"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements and negotiations"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/29/2014--Introduced.
Made in the U.S.A. Act - Prohibits the head of a federal agency from obligating or expending funds or providing financial assistance for projects for the construction, alteration, maintenance, or repair of a public building or public work unless substantially all of the iron, steel, wood products, cement, and manufactured goods used in the project are produced in the United States (Buy American requirements).

Authorizes the head of an agency to waive such prohibition in certain circumstances.

Amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to the Build America Bond program, to: (1) extend permanently the authority to issue such bonds and the authority for payments to issuers of such bonds, (2) reduce the bond holder tax credit percentage, and (3) treat as bonds qualified for the tax credit any bond (or series of bonds) issued to refund a qualified bond if certain criteria are met.

Revises Buy American requirements with respect to federal-aid highways, particularly the handling of waiver requests.

Revises similar Buy American requirements with respect to public transportation and Amtrak, particularly rolling stock. Requires the cost of rolling stock components and subcomponents produced in the United States to increase from 60% in FY2015 by 10% annual increments up to 100% for FY2019 and ensuing fiscal years.

Prescribes Buy American requirements for procurement of a facility or equipment under federal aviation programs similar to those for rolling stock.

Requires the Secretary of Transportation (DOT) to report annually to Congress on: (1) each project for which a waiver of Buy American requirements was issued; and (2) the country of origin and product specifications for steel, iron, or manufactured goods acquired pursuant to each waiver.</summary>
</bill>
