<bill session="113" type="h" number="4205" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-03-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-03-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Design Services Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 to authorize the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to carry out a loan repayment program for certain architects, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412192"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400130" joined="2014-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412257" joined="2014-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412521" joined="2014-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412293" joined="2014-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400271" joined="2014-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400661" joined="2014-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="2014-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="408211" joined="2014-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412411" joined="2014-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412186" joined="2014-03-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-03-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Libraries and archives"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
    <term name="Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/11/2014--Introduced.
National Design Services Act of 2014 - Amends the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 to authorize the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to establish a loan repayment program for eligible architects who provide certain design services on behalf of a Community Design Center (a non-profit organization operated and managed by a licensed architect that conducts research and provides design services for community development projects).

Requires an eligible architect, in order to participate in the loan repayment program, to enter into a written contract with the Secretary that contains:

 an agreement under which: (1) the architect agrees to provide eligible design services on behalf of a Community Design Center for at least one year, and (2) the Secretary agrees to pay the principal and interest of the architect's qualifying educational loans for the period of time the architect provides such services; a provision that any U.S. financial obligation arising out of the contract, and any obligation of the architect, is contingent upon appropriations for the loan repayment program; and a statement of the damages to which the United States is entitled if the eligible architect breaches the contract.</summary>
</bill>
