<bill session="113" type="h" number="5289" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Indian River Lagoon Nutrient Removal Assistance Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the Indian River Lagoon Nutrient Removal Assistance Grant Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412527"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-30">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-30">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation and pollution"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/2014--Introduced.
Indian River Lagoon Nutrient Removal Assistance Act of 2014 - Requires the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to establish an Indian River Lagoon Nutrient Removal Assistance Grant Program to assist projects related to the protection and restoration of the Indian River Lagoon in Florida.

Directs the EPA to issue regulations regarding grant selection criteria that prioritize projects that: (1) produce the greatest nutrient load reductions, (2) result in the greatest environmental benefits to the Lagoon, and (3) advance the goals and objectives of the comprehensive and management plan for the Indian River Lagoon approved under the National Estuary program of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act).

Requires the EPA to issue regulations to increase by 5% each civil penalty amount established for a violation of the Clean Water Act.

Amends the Internal Revenue Code to establish an Indian River Lagoon Nutrient Removal Assistance Trust Fund for the Program. Requires an amount equal to the increase in civil penalties to be transferred to the Fund.</summary>
</bill>
