<bill session="113" type="h" number="4048" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-02-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-02-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-02-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Securing Our Nation's Application Privacy Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SNAP Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Federal Trade Commission to promulgate regulations prohibiting mobile applications from accessing certain content and functions of a mobile device when such applications are not actively in use unless the user is provided with a disclosure of such access and grants affirmative express consent to such access.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412488"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412199" joined="2014-03-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-02-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF17" subcommittee="Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/11/2014--Introduced.
Securing Our Nation's Application Privacy Act of 2014 or the SNAP Act of 2014 - Directs the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to promulgate regulations that require any person who develops, sells or offers for sale, or makes available to consumers: (1) a software program that runs on the mobile platform or operating system of a mobile device (mobile application) to ensure that such application does not access specified content or functions stored on a mobile device while the application is not actively in use, unless the application triggers disclosure and consent functions of the mobile platform or operating system and the user grants affirmative express consent; and (2) a mobile platform or operating system to ensure that such platform or operating system provides device users with a disclosure immediately before any application that is not actively in use accesses any such content or functions and prevents such access unless the user grants such express consent.

Specifies categories of content and functions prohibited from being accessed without consent, including: (1) geographic location; (2) contact information; (3) photographs, videos, or audio recordings; (4) events or notations stored in a calendar application; and (5) a camera, microphone, or any information obtained from such a camera or microphone.

Requires violations of such regulations to be treated as unfair or deceptive acts or practice under the Federal Trade Commission Act.</summary>
</bill>
