<bill session="113" type="s" number="1419" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-11-13">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-11-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Marine and Hydrokinetic Renewable Energy Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Marine and Hydrokinetic Renewable Energy Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to promote research, development, and demonstration of marine and hydrokinetic renewable energy technologies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300100"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412545" joined="2013-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2013-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2013-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412507" joined="2013-12-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6211-6213"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6213-6214" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-27">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 113-284.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-11-13" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-12-10">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Landrieu with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 113-294.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-12-10" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="634">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 634.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG07" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/1/2013--Introduced.
Marine and Hydrokinetic Renewable Energy Act of 2013 - Amends the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 to redefine "marine and hydrokinetic renewable energy" as energy (currently electrical energy) from: (1) waves, tides, and currents in oceans, estuaries, and tidal areas; (2) free flowing water in rivers, lakes, and streams; (3) free flowing water in man-made channels; and (4) differentials in ocean temperature (ocean thermal energy conversion).

Requires the Secretary of Energy (DOE), in addition to current consulting requirements, to consult with the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) in carrying out the program of research, development, demonstration, and commercial application to expand marine and hydrokinetic renewable energy production.

Expands such program, including by: (1) adding as a purpose the support of in-water testing and demonstration of marine and hydrokinetic renewable energy technologies; (2) incorporating technology development assistance to improve the components, processes, and systems used for power generation from such resources; (3) establishing critical testing infrastructure; (4) increasing the reliability and survivability of such technologies; and (5) supporting in-water technology development with international partners.

Extends the authorization of funding for such program through FY2017.

Amends the Federal Power Act to authorize FERC to issue a pilot license: (1) to construct, operate, and maintain a hydrokinetic pilot project that meets the criteria listed in this Act; and (2) for such a project located in the ocean if the project covers a surface area of not more than one square nautical mile. Authorizes FERC to grant a pilot license for a project that covers a larger surface area for good cause.</summary>
</bill>
