<bill session="113" type="s" number="258" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-11-21">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-11-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Grazing Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Grazing Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 to improve the management of grazing leases and permits, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412251"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300030" joined="2013-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2013-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400134" joined="2013-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="2013-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412218" joined="2013-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412494" joined="2013-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412495" joined="2013-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412322" joined="2013-02-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-25">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands, Forests, and Mining. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 113-28.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-11-21" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-05-22">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Landrieu with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 113-166.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-05-22" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="392">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 392.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG03" subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="657"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="657"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2954"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/22/2014--Reported to Senate amended.
Grazing Improvement Act - Amends the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 to revise provisions related to grazing leases and permits.

Extends the maximum period of a term for grazing permits and leases for domestic livestock grazing on public lands or lands within national forests in 16 contiguous western states from 10 years to 20 years, if the Secretary of Interior with respect to land administered by Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture with respect to National Forest Service System land (the Secretary concerned) has assessed and evaluated the grazing allotment and determined that the grazing allotment meets applicable standards or objectives.

Requires a permit or lease to be continued until the Secretary concerned completes any environmental analysis and documentation for the permit or lease required under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (NEPA) and other applicable laws.

Instructs the Secretary concerned to seek to conduct environmental reviews on an allotment or multiple allotment basis, if the allotments share similar ecological conditions for purposes of compliance with NEPA and other applicable laws.

Permits the exclusion of grazing permits or leases from environmental assessment or environmental impact statement requirements under NEPA if: (1) the issued permit or lease continues the current grazing management of the allotment, and (2) the Secretary concerned has determined that the allotment meets applicable standards or objectives. Permits the exclusion of the trailing and crossing of livestock across public land from such requirements.

Gives the Secretary concerned sole discretion to determine the priority and timing for completing each required environmental analysis based on environmental significance and available funding.

Establishes in the Departments of the Interior and of Agriculture (USDA) a pilot program that: (1) authorizes the voluntary relinquishment of grazing permits or leases in New Mexico and Oregon, and (2) provides that grazing permits or leases voluntarily relinquished shall be permanently retired from further grazing authorization.</summary>
</bill>
