<bill session="113" type="h" number="4534" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-18">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Native American Children's Safety Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Native American Children's Safety Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Indian Child Protection and Family Violence Prevention Act to require background checks before foster care placements are ordered in tribal court proceedings, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412555"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee Indian and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-29">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18">
      <text>Subcommittee Indian and Alaska Native Affairs Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-09-18" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-12-22T17:24:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 113-699.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-12-22T17:24:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="530">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 530.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII24" subcommittee="Indian and Alaska Native Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="s" number="2160"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/30/2014--Introduced.
Native American Children's Safety Act - Amends the Indian Child Protection and Family Violence Prevention Act (Act) to prohibit any foster care placement over which an Indian tribe has exclusive jurisdiction from being ordered until the tribal social services agency: (1) completes an investigation of the character of each covered individual who resides in the household or is employed at the institution in which the foster care placement will be made, and (2) concludes that each of those individuals meets the standards of character the tribe is required to establish.

Defines a "covered individual" as an adult and any other individual the tribe determines is subject to such character investigation.

Requires the tribal social services agency, as part of those investigations, to: (1) perform criminal records checks, including fingerprint-based checks of national crime information databases; (2) check any child abuse and neglect registry maintained by the state in which the individual resides; and (3) request any other state in which the individual resided during the preceding five years to allow the agency to check its registry.

Prohibits a foster care placement from being ordered if the investigation reveals that the covered individual: (1) has been found guilty by a federal, state, or tribal court of a felony involving child abuse or neglect, spousal abuse, a crime against a child, violence, or drugs; or (2) is listed on a child abuse and neglect registry in the state where the individual resides or resided within the preceding five years.

Excepts emergency foster care placements from such requirements.

Requires each Indian tribe to establish procedures to recertify homes or institutions in which foster care placements are made.

Directs the Secretary of the Interior to promulgate a regulation establishing: (1) procedures for investigating the character of any covered individual who resides in the home or is employed at the institution in which the child is placed after the investigations that preceded that placement occurred, (2) self-reporting requirements for foster care homes or institutions that have knowledge that a covered individual residing on their premises would fail the character investigation, (3) procedures and guidelines for emergency foster care placements, and (4) procedures for certifying compliance with the Act.</summary>
</bill>
