<bill session="113" type="h" number="3869" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-01-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-01-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-01-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fluke Fairness Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for an equitable management of summer flounder based on geographic, scientific, and economic data and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400031"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412451" joined="2014-01-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400219" joined="2014-01-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-01-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII22" subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1757"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Atlantic Ocean"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hunting and fishing"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/14/2014--Introduced.
Fluke Fairness Act - Directs the Mid-Atlantic Fishery Management Council to submit for approval by the Secretary of Commerce a modified fishery management plan for the commercial and recreational management of summer flounder, or an amendment to such plan, that: (1) is based on the best scientific information available; (2) reflects changes in the distribution, abundance, and location of summer flounder in establishing distribution of the commercial and recreational catch quotas; (3) considers regional, coastwide, or other management measures that comply with national standards under the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act; and (4) prohibits the allocation of catch quotas on a state-by-state basis using historical landings data that does not reflect the status of the summer flounder stock, based on the most recent scientific information.

Requires the Council, in preparing such modifications or amendments, to consult with the Atlantic States Marine Fisheries Commission.

Directs the Secretary to prepare and approve a plan if the Council fails to submit such modifications or amendments.

Requires a Comptroller General (GAO) report that assesses whether the subsequent implementation of the approved plan complies with national standards.</summary>
</bill>
