<bill session="113" type="h" number="3380" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-10-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-10-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To delay any increases in premium rates for flood insurance coverage under the National Flood Insurance Program until the Federal Emergency Management Agency completes a comprehensive review and updating of all flood insurance rate maps and the Army Corps of Engineers reviews and certifies that such maps include all flood mitigation and flood control projects completed by the Corps.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400331"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/30/2013--Introduced.
Prohibits the risk premium rates for flood insurance coverage made available under the National Flood Insurance Program from being increased from such rates in effect as of September 30, 2013, until: (1) the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) completes a first comprehensive review and updating of all flood insurance rate maps for such Program pursuant to the Biggert-Waters Flood Insurance Reform Act of 2012, and (2) the Chief of Engineers reviews and certifies that such updated rate maps accurately reflect all flood mitigation and flood control projects completed within the affected watershed by the Army Corps of Engineers.

Directs the Administrator to refund to insureds any premiums for flood insurance coverage under the National Flood Insurance Program collected in excess of the rates required under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
