<bill session="113" type="h" number="4823" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Widening Internet Readiness for Employment Development Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">WIRED Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 to require one-stop delivery systems under such Act to offer services through Internet websites and to direct the Secretary of Labor to develop standards and best practices for such websites.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412514"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412550" joined="2014-06-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Training" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/10/2014--Introduced.
Widening Internet Readiness for Employment Development Act or WIRED Act - Amends the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 to revise one-stop delivery system requirements.

Requires the Secretary of Labor to establish certain standards and best practices for the provision of employment and training services for adults and dislocated workers on Internet websites maintained by one-stop delivery systems.

Requires the one-stop delivery system, at a minimum, to make those services accessible through an Internet website that: (1) is unique to the particular one-stop system, and (2) meets and incorporates those standards and best practices.</summary>
</bill>
