<bill session="113" type="h" number="5411" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Trafficking Awareness Training for Health Care Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the development and dissemination of evidence-based best practices for health care professionals to recognize victims of a severe form of trafficking and respond to such individuals appropriately, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412457"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1362-1363"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Nursing"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/8/2014--Introduced.
Trafficking Awareness Training for Health Care Act of 2014 - Requires the Administrator of the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality to award one medical or nursing school a grant to develop best practices for health care professionals to recognize and respond appropriately to victims of severe forms of human trafficking.

Requires the grantee to: (1) develop methods or materials to train health care professionals on best practices, (2) make a subgrant to one entity in each of the 10 administrative regions of the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to create a pilot program to test the best practices and training, and (3) analyze the results of the pilot programs and determine which best practices are evidence-based.

Directs HHS to disseminate evidence-based best practices on their website and to health care profession schools.</summary>
</bill>
