<bill session="113" type="hr" number="700" updated="2015-09-01T10:18:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-08-01T12:03:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-08-01T12:03:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Waiving a requirement of clause 6(a) of rule XIII with respect to consideration of certain resolutions reported from the Committee on Rules, and providing for consideration of motions to suspend the rules.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400077"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31T18:34:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 113-570, by Mr. Cole.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31T18:34:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule waives the reqirement for a two-thirds vote to consider a report from the Committee on Rules on the same day it is presented to the House with respect to any resolution reported through September 5, 2014 providing for consideration or disposition of measures relating to the ongoing humanitarian crisis on the U.S. southern border, border security, and related immigration law. The rule also makes it in order at any time through the legislative day of September 5, 2014, for hte Speaker to entertain motions tht athe House suspend the rules on measures addressing the ongoing humanitarian</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-07-31T18:34:00-04:00" state="REPORTED" calendar="House" number="134">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 134.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-08-01T10:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7191-7204" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-08-01T10:04:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 700.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-08-01T10:52:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House resumed debate on H. Res. 700.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-08-01T11:56:00-04:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 226 - 184 (Roll no. 474).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7203-7204" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="475" datetime="2014-08-01T12:03:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 219 - 190 (Roll no. 475).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7191" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-08-01T12:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/1/2014--Passed House without amendment.
Waives a specified requirement of Rule XIII (Calendar and Committee Reports) to allow consideration of any resolution reported from the Committee on Rules through the legislative day of September 5, 2014, providing for consideration or disposition of a measure relating to the ongoing humanitarian crisis on the U.S. southern border, border security, and related immigration law, on the same day it is presented to the House.</summary>
</bill>
