<bill session="113" type="s" number="2893" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Workforce Residential Housing Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the use of multifamily housing subject to a mortgage insured under section 207 of the National Housing Act as short-term residential housing.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400284"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412554" joined="2014-09-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1217"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Housing supply and affordability"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/18/2014--Introduced.
Workforce Residential Housing Act of 2014 - Amends the National Housing Act to except from the prohibition against the use of houses built with federally insured mortgages for transient or hotel housing certain mulifamily housing that is a short-term residential property, provided that the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) has determined that the provision of such insurance is appropriate.

Defines "short-term residential property" as multifamily housing that:

 has more than 50 dwelling units, each of which contains a kitchen and bathroom facilities; provides mailboxes for each unit; rents the units for a minimum stay of seven days; and does not provide food or beverage services, daily maid services, furnishing and laundering of linen without charge, or bellhop services. Directs the Secretary to: (1) evaluate the risk of providing mortgage insurance for short-term residential properties, and (2) report to Congress on whether any additional risk to the General Insurance Fund resulting from the provision of mortgage insurance for such properties is appropriate.</summary>
</bill>
