<bill session="113" type="h" number="4642" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-05-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Boating Occupancy and Teaching Safety Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">BOATS Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require all recreational vessels to have and post passenger capacity limits, to amend title 46, United States Code, to authorize States to enter into contracts for the provision of boating safety education services under State recreational boating safety programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400195"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-09">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-09">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-09">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW07" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII22" subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2774"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/9/2014--Introduced.
Boating Occupancy and Teaching Safety Act or the BOATS Act - Directs the Commandant of the Coast Guard to: (1) establish maximum passenger capacity and maximum weight capacity standards for recreational vessels, and (2) require manufacturers and operators of passenger vessels to permanently display in a legible manner that is clearly visible, including on each flying bridge of the vessel, to vessel passengers such maximum capacity requirements and a notice of the need to balance vessel weight to avoid capsizing.

Defines "flying bridge" to mean an open deck above the main navigating bridge of a recreational vessel.

Amends federal shipping law to revise state recreational boating safety program requirements.

Allows a state to contract with a local government or private entity to provide boating safety education services under a state recreational boating safety program. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to make amounts in the Sport Fish Restoration and Boating Trust Fund available for expenditures to carry out the purposes of the Dingell-Johnson Sport Fish Restoration Act (as in effect upon enactment of this Act).</summary>
</bill>
