<bill session="113" type="h" number="5594" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To suspend from the visa waiver program any country that has identified passport holders fighting with an Islamist extremist organization, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412532"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412569" joined="2014-09-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-10-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border and Maritime Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-10-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Border Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM11" subcommittee="Border and Maritime Security" name="House Homeland Security"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/18/2014--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to:

 suspend from the visa waiver program any country that has identified passport holders fighting with Islamic extremist organizations, including such groups as the Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant (ISIL) and al-Qaeda affiliated organizations; and restore a suspended country's program participation upon a determination by the Secretary of State, the Secretary of DHS, and the Director of National Intelligence of the ability of both the suspended country and the United States to identify, track, and negate the risk of any individual entering the United States from such country under the program. Expresses the sense of the Congress that:

 the Comptroller General (GAO) should review the national security risks associated with the visa waiver program and report the results to Congress; the Secretary of DHS should strengthen the electronic travel authorization system (ESTA), identify any individual fighting with an Islamic extremist organization, and deny that individual the ability to enter the United States by means of ESTA; and the Secretary DHS should expeditiously complete the biometric entry and exit data system.</summary>
</bill>
