<bill session="113" type="s" number="1666" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-11-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-11-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-11-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Healthcare Privacy and Anti-Fraud Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to improve the patient navigator program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412491"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400040" joined="2013-11-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="2013-11-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400134" joined="2013-11-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2013-11-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412320" joined="2013-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300072" joined="2013-11-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="2013-11-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300088" joined="2013-12-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-11-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/7/2013--Introduced.
Healthcare Privacy and Anti-Fraud Act - Amends the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to issue guidance (including concerning liability) to protect the privacy of individually identifiable information submitted to, or accessed by, health care exchange navigators.

Requires entities receiving grants under the navigator program to ensure that their employees undergo background checks, take an oath not to disclose individually identifiable information, and meet educational and licensure requirements comparable to those applicable to health insurance agents and brokers in the state.

Imposes criminal penalties for disclosure of individually identifiable information and misrepresentation as a navigator.

Directs the Secretary to annually make available a list of entities providing navigator services and a list of those determined to be ineligible or convicted of offenses described in this Act. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to exempt individuals from the penalty for not maintaining minimum essential coverage for any month if the failure resulted from advice of a navigator or a person purporting to provide such services.</summary>
</bill>
