<bill session="113" type="h" number="4387" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-20">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-06-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FSOC Transparency and Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Financial Stability Act of 2010 to require the Financial Stability Oversight Council to hold open meetings and comply with the requirements of the Federal Advisory Committee Act, to provide additional improvements to the Council, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400145"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="2014-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412508" joined="2014-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412479" joined="2014-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412422" joined="2014-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412484" joined="2014-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412474" joined="2014-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412305" joined="2014-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412551" joined="2014-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412411" joined="2014-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412570" joined="2014-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412461" joined="2014-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412548" joined="2014-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400627" joined="2014-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-20">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-20">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-06-20" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 32 - 27.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Financial Stability Oversight Council"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/3/2014--Introduced.
FSOC Transparency and Accountability Act - Amends the Financial Stability Act of 2010 to repeal the nonapplicability of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (FACA) to the Financial Stability Oversight Council (thus applying FACA to the Council).

Declares the Council an agency for purposes of the "Government in the Sunshine Act" (and its open meeting requirements).

 Revises the voting profile of Council members to single out the following member agencies as each having collectively one vote: (1) the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, (2) the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC), (3) the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC), (4) the Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC), and (5) the National Credit Union Administration (NCUA) Board.

Directs such member agencies to: (1) determine their Council vote by using the voting process normally applicable to votes by their members, and (2) cast the one collective Council vote by the agency head.

Permits any Council member to select to have one or more individuals on the member's staff attend a meeting of the Council, including any meeting of representatives of the member agencies other than the members themselves.

Requires all Council meetings to be open to attendance and participation by members of specified congressional committees, including any meeting of representatives of the member agencies other than the members themselves.</summary>
</bill>
