<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H692046B8509C499BAA36BA845217B2FD" public-private="public"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HR 1772 RH: Legal Workforce Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2014-12-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code> 
<calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 508</calendar> 
<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress> <session display="yes"> 2d Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 1772</legis-num> 
<associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 113–677, Part I]</associated-doc> 
<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20130426">April 26, 2013</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000583">Mr. Smith of Texas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000289">Mr. Goodlatte</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000059">Mr. Calvert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000566">Mr. Gowdy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000796">Mr. Westmoreland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001187">Mr. Stivers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000567">Mr. Lance</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000210">Mr. King of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000191">Mr. DeFazio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000244">Mr. Sensenbrenner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000448">Mr. Franks of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000592">Mr. Poe of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001183">Mr. Schweikert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000487">Mr. Royce</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001243">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000445">Mr. Forbes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001076">Mr. Chaffetz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001248">Mr. Burgess</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000573">Mr. Labrador</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000460">Mr. Farenthold</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001065">Mr. Holding</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001250">Mr. Bishop of Utah</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="I000056">Mr. Issa</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00" added-display-style="italic" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name> and <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc> 
</action> 
<action>
<action-date date="20141216">December 16, 2014</action-date>
<action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="H001055">Mr. Heck of Nevada</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000522">Mr. Smith of New Jersey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001048">Mr. Culberson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000013">Mr. Bachus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000067">Mr. Hall</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000250">Mr. Sessions</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000372">Mr. Frelinghuysen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000220">Mr. Kingston</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001192">Mr. Stewart</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001274">Mr. Brooks of Alabama</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001158">Mr. Marchant</cosponsor> </action-desc>
</action>
<action> 
<action-date date="20141216">December 16, 2014</action-date> 
<action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00" added-display-style="italic" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name> with an amendment</action-desc> 
<action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction> 
</action> 
<action>
<action-date date="20141216">December 16, 2014</action-date>
<action-desc>The <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committees on Ways and Means</committee-name> and <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and the Workforce</committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc>
<action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on April 26, 2013</action-instruction>
</action>
<action display="yes"> 
<action-desc display="yes"><pagebreak/></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to make mandatory and permanent requirements relating to use of an electronic employment eligibility verification system, and for other purposes.<pagebreak/></official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HJU00" reported-display-style="italic" id="H60F29C70A98541FDAD9FBBAEDD15BE9D"> 
<section id="H408ACADF69E8412FA5AF60AD668A0126" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Legal Workforce Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H0B63184AEEDE429AB92E3AF173BCBCB8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Employment eligibility verification process</header> 
<subsection id="H07DA4C605B69474F9F627DDFB1F933D7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 274A(b) of the <act-name parsable-cite="INA">Immigration and Nationality Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1324a">8 U.S.C. 1324a(b)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H959E3C7370A54858B84FB3755495FF81" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="HAE17468765684E3686F99FBB349439CD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Employment eligibility verification process</header> 
<paragraph id="H19DD3DEC9AB840E097BAC23490182750"><enum>(1)</enum><header>New hires, recruitment, and referral</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirements referred to in paragraphs (1)(B) and (3) of subsection (a) are, in the case of a person or other entity hiring, recruiting, or referring an individual for employment in the United States, the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD00E485033104B8AA1748B6DE39C34A7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Attestation after examination of documentation</header> 
<clause display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0C8E3A8D1AEE468EA7297CBB0972F9A1"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Attestation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the verification period (as defined in subparagraph (E)), the person or entity shall attest, under penalty of perjury and on a form, including electronic and telephonic formats, designated or established by the Secretary by regulation not later than 6 months after the date of the enactment of the Legal Workforce Act, that it has verified that the individual is not an unauthorized alien by—</text> 
<subclause id="H0BADA186EC1D41C1BD90DC54B7C8F11D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>obtaining from the individual the individual’s social security account number and recording the number on the form (if the individual claims to have been issued such a number), and, if the individual does not attest to United States nationality under subparagraph (B), obtaining such identification or authorization number established by the Department of Homeland Security for the alien as the Secretary of Homeland Security may specify, and recording such number on the form; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H32A8F6BA244843B99C8E00DEA31F35AE"><enum>(II)</enum><text>examining—</text> 
<item id="H695ABF0ADC724A00A88274DB2242B6CF"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a document relating to the individual presenting it described in clause (ii); or</text></item> 
<item id="HB2645D3C91FD4EE09C3858FCADDB0B78"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a document relating to the individual presenting it described in clause (iii) and a document relating to the individual presenting it described in clause (iv).</text></item></subclause></clause> 
<clause display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBA845F386D834C80879458BDDC97162B"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Documents evidencing employment authorization and establishing identity</header><text>A document described in this subparagraph is an individual’s—</text> 
<subclause id="H348DE050D7154FA6875BF697939CA37D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>unexpired United States passport or passport card;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HBEAD87E4F42A4482AD046648DE92E77E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>unexpired permanent resident card that contains a photograph;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H5074792C8A684077991EB4B27401B301"><enum>(III)</enum><text>unexpired employment authorization card that contains a photograph;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H9A023F97C2474A14B010F3FE37BE21C5"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a nonimmigrant alien authorized to work for a specific employer incident to status, a foreign passport with Form I–94 or Form I–94A, or other documentation as designated by the Secretary specifying the alien’s nonimmigrant status as long as the period of status has not yet expired and the proposed employment is not in conflict with any restrictions or limitations identified in the documentation;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H7AF5AE9494AB4E31B0F1AE06D1298F18"><enum>(V)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">passport from the Federated States of Micronesia (FSM) or the Republic of the Marshall Islands (RMI) with Form I–94 or Form I–94A, or other documentation as designated by the Secretary, indicating nonimmigrant admission under the Compact of Free Association Between the United States and the FSM or RMI; or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H6F4DC52AF11F4AEBA23A32BA5A75261E"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>other document designated by the Secretary of Homeland Security, if the document—</text> 
<item id="HB0518474291C4A73AC28C34DF40C8997"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">contains a photograph of the individual and biometric identification data from the individual and such other personal identifying information relating to the individual as the Secretary of Homeland Security finds, by regulation, sufficient for purposes of this clause;</text></item> 
<item id="HC847D72118D04FCFAAD0EA424DDE619C"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>is evidence of authorization of employment in the United States; and</text></item> 
<item id="HC085E51AC39942D59E49073151DED4C5"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>contains security features to make it resistant to tampering, counterfeiting, and fraudulent use.</text></item></subclause></clause> 
<clause display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE3B7BE97AC8440D8B15A36BD0AFBCC08"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Documents evidencing employment authorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A document described in this subparagraph is an individual's social security account number card (other than such a card which specifies on the face that the issuance of the card does not authorize employment in the United States).</text></clause> 
<clause display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H11F5AADB7AFB4FC9BBD2DFC4E7851811"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Documents establishing identity of individual</header><text>A document described in this subparagraph is—</text> 
<subclause id="H977EC4C4348549AC90EA5AB1DA3D8116"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an individual's unexpired State issued driver’s license or identification card if it contains a photograph and information such as name, date of birth, gender, height, eye color, and address;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HE66F5C72AA2B4C37AC186AD0BD154D7F"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an individual's unexpired U.S. military identification card;</text></subclause> 
<subclause commented="no" id="H5B05546BA9F4405DA7C63CA731707CC5"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an individual's unexpired Native American tribal identification document issued by a tribal entity recognized by the Bureau of Indian Affairs; or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HB8764C47014841639C69B1582BF8220C"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an individual under 18 years of age, a parent or legal guardian’s attestation under penalty of law as to the identity and age of the individual.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H499A16D88548445DB16248C7222401D2"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Authority to prohibit use of certain documents</header><text>If the Secretary of Homeland Security finds, by regulation, that any document described in clause (i), (ii), or (iii) as establishing employment authorization or identity does not reliably establish such authorization or identity or is being used fraudulently to an unacceptable degree, the Secretary may prohibit or place conditions on its use for purposes of this paragraph.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB9806EA27F9C4FAB922EFF4E490FC093"><enum>(vi)</enum><header>Signature</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such attestation may be manifested by either a hand-written or electronic signature.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7E7DF81F5C9A4B27A3125459CA3FBA9A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Individual attestation of employment authorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the verification period (as defined in subparagraph (E)), the individual shall attest, under penalty of perjury on the form designated or established for purposes of subparagraph (A), that the individual is a citizen or national of the United States, an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence, or an alien who is authorized under this Act or by the Secretary of Homeland Security to be hired, recruited, or referred for such employment. Such attestation may be manifested by either a hand-written or electronic signature. The individual shall also provide that individual’s social security account number (if the individual claims to have been issued such a number), and, if the individual does not attest to United States nationality under this subparagraph, such identification or authorization number established by the Department of Homeland Security for the alien as the Secretary may specify.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2353CD3AAC34408C8959F120E5909606"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Retention of verification form and verification</header> 
<clause id="H0FFD6E1E174C45F68FCAA5F9F0325AC4"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>After completion of such form in accordance with subparagraphs (A) and (B), the person or entity shall—</text> 
<subclause id="H37DA0AE890814C05BF4C7C1C854EDFD2"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">retain a paper, microfiche, microfilm, or electronic version of the form and make it available for inspection by officers of the Department of Homeland Security, the Special Counsel for Immigration-Related Unfair Employment Practices, or the Department of Labor during a period beginning on the date of the recruiting or referral of the individual, or, in the case of the hiring of an individual, the date on which the verification is completed, and ending—</text> 
<item id="H9A4653287CB34CD8A4E6FA1D9CC1D3A0"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>in the case of the recruiting or referral of an individual, 3 years after the date of the recruiting or referral; and</text></item> 
<item id="HC769291F70864EDDAD4709FE54A4D2FB"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of the hiring of an individual, the later of 3 years after the date the verification is completed or one year after the date the individual’s employment is terminated; and</text></item></subclause> 
<subclause id="H1271B2E9E89C45AD867AEFA731A789D7"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">during the verification period (as defined in subparagraph (E)), make an inquiry, as provided in subsection (d), using the verification system to seek verification of the identity and employment eligibility of an individual.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H9C2CBE4466CF492A9CAA600398AC629F"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Confirmation</header> 
<subclause id="H7D9D97F2F6FA45A98BBFC8A1A43A4669"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Confirmation received</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the person or other entity receives an appropriate confirmation of an individual’s identity and work eligibility under the verification system within the time period specified, the person or entity shall record on the form an appropriate code that is provided under the system and that indicates a final confirmation of such identity and work eligibility of the individual.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HA8461AB1575E4F508B36BFBE9553BD7A"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Tentative nonconfirmation received</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the person or other entity receives a tentative nonconfirmation of an individual’s identity or work eligibility under the verification system within the time period specified, the person or entity shall so inform the individual for whom the verification is sought. If the individual does not contest the nonconfirmation within the time period specified, the nonconfirmation shall be considered final. The person or entity shall then record on the form an appropriate code which has been provided under the system to indicate a final nonconfirmation. If the individual does contest the nonconfirmation, the individual shall utilize the process for secondary verification provided under subsection (d). The nonconfirmation will remain tentative until a final confirmation or nonconfirmation is provided by the verification system within the time period specified. In no case shall an employer terminate employment of an individual because of a failure of the individual to have identity and work eligibility confirmed under this section until a nonconfirmation becomes final. Nothing in this clause shall apply to a termination of employment for any reason other than because of such a failure. In no case shall an employer rescind the offer of employment to an individual because of a failure of the individual to have identity and work eligibility confirmed under this subsection until a nonconfirmation becomes final. Nothing in this subclause shall apply to a recission of the offer of employment for any reason other than because of such a failure.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H9FD1B3F485734AB5B11C316B522B1F01"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Final confirmation or nonconfirmation received</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a final confirmation or nonconfirmation is provided by the verification system regarding an individual, the person or entity shall record on the form an appropriate code that is provided under the system and that indicates a confirmation or nonconfirmation of identity and work eligibility of the individual.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H01F9DDD7887E4058BE3C8B65169B9B98"><enum>(IV)</enum><header>Extension of time</header><text>If the person or other entity in good faith attempts to make an inquiry during the time period specified and the verification system has registered that not all inquiries were received during such time, the person or entity may make an inquiry in the first subsequent working day in which the verification system registers that it has received all inquiries. If the verification system cannot receive inquiries at all times during a day, the person or entity merely has to assert that the entity attempted to make the inquiry on that day for the previous sentence to apply to such an inquiry, and does not have to provide any additional proof concerning such inquiry.</text></subclause> 
<subclause commented="no" id="HCD2BDE0D4806425196BC9FEDA9C9B808"><enum>(V)</enum><header>Consequences of nonconfirmation</header> 
<item commented="no" id="HFC2017C145324D8BAAD37F01B44A69C9"><enum>(aa)</enum><header>Termination or notification of continued employment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the person or other entity has received a final nonconfirmation regarding an individual, the person or entity may terminate employment of the individual (or decline to recruit or refer the individual). If the person or entity does not terminate employment of the individual or proceeds to recruit or refer the individual, the person or entity shall notify the Secretary of Homeland Security of such fact through the verification system or in such other manner as the Secretary may specify.</text></item> 
<item commented="no" id="H81DAC8884DB040F9B54E1DF624C68E83"><enum>(bb)</enum><header>Failure to notify</header><text>If the person or entity fails to provide notice with respect to an individual as required under item (aa), the failure is deemed to constitute a violation of subsection (a)(1)(A) with respect to that individual.</text></item></subclause> 
<subclause id="HA8549891555D4BF3A23B01907FE67FED"><enum>(VI)</enum><header>Continued employment after final nonconfirmation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the person or other entity continues to employ (or to recruit or refer) an individual after receiving final nonconfirmation, a rebuttable presumption is created that the person or entity has violated subsection (a)(1)(A).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HC3A35659268341899C80275A37DC3B9C"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Effective dates of new procedures</header> 
<clause commented="no" id="H29C89293118F4C7EBBECD494EDDBDBFB"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Hiring</header><text>Except as provided in clause (iii), the provisions of this paragraph shall apply to a person or other entity hiring an individual for employment in the United States as follows:</text> 
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFF6FD0D6FC824F689475A85CA5BD91DC"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to employers having 10,000 or more employees in the United States on the date of the enactment of the Legal Workforce Act, on the date that is 6 months after the date of the enactment of such Act.</text></subclause> 
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9686E9C346BB4A6893E2112D0FAF5AFC"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to employers having 500 or more employees in the United States, but less than 10,000 employees in the United States, on the date of the enactment of the Legal Workforce Act, on the date that is 12 months after the date of the enactment of such Act.</text></subclause> 
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H934CE43E10E345CE9985FFA29812C9CB"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to employers having 20 or more employees in the United States, but less than 500 employees in the United States, on the date of the enactment of the Legal Workforce Act, on the date that is 18 months after the date of the enactment of such Act.</text></subclause> 
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H551A7DC3A7814B6696AB6AB2584CF6DC"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to employers having 1 or more employees in the United States, but less than 20 employees in the United States, on the date of the enactment of the Legal Workforce Act, on the date that is 24 months after the date of the enactment of such Act.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H14A1ABDF91AE4CDDB54AE757777EFE34"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Recruiting and referring</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in clause (iii), the provisions of this paragraph shall apply to a person or other entity recruiting or referring an individual for employment in the United States on the date that is 12 months after the date of the enactment of the Legal Workforce Act.</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="H7BDBDB64F2784F1CBE9067F28D42F85D"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Agricultural labor or services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to an employee performing agricultural labor or services, this paragraph shall not apply with respect to the verification of the employee until the date that is 24 months after the date of the enactment of the Legal Workforce Act. For purposes of the preceding sentence, the term <quote>agricultural labor or services</quote> has the meaning given such term by the Secretary of Agriculture in regulations and includes agricultural labor as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/3121">section 3121(g)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, agriculture as defined in section 3(f) of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/203">29 U.S.C. 203(f)</external-xref>), the handling, planting, drying, packing, packaging, processing, freezing, or grading prior to delivery for storage of any agricultural or horticultural commodity in its unmanufactured state, all activities required for the preparation, processing or manufacturing of a product of agriculture (as such term is defined in such section 3(f)) for further distribution, and activities similar to all the foregoing as they relate to fish or shellfish in aquaculture facilities. An employee described in this clause shall not be counted for purposes of clause (i).</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="HB29EA931FFA240B1B18CB2F9D5907BDF"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Transition rule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to paragraph (4), the following shall apply to a person or other entity hiring, recruiting, or referring an individual for employment in the United States until the effective date or dates applicable under clauses (i) through (iii):</text> 
<subclause commented="no" id="H5311622EEB724C1C97EAA004656C6A27"><enum>(I)</enum><text>This subsection, as in effect before the enactment of the Legal Workforce Act.</text></subclause> 
<subclause commented="no" id="HCA1990A810634D4B874A80EED4933ED2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Subtitle A of title IV of the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1324a">8 U.S.C. 1324a</external-xref> note), as in effect before the effective date in section 7(c) of the Legal Workforce Act.</text></subclause> 
<subclause commented="no" id="HC286828E8F4D4BA688B4FEE1E94BFE39"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any other provision of Federal law requiring the person or entity to participate in the E-Verify Program described in section 403(a) of the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1324a">8 U.S.C. 1324a</external-xref> note), as in effect before the effective date in section 7(c) of the Legal Workforce Act, including Executive Order 13465 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1324a">8 U.S.C. 1324a</external-xref> note; relating to Government procurement).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5ED069DF967F4369895A1FDD39175D09"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Verification period defined</header> 
<clause id="H7D94D8647F0A4C8EA36921F6F97FA10B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this paragraph:</text> 
<subclause id="H48927BA07BB84EF6B0C7FA277BBE0DB9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>In the case of recruitment or referral, the term <term>verification period</term> means the period ending on the date recruiting or referring commences.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HFE391726A55040D1A95EACBE0EAA62B1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>In the case of hiring, the term <term>verification period</term> means the period beginning on the date on which an offer of employment is extended and ending on the date that is 3 business days after the date of hire, except as provided in clause (iii). The offer of employment may be conditioned in accordance with clause (ii).</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HBDE75C5D20FE4BCEAC9784C1B95ED4FC"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Job offer may be conditional</header><text>A person or other entity may offer a prospective employee an employment position that is conditioned on final verification of the identity and employment eligibility of the employee using the procedures established under this paragraph.</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="H926AEA7E79C34AE2958B1BA1E65281D5"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Special rule</header><text>Notwithstanding clause (i)(II), in the case of an alien who is authorized for employment and who provides evidence from the Social Security Administration that the alien has applied for a social security account number, the verification period ends three business days after the alien receives the social security account number.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="HE0764D5EE6A4439BBE247E689E1E071D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reverification for individuals with limited work authorization</header> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HE37CFCC4978C4A6C9655BA953B148046"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), a person or entity shall make an inquiry, as provided in subsection (d), using the verification system to seek reverification of the identity and employment eligibility of all individuals with a limited period of work authorization employed by the person or entity during the 3 business days after the date on which the employee's work authorization expires as follows:</text> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2BB98BF9811248A390C2DD76B7C4250C"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to employers having 10,000 or more employees in the United States on the date of the enactment of the Legal Workforce Act, beginning on the date that is 6 months after the date of the enactment of such Act.</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H303DB0D1DF0C4960B21F2BFE37667F2C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to employers having 500 or more employees in the United States, but less than 10,000 employees in the United States, on the date of the enactment of the Legal Workforce Act, beginning on the date that is 12 months after the date of the enactment of such Act.</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEB03BEA8B6454D278130CB6B538B1FF4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to employers having 20 or more employees in the United States, but less than 500 employees in the United States, on the date of the enactment of the Legal Workforce Act, beginning on the date that is 18 months after the date of the enactment of such Act.</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H918E087872BD4D4E8C2A408F39FC7534"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to employers having 1 or more employees in the United States, but less than 20 employees in the United States, on the date of the enactment of the Legal Workforce Act, beginning on the date that is 24 months after the date of the enactment of such Act.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H32CB524818F644E5AAFE0CCBE71FE971"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Agricultural labor or services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to an employee performing agricultural labor or services, or an employee recruited or referred by a farm labor contractor (as defined in section 3 of the Migrant and Seasonal Agricultural Worker Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1801">29 U.S.C. 1801</external-xref>)), subparagraph (A) shall not apply with respect to the reverification of the employee until the date that is 24 months after the date of the enactment of the Legal Workforce Act. For purposes of the preceding sentence, the term <quote>agricultural labor or services</quote> has the meaning given such term by the Secretary of Agriculture in regulations and includes agricultural labor as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/3121">section 3121(g)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, agriculture as defined in section 3(f) of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/203">29 U.S.C. 203(f)</external-xref>), the handling, planting, drying, packing, packaging, processing, freezing, or grading prior to delivery for storage of any agricultural or horticultural commodity in its unmanufactured state, all activities required for the preparation, processing, or manufacturing of a product of agriculture (as such term is defined in such section 3(f)) for further distribution, and activities similar to all the foregoing as they relate to fish or shellfish in aquaculture facilities. An employee described in this subparagraph shall not be counted for purposes of subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HFC6C6686CC3F4D6B8EDF6B152FBE5CEB"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Reverification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1)(C)(ii) shall apply to reverifications pursuant to this paragraph on the same basis as it applies to verifications pursuant to paragraph (1), except that employers shall—</text> 
<clause id="HCC3B3DFBEB8041B29B6C848B823B0D65"><enum>(i)</enum><text>use a form designated or established by the Secretary by regulation for purposes of this paragraph; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H0C14E79865AF4496B26CC46CA0C72DF1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">retain a paper, microfiche, microfilm, or electronic version of the form and make it available for inspection by officers of the Department of Homeland Security, the Special Counsel for Immigration-Related Unfair Employment Practices, or the Department of Labor during the period beginning on the date the reverification commences and ending on the date that is the later of 3 years after the date of such reverification or 1 year after the date the individual’s employment is terminated.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H63FC31EC99D8427D8DC9A0D8FE49A949"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Previously hired individuals</header> 
<subparagraph id="H174A5E667EDF4E9C8285AC15E4B85E59"><enum>(A)</enum><header>On a mandatory basis for certain employees</header> 
<clause id="HDB2998B70C7F44629F6BA87E026EA0CE"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than the date that is 6 months after the date of the enactment of the Legal Workforce Act, an employer shall make an inquiry, as provided in subsection (d), using the verification system to seek verification of the identity and employment eligibility of any individual described in clause (ii) employed by the employer whose employment eligibility has not been verified under the E-Verify Program described in section 403(a) of the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1324a">8 U.S.C. 1324a</external-xref> note).</text></clause> 
<clause id="H1E6AF12589704854BE3A0C8D540A6C78"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Individuals described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual described in this clause is any of the following:</text> 
<subclause id="HED3C500424384F54A30739C0E25A0CBD"><enum>(I)</enum><text>An employee of any unit of a Federal, State, or local government.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H6764E6E5E8BB4FCAAE223441E48A369F"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An employee who requires a Federal security clearance working in a Federal, State or local government building, a military base, a nuclear energy site, a weapons site, or an airport or other facility that requires workers to carry a Transportation Worker Identification Credential (TWIC).</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H4308D7DF798B457AAF72903DBEC088E7"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An employee assigned to perform work in the United States under a Federal contract, except that this subclause—</text> 
<item id="HE2D0F47E4ED64E18AEEB02AFE41DF29E"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>is not applicable to individuals who have a clearance under Homeland Security Presidential Directive 12 (HSPD 12 clearance), are administrative or overhead personnel, or are working solely on contracts that provide Commercial Off The Shelf goods or services as set forth by the Federal Acquisition Regulatory Council, unless they are subject to verification under subclause (II); and</text></item> 
<item id="HBA6078032EC14E77B82C1E4C08BF1B7B"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>only applies to contracts over the simple acquisition threshold as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="regulation" parsable-cite="cfr/48/2.101">section 2.101</external-xref> of title 48, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE2CBEBA1F77946518B7776476E9C6CA6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>On a mandatory basis for multiple users of same social security account number</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an employer who is required by this subsection to use the verification system described in subsection (d), or has elected voluntarily to use such system, the employer shall make inquiries to the system in accordance with the following:</text> 
<clause id="H1CD951E3D8954E179DDF50ED3C9BF6D8"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commissioner of Social Security shall notify annually employees (at the employee address listed on the Wage and Tax Statement) who submit a social security account number to which more than one employer reports income and for which there is a pattern of unusual multiple use. The notification letter shall identify the number of employers to which income is being reported as well as sufficient information notifying the employee of the process to contact the Social Security Administration Fraud Hotline if the employee believes the employee’s identity may have been stolen. The notice shall not share information protected as private, in order to avoid any recipient of the notice from being in the position to further commit or begin committing identity theft.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE94793B0CDBA4CC6B97B6AB72EED4BD3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the person to whom the social security account number was issued by the Social Security Administration has been identified and confirmed by the Commissioner, and indicates that the social security account number was used without their knowledge, the Secretary and the Commissioner shall lock the social security account number for employment eligibility verification purposes and shall notify the employers of the individuals who wrongfully submitted the social security account number that the employee may not be work eligible.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H25B346BA370C455D8432BE2276885FA5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each employer receiving such notification of an incorrect social security account number under clause (ii) shall use the verification system described in subsection (d) to check the work eligibility status of the applicable employee within 10 business days of receipt of the notification.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6E6EF0131EAD4C89B19DD3474D9F4AC3"><enum>(C)</enum><header>On a voluntary basis</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to paragraph (2), and subparagraphs (A) through (C) of this paragraph, beginning on the date that is 30 days after the date of the enactment of the Legal Workforce Act, an employer may make an inquiry, as provided in subsection (d), using the verification system to seek verification of the identity and employment eligibility of any individual employed by the employer. If an employer chooses voluntarily to seek verification of any individual employed by the employer, the employer shall seek verification of all individuals employed at the same geographic location or, at the option of the employer, all individuals employed within the same job category, as the employee with respect to whom the employer seeks voluntarily to use the verification system. An employer’s decision about whether or not voluntarily to seek verification of its current workforce under this subparagraph may not be considered by any government agency in any proceeding, investigation, or review provided for in this Act.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H2D7CF675D0CD4C7E89ADA00B756DC7AE"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Verification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1)(C)(ii) shall apply to verifications pursuant to this paragraph on the same basis as it applies to verifications pursuant to paragraph (1), except that employers shall—</text> 
<clause id="H84EF6681B5EB43009CFE9D3AE1976AB2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>use a form designated or established by the Secretary by regulation for purposes of this paragraph; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H453412B01D0A4677895EB3EA6FDE0D7D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">retain a paper, microfiche, microfilm, or electronic version of the form and make it available for inspection by officers of the Department of Homeland Security, the Special Counsel for Immigration-Related Unfair Employment Practices, or the Department of Labor during the period beginning on the date the verification commences and ending on the date that is the later of 3 years after the date of such verification or 1 year after the date the individual’s employment is terminated.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H31B973FC324044A293A78387F9CF65C2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Early compliance</header> 
<subparagraph id="HDF61C4B421AC47DCA88CDC1721EE1639"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Former E-Verify required users, including Federal contractors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding the deadlines in paragraphs (1) and (2), beginning on the date of the enactment of the Legal Workforce Act, the Secretary is authorized to commence requiring employers required to participate in the E-Verify Program described in section 403(a) of the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1324a">8 U.S.C. 1324a</external-xref> note), including employers required to participate in such program by reason of Federal acquisition laws (and regulations promulgated under those laws, including the Federal Acquisition Regulation), to commence compliance with the requirements of this subsection (and any additional requirements of such Federal acquisition laws and regulation) in lieu of any requirement to participate in the E-Verify Program.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3BBFB0B6E1E645E8A5F72BA2B7D33A95"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Former E-Verify voluntary users and others desiring early compliance</header><text>Notwithstanding the deadlines in paragraphs (1) and (2), beginning on the date of the enactment of the Legal Workforce Act, the Secretary shall provide for the voluntary compliance with the requirements of this subsection by employers voluntarily electing to participate in the E-Verify Program described in section 403(a) of the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1324a">8 U.S.C. 1324a</external-xref> note) before such date, as well as by other employers seeking voluntary early compliance.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD212B7C0EB55440887824BDBD6980DDF"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Copying of documentation permitted</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the person or entity may copy a document presented by an individual pursuant to this subsection and may retain the copy, but only (except as otherwise permitted under law) for the purpose of complying with the requirements of this subsection.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCF2CC075253D444BBC258F689FAFE05C"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Limitation on use of forms</header><text>A form designated or established by the Secretary of Homeland Security under this subsection and any information contained in or appended to such form, may not be used for purposes other than for enforcement of this Act and any other provision of Federal criminal law.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2111131BCE614A49869497EDCFEBE013"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Good faith compliance</header> 
<subparagraph id="H57607598645B485D9BEF4E581E067177"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, a person or entity is considered to have complied with a requirement of this subsection notwithstanding a technical or procedural failure to meet such requirement if there was a good faith attempt to comply with the requirement.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF8964BD98F934A81893667ABD1532E2E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception if failure to correct after notice</header><text>Subparagraph (A) shall not apply if—</text> 
<clause id="H7B262D4DC4CD447482A5F8A067205D23"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the failure is not de minimus;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HABC2A0B2546B41B798D1FE3CC1938EAC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Secretary of Homeland Security has explained to the person or entity the basis for the failure and why it is not de minimus;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H3BB358E0392F420E9C12C013A3515618"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the person or entity has been provided a period of not less than 30 calendar days (beginning after the date of the explanation) within which to correct the failure; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H85655313ACE2440F970A58954CC64A24"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the person or entity has not corrected the failure voluntarily within such period.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9087B80B56844DC2887BD15524E5B793"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Exception for pattern or practice violators</header><text>Subparagraph (A) shall not apply to a person or entity that has or is engaging in a pattern or practice of violations of subsection (a)(1)(A) or (a)(2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3627233EAF384EF2A971B39DD844CCEA"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Single extension of deadlines upon certification</header><text>In a case in which the Secretary of Homeland Security has certified to the Congress that the employment eligibility verification system required under subsection (d) will not be fully operational by the date that is 6 months after the date of the enactment of the Legal Workforce Act, each deadline established under this section for an employer to make an inquiry using such system shall be extended by 6 months. No other extension of such a deadline shall be made.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H922263C71F5E40B4A1A1211D4CC43C99"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Date of hire</header><text>Section 274A(h) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1324a">8 U.S.C. 1324a(h)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDA097E9CDE774EB798793650A348A6AA" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="H13BB380BB7E7447F8C94799579001A73"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Definition of date of hire</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As used in this section, the term <quote>date of hire</quote> means the date of actual commencement of employment for wages or other remuneration, unless otherwise specified.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
<section id="H49546A1CD997436D82F9EF5797EBA0E3"><enum>3.</enum><header>Employment eligibility verification system</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 274A(d) of the <act-name parsable-cite="INA">Immigration and Nationality Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1324a">8 U.S.C. 1324a(d)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block act-name="Immigration and Nationality Act" id="HF2F085CB767C46ABAD88C453BF4ACB90" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="HAAB11F1157D6466ABFC76C8EB70FF971"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Employment eligibility verification system</header> 
<paragraph id="HEAFB0BB0F2E24060B5105BA1261E8369"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Patterned on the employment eligibility confirmation system established under section 404 of the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1324a">8 U.S.C. 1324a</external-xref> note), the Secretary of Homeland Security shall establish and administer a verification system through which the Secretary (or a designee of the Secretary, which may be a nongovernmental entity)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HFCE31831DD0C492CA2A252DEF4E1B531"><enum>(A)</enum><text>responds to inquiries made by persons at any time through a toll-free telephone line and other toll-free electronic media concerning an individual’s identity and whether the individual is authorized to be employed; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAEBEAF44878B4FAC97287320EB368CDC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>maintains records of the inquiries that were made, of verifications provided (or not provided), and of the codes provided to inquirers as evidence of their compliance with their obligations under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H42D24C8253B944389B59C66AA503638C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Initial response</header><text>The verification system shall provide confirmation or a tentative nonconfirmation of an individual’s identity and employment eligibility within 3 working days of the initial inquiry. If providing confirmation or tentative nonconfirmation, the verification system shall provide an appropriate code indicating such confirmation or such nonconfirmation.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF19D867947204A6F80B18D4944779C57"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secondary confirmation process in case of tentative nonconfirmation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In cases of tentative nonconfirmation, the Secretary shall specify, in consultation with the Commissioner of Social Security, an available secondary verification process to confirm the validity of information provided and to provide a final confirmation or nonconfirmation not later than 10 working days after the date on which the notice of the tentative nonconfirmation is received by the employee. The Secretary, in consultation with the Commissioner, may extend this deadline once on a case-by-case basis for a period of 10 working days, and if the time is extended, shall document such extension within the verification system. The Secretary, in consultation with the Commissioner, shall notify the employee and employer of such extension. The Secretary, in consultation with the Commissioner, shall create a standard process of such extension and notification and shall make a description of such process available to the public. When final confirmation or nonconfirmation is provided, the verification system shall provide an appropriate code indicating such confirmation or nonconfirmation.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="HB7B6760597AE420587FB6613E3674F56"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Design and operation of system</header><text>The verification system shall be designed and operated—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H3379FD1A4CFC4182AD224E5546960D76"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to maximize its reliability and ease of use by persons and other entities consistent with insulating and protecting the privacy and security of the underlying information;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H5336155647334DBD9F5226D754E4EE59"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to respond to all inquiries made by such persons and entities on whether individuals are authorized to be employed and to register all times when such inquiries are not received;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H010BD62CDA08410DBCD81BDB076A8C63"><enum>(C)</enum><text>with appropriate administrative, technical, and physical safeguards to prevent unauthorized disclosure of personal information;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H701437F3464B4A6C916839E580F82D37"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to have reasonable safeguards against the system’s resulting in unlawful discriminatory practices based on national origin or citizenship status, including—</text> 
<clause commented="no" id="HBC1DA34CE21349909354EE53B2597BF2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the selective or unauthorized use of the system to verify eligibility; or</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="HD68303EEE85245BCA2585A785597888B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the exclusion of certain individuals from consideration for employment as a result of a perceived likelihood that additional verification will be required, beyond what is required for most job applicants;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H97DEA1F53B5A42D58049C2CAD092F27F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>to maximize the prevention of identity theft use in the system; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H233C19F5748944BD8C0B97E86B91B0D5"><enum>(F)</enum><text>to limit the subjects of verification to the following individuals:</text> 
<clause commented="no" id="HDCB7EF6AF2D9484AA2B1DF4E4ABD1D73"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Individuals hired, referred, or recruited, in accordance with paragraph (1) or (4) of subsection (b).</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="H2E56FECBA3444A83BC3F92D963CCD677"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Employees and prospective employees, in accordance with paragraph (1), (2), (3), or (4) of subsection (b).</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="HB89136358A91444BAAC8774E3D917D80"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Individuals seeking to confirm their own employment eligibility on a voluntary basis.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H40C1AD9491B7401397486F3724B79042"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Responsibilities of Commissioner of Social Security</header><text>As part of the verification system, the Commissioner of Social Security, in consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security (and any designee of the Secretary selected to establish and administer the verification system), shall establish a reliable, secure method, which, within the time periods specified under paragraphs (2) and (3), compares the name and social security account number provided in an inquiry against such information maintained by the Commissioner in order to validate (or not validate) the information provided regarding an individual whose identity and employment eligibility must be confirmed, the correspondence of the name and number, and whether the individual has presented a social security account number that is not valid for employment. The Commissioner shall not disclose or release social security information (other than such confirmation or nonconfirmation) under the verification system except as provided for in this section or section 205(c)(2)(I) of the Social Security Act.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB1D30DFC00BB408CA0A9A1297C30810B"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Responsibilities of Secretary of Homeland Security</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As part of the verification system, the Secretary of Homeland Security (in consultation with any designee of the Secretary selected to establish and administer the verification system), shall establish a reliable, secure method, which, within the time periods specified under paragraphs (2) and (3), compares the name and alien identification or authorization number (or any other information as determined relevant by the Secretary) which are provided in an inquiry against such information maintained or accessed by the Secretary in order to validate (or not validate) the information provided, the correspondence of the name and number, whether the alien is authorized to be employed in the United States, or to the extent that the Secretary determines to be feasible and appropriate, whether the records available to the Secretary verify the identity or status of a national of the United States.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H905C859F8D2549288D347A4AA85B8B80"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Updating information</header><text>The Commissioner of Social Security and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall update their information in a manner that promotes the maximum accuracy and shall provide a process for the prompt correction of erroneous information, including instances in which it is brought to their attention in the secondary verification process described in paragraph (3).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H357E67F2A9E3440D97F320B595A70F5D"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Limitation on use of the verification system and any related systems</header> 
<subparagraph id="HC81AB7BF021540E4A2170D391F43CAB1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>No national identification card</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to authorize, directly or indirectly, the issuance or use of national identification cards or the establishment of a national identification card.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H8EBC35F006864F93B2DDEC7B1754E71A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Critical infrastructure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may authorize or direct any person or entity responsible for granting access to, protecting, securing, operating, administering, or regulating part of the critical infrastructure (as defined in section 1016(e) of the Critical Infrastructure Protection Act of 2001 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5195c">42 U.S.C. 5195c(e)</external-xref>)) to use the verification system to the extent the Secretary determines that such use will assist in the protection of the critical infrastructure.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC6DF5478B33C4213ADBFDCDA4042003F"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Remedies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an individual alleges that the individual would not have been dismissed from a job but for an error of the verification mechanism, the individual may seek compensation only through the mechanism of the Federal Tort Claims Act, and injunctive relief to correct such error. No class action may be brought under this paragraph.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7C1DB545C2AD46479F9FE41E4BC0EF5D"><enum>4.</enum><header>Recruitment, referral, and continuation of employment</header> 
<subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC539F60D7FA444CEB325EB243213D1C6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Additional changes to rules for recruitment, referral, and continuation of employment</header><text>Section 274A(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1324a">8 U.S.C. 1324a(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H28A11FDF990F4D0F9EE1032BC5B05457"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(A), by striking <quote>for a fee</quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H307CF589B9D54652A9A3BC1CCFE240DA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by amending subparagraph (B) to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H23964DEA633243639C88EE3DEFCEBA98" style="OLC"> 
<subparagraph id="H931A02DFC9DC4D3392A015093603B47F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to hire, continue to employ, or to recruit or refer for employment in the United States an individual without complying with the requirements of subsection (b).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0176732E7D884B17B3C3992FC06E4F2A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>after hiring an alien for employment in accordance with paragraph (1),</quote> and inserting <quote>after complying with paragraph (1),</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC5C7C9F0899A46D0BF20CB3941473CA2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 274A(h) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1324a">8 U.S.C. 1324a(h)</external-xref>), as amended by section 2(b) of this Act, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA7361BAA2F7844059265C37FF437F2E7" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="H37BFBC76B8694559A3BE58506ADA86D6"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Definition of recruit or refer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As used in this section, the term <term>refer</term> means the act of sending or directing a person who is in the United States or transmitting documentation or information to another, directly or indirectly, with the intent of obtaining employment in the United States for such person. Only persons or entities referring for remuneration (whether on a retainer or contingency basis) are included in the definition, except that union hiring halls that refer union members or nonunion individuals who pay union membership dues are included in the definition whether or not they receive remuneration, as are labor service entities or labor service agencies, whether public, private, for-profit, or nonprofit, that refer, dispatch, or otherwise facilitate the hiring of laborers for any period of time by a third party. As used in this section, the term <term>recruit</term> means the act of soliciting a person who is in the United States, directly or indirectly, and referring the person to another with the intent of obtaining employment for that person. Only persons or entities referring for remuneration (whether on a retainer or contingency basis) are included in the definition, except that union hiring halls that refer union members or nonunion individuals who pay union membership dues are included in this definition whether or not they receive remuneration, as are labor service entities or labor service agencies, whether public, private, for-profit, or nonprofit that recruit, dispatch, or otherwise facilitate the hiring of laborers for any period of time by a third party.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H24E350BA38724988ABC3788DB6517B0D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall take effect on the date that is 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, except that the amendments made by subsection (a) shall take effect 6 months after the date of the enactment of this Act insofar as such amendments relate to continuation of employment.</text></subsection></section> 
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H314920E880194A20A69165C6506AEBD0" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>5.</enum><header>Good faith defense</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 274A(a)(3) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1324a">8 U.S.C. 1324a(a)(3)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFAD216F4B27445D1BEB5586A81D30000" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="H1C9E726B39EC4A12813942BBCF31D979"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Good faith defense</header> 
<subparagraph id="HA617263F2CD14F42956CE351F2A04398"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Defense</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An employer (or person or entity that hires, employs, recruits, or refers (as defined in subsection (h)(5)), or is otherwise obligated to comply with this section) who establishes that it has complied in good faith with the requirements of subsection (b)—</text> 
<clause id="H08F34261E636490F90391E72CF7F6DB2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall not be liable to a job applicant, an employee, the Federal Government, or a State or local government, under Federal, State, or local criminal or civil law for any employment-related action taken with respect to a job applicant or employee in good-faith reliance on information provided through the system established under subsection (d); and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB8BA2FE24FE241098C69F3DDFE51BB80"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has established compliance with its obligations under subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (1) and subsection (b) absent a showing by the Secretary of Homeland Security, by clear and convincing evidence, that the employer had knowledge that an employee is an unauthorized alien.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9F6374D71CCB49DC842861D07DE063E0" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Mitigation element</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subparagraph (A)(i), if an employer proves by a preponderance of the evidence that the employer uses a reasonable, secure, and established technology to authenticate the identity of the new employee, that fact shall be taken into account for purposes of determining good faith use of the system established under subsection (d).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD3C6E13932F44759B062D3262E7A0DAC"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Failure to seek and obtain verification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the effective dates and other deadlines applicable under subsection (b), in the case of a person or entity in the United States that hires, or continues to employ, an individual, or recruits or refers an individual for employment, the following requirements apply:</text> 
<clause id="H84A0B13E64FB42049CEF49FF2074D415"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Failure to seek verification</header> 
<subclause id="H36F9D7C902C4457180DF3FE6690DD263"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the person or entity has not made an inquiry, under the mechanism established under subsection (d) and in accordance with the timeframes established under subsection (b), seeking verification of the identity and work eligibility of the individual, the defense under subparagraph (A) shall not be considered to apply with respect to any employment, except as provided in subclause (II).</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H6C07DC66D3F24DA8B3745172FBBA2B2C"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Special rule for failure of verification mechanism</header><text>If such a person or entity in good faith attempts to make an inquiry in order to qualify for the defense under subparagraph (A) and the verification mechanism has registered that not all inquiries were responded to during the relevant time, the person or entity can make an inquiry until the end of the first subsequent working day in which the verification mechanism registers no nonresponses and qualify for such defense.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H57D0CC9564AF4B1DA49A73314191E7B6"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Failure to obtain verification</header><text>If the person or entity has made the inquiry described in clause (i)(I) but has not received an appropriate verification of such identity and work eligibility under such mechanism within the time period specified under subsection (d)(2) after the time the verification inquiry was received, the defense under subparagraph (A) shall not be considered to apply with respect to any employment after the end of such time period.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section id="H221622D7024C4CFBB9BE67C63C4B0A4A"><enum>6.</enum><header>Preemption and States’ Rights</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 274A(h)(2) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1324a">8 U.S.C. 1324a(h)(2)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H42241FAFCEC64D8599C0381BB6510092" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="H9242A6F076AE4DA78E5B7E19D02637D6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Preemption</header> 
<subparagraph id="H501E6EBB47CA448DBF710123AE6E6F9B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Single, national policy</header><text>The provisions of this section preempt any State or local law, ordinance, policy, or rule, including any criminal or civil fine or penalty structure, insofar as they may now or hereafter relate to the hiring, continued employment, or status verification for employment eligibility purposes, of unauthorized aliens.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFC172780BB624B4296C6CC9960743D43"><enum>(B)</enum><header>State enforcement of Federal law</header> 
<clause id="H9C4D9F9C79934A38AEC928D0F9555F15"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Business licensing</header><text>A State, locality, municipality, or political subdivision may exercise its authority over business licensing and similar laws as a penalty for failure to use the verification system described in subsection (d) to verify employment eligibility when and as required under subsection (b).</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4677D569B93A429694D1EC0161D2D8DC"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>General rules</header><text>A State, at its own cost, may enforce the provisions of this section, but only insofar as such State follows the Federal regulations implementing this section, applies the Federal penalty structure set out in this section, and complies with all Federal rules and guidance concerning implementation of this section. Such State may collect any fines assessed under this section. An employer may not be subject to enforcement, including audit and investigation, by both a Federal agency and a State for the same violation under this section. Whichever entity, the Federal agency or the State, is first to initiate the enforcement action, has the right of first refusal to proceed with the enforcement action. The Secretary must provide copies of all guidance, training, and field instructions provided to Federal officials implementing the provisions of this section to each State.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section commented="no" id="H6915C4718D6D4523A6D34E68C1EACBD6"><enum>7.</enum><header>Repeal</header> 
<subsection commented="no" id="HFAD6E8B0F9C74D12BBF4D51FBB8A27CB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subtitle A of title IV of the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1324a">8 U.S.C. 1324a</external-xref> note) is repealed.</text></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" id="HC2E0CF901D364578B67C56324C0B971A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>References</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any reference in any Federal law, Executive order, rule, regulation, or delegation of authority, or any document of, or pertaining to, the Department of Homeland Security, Department of Justice, or the Social Security Administration, to the employment eligibility confirmation system established under section 404 of the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1324a">8 U.S.C. 1324a</external-xref> note) is deemed to refer to the employment eligibility confirmation system established under section 274A(d) of the Immigration and Nationality Act, as amended by section 3 of this Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" id="H0F5012DE6F114D15962B88524FF3F1CE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section shall take effect on the date that is 36 months after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H7496CF920501496D89C216B952A25954"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Clerical Amendment</header><text>The table of sections, in section 1(d) of the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996, is amended by striking the items relating to subtitle A of title IV.</text></subsection></section> 
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB8ECA28468234FE38DB7AC4DE1323609" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>8.</enum><header>Penalties</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 274A of the <act-name parsable-cite="INA">Immigration and Nationality Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1324a">8 U.S.C. 1324a</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H1298BC1AE251451AB8BD7CDB155ACCD3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (e)(1)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H81333A4FC8CF461D93C07E8AB12AC181"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Attorney General</quote> each place such term appears and inserting <quote>Secretary of Homeland Security</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H09755DBD32344556A49A16C1BDB60380"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D), by striking <quote>Service</quote> and inserting <quote>Department of Homeland Security</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H10F34369A99544168028ABBBBD18B3A7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (e)(4)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H273617D6F42B4AF697E2D81B81A3023F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), in the matter before clause (i), by inserting <quote>, subject to paragraph (10),</quote> after <quote>in an amount</quote>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H65DABB88418A43A7B05C6327B32EB8BF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)(i), by striking <quote>not less than $250 and not more than $2,000</quote> and inserting <quote>not less than $2,500 and not more than $5,000</quote>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA9A5E58FD94E430E8E29B8EE158C409C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)(ii), by striking <quote>not less than $2,000 and not more than $5,000</quote> and inserting <quote>not less than $5,000 and not more than $10,000</quote>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H44649F107B4C4E51A98F92BA5D0F6F89"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)(iii), by striking <quote>not less than $3,000 and not more than $10,000</quote> and inserting <quote>not less than $10,000 and not more than $25,000</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC18A5C4059F94526833EF8C42292B491"><enum>(E)</enum><text>by moving the margin of the continuation text following subparagraph (B) two ems to the left and by amending subparagraph (B) to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H99E510E096844BDEB901F2744E003D6B" style="OLC"> 
<subparagraph id="H2EB8D24B6BDD426EB1F87C44015841A3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may require the person or entity to take such other remedial action as is appropriate.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H45CD81FE9D39441193BABD0FCAF0BD21"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (e)(5)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE17BF6FA959B44B58D8B3EBB2C62C4CB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the paragraph heading, strike <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">paperwork</header-in-text></quote>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEBBB8E5A5A5346BA8D257DFEBA4F39A0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, subject to paragraphs (10) through (12),</quote> after <quote>in an amount</quote>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDFB7F318D21045628FABBE1AE28EF87E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>$100</quote> and inserting <quote>$1,000</quote>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEB2D52E775854ABA821DFA8EC2DD8142"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by striking <quote>$1,000</quote> and inserting <quote>$25,000</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H47CFE35446C64038B6371B9102E6475F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following: <quote>Failure by a person or entity to utilize the employment eligibility verification system as required by law, or providing information to the system that the person or entity knows or reasonably believes to be false, shall be treated as a violation of subsection (a)(1)(A).</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7ABBEC4308F04D18BB5D3DB76677D68F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end of subsection (e) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HA90A16FD52434564AB36F15D70A01C3E" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="HEEF8533650CD451D9CAC8E86861AB3D8"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Exemption from penalty for good faith violation</header><text>In the case of imposition of a civil penalty under paragraph (4)(A) with respect to a violation of subsection (a)(1)(A) or (a)(2) for hiring or continuation of employment or recruitment or referral by person or entity and in the case of imposition of a civil penalty under paragraph (5) for a violation of subsection (a)(1)(B) for hiring or recruitment or referral by a person or entity, the penalty otherwise imposed may be waived or reduced if the violator establishes that the violator acted in good faith.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD7E06C6FE8344EA28BB7F8CA04246F57"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Authority to debar employers for certain violations</header> 
<subparagraph id="H3BD337E3F36E4ABE8625F5C76C3A83D7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a person or entity is determined by the Secretary of Homeland Security to be a repeat violator of paragraph (1)(A) or (2) of subsection (a), or is convicted of a crime under this section, such person or entity may be considered for debarment from the receipt of Federal contracts, grants, or cooperative agreements in accordance with the debarment standards and pursuant to the debarment procedures set forth in the Federal Acquisition Regulation.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE0BB65F6A56842C79C82B385CFB4D122"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Does not have contract, grant, agreement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary of Homeland Security or the Attorney General wishes to have a person or entity considered for debarment in accordance with this paragraph, and such an person or entity does not hold a Federal contract, grant or cooperative agreement, the Secretary or Attorney General shall refer the matter to the Administrator of General Services to determine whether to list the person or entity on the List of Parties Excluded from Federal Procurement, and if so, for what duration and under what scope.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H81A8A71C44D845398DF122090C6B5207"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Has contract, grant, agreement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary of Homeland Security or the Attorney General wishes to have a person or entity considered for debarment in accordance with this paragraph, and such person or entity holds a Federal contract, grant or cooperative agreement, the Secretary or Attorney General shall advise all agencies or departments holding a contract, grant, or cooperative agreement with the person or entity of the Government’s interest in having the person or entity considered for debarment, and after soliciting and considering the views of all such agencies and departments, the Secretary or Attorney General may refer the matter to any appropriate lead agency to determine whether to list the person or entity on the List of Parties Excluded from Federal Procurement, and if so, for what duration and under what scope.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6EC5D68E8C9D472F826468E5C0ADFDB3"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any decision to debar a person or entity in accordance with this paragraph shall be reviewable pursuant to part 9.4 of the Federal Acquisition Regulation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9CE3BA8F00C840559DC0CB264FC40892"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Office for State and local government complaints</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall establish an office—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF0ADF22CA05A47C1ABAE182FFFCCE7F9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to which State and local government agencies may submit information indicating potential violations of subsection (a), (b), or (g)(1) that were generated in the normal course of law enforcement or the normal course of other official activities in the State or locality;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE8438FD9F1CB48EAB2BDBA8BA160D60E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that is required to indicate to the complaining State or local agency within 5 business days of the filing of such a complaint by identifying whether the Secretary will further investigate the information provided;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE51A53D7A332432CA3DA6A57F609C57C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>that is required to investigate those complaints filed by State or local government agencies that, on their face, have a substantial probability of validity;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB0066BB0C00E42358ECC149A3C287578"><enum>(D)</enum><text>that is required to notify the complaining State or local agency of the results of any such investigation conducted; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8DBBE9509AED425B94DC05CEDD4D7E48"><enum>(E)</enum><text>that is required to report to the Congress annually the number of complaints received under this paragraph, the States and localities that filed such complaints, and the resolution of the complaints investigated by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6936AC0EE5D84CC2B64272AB4AE32D04"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (1) of subsection (f) to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H6B89B7F253CB4F028E6247B5C4099153" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="H41172B2F5DA3498B830ABA275DD7F138"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Criminal penalty</header><text>Any person or entity which engages in a pattern or practice of violations of subsection (a)(1) or (2) shall be fined not more than $5,000 for each unauthorized alien with respect to which such a violation occurs, imprisoned for not more than 18 months, or both, notwithstanding the provisions of any other Federal law relating to fine levels.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HD37DACF26E2745939AC27476FDB46C8B"><enum>9.</enum><header>Fraud and misuse of documents</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/1546">Section 1546(b)</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H72952D306271419C93DA3C01D6E81A74"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>identification document,</quote> and inserting <quote>identification document or document meant to establish work authorization (including the documents described in section 274A(b) of the Immigration and Nationality Act),</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5717B45002B04215BFA5EEBEDCE66837"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>identification document</quote> and inserting <quote>identification document or document meant to establish work authorization (including the documents described in section 274A(b) of the Immigration and Nationality Act),</quote>.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HB3F9447CB4974B28A7D9940F72026AAA"><enum>10.</enum><header>Protection of Social Security Administration programs</header> 
<subsection id="H33B1E7F741EC482B85D2381DCC040BC5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Funding under agreement</header><text>Effective for fiscal years beginning on or after October 1, 2013, the Commissioner of Social Security and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall enter into and maintain an agreement which shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H3EBDB418FF454051BAC94440C6B02310"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide funds to the Commissioner for the full costs of the responsibilities of the Commissioner under section 274A(d) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1324a">8 U.S.C. 1324a(d)</external-xref>), as amended by section 3 of this Act, including (but not limited to)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6582045AAAB24CAB8BA28EE423120BD0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>acquiring, installing, and maintaining technological equipment and systems necessary for the fulfillment of the responsibilities of the Commissioner under such section 274A(d), but only that portion of such costs that are attributable exclusively to such responsibilities; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H18979FE46A1847E8B3E4BB4E0AD813C7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>responding to individuals who contest a tentative nonconfirmation provided by the employment eligibility verification system established under such section;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBDF812F7FC3044B0A4824C8B4C1EEDE6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide such funds annually in advance of the applicable quarter based on estimating methodology agreed to by the Commissioner and the Secretary (except in such instances where the delayed enactment of an annual appropriation may preclude such quarterly payments); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAAE7B9BBDC6745FA86FD7189585B1802"><enum>(3)</enum><text>require an annual accounting and reconciliation of the actual costs incurred and the funds provided under the agreement, which shall be reviewed by the Inspectors General of the Social Security Administration and the Department of Homeland Security.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3F64F86078F54B72B091B101418CD972"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Continuation of employment verification in absence of timely agreement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any case in which the agreement required under subsection (a) for any fiscal year beginning on or after October 1, 2013, has not been reached as of October 1 of such fiscal year, the latest agreement between the Commissioner and the Secretary of Homeland Security providing for funding to cover the costs of the responsibilities of the Commissioner under section 274A(d) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1324a">8 U.S.C. 1324a(d)</external-xref>) shall be deemed in effect on an interim basis for such fiscal year until such time as an agreement required under subsection (a) is subsequently reached, except that the terms of such interim agreement shall be modified by the Director of the Office of Management and Budget to adjust for inflation and any increase or decrease in the volume of requests under the employment eligibility verification system. In any case in which an interim agreement applies for any fiscal year under this subsection, the Commissioner and the Secretary shall, not later than October 1 of such fiscal year, notify the Committee on Ways and Means, the Committee on the Judiciary, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance, the Committee on the Judiciary, and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate of the failure to reach the agreement required under subsection (a) for such fiscal year. Until such time as the agreement required under subsection (a) has been reached for such fiscal year, the Commissioner and the Secretary shall, not later than the end of each 90-day period after October 1 of such fiscal year, notify such Committees of the status of negotiations between the Commissioner and the Secretary in order to reach such an agreement.</text></subsection></section> 
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEB301381B8A74F7583F094B1534A1B5B" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>11.</enum><header>Fraud prevention</header> 
<subsection id="H7AFAB2E556EC4FBEB34607419002E878"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Blocking misused social security account numbers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with the Commissioner of Social Security, shall establish a program in which social security account numbers that have been identified to be subject to unusual multiple use in the employment eligibility verification system established under section 274A(d) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1324a">8 U.S.C. 1324a(d)</external-xref>), as amended by section 3 of this Act, or that are otherwise suspected or determined to have been compromised by identity fraud or other misuse, shall be blocked from use for such system purposes unless the individual using such number is able to establish, through secure and fair additional security procedures, that the individual is the legitimate holder of the number.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA5ECB34BBDFA4BD3A80DB2B1F6AAAE3C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Allowing suspension of use of certain social security account numbers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with the Commissioner of Social Security, shall establish a program which shall provide a reliable, secure method by which victims of identity fraud and other individuals may suspend or limit the use of their social security account number or other identifying information for purposes of the employment eligibility verification system established under section 274A(d) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1324a">8 U.S.C. 1324a(d)</external-xref>), as amended by section 3 of this Act. The Secretary may implement the program on a limited pilot program basis before making it fully available to all individuals.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2DD7CB07F5FA4DE4A436A0C630E63278"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Allowing parents To prevent theft of their child’s identity</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with the Commissioner of Social Security, shall establish a program which shall provide a reliable, secure method by which parents or legal guardians may suspend or limit the use of the social security account number or other identifying information of a minor under their care for the purposes of the employment eligibility verification system established under 274A(d) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1324a">8 U.S.C. 1324a(d)</external-xref>), as amended by section 3 of this Act. The Secretary may implement the program on a limited pilot program basis before making it fully available to all individuals.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H49E51E0E4D324A52925A515C7A099224" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>12.</enum><header>Use of Employment Eligibility Verification Photo Tool</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">An employer who uses the photo matching tool used as part of the E-Verify System shall match the photo tool photograph to both the photograph on the identity or employment eligibility document provided by the employee and to the face of the employee submitting the document for employment verification purposes. </text></section> 
<section id="H15BD857025BA412BA1EC39B349FA325A"><enum>13.</enum><header>Identity authentication employment eligibility verification pilot programs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 48 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security, after consultation with the Commissioner of Social Security and the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, shall establish by regulation not less than 2 Identity Authentication Employment Eligibility Verification pilot programs, each using a separate and distinct technology (the <quote>Authentication Pilots</quote>). The purpose of the Authentication Pilots shall be to provide for identity authentication and employment eligibility verification with respect to enrolled new employees which shall be available to subject employers who elect to participate in either of the Authentication Pilots. Any subject employer may cancel the employer’s participation in the Authentication Pilot after one year after electing to participate without prejudice to future participation. The Secretary shall report to the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate the Secretary’s findings on the Authentication Pilots, including the authentication technologies chosen, not later than 12 months after commencement of the Authentication Pilots.</text></section> 
<section id="HC494B412CB224345BA89A728013423BD"><enum>14.</enum><header>Inspector General audits</header> 
<subsection id="H4B8FC27E6AAE4B2A9BBD9D8E6ED41038"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Inspector General of the Social Security Administration shall complete audits of the following categories in order to uncover evidence of individuals who are not authorized to work in the United States:</text> 
<paragraph id="HC9A9FB65C9A048298C1671488479EDE6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Workers who dispute wages reported on their social security account number when they believe someone else has used such number and name to report wages.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF46EEE2FA69F48B7A217152A4396C7F7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Children’s social security account numbers used for work purposes.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4136094DD01749EDA31C4466FC4F4C66"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Employers whose workers present significant numbers of mismatched social security account numbers or names for wage reporting.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE041FB7C63364C1580ACB7EA3AF889BE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Submission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Inspector General of the Social Security Administration shall submit the audits completed under subsection (a) to the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representative and the Committee on Finance of the Senate for review of the evidence of individuals who are not authorized to work in the United States. The Chairmen of those Committees shall then determine information to be shared with the Secretary of Homeland Security so that such Secretary can investigate the unauthorized employment demonstrated by such evidence.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
<endorsement display="yes"> 
<action-date date="20141216">December 16, 2014</action-date> 
<action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00" added-display-style="italic" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name> with an amendment</action-desc>
<action-date date="20141216">December 16, 2014</action-date>
<action-desc>The <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committees on Ways and Means</committee-name> and <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and the Workforce</committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement> 
</bill> 


