<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE amendment-doc PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/amend.dtd//EN" "amend.dtd">
<amendment-doc amend-degree="first" amend-type="engrossed-amendment"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HCON 58 EAS: </dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2013-10-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<engrossed-amendment-form>
<congress display="no">113th CONGRESS</congress><session display="no">1st Session</session><legis-num display="no">H. CON. RES. 58</legis-num><current-chamber display="yes">In the Senate of the United States,</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20131010">October 10, 2013.</action-date></action><legis-type display="yes">Amendments:</legis-type></engrossed-amendment-form><engrossed-amendment-body><section id="id3ae88586ed694af99a4fbc95378f424e" section-type="resolved"><text>That the resolution from the House of Representatives (H. Con. Res. 58) entitled <quote>Concurrent resolution expressing the sense of Congress regarding the need for the continued availability of religious services to members of the Armed Forces and their families during a lapse in appropriations.</quote>, do pass with the following</text></section><amendment><amendment-instruction blank-lines-after="0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Strike the preamble and insert the following:</text></amendment-instruction><amendment-block blank-lines-after="1" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic"><preamble changed="added" reported-display-style="italic"><whereas><text>Whereas the Department of Defense determined that some contractor clergy, like other Department of Defense contractors, were unable to perform their contractual duties during the current lapse in appropriations;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas this determination may have impacted the ability of members of the Armed Forces and their families to worship and participate in religious activities;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas military chaplains on active duty, like all military personnel on active duty, continue to perform their duties during the current lapse in appropriations;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Department continues to analyze its authorities under the Pay Our Military Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/39">Public Law 113–39</external-xref>) with respect to contractors; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Pay Our Military Act appropriates such sums as are necessary to pay contractors of the Department whom the Secretary of Defense determines are providing support to members of the Armed Forces: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble></amendment-block><amendment-instruction blank-lines-after="0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>On page 2, strike line 3 and all that follows through page 3, line 2, and insert the following:</text></amendment-instruction><amendment-block blank-lines-after="1" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic"><paragraph id="ideecc3846c482443fb172c3e609df0c27"><enum>(1)</enum><text>finds that the provision and availability of religious services and clergy is important to the morale and wellbeing of many members of the Armed Forces and their families; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id63d377e23e0e42188e5b21d5f8e0fdc0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>hopes the Secretary of Defense is able to determine that contractor clergy provide necessary support to military personnel, and would therefore be covered under the appropriations made available under the Pay Our Military Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/39">Public Law 113–39</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></amendment-block></amendment></engrossed-amendment-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestor></attestor><role>Secretary</role></attestation-group></attestation><endorsement></endorsement></amendment-doc>


