<bill session="113" type="s" number="2681" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Keeping Jobs in America Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide incentives for businesses to keep jobs in the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300080"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412602" joined="2014-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="851"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="337"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2562"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2569"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Lighting and heating"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Taxation of foreign income"/>
    <term name="U.S. territories and protectorates"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/29/2014--Introduced.
Keeping Jobs in America Act - Directs the Secretary of Commerce to establish a program to award grants to states that are recruiting high-value jobs (e.g., manufacturing, software publishing, and computer system design jobs that pay a higher than average wage). Allows the use of grants to issue forgivable loans to entities that employ not fewer than 50 full-time employees in high-value jobs&#160;and that are deciding whether to locate in&#160;rural and distressed areas.

Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) grant business taxpayers a&#160;tax credit for up to 20% of insourcing expenses incurred for eliminating a&#160;business located outside the United States and&#160; relocating it within the United States, and (2) deny a tax deduction for outsourcing expenses incurred in relocating a U.S. business outside the United States. Requires an increase in the taxpayer's employment of full-time employees&#160;in the United States in order to claim the tax credit for insourcing expenses.

Extends through 2017 the additional allowance for depreciation of business property (bonus depreciation) and the election to accelerate the alternative minimum tax credit in lieu of bonus depreciation. Makes permanent: (1) the increased $500,000 expensing allowance for depreciable business property and qualified real property, and (2) the new markets tax credit.</summary>
</bill>
