<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Enrolled-Bill" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H83A974CC61DA44AD9A02E423183BDB11" public-private="public" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title> HR 356 ENR: Hill Creek Cultural Preservation and Energy Development Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">IB</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">One Hundred Thirteenth Congress of the United States of America</congress> <session display="yes">At the Second Session</session><enrolled-dateline>Begun and held at the City of Washington on Friday, the third day of January, two thousand and fourteen</enrolled-dateline> 
<legis-num>H. R. 356</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no"></current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To clarify authority granted under the Act entitled <quote>An Act to define the exterior boundary of the Uintah and Ouray Indian Reservation in the State of Utah, and for other purposes</quote>.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H27057B19D96A4D0B867A6B677D2B8071" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HEBFF78954DF340C582097391D2F809EF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Hill Creek Cultural Preservation and Energy Development Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> 
<section id="H5DCD5A0AC2D2493895E8F33B2A75E242" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Clarification of authority</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Act entitled <quote>An Act to define the exterior boundary of the Uintah and Ouray Indian Reservation in the State of Utah, and for other purposes</quote>, approved March 11, 1948 (62 Stat. 72), as amended by the Act entitled <quote>An Act to amend the Act extending the exterior boundary of the Uintah and Ouray Indian Reservation in the State of Utah so as to authorize such State to exchange certain mineral lands for other lands mineral in character</quote> approved August 9, 1955, (69 Stat. 544), is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2301936AC7BC4C4080E9A376943F3640" style="traditional"> 
<section id="H7032637BECC842B6A813325027485C7A"><enum>5.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In order to further clarify authorizations under this Act, the State of Utah is hereby authorized to relinquish to the United States, for the benefit of the Ute Indian Tribe of the Uintah and Ouray Reservation, State school trust or other State-owned subsurface mineral lands located beneath the surface estate delineated in Public Law 440 (approved March 11, 1948) and south of the border between Grand County, Utah, and Uintah County, Utah, and select in lieu of such relinquished lands, on an acre-for-acre basis, any subsurface mineral lands of the United States located beneath the surface estate delineated in Public Law 440 (approved March 11, 1948) and north of the border between Grand County, Utah, and Uintah County, Utah, subject to the following conditions:</text> 
<paragraph id="H85C2C6CDDAF64B8881728C604B361D9E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reservation by united states</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Interior shall reserve an overriding interest in that portion of the mineral estate comprised of minerals subject to leasing under the Mineral Leasing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/171">30 U.S.C. 171 et seq.</external-xref>) in any mineral lands conveyed to the State.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDAE4B5B6C84F4A32B808E5C71DA0776C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Extent of overriding interest</header><text>The overriding interest reserved by the United States under paragraph (1) shall consist of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H478A1F4B325F447EB4E81084FDF3914C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>50 percent of any bonus bid or other payment received by the State as consideration for securing any lease or authorization to develop such mineral resources;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H94189357E832431690A45B0B018FB1EE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>50 percent of any rental or other payments received by the State as consideration for the lease or authorization to develop such mineral resources;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF3E7BA6083534D01B7703EC636EFF1AC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a 6.25 percent overriding royalty on the gross proceeds of oil and gas production under any lease or authorization to develop such oil and gas resources; and</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3B7251AD97B246BFBC9FA409055196AA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an overriding royalty on the gross proceeds of production of such minerals other than oil and gas, equal to 50 percent of the royalty rate established by the Secretary of the Interior by regulation as of October 1, 2011.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE9C4ED1FE3F842929BAF79F684CE578B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reservation by state of Utah</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The State of Utah shall reserve, for the benefit of its State school trust, an overriding interest in that portion of the mineral estate comprised of minerals subject to leasing under the Mineral Leasing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/181">30 U.S.C. 181 et seq.</external-xref>) in any mineral lands relinquished by the State to the United States.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H38EB6FF34C8944ACB10E733287A6F306"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Extent of overriding interest</header><text>The overriding interest reserved by the State under paragraph (3) shall consist of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC85C0EDF97434621B076A606DC5CA534"><enum>(A)</enum><text>50 percent of any bonus bid or other payment received by the United States as consideration for securing any lease or authorization to develop such mineral resources on the relinquished lands;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2CFC3223D91746B7834F97BD2CFEEBC5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>50 percent of any rental or other payments received by the United States as consideration for the lease or authorization to develop such mineral resources;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE0D4F6174D1D488AA2BA7EFD5E792E7D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a 6.25 percent overriding royalty on the gross proceeds of oil and gas production under any lease or authorization to develop such oil and gas resources; and</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9CEDEE9D40CB481D9F025523BD100AAD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an overriding royalty on the gross proceeds of production of such minerals other than oil and gas, equal to 50 percent of the royalty rate established by the Secretary of the Interior by regulation as of October 1, 2011.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBF584BF53D684369993A9375C44C23D9"><enum>(5)</enum><header>No obligation to lease</header><text>Neither the United States nor the State shall be obligated to lease or otherwise develop oil and gas resources in which the other party retains an overriding interest under this section.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H90BA039933FA4DE98876D89D3AB0F14B"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Cooperative agreements</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior is authorized to enter into cooperative agreements with the State and the Ute Indian Tribe of the Uintah and Ouray Reservation to facilitate the relinquishment and selection of lands to be conveyed under this section, and the administration of the overriding interests reserved hereunder.</text> </paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section> 
</legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><role>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</role></attestation-group><attestation-group><role>Vice President of the United States and President of the Senate.</role></attestation-group></attestation>
</bill> 


