<bill session="113" type="h" number="4309" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-04-09">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-04-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-03-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Sikes Act to make certain improvements to the administration of cooperative agreements for land management related to Department of Defense readiness activities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400041"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-03-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-26">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-26">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-09">
      <text>Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-09">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-04-09" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-07-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Readiness.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-08T13:00:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 113-647, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-08T13:00:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee on Armed Services discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-12-08T13:00:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="485">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 485.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSII22" subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS03" subcommittee="Readiness" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1080"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1960"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military readiness"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/8/2014--Reported to House amended, Part I.
Amends the Sikes Act (conservation programs on federal lands) to allow funds appropriated to the Department of Defense (DOD) that are obligated to cooperative agreements with states, local governments, Indian tribes, nongovernmental organizations, and individuals for maintenance and improvement of natural resources located off of military or state-owned National Guard installations (but that are related to current or anticipated military activities) to be:

 paid in a lump sum and include an amount intended to cover the future costs of the activities under the agreement; invested by the recipient in accordance with the recipient's own investment management guidelines, with any investment interest or income permitted to be applied for the same purposes as the principal; and used only for the direct costs of maintaining and improving the natural resources pursuant to an approved DOD Integrated Natural Resource Management Plan and for certain indirect and administrative costs that do not exceed 10% of the total cost of the project. Allows such cooperative agreements to be used to acquire property or services for the direct benefit or use of the U.S. government.

Prohibits amounts available to DOD from being used under such Act to acquire fee title interest in real property for such natural resources projects that are not on a military installation.

Requires the Inspector General of DOD to: (1) conduct an audit of the natural resources projects funded with amounts available to DOD under the Sikes Act that are not on a military installation, and (2) report to Congress on the audit by October 1, 2018.

Terminates this Act on October 1, 2019, except that any cooperative agreement entered into under this Act on or before September 30, 2019, shall continue.</summary>
</bill>
