<bill session="113" type="s" number="2484" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-17">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-09-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">South Pacific Fisheries Convention Implementation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">South Pacific Fisheries Convention Implementation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to implement the Convention on the Conservation and Management of the High Seas Fishery Resources in the South Pacific Ocean, as adopted at Auckland on November 14, 2009, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412507"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-09-17" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-12-08">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Rockefeller with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-12-08" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="622">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 622.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-12-12">
      <text>By Senator Rockefeller from Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation filed written report. Report No. 113-315.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="Oceania"/>
    <term name="Pacific Ocean"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/17/2014--Introduced.
South Pacific Fisheries Convention Implementation Act - Authorizes the Department of Commerce to promulgate regulations to implement the Convention on the Conservation and Management of the High Seas Fishery Resources in the South Pacific Ocean, which was adopted at Auckland, New Zealand, on November 14, 2009. (The Convention includes the objectives of ensuring the long term conservation and sustainable use of fishery resources and safeguarding the marine ecosystems in the Convention Area.) Applies this Act within the boundaries of any state bordering on the Convention Area if specified conditions are met.

 Requires the President to appoint the U.S. representative to the South Pacific Fisheries Commission. Establishes an advisory committee for the Commission.

 Requires Commerce to develop a memorandum of understanding with the Western Pacific Regional Fishery Management Council to clarify the role of the Council with respect to participating in or working with U.S. delegations to international fishery organizations and making recommendations related to fishery resources in the Convention Area.

 Sets forth the Department of State's authority and responsibilities with respect to the Commission.

 Requires Commerce and the Department of Homeland Security (the department in which the Coast Guard is operating) to administer and enforce this Act, except to the extent otherwise provided for in the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act.

Sets forth prohibited fishing and shipping acts in the Convention Area.

 Establishes notification requirements commercial fishing vessels before entering or transiting the exclusive economic zone of the Convention Area, if the vessels do not carry vessel monitoring systems capable of communicating with U.S. enforcement authorities.</summary>
</bill>
