<bill session="113" type="s" number="2922" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-12-11">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-12-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-11-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Hong Kong Human Rights and Democracy Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Hong Kong Human Rights and Democracy Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reinstate reporting requirements related to United States-Hong Kong relations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400050"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2014-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2014-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2014-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412491" joined="2014-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2014-11-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-11-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-12-11" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-12-11">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Menendez with an amendment. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-12-11" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="651">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 651.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-12-12">
      <text>By Senator Menendez from Committee on Foreign Relations filed written report. Report No. 113-313.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="5696"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Hong Kong"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International exchange and broadcasting"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="Political movements and philosophies"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="United Kingdom"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/11/2014--Reported to Senate amended.
Hong Kong Human Rights and Democracy Act - States that it is U.S. policy to:

 reaffirm the principles set forth in the United States-Hong Kong Policy Act of 1992; support the democratic aspirations of the people of Hong Kong; urge China's government to uphold its commitments to Hong Kong; support the establishment by 2017 of a democratic option to nominate and elect the Chief Executive of Hong Kong, and the establishment by 2020 of democratic elections for all members of the Hong Kong Legislative Council; and support freedom of the press. Amends the United States-Hong Kong Policy Act of 1992 to direct the Secretary of State to report by March 31, 2015, to Congress on conditions in Hong Kong that are of U.S. interest, and annually thereafter for 10 years or until the Secretary certifies that Hong Kong has held free and fair elections for 2 consecutive Chief Executive and 2 consecutive Legislative Council periods.

 Directs the Secretary to certify annually to Congress whether Hong Kong is sufficiently autonomous to justify separate treatment different from that accorded to China in any new laws, agreements, treaties, or arrangements entered into between the United States and Hong Kong.

 Exempts from the certification requirement new laws, agreements, treaties, or arrangements that support human rights, rule of law, or democracy in Hong Kong.

 Authorizes the Secretary to waive the certification requirement if in U.S. national interests, and with congressional notification.</summary>
</bill>
