<bill session="113" type="h" number="5318" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Label and Transport Tissues Safely Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">LATTS Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure certain safety measures are utilized in the interest of public health security with respect to labeling and transporting human tissue specimen or collection of specimens into interstate commerce.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412397"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400141" joined="2014-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-08-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Organ and tissue donation and transplantation"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2014--Introduced.
Label and Transport Tissues Safely Act of 2014 or the LATTS Act of 2014 - Sets forth guidelines for handling human tissue specimens.

Prohibits sale of human tissue for research or education unless the seller has a non-transplant tissue bank license and each package of tissue is labeled with specified information.

Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish a process for the approval, suspension, and revocation of non-transplant tissue bank licenses.

Prohibits falsely labeling packages of human tissue.

Allows HHS or any accrediting body authorized by HHS to enter and inspect any establishment engaged in the preparation of any human tissue specimen.

Requires HHS to recall any human tissue specimen that is an imminent or substantial hazard to public health.</summary>
</bill>
