<bill session="113" type="s" number="2419" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">VA Accountability Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to protect America's veterans from dishonesty and malfeasance in the delivery of medical services and to hold the Department of Veterans Affairs accountable to those they serve.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400408"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/3/2014--Introduced.
VA Accountability Act of 2014 - Prohibits any officer, employee, or agent of the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) from:

 knowingly falsifying an individual's VA health records; knowingly destroying or excluding information from such records with the intent to defraud the individual, a federal officer or employee, or a Member of Congress; directing another individual to engage in such prohibited conduct; or knowing of such prohibited conduct by an individual under his or her supervision and failing to stop, if possible, or report to a superior the commission of such conduct. Allows an individual aggrieved by such conduct to bring a civil action against the officer, employee, or agent in an appropriate U.S. district court for damages or other legal or equitable relief.

Authorizes the VA Secretary to terminate, without prior notice or cause, the employment and benefits of a VA officer, employee, or agent found by such court to have violated this Act.

Provides that this Act shall apply to conduct committed before, on, or after its enactment.</summary>
</bill>
