<bill session="113" type="h" number="3392" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-10-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-10-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medicare Part D Patient Safety and Drug Abuse Prevention Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for a PDP safety program to prevent fraud and abuse in the dispensing of controlled substances under part D of the Medicare program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412250"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412445" joined="2014-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412293" joined="2013-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400340" joined="2013-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412411" joined="2014-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400431" joined="2013-11-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-30">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-30">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Insurance industry and regulation"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/30/2013--Introduced.
Medicare Part D Patient Safety and Drug Abuse Prevention Act of 2013 - Amends part D (Voluntary Prescription Drug Benefit Program) of title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to establish a safe pharmacy access program under which a prescription drug plan (PDP) sponsor (or a Medicare Advantage (MA) organization offering an MA-PD plan) shall have in place procedures designed to prevent fraud and abuse in the dispensing of certain controlled substances under Medicare part D.

Allows a PDP sponsor to suspend payments and clean claim notifications to a pharmacy pending an investigation of a credible allegation of fraud against the pharmacy, unless the Secretary determines there is a good cause not to suspend payments.

Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), under contracts entered into under the Medicare integrity program with Medicare drug integrity contractors (MEDICs), to authorize such MEDICs to obtain prescription and medical records directly from entities such as pharmacies, PDPs, and physicians. Requires a MEDIC to acknowledge receipt of a PDP sponsor referral of information for investigation, report back to the sponsor the investigation results within 45 days, and share them with appropriate agencies.

Requires electronic transmission (e-prescribing) of prescriptions for certain covered Medicare part D controlled substances.</summary>
</bill>
