<bill session="113" type="h" number="3194" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-09-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-09-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-09-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection Judicial Fairness Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act to remove certain special deference provided by courts to the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection when the Bureau is interpreting provisions of a Federal consumer financial law.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412488"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-09-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-26">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-26">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU05" subcommittee="Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="605"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2385"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Consumer Financial Protection Bureau"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/26/2013--Introduced.
Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection Judicial Fairness Act - Amends the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act to repeal the requirement that the deference that a court affords to the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB) regarding the meaning or interpretation of any federal consumer financial law be applied as if it were the only agency authorized to apply, enforce, interpret, or administer federal consumer financial law.</summary>
</bill>
