<bill session="113" type="hr" number="714" updated="2015-09-01T10:18:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-12-03T18:49:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-12-03T18:49:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Reaffirming the peaceful and collaborative resolution of maritime and jurisdictional disputes in the South China Sea and the East China Sea as provided for by universally recognized principles of international law, and reaffirming the strong support of the United States Government for freedom of navigation and other internationally lawful uses of sea and airspace in the Asia-Pacific region.</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by house">To reaffirm the strong support of the United States Government for the peaceful and collaborative resolution of maritime and jurisdictional disputes in the South China Sea and the East China Sea as provided for by universally recognized principles of international law, and to reaffirm the vital interest of the United States in freedom of navigation and other internationally lawful uses of sea and airspace in the Asia-Pacific region.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400128"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412512" joined="2014-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400041" joined="2014-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400071" joined="2014-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="2014-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2014-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="410396" joined="2014-11-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Asia and the Pacific.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-17">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-17">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Unanimous Consent .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-20">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-11-20" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-12-03T18:26:00-05:00">
      <text>Ms. Ros-Lehtinen moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-03T18:26:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8350-8354" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-03T18:26:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Res. 714.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2014-12-03T18:49:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8350-8351" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-12-03T18:49:00-05:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSFA05" subcommittee="Asia and the Pacific" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="ASEAN countries"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Pacific Ocean"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/3/2014--Passed House amended.
Reaffirms U.S. support for the peaceful resolution of maritime territorial disputes in the South China Sea and the East China Sea.

Reaffirms support for freedom of navigation and overflight and condemns coercive actions or the use of force to impede these freedoms in international maritime domains and airspace.

Declares that the House of Representatives does not recognize the East China Sea Air Defense Identification Zone, declared by china, which is contrary to freedom of overflight in international airspace.

Calls on China to refrain from taking similar provocative actions elsewhere in the Asia-Pacific region, including in the South China Sea.

Urges the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN), U.S. allies and partners, and all claimants to fairly resolve these outstanding disputes, including through the conclusion of a Code of Conduct for the South China Sea.

Urges as well the conclusion of the annex to the non-binding memorandum of understanding between the United States and China on "rules of behavior for safety of air and maritime encounters" addressing air-to-air encounters in 2015.

Supports continued U.S. operations to support freedom of navigation in international waters and air space in the South China Sea and the East China Sea.

 Encourages continued U.S. efforts to strengthen regional partnerships to build capacity for maritime domain awareness in support of freedom of navigation, maintenance of peace and stability, and respect for principles of international law.</summary>
</bill>
