<bill session="113" type="s" number="2889" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Universal Home Design Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require compliance with established universal home design guidelines, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300051"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5790"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5793-5794" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Access Board"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Housing for the elderly and disabled"/>
    <term name="Housing industry and standards"/>
    <term name="Housing supply and affordability"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/18/2014--Introduced.
Universal Home Design Act of 2014 - Requires the Architectural and Transportation Barriers Compliance Board (Access Board) to develop guidelines setting forth the minimum technical criteria and scoping requirements for certain federally assisted single family houses, townhouses, and other specified kinds of dwelling to comply with universal home design.

Requires universal home design to include architectural and other landscaping features that allow basic access to and within a residential dwelling by an individual with a disability who cannot climb stairs, including an individual who uses a mobility device such as a wheelchair.

Requires each applicant for such federal financial assistance to submit compliance assurances to the relevant federal agency.

Permits: (1) private civil actions in a U.S. district court for violations of this Act, and (2) the Attorney General to commence civil actions or intervene in civil actions under it.

Directs the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to establish an Office of Accessible Housing and Development to: (1) disseminate information to the public about the importance of universal home design, including through a website; (2) survey and report to the Secretary on the availability of affordable and accessible housing; and (3) promote universal home design.</summary>
</bill>
