<bill session="113" type="h" number="5759" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-12-04T14:29:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-12-04T14:29:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-11-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Executive Amnesty Prevention Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Preventing Executive Overreach on Immigration Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a rule of construction clarifying the limitations on executive authority to provide certain forms of immigration relief.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412525"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412469" joined="2014-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412395" joined="2014-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412601" joined="2014-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400116" joined="2014-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400651" joined="2014-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412603" joined="2014-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400224" joined="2014-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412510" joined="2014-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412445" joined="2014-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412295" joined="2014-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412487" joined="2014-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412409" joined="2014-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412443" joined="2014-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412551" joined="2014-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400340" joined="2014-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400400" joined="2014-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412548" joined="2014-12-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-11-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-04T12:25:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 770.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8632-8651" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H8632-8633" label="text of amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-04T12:25:00-05:00">
      <text>Resolution provides for consideration of the Senate amendment to H.R. 3979; consideration of the bill H.R. 5759; and consideration of the bill H.R. 5781.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-04T12:25:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 770, the House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 5759.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-04T12:25:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House resumed debate on H.R. 5759.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-04T13:46:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8649" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-04T13:46:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Murphy (FL) moved to recommit with instructions to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8649" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H8649" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-04T13:47:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Murphy (FL) motion to recommit with instructions, pending reservation of a point of order. The instructions contained in the motion seek to report the same back to the House forthwith with an amendment to ensure that nothing in the underlying legislation would impact the relief provided to parents, spouses, and children of U.S. citizens who are current members or veterans of the U.S. Armed Forces, the Selected Reserve of the Ready Reserve, or who seek to enlist in the Armed Forces, which is consistent with current law, but will be halted by the underlying legislation. Additionally, the motion would protect victims of domestic violence who have successfully petitioned for relief under the Violence Against Women Act; and victims of crimes and serious forms of human trafficking from further abuse. Lastly, the motion would protect Cuban nationals or any                persons of any other nationality deserving of  such protections,            already in the U.S. or in tran sit to the U.S.. Subse</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-04T13:54:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8650" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-04T14:20:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 194 - 225 (Roll no. 549).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="550" datetime="2014-12-04T14:29:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 219 - 197, 3 Present (Roll no. 550).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-12-04T14:29:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-08">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-12-09" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="626">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 626.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Border Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hr" number="770"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="3015"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Congressional-executive branch relations"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/4/2014--Passed House amended.
Preventing Executive Overreach on Immigration Act of 2014 - Prohibits the executive branch of the government from:

 exempting or deferring from removal, by executive order, regulation, or any other means, categories of aliens considered under the immigration laws to be unlawfully present in the United States; treating such aliens as if they were lawfully present or had a lawful immigration status; or treating them other than as unauthorized aliens. States that such prohibition shall not apply:

 to the extent prohibited by the Constitution; upon the request of federal, state, or local law enforcement agencies for purposes of maintaining aliens in the United States to be tried for crimes or to be trial witnesses; or for humanitarian purposes where the aliens are at imminent risk of serious bodily harm or death. Declares that any executive branch action intending to circumvent the objectives of this Act shall be null and void and without legal effect.

 States that this Act shall take effect as if enacted on November 20, 2014, and shall apply to requests (whether the request is original or for reopening of a previously denied request) submitted on or after that date for: (1) work authorization; or (2) exemption from, or deferral of, removal.</summary>
</bill>
