<bill session="113" type="s" number="2688" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Union Transparency and Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to ensure labor organization transparency and accountability.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400546"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300002" joined="2014-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2014-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2014-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Labor-management relations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/2014--Introduced.
Union Transparency and Accountability Act - Amends the Labor-Management Reporting and Disclosure Act of 1959 to revise specified current reporting requirements to require every labor organization to file annually with the Secretary of Labor (currently, the Office of Labor Management Standards of the Department of Labor) its:

 form LM-2, as published in the appendix to the final rule issued by the Secretary entitled "Labor Organization Annual Financial Reports" dated January 21, 2009, or a successor form including the same information; and form T-1, as published in the appendix to the final rule issued by the Secretary entitled "Labor Organization Annual Financial Reports for Trusts in Which a Labor Organization is Interested, Form T-1" dated October 2, 2008, or a successor form including the same information. Requires similarly certain labor organization officers or employees (as under current law) to file annually with the Secretary form LM-30, as published in the appendix to the final rule issued by the Secretary entitled "Labor Organization Officer and Employee Report, Form LM-30" dated July 2, 2007, or a successor form including the same information.

Prescribes civil penalties for any labor organization that fails to disclose to its members specified information contained in a report, including a financial report, required to be filed with the Secretary.

Revises the authority of the Secretary to bring a civil action in a U.S. district Court or in the U.S. District Court for the District of Columbia for the actual or imminent failure of any person to file required reports.

Requires the Secretary to establish certain standards and procedures for the imposition by the appropriate district court of civil fines for persons, labor organizations, or employers who violate specified reporting requirements.

Prescribes a civil fine of up to $250 a day from the date of a violation, with an aggregate maximum of $45,000, both amounts adjusted for inflation.

Prescribes certain whistleblower protections for labor organization employees who file complaints or institute, or cause to be instituted, proceedings under the Act, or testify or are about to tesify in any such proceedings.</summary>
</bill>
