<bill session="113" type="h" number="4977" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">COVER Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Creating Options for Veterans Expedited Recovery Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a commission to examine the evidence-based therapy treatment model used by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs for treating mental illnesses of veterans and the potential benefits of incorporating complimentary alternative treatments available in non-Department of Veterans Affairs medical facilities within the community.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412250"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412516" joined="2014-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412529" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412603" joined="2014-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412286" joined="2014-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412557" joined="2014-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412191" joined="2014-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412519" joined="2014-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400352" joined="2014-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412214" joined="2014-07-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR03" subcommittee="Health" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Alternative treatments"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Drug therapy"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/26/2014--Introduced.
Creating Options for Veterans Expedited Recovery Act or the COVER Act - Establishes the Veterans Expedited Recovery Commission to:

 examine the efficacy of the evidence-based therapy model used by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs for treating mental health illnesses of veterans and identify areas to improve wellness-based outcomes; conduct a patient-centered survey within each of the Veterans Integrated Service Networks to examine the experience of veterans with the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) when seeking medical assistance for mental health issues through the VA health care system, their experience with non-VA facilities and health professionals for such issues, their preferences regarding available treatments for such issues and which methods they believe to be most effective, their experience with complementary alternative treatment therapies, the prevalence of prescribing prescription medication among veterans seeking treatment through the VA health care system to address mental health issues, and the Secretary's outreach efforts regarding the availability of benefits and treatments for such issues; examine available research on complementary alternative treatment therapies for mental health issues (including music, yoga, and meditation therapy) and identify what benefits could be made with the inclusion of such treatments for veterans; and study the potential increase in the approval by the Secretary of claims for compensation relating to mental health issues for veterans who served Operation Enduring Freedom, Operation Iraqi Freedom, and Operation New Dawn. Directs the Secretary, upon a report by the Commission, to submit: (1) an action plan for implementing recommendations and a time frame for implementing complementary alternative treatments, or (2) a justification for not doing so and an alternative solution to improve the efficacy of the therapy model.</summary>
</bill>
