<bill session="113" type="h" number="4485" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-04-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-04-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fair Military Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Furthering Accountability and Individual Rights within the Military Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for additional enhancements to the sexual assault prevention and response activities of the Armed Forces.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400411"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412555" joined="2014-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2014-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412307" joined="2014-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="2014-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400379" joined="2014-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412254" joined="2014-04-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-10">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-10">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW07" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Military command and structure"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Military law"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/10/2014--Introduced.
Furthering Accountability and Individual Rights within the Military Act of 2014 or the Fair Military Act - Directs each Secretary of a military department to ensure that: (1) the written performance appraisals of each member of the Armed Forces include an assessment of the extent to which the member supports that Armed Force's sexual assault prevention and response program, and (2) the performance appraisals of each commanding officer indicate the extent to which such officer has established a command climate in which allegations of sexual assault are properly managed and fairly evaluated and in which a victim can report criminal activity without fear of retaliation.

Requires modification of the Military Rules of Evidence to clarify that the general military character of an accused is not admissible for the purpose of showing the probability of his or her innocence, except that an accused may offer evidence of a trait of his or her military character when that trait is relevant to an element of the offense for which he or she has been charged.

Directs the Secretaries of the military departments and any department in which the Coast Guard is operating to ensure that the provisions of Title XVII (Sexual Assault Prevention and Response and Related Reforms) of the National Defense Authorization Act (NDAA) for FY2014 and this Act apply to the United States Military Academy, the Naval Academy, the Air Force Academy, and the Coast Guard Academy.

Requires the independent judicial proceedings panel to conduct assessments of: (1) the use of mental health records by the defense during preliminary hearing and court-martial proceedings, and (2) the use of such records in similar civilian proceedings to determine whether any significant discrepancies exist between the two legal systems.

Directs the Comptroller General (GAO) to submit to the Senate and House Armed Services Committees a report describing the status of the implementation of the sexual assault provisions contained in the NDAAs for FY2012, FY2013, and FY2014 and the sexual assault prevention initiatives announced in memoranda by the Secretary of Defense (DOD) on May 6, 2013, and August 14, 2013.</summary>
</bill>
