<bill session="113" type="h" number="4013" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-02-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-02-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-02-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration to establish a program allowing low volume motor vehicle manufacturers to produce a limited number of vehicles annually within a regulatory system that addresses the unique safety and financial issues associated with limited production, and to direct the Environmental Protection Agency to allow low volume motor vehicle manufacturers to install engines from vehicles that have been issued certificates of conformity.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412011"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400628" joined="2014-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412283" joined="2014-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412510" joined="2014-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412309" joined="2014-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400381" joined="2014-09-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-02-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-09">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-10">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-10">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 15 - 6 .</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSIF17" subcommittee="Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/6/2014--Introduced.
Low Volume Motor Vehicle Manufacturers Act of 2014 - Directs the Secretary of Transportation (DOT) to exempt from certain federal motor vehicle safety and labeling standards (except any standard relating to motor vehicle equipment) up to: (1) 1,000 replica motor vehicles per year manufactured or imported by a low volume manufacturer, and (2) 50 non-replica motor vehicles per year manufactured or imported by a single low volume manufacturer that has evidence of a sales contract.

Defines the term "low volume manufacturer" to mean a motor vehicle manufacturer who annually produces no more than 5,000 motor vehicles worldwide.

Directs the Secretary to permit manufacturers to assign vehicle identification numbers.

Requires manufacturers to register with the Secretary to qualify for an exemption.

Directs the Secretary to require a manufacturer to affix a permanent label to: (1) an exempt non-replica motor vehicle that identifies the motor vehicle safety and labeling standards from which that vehicle is exempt, and (2) an exempt replica motor vehicle that designates the model year that vehicle replicates.

Subjects low-volume manufacturers to all federal motor vehicle safety defect notification, recall, and remedy requirements if a particular motor vehicle has any defects related to motor vehicle safety or any nonconformities regarding any standards other than specified standards.

Amends the Clean Air Act to allow a low volume motor vehicle manufacturer to install in an exempted specifically produced replica or non-replica motor vehicle a motor vehicle engine (including engine emission controls) from a motor vehicle that has been issued a certificate of conformity with Environmental Protection Administration (EPA) emission control standards if certain requirements are met.</summary>
</bill>
