<bill session="113" type="h" number="3390" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-10-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-10-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Lake Tahoe Restoration Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for environmental restoration activities and forest management activities in the Lake Tahoe Basin, to amend title 18, United States Code, to prohibit the importation or shipment of quagga mussels, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412500"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412382" joined="2013-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412446" joined="2013-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2014-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412559" joined="2013-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412521" joined="2014-01-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400403" joined="2014-01-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412318" joined="2013-10-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committees on Transportation and Infrastructure, Agriculture, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-30">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-30">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-30">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-30">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Energy, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="Public Lands and Environmental Regulation" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII22" subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG15" subcommittee="Conservation, Energy, and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1451"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Regional and metropolitan planning"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/30/2013--Introduced.
Lake Tahoe Restoration Act of 2013 - Amends the Lake Tahoe Restoration Act to require the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the U.S. Forest Service, to: (1) conduct forest management activities in the Lake Tahoe Basin in a manner that helps achieve and maintain the environmental threshold carrying capacities established by the Tahoe Regional Planning Agency (Agency) and attains multiple ecosystem benefits, unless the attainment of such benefits would excessively increase the project's cost in relation to the additional benefits gained; (2) establish post-project ground condition criteria for ground disturbance caused by forest management activities; and (3) provide for monitoring to ascertain the attainment of such conditions.

Requires the Lake Tahoe Basin Management Unit to: (1) manage vehicular parking and traffic in the Unit, and (2) support the attainment of the environmental threshold carrying capacities.

Withdraws federal land located in the Unit from: (1) all forms of entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws; (2) location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and (3) disposition under all laws relating to mineral and geothermal leasing. Exempts a land conveyance from withdrawal if carried out under the Lake Tahoe Restoration Act or the Santini-Burton Act.

Requires the Chair of the Lake Tahoe Federal Interagency Partnership to submit to Congress a prioritized list of all Environmental Improvement Program projects for the Basin. Authorizes the Secretary, the Director of the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, the Director of the U.S. Geological Survey (USGS), and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to carry out or provide financial assistance to specified projects and projects included in the prioritized list that have been subject to environmental review and approval under federal and state law and the Tahoe Regional Planning Compact.

Requires the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service to deploy strategies consistent with the Lake Tahoe Aquatic Invasive Species Management Plan to prevent the introduction of aquatic invasive species into the Lake Tahoe Basin.

Requires the Secretary, the Administrator, the Agency, California, Nevada, and the Tahoe Science Consortium to implement a Lake Tahoe Basin Program that includes: (1) developing and updating an integrated multiagency programmatic assessment and monitoring plan and evaluating the effectiveness of the Agency's Environmental Improvement Program, and (2) providing support to governments in reducing pollutants that contribute to the loss of lake clarity.

Prohibits: (1) the importation of the quagga mussel of the species Dreissena rostriformis into the United States, a U.S. territory, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, or any U.S. possession; and (2) the shipment of the mussel between the continental United States, the District of Columbia, Hawaii, Puerto Rico, or a U.S. possession. Requires the prohibited mussels to be exported or destroyed at the expense of the importer or consignee.

Provides that nothing in this Act applies to: (1) the importation or transportation of prohibited species through the operation of a public water system or a related water conveyance, storage, or distribution facility; or (2) the possession or conveyance of water supplies containing prohibited species by a public water system operator.</summary>
</bill>
