<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HBD556A6943CC40058BCD1C12E717C52D" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HR 5877 IH: American Pension Investments Modernization Act of 2014</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2014-12-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 5877</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20141211">December 11, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="W000187">Ms. Waters</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 and title 5, United States Code, to
			 require plans to establish policies addressing firm-specific risks in
			 asset management services, greater diversification in investment
			 strategies, and the inclusion of diverse asset managers and minority
			 brokerage firms, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H0E3DFBA5192B425A8A223EABDF2C5D45" style="OLC">
		<section id="H215447F95E7F4F40A9E7E0CCA5049B07" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>American Pension Investments Modernization Act of 2014</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="H2D3CA68A5BE748EE9D2626303BEE2BB8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Consideration of firm-specific risks and inclusion of diverse asset managers in ERISA plans</header>
			<subsection id="HBF7BD772507B4EA1A5812507EF44F3F3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 404(a) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1104">29 U.S.C. 1104(a)</external-xref>) is
			 amended—</text>
				<paragraph id="H9F7920A3B26E41518BBB71483E07162B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text>
					<subparagraph id="H72AD8735878E4F40B60505DC3344F6DE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDEE291A9C1FE4011BC051EB5798D9A66"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by designating subparagraph (D) as subparagraph (E); and</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEBD71B510B044AE1828B299022716807"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (C) the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H352B4061DCC54179862307F9856C2AD1" style="OLC">
							<subparagraph id="H4F8139768EF5439992D777D5892F95F7" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in any case in which the fiduciary appoints an investment manager or managers to manage any assets
			 of a plan under section 402(c)(3), or business enterprise or enterprises
			 for brokerage and investment banking services, by establishing policies
			 under which the fiduciary will consider—</text>
								<clause id="H7B54636084F7490CA42BBC1714D468C7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the concentration level of the plan’s exposure to firm-specific risks, including operational,
			 compliance, and fraud risks;</text>
								</clause><clause id="H968EAFBD42DA4B59AED85CFB9FF89346"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the inclusion, to the greatest extent feasible, of minority business enterprises for brokerage and
			 investment banking services; and</text>
								</clause><clause id="H6ACE4BFDA5F44CAA8C5638A88F7023B0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the utilization of diverse asset managers, taking into consideration the investment opportunities
			 they offer in sectors, strategies, geographies, and demographics not
			 meaningfully available to the plans.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0727D4D98E6E4AEEB5489A511F544DA7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H89BD224479A34EB69E287AB1935C10B7" style="OLC">
						<paragraph id="H85CDC2B9EC084C36B25C81C5D1182738" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum>
							<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H92B5515A246A4562A4096326EECDE130"><enum>(A)</enum><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <quote>minority business enterprise</quote> means any business entity—</text>
								<clause id="HBE3541432B2E49B3A5E445A9441FCCA0" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum>
									<text>not less than 51 percent of which is owned by one or more individuals described in subparagraph (C)
			 or, in the case of any publicly owned business, not less than 51 percent
			 of the stock of which is owned by such individuals; or</text>
								</clause><clause id="H3730C092FF2E41D388B82A5B6EA5F979" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum>
									<subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H934FD26A40E8476C9765A7CDBC9728BF"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not less than 35 percent of which is owned by one or more individuals described in subparagraph (C)
			 or, in the case of any publicly owned business, not less than 35 percent
			 of the stock of which is owned by such individuals; and</text>
									</subclause><subclause id="H088749E8EEDA4B6DA5EA12152A7EB807" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the management and daily business operations of which are controlled by one or more individuals
			 described in subparagraph (C).</text>
									</subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBC1E64999EC14575A2CAE63AC82A8792" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <quote>diverse asset manager</quote> means a minority business enterprise that manages an investment portfolio of at least $100,000,000
			 and not more than $25,000,000,000.</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6EDCFF132D544BB595111B6AE35E54B8" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An individual described in this subparagraph is—</text>
								<clause id="H5028BB816CDF4B599F6E063D6092F7EF"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an African-American, Hispanic-American, Asian Pacific American, Subcontinent Asian American, or
			 Native American;</text>
								</clause><clause id="H97481E42DDD542FDA7013A99D139CC92"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a woman; or</text>
								</clause><clause id="HEA29D40E791F41CE90A99E06F671B689"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a veteran (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/101">section 101(2)</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H36446DCCD3B64BB996CEAFACA14B29E4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Issuance of guidance by Secretary of Labor</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Labor shall
			 issue guidance relating to the requirement imposed by section 404(a)(1)(D)
			 of such Act (as amended by subsection (a)). In issuing guidance under this
			 subsection, the Secretary of Labor shall consider successful practices
			 from State, local, and private-sector retirement systems’ utilization of
			 diverse and emerging asset managers and of minority business enterprises
			 for brokerage and investment banking services, including established
			 efforts, programs, plans, and goals designed to increase their
			 participation in financial services, and providing pension plans with
			 greater access to investment opportunities that may otherwise be
			 overlooked.</text>
			</subsection></section><section commented="no" id="H2D9A2AF5BECF4EC4ADF217A30CA1A719"><enum>3.</enum><header>Consideration of firm-specific risks and inclusion of diverse asset managers in the Thrift Savings
			 Plan</header>
			<subsection id="HF9E07C4A9A0A4A788698E66AF350F944"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/8472">Section 8472</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE7A922A8C02A40B295D6C8E537640300" style="USC">
					<subsection id="H6BC4AC74E11A4A3D910D693EF0EB2329"><enum>(k)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In establishing policies under subsection (f)(1)(A), the Board shall take into account the guidance
			 issued by the Secretary of Labor pursuant to section 404(a)(1)(D) of the
			 Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1104">29 U.S.C. 1104(a)</external-xref>).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="H524BC6A4416340ADA371035AA764A52E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 8477(b)(1)(C) of such title is amended by inserting after <quote>of this title,</quote> the following: <quote>and consistent with the policies developed under section 8472(k),</quote>.</text>
			</subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB854139B4669438EAAF8929B82D5954B" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>4.</enum><header>Active management option under the Thrift Savings Plan</header>
			<subsection id="HC5957DD640F146CCA50B6BF6DB412E0A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter III of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/84">chapter 84</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by inserting at the end the
			 following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6631E7150BF9427FA1D792F15F38E354" style="USC">
					<section id="H0A28C7E35BD74EDF940A47206CC15F72"><enum>8440g.</enum><header>Active management option</header>
						<subsection id="HED4B261640BA48DE8A9E3112E28EACCB"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board shall provide employees and Members and former employees or Members the option to
			 participate in actively managed funds within such employee or Member’s
			 Thrift Savings Fund account. Such option or options shall allow not more
			 than 20 percent of an employee or Member’s (or former employee or
			 Member’s) funds to be actively managed.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="H24C1B573C42D47669990D7981626EE6E"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Notwithstanding the requirement of subsection (a), the Board may not subject more than 20 percent
			 of the total assets under management of the Thrift Savings Fund to active
			 management.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="H79A3B667D54742208764B248A79E87CA"><enum>(c)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board shall promulgate guidelines regarding the active management of funds under this section.
			 In promulgating such guidelines, the Board shall consider modern and
			 successful practices from State, local, and private-sector retirement
			 systems’ utilization of active management strategies in order to—</text>
							<paragraph id="H823939DEE768436BB730B5D0345B4D2C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reduce market downside risks to the best extent possible, including dramatic swings in major market
			 indexes;</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="H3544DA0ABFEE40719367F8F7F5015078"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">take advantage of research and investment opportunities offered by small-, minority-, women- and
			 veteran-owned firms that specialize in less traditional asset classes, or
			 less efficient market segments with high-growth potentials, including
			 investments in sectors, strategies, geographies and demographics that are
			 not meaningfully available to large passively invested funds; and</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="HD544929EB4E74C10BD8EF9FBB7EF2D19"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">take advantage of more effective portfolio designs that diversify across active and passive
			 investment strategies and managers.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="H36C44FF7C31B46D9A60BEE9A1E031AEA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for such subchapter is amended by adding after the item relating to section
			 8440f the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H18F178953B984515B49181A259E1425F" style="USC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">8440g. Active management option.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="HA530FC1EC0C34B9D894466BB833C62D9"><enum>5.</enum><header>Reports</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the issuance of guidance under section 2(b) and annually thereafter,
			 the Secretary of Labor and the Chairman of the Federal Retirement Thrift
			 Investment Board shall submit a report to Congress on the progress
			 achieved and efforts being made to implement the amendments made by
			 sections 2 and 3, respectively. Such report shall include such
			 recommendations as the Secretary and the Chairman, respectively, deem
			 necessary or appropriate. In addition, each report shall include—</text>
			<paragraph id="H29073C88BD904F9CA0E5AD8CBFAA4623"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an assessment of the extent to which compliance with the requirements contained in such amendments
			 is being achieved;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H28C3969D89CA463EBEA00654CB1EFFFF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a summary of the enforcement actions taken by each of the agencies assigned administrative
			 enforcement responsibilities for such requirements;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HCBB0B9C48E464021BE429656EB0B55AB"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the extent feasible, with respect to the Thrift Savings Plan and terminated plans within the
			 meaning of title IV of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of
			 1974—</text>
				<subparagraph id="H08A9440A133243309D1F1BB0F00B0A1D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a list of all asset management firms (minority-owned and others) to which plan funds were
			 allocated, and the amount allocated to each asset management firm;</text>
				</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC91DF51164294762A96547D88A28689C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the fees charged by each asset management firm, including proceeds from security lending, if any;</text>
				</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7F415F341A12450A885F2FCDD05EED75"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the list of all firms (minority-owned and others) used for brokerage and investment banking
			 services, and the amount of transactions executed; and</text>
				</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H85606D46AB2941BE90EE19B91B1D62A9"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the fees charged by each firm used for brokerage and investment banking services.</text>
				</subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H9D8CFD436F974631AA24C4D1ADC9E19B"><enum>6.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The amendments made by sections 2 and 3 shall apply with respect to plan years beginning at least 9
			 months after the issuance of guidance under section 2(b).</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


