<bill session="113" type="h" number="5121" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Restore Unalienable Rights Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit the indefinite detention of United States citizens and lawful resident aliens, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412547"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, and Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-16">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-16">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-16">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU10" subcommittee="Constitution and Civil Justice" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Due process and equal protection"/>
    <term name="Military law"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/16/2014--Introduced.
Restore Unalienable Rights Act of 2014 - Amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2012 (with respect to the authority of the President to use all necessary and appropriate force pursuant to the Authorization for Use of Military Force under P.L. 107-40) to prohibit U.S. Armed Forces from detaining, pending disposition under the law of war, a U.S. citizen or lawful resident alien of the United States who was captured, detained, or arrested in the United States.

Amends the federal criminal code to prohibit an authorization to use military force, a declaration of war, or any similar authority from authorizing the detention without charge or trial of a citizen or lawful permanent resident of the United States apprehended in the United States.</summary>
</bill>
