<bill session="113" type="s" number="2300" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-05-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Jacob Sexton Military Suicide Prevention Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 10, United States Code, to require the Secretary of Defense to conduct periodic mental health assessments for members of the Armed Forces and to submit reports with respect to mental health, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412205"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2014-05-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/7/2014--Introduced.
Jacob Sexton Military Suicide Prevention Act of 2014 - Directs the Secretary of Defense (DOD), at least once each year, to: (1) provide a person-to-person mental health assessment for each member of the Armed Forces on active duty and for each member of the Ready Reserve of an Armed Force for the purpose of identifying mental health conditions to determine which members are in need of additional care, treatment, or other services; and (2) submit to the House and Senate Armed Services Committees a report on such assessments, including on the number of members referred for care and services based on mental health conditions detected.

Requires the Secretary to: (1) convene an interagency working group to review and recommend collaborative approaches to improving the provision of mental health services to members of the National Guard and the Reserves; (2) report the findings and recommendations of the working group to specified congressional committees; and (3) report to the Armed Services Committees on an evaluation of specific tools, processes, and best practices to improve the identification of, and treatment by the Armed Forces of, mental health conditions and traumatic brain injury among members of the Armed Forces.</summary>
</bill>
