<bill session="113" type="h" number="5864" updated="2015-09-01T17:50:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-12-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-12-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-12-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FPS Improvement Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To protect Federal employees and visitors, improve the security of Federal facilities, authorize and modernize the Federal Protective Service, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412258"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-12-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Protection of officials"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/11/2014--Introduced.
FPS Improvement Act of 2014 - Assigns responsibility to the Federal Protective Service (FPS) for the protection of federal buildings, grounds, and property and persons on the property. Authorizes FPS to: (1) designate Department of Homeland Security (DHS) employees with enhanced law enforcement powers for duty in connection with the protection of federal property and persons on the property, (2) authorize protective service guards for the protection of federal buildings and grounds, and (3) assess security charges to owners or tenants of a federal facility protected by FPS that is not in compliance with federal security standards. Requires tenants at federal facilities to maintain a Facility Security Committee.

Establishes the Interagency Security Committee to develop safety and security standards and best practices to mitigate the effects of natural and manmade hazards in federal facilities.

Requires reports on: (1) FPS personnel needs, (2) the feasibility of federalizing the protective service guard workforce, (3) a method for funding FPS, and (4) methods to detect or prevent explosives from entering federal facilities.</summary>
</bill>
