<bill session="113" type="h" number="4588" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-05-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting the Rights of Musicians Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to deny the right to grant retransmission consent to a television broadcast station if an AM or FM radio broadcast station licensed to the same licensee transmits a sound recording without providing compensation for programming.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400032"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="2014-05-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF16" subcommittee="Communications and Technology" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Music"/>
    <term name="Sound recording"/>
    <term name="Television and film"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/7/2014--Introduced.
Protecting the Rights of Musicians Act - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to exempt from retransmission consent requirements under which cable systems or other multichannel video programming distributors (MVPDs) are prohibited from retransmitting the signal of a television broadcasting station without the originating station's consent (which is generally obtained through a retransmission consent agreement under which the cable system or other MVPD provides a negotiated payment or other consideration to the station in exchange for retransmission authority) the retransmission of the signal of a television broadcast station if the licensee of such station is also the licensee of an AM or FM radio broadcast station that has transmitted a sound recording over such radio station without providing compensation for all programming carried over the signal.</summary>
</bill>
