<bill session="113" type="h" number="5388" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Captive Insurers Clarification Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To clarify the definition of nonadmitted insurer under the Nonadmitted and Reinsurance Reform Act of 2010, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412239"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU05" subcommittee="Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="s" number="2726"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Insurance industry and regulation"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2014--Introduced.
Captive Insurers Clarification Act - Amends the Nonadmitted and Reinsurance Reform Act of 2010 to define "captive insurance company" as an insurance company wholly owned directly or indirectly: (1) by a single parent company, and whose primary purpose is to insure the risks of that single parent company or its affiliates; (2) by a group of companies, and whose primary purpose is to insure the risks of that group or its affiliates; and (3) by an industry, trade, or service group or association, and whose primary purpose is to insure the risks of any member in that group or association, including any member affiliate.

Excludes a captive insurance company from the meaning of a "nonadmitted insurer" (that is not licensed to engage in the business of insurance in a state), and from any requirements (including state tax requirements) applying to a nonadmitted insurer.</summary>
</bill>
