<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="HE79349E70B3142559BC35ECDF78F16F0" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HRES 499 IH: Condemning the violation of Ukrainian sovereignty, independence, and territorial integrity by military forces of the Russian Federation.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2014-03-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 499</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20140305">March 5, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000487">Mr. Royce</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="E000179">Mr. Engel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001094">Mr. Cook</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001179">Mr. Marino</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000378">Mr. Kinzinger of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000435">Ms. Ros-Lehtinen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000610">Mr. Deutch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001065">Mr. Holding</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001032">Mr. Holt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001189">Mr. Messer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000522">Mr. Smith of New Jersey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000266">Mr. Chabot</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000376">Mr. Kelly of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000605">Mr. Perry</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000592">Mr. Poe of Texas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001165">Mr. Sires</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name> and <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Condemning the violation of Ukrainian sovereignty, independence, and territorial integrity by
			 military forces of the Russian Federation.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas><text>Whereas the United States has been strongly committed to the sovereignty, democratic development,
			 and prosperity of Ukraine since the recovery of its independence in 1991;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Ukrainian people have the right to freely determine their future, including their
			 country’s relationship with other countries and international
			 organizations, without interference, intimidation, or coercion by other
			 countries;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas closer relations with Europe hold out the prospect of a more stable and prosperous Ukraine,
			 which would be of benefit to all countries, including Russia;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the military intervention by the Russian Federation in Crimea is a violation of Ukraine’s
			 sovereignty, independence, and territorial integrity;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas this military intervention is a violation of international law, including the Russian
			 Federation’s obligations under the United Nations Charter;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas this military intervention is a violation of the Russian Federation’s obligations under the
			 1994 Budapest Memorandum on Security Assurances, in which it pledged to
			 respect the independence and sovereignty and the existing borders of
			 Ukraine and to refrain from the threat or use of force against the
			 territorial integrity or political independence of Ukraine;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas by its military intervention in Ukraine, the Russian Federation has violated the provisions
			 of the Helsinki Final Act Declaration of Principles Regarding Relations
			 Between Participating States of the Organization for Security and
			 Cooperation in Europe;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Russian Federation’s military intervention in Crimea represents a reckless escalation
			 of its long-standing efforts to pressure Ukraine through political,
			 diplomatic, and economic means to reduce its ties to Europe and the West
			 and force it into a closer association with Russia, including through the
			 establishment of a Eurasian Union;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Russian Federation has used and is continuing to use coercive economic measures,
			 including the manipulation of energy prices and supplies, to place
			 political pressure on Ukraine and other countries in the region;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Government of Ukraine has exercised extraordinary restraint to date in response to the
			 use of force against it on its territory; and</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the immediate deployment of international monitors from either the Organization for
			 Security and Cooperation in Europe or the United Nations to Crimea and in
			 other Ukrainian regions would provide transparency and objective reporting
			 regarding threats of violence and military activity, and also enhance the
			 security of the Ukrainian people in all regions: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body id="H0008F210CA404222874AAB578D4CCF3A" style="traditional">
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H58BF50FC45C143A9BF620C4582766DCD" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the House of Representatives—</text>
			<paragraph id="H0154947B3AB3437794208ECD22AA60DA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>condemns the violation of Ukrainian sovereignty, independence, and territorial integrity by
			 military forces of the Russian Federation;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HA0FB8B1D354B41839C2D3710354123B6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>states that the military intervention by the Russian Federation—</text>
				<subparagraph id="HBF0566B098B7452596FD760C3C547D1D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is in breach of its obligations under the United Nations Charter;</text>
				</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H83C6B5E14B2B4AD3B95FD3068B560EF9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is in violation of the 1994 Budapest Memorandum on Security Assurances, in which it pledged to
			 respect the independence and sovereignty and the existing borders of
			 Ukraine and to refrain from the threat of use of force against the
			 territorial integrity or political independence of Ukraine; and</text>
				</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H661BC2E4BF944BB28E808198962D54F7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>poses a threat to international peace and security;</text>
				</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4FFB09943B894AFBA38B8D138146D7BD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>calls on the Russian Federation to remove all of its military forces from Ukraine’s Crimean
			 peninsula, other than at those operating in accordance with its 1997
			 agreement on the Status and Conditions of the Black Sea Fleet Stationing
			 on the Territory of Ukraine, and to refrain from interference in all
			 regions of Ukraine;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H935034DD2EDD4A11A9D0CBA5C260D8C2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>declares that the Ukrainian people have the right to determine their own future free from outside
			 interference;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HACDD008DD82F44E58990A3D0BD9A4511"><enum>(5)</enum><text>commends the Ukrainian Government for its continued restraint and avoidance of military
			 provocations;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HBD1138CE27524454A50E70367D6BFE99"><enum>(6)</enum><text>calls on the Ukrainian Government to continue to protect the rights of all minority populations
			 within Ukraine and make clear that it represents all Ukrainian citizens;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HD2D6568343B845C8BC1E431E2C6C0D92"><enum>(7)</enum><text>calls on all Ukrainians to respect the legitimate government authorities in all parts of Ukraine,
			 including in eastern and southern Ukraine;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H2CAFD76D077746B2B6CF38CD1FDA2D1F"><enum>(8)</enum><text>calls for the deployment of independent monitors from the Organization for Security and Cooperation
			 in Europe in Crimea and other areas of Ukraine;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H19CC26C7089B4E1694975A06299ACBC0"><enum>(9)</enum><text>calls upon the President and the leaders of the other democratic states to not attend the G8
			 summit in Sochi, Russia and to consider expelling Russia from the group,
			 given its international aggression and internal repression that are
			 inconsistent with democratic standards;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H127C5BBEB85D42D5BDEF48C1EBA7D066"><enum>(10)</enum><text>calls on the Administration to work with our European allies and other countries to impose visa,
			 financial, trade, and other sanctions on senior Russian Federation
			 officials, majority state-owned banks and commercial organizations, and
			 other state agencies, as appropriate;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H7F158E268F8C4C9DB20A01B48A14F89A"><enum>(11)</enum><text>states that the United States should participate with its European allies and other countries in a
			 joint effort to provide the Ukrainian government with financial, economic,
			 and technical assistance, including asset recovery, to assist an economic
			 recovery program that includes fundamental reforms;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H2791A53EAAA44038AB3C80E2F878C857"><enum>(12)</enum><text>calls on the United States, its European allies, and other countries and international
			 organizations to provide assistance to ensure that new elections scheduled
			 for May 2014 are free, fair, and in full accordance with international
			 standards;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H5AB7EDC0D381463B87D91D4D662DEE75"><enum>(13)</enum><text>calls on the United States and its European allies and other countries to develop a long-term
			 strategy to support economic development in Ukraine, including enhanced
			 relationships with Western countries, organizations and institutions;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H4F1BD2ED3327442AAD274678A4CA171E"><enum>(14)</enum><text>supports efforts by Ukraine to achieve energy independence; and</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HE5DD962F7DC14505BEDB06A83508B7BC"><enum>(15)</enum><text>affirms the right of all countries in the region to exercise their sovereign rights within their
			 internationally recognized borders free from outside intervention and to
			 conduct their foreign policy in accordance with their determination of the
			 best interests of their peoples.</text>
			</paragraph></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


