<bill session="113" type="h" number="5100" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SCORE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Standardization of Collegiate Oversight of Revenues and Expenditures Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require institutions of higher education to report revenue generated by each sports team, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400326"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400318" joined="2014-07-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Training" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="School athletics"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/14/2014--Introduced.
Standardization of Collegiate Oversight of Revenues and Expenditures Act or the SCORE Act - Amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require each coeducational institution of higher education (IHE) that is participating in a title IV program and has an intercollegiate athletic program to include in its annual report on its intercollegiate athletic program: (1) the amount of revenue generated by each item on a list of categorized sources, disaggregated by each sports team; and (2) the expenses attributable to each item on a list of categorized activities or obligations, disaggregated by each sports team.

Prohibits an IHE from being a member of any intercollegiate athletic association or participating in any national intercollegiate athletics competition organized by any person, unless such association or person annually reports and disaggregates by sport, athletic event, or contract, as applicable: (1) the total generated revenue and amount of revenue generated by each item on a list of categorized sources, (2) the amount of expenses attributable to each item on a list of categorized activities or obligations, and (3) executive compensation schedules.

Directs the Secretary of Education to: (1) define the categories of information that must be reported pursuant to this Act; and (2) biannually review and, as necessary, update each definition in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles or significant changes in the national system of intercollegiate athletics.

Directs the Secretary to appoint a task force, made up of representatives from division I, II, and III schools in the National Collegiate Athletic Association (NCAA), with which the Secretary is to consult in defining or redefining each category.</summary>
</bill>
