<bill session="113" type="s" number="2238" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-04-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-04-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Crimea Annexation Non-recognition Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to ensure that the United States Government in no way recognizes Russia's annexation of Crimea.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402675"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2014-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2014-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2014-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="2014-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="2014-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2014-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400222" joined="2014-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300072" joined="2014-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400325" joined="2014-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412322" joined="2014-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412491" joined="2014-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2014-04-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Customs enforcement"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans and debt"/>
    <term name="Geography"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development programs"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
    <term name="Ukraine"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/10/2014--Introduced.
Crimea Annexation Non-recognition Act of 2014 - States that it is U.S. policy to not recognize the de jure or de facto sovereignty of the Russian Federation over Crimea, its airspace, or its territorial waters.

Prohibits: (1) any federal department or agency from taking any action that recognizes or implies recognition of sovereignty of the Russian Federation over Crimea, its airspace, or its territorial waters; (2) the Government Printing Office (GPO) from printing any map, document, or other paper indicating Crimea as part of the territory of the Russian Federation; and (3) any federal department or agency from taking any action to facilitate, finance, or guarantee any investment in Crimea that involves any official or entity of the government of the Russian Federation, or any business, bank, or other financial entity whose headquarters or principal place of business is in the Russian Federation.

Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to require the U.S. representatives to the International Monetary Fund (IMF), the World Bank Group, and certain other international financial institutions to oppose any loan, loan guarantee, or transfer of funds to Crimea related to activity involving: (1) any official or entity of the government of the Russian Federation, or (2) any financial institution or other entity whose headquarters or principal place of business is in the Russian Federation.

States that in any matter before a U.S. court the Department of Justice (DOJ) shall affirm the U.S. policy of not recognizing the de jure or de facto sovereignty of the Russian Federation over Crimea, its airspace, or its territorial waters.

 Prohibits: (1) a foreign vessel arriving from a port in Crimea from entering a U.S. port if it is transporting goods for which export documents are issued or approved by Russian Federation customs authorities; (2) the Secretary of Defense (DOD) from taking any action that implies recognition of the sovereignty of the Russian Federation over Crimea, its airspace, or its territorial waters; and (3) any U.S. flagged vessel or U.S. certified aircraft or air carrier from taking any action that implies recognition of the sovereignty of the Russian Federation over Crimea or its territorial waters.

Prohibits the obligation or expenditure of any amounts to provide economic support fund assistance, development assistance, or security assistance to the government of any country that has recognized the sovereignty of the Russian Federation over Crimea, its airspace, or its territorial waters.</summary>
</bill>
