<bill session="113" type="h" number="3994" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-02-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-02-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-02-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Lands Invasive Species Control, Prevention, and Management Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve the control and management of invasive species that threaten and harm Federal lands under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400029"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412559" joined="2014-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412294" joined="2014-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400313" joined="2014-02-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-02-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-05">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-05">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee Indian and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Energy, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-09">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII10" subcommittee="Public Lands and Environmental Regulation" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII22" subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII24" subcommittee="Indian and Alaska Native Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG15" subcommittee="Conservation, Energy, and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animal and plant health"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="General public lands matters"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Pest management"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/5/2014--Introduced.
Federal Lands Invasive Species Control, Prevention, and Management Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior (respecting federal lands administered through the Bureau of Indian Affairs [BIA], Bureau of Land Management [BLM], Bureau of Reclamation, National Park Service, or U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service) and the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) (respecting federal lands administered through the U.S. Forest Service) to plan and carry out activities on lands directly managed by the Secretary concerned to control and manage invasive species in order to inhibit or reduce their populations and to effectuate restoration or reclamation efforts.

Requires the Secretary concerned to develop a strategic plan for the implementation of an invasive species program that endeavors to achieve an annual 5% net reduction of invasive species populations on lands managed by that Secretary.

Requires the Secretary concerned to use: (1) no less than 75% of funds each fiscal year for on-the-ground control and management of invasive species; (2) no more than 15% of such funds for investigations, development activities, and outreach and public awareness efforts to address invasive species control and management needs; and (3) no more than 10% for administrative costs.

Requires the Secretaries, in selecting the method or methods to control or manage an invasive species as part of a specific control or management project, to require the use of the least costly options necessary to perform effectively, based on sound scientific data and other commonly used cost-effective benchmarks in the area.</summary>
</bill>
