<bill session="113" type="s" number="2582" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ADAPT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Diversification and Progress in Trade Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a pilot program to assist in expanding and diversifying the business of small business concerns that rely on amounts awarded for Federal contracts and subcontracts.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400413"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Business education"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/10/2014--Introduced.
American Diversification and Progress in Trade Act of 2014 or the ADAPT Act - Directs the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) to establish a pilot program to assist in expanding and diversifying the business of small businesses the majority of whose business consists of amounts awarded under federal contracts and subcontracts, particularly in geographic areas, including rural areas, where amounts awarded for federal contracts and subcontracts are a significant driver of the local economy.

Requires the Administrator to report to Congress on how SBA is addressing the need for such small businesses to expand and diversify business during periods of decline in appropriations for federal contracting, including an analysis of how such declines would impact growth among such small businesses, particularly those owned and controlled by service-disabled veterans, women, or socially and economically disadvantaged.</summary>
</bill>
