<bill session="113" type="h" number="4943" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Child Protection Training Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve the training of child protection professionals.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412214"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400259" joined="2014-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="408211" joined="2014-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412402" joined="2014-06-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-23">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-23">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Training" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="s" number="1722"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/23/2014--Introduced.
National Child Protection Training Act - Directs the Attorney General, through the Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention, to establish a program to sustain at least four regional training centers affiliated with institutions of higher education.

Requires the regional training centers to: (1) develop model interdisciplinary undergraduate curricula on recognizing and responding to cases of child maltreatment that consists of at least a three-course certificate program or minor degree; (2) develop related model graduate curricula for medical schools, law schools, seminaries, and other institutions of higher education that instruct students likely to become child protection professionals or other professionals required by law to report cases of child maltreatment; (3) disseminate such curricula, upon the Attorney General's approval, to institutions of higher education; (4) develop "laboratory" training facilities that allow for simulated, interactive, and intensive training of students preparing for child protection careers as well as child protection professionals currently in the field; (5) assist communities in developing evidence-based prevention programs; and (6) assist states in developing and maintaining forensic interview training programs.</summary>
</bill>
