<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1D5518AFC77148A09D7AB480859D925C" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HR 677 IH: Inter-Affiliate Swap Clarification Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2013-02-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 677</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20130213">February 13, 2013</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001187">Mr. Stivers</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="F000455">Ms. Fudge</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000564">Mr. Gibson</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001183">Mr. Schweikert</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To exempt inter-affiliate swaps from certain regulatory requirements put in place by the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H501F06EE568B40FC9DCBC182E7E5A8AA" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HDD3BD8DC1190436D8BEFCC367DC65C67" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Inter-Affiliate Swap Clarification Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section>
<section id="H68A1FB69B0AA488DA2F524E01210BD5F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Treatment of affiliate transactions</header> 
<subsection id="HAA221B0582224D89B648BC11A0E6A1EB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Commodity Exchange Act amendments</header> 
<paragraph id="H4B4D8B262937415EA854D47B20EBA65E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Treatment of affiliate transactions</header><text>Section 1a(47) of the Commodity Exchange Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1a">7 U.S.C. 1a(47)</external-xref>), as added by section 721(a)(21) of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H58B20B3197474F5D976DA4548E0B1C44" style="OLC"> 
<subparagraph id="HCB358F841F1345E09BAD3F2CA236E798"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Treatment of affiliate transactions</header> 
<clause id="HE195E3EAF41E42DDABFA5D7F7F6189C9"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purposes of any clearing and execution requirements under section 2(h) and any applicable margin and capital requirements of section 4s(e) and for purposes of defining <quote>swap dealer</quote> or <quote>major swap participant</quote>, and reporting requirements other than those set forth in clause (ii), the term <term>swap</term> does not include any agreement, contract, or transaction that—</text> 
<subclause id="H6C120507F86044F9A4687B5A7A6643F7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>would otherwise be included as a <quote>swap</quote> under subparagraph (A); and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H2550750A9DB84E988CFB911064773A74"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is entered into by parties, neither of which is a ‘swap dealer’ that is an insured depository institution or a ‘major swap participant’ that is an insured depository institution, that report information or prepare financial statements on a consolidated basis, or for which a company affiliated with both parties reports information or prepares financial statements on a consolidated basis.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H6E99D8FD53844ACFB8B81FA4BEDCB421"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">All agreements, contracts, or transactions described in clause (i) shall be reported to either a swap data repository, or, if there is no swap data repository that would accept such agreements, contracts, or transactions, to the Commission pursuant to section 4r, or to a swap data repository or to the Commission pursuant to section 2(h)(5), within such time period as the Commission may by rule or regulation prescribe. Nothing in this subparagraph shall prohibit the Commission from establishing public reporting requirements for covered transactions between affiliates as described in sections 23A and 23B of the Federal Reserve Act in a manner consistent with rules governing the treatment of such covered transactions pursuant to section 2(a)(13) of this Act.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H71D581573EE84B10874132AE5CEF944F"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Protection of insurance funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this subparagraph shall be construed to prevent the regulator of a Federal or State insurance fund or guaranty fund from exercising its other existing authority to protect the integrity of such a fund, except that such regulator shall not subject agreements, contracts, or transactions described in clause (i) to clearing and execution requirements under section 2 of this Act, to any applicable margin and capital requirements of section 4s(e) of this Act, or to reporting requirements of title VII of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/203">Public Law 111–203</external-xref> other than those set forth in clause (ii) of this subparagraph.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF2795FE64E9544119F74D066C11AAF80"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Preservation of federal reserve act authority</header><text>Nothing in this subparagraph shall exempt a transaction described in this subparagraph from sections 23A or 23B of the Federal Reserve Act or implementing regulations thereunder.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H90C629E1AC3D4BE78AED305B87C051BF"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Preservation of federal and state regulatory authorities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this subparagraph shall affect the Federal banking agencies’ safety-and-soundness authorities over banks established in law other than title VII of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/203">Public Law 111–203</external-xref> or the authorities of State insurance regulators over insurers, including the authority to impose capital requirements with regard to swaps. For purposes of this clause, the term ‘bank’ shall be defined pursuant to section 3(a)(6) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934, ‘insurer’ shall be defined pursuant to title V of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/203">Public Law 111–203</external-xref>, and ‘swap’ shall be defined pursuant to title VII of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/203">Public Law 111–203</external-xref>.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H712F8867D360491A956052B3ED7A6CBE"><enum>(vi)</enum><header>Prevention of evasion</header><text>The Commission may prescribe rules under this subparagraph (and issue interpretations of such rules) as determined by the Commission to be necessary to include in the definition of swaps under this paragraph any agreement, contract, or transaction that has been structured to evade the requirements of this Act applicable to swaps.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H14BE7B338F804A07BADE2C7F878A213A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Treatment of affiliates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2(h)(7)(D)(i) of the Commodity Exchange Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2">7 U.S.C. 2(h)(7)(D)(i)</external-xref>), as added by section 723(a) of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act, is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HB4BF7B68052A40618FAFD9409A40D274" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<clause id="HB7E66F509EDF49AFA80752B2ED7E65E2"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An affiliate of a person that qualifies for an exception under subparagraph (A) (including affiliate entities predominantly engaged in providing financing for the purchase of the merchandise or manufactured goods of the person) may qualify for the exception only if the affiliate enters into the swap to hedge or mitigate the commercial risk of the person or other affiliate of the person that is not a financial entity.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCB6C19388BD648CCAFC17CB05CB74083"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Securities Exchange Act of 1934 amendments</header> 
<paragraph id="H440848B8A08B4D1CB23A10E0FB757D4F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Treatment of affiliate transactions</header><text>Section 3(a)(68) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78c">15 U.S.C. 78c(a)(68)</external-xref>), as added by section 761(a)(6) of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HAA97D186CA8148978934171A2C86F593" style="OLC"> 
<subparagraph id="H63A9F34E07BA441D8E0D239C1705B9E2"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Treatment of affiliate transactions</header> 
<clause id="H4A6FEDA20DC248E59956D2BAA1DBF4A9"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For the purposes of any clearing and execution requirements under section 3C and any applicable margin and capital requirements of section 15F(e), and for purposes of defining <quote>security-based swap dealer</quote> or a <quote>major security-based swap participant</quote>, and reporting requirements other than those set forth in clause (ii), the term <term>security-based swap</term> does not include any agreement, contract, or transaction that—</text> 
<subclause id="HD477294F55CD475AB1F2B90AF99F0DAD"><enum>(I)</enum><text>would otherwise be included as a <quote>security-based swap</quote> under subparagraph (A); and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H1ABEC9BDDD2F4DD4A6D910ECDC231845"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is entered into by parties, neither of which is a ‘security-based swap dealer’ that is an insured depository institution or a ‘major security-based swap participant’ that is an insured depository institution, that report information or prepare financial statements on a consolidated basis, or for which a company affiliated with both parties reports information or prepares financial statements on a consolidated basis.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H0029EFB398464851BA8F7A6320DF1FA1"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text>All agreements, contracts, or transactions described in clause (i) shall be reported to either a security-based swap data repository, or, if there is no security-based swap data repository that would accept such agreements, contracts, or transactions, to the Commission pursuant to section 13A, within such time period as the Commission may by rule or regulation prescribe.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H9CD506435A5F4370934756AE8C28062C"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Preservation of federal reserve act authority</header><text>Nothing in this subparagraph shall exempt a transaction described in this subparagraph from sections 23A or 23B of the Federal Reserve Act or implementing regulations thereunder.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H7FC8781057D74F65A7E15FB5AF6FB1C6"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Protection of insurance funds</header><text>Nothing in this subparagraph shall be construed to prevent the regulator of a Federal or State insurance fund or guaranty fund from exercising its other existing authority to protect the integrity of such a fund, except that such regulator shall not subject security-based swap transactions between affiliated companies to clearing and execution requirements under section 3C, to any applicable margin and capital requirements of section 15F(e), or to reporting requirements of title VII of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/203">Public Law 111–203</external-xref> other than those set forth in clause (ii).</text></clause> 
<clause id="H1CEFE04609974E538BCB0DF3E33626E2"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Preservation of federal and state regulatory authorities</header><text>Nothing in this subparagraph shall affect the Federal banking agencies’ safety-and-soundness authorities over banks established in law other than title VII of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/203">Public Law 111–203</external-xref> or the authorities of State insurance regulators over insurers, including the authority to impose capital requirements with regard to security-based swaps. For purposes of this clause, the term ‘bank’ shall be defined pursuant to section 3(a)(6) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934, ‘insurer’ shall be defined pursuant to title V of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/203">Public Law 111–203</external-xref>, and ‘security-based swap’ shall be defined pursuant to title VII of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/203">Public Law 111–203</external-xref>.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H641B44B2893840EC920BAA6322D10924"><enum>(vi)</enum><header>Prevention of evasion</header><text>The Commission may prescribe rules under this subparagraph (and issue interpretations of such rules) as determined by the Commission to be necessary to include in the definition of security-based swap under this paragraph any agreement, contract, or transaction that has been structured to evade the requirements of this Act applicable to security-based swaps.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H28349A22A15D4FC6B99BCAD2B1AD313F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Treatment of affiliates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3C(g)(4)(A) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78c-3">15 U.S.C. 78c-3(g)(4)(A)</external-xref>), as added by section 763(a) of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act, is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HFFD0DC245919406D8046CD93F7EFA1C0" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<clause id="H71121BABAC3D40829C20B03E832F4851"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An affiliate of a person that qualifies for an exception under this subsection (including affiliate entities predominantly engaged in providing financing for the purchase of the merchandise or manufactured goods of the person) may qualify for the exception only if the affiliate enters into the security-based swap to hedge or mitigate the commercial risk of the person or other affiliate of the person that is not a financial entity.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 

