<bill session="113" type="h" number="706" updated="2015-09-01T17:49:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-18">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-02-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Blackstone River Valley National Historical Park Establishment Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Blackstone River Valley National Historical Park Establishment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the Blackstone River Valley National Historical Park, to dedicate the Park to John H. Chafee, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412470"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400230" joined="2013-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2013-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400291" joined="2013-02-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-02-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18">
      <text>Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-09-18" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-12-22T16:15:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 113-687.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-12-22T16:15:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="518">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 518.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII10" subcommittee="Public Lands and Environmental Regulation" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3979"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="371"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="371"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Massachusetts"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Rhode Island"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/22/2014--Reported to House amended.
Blackstone River Valley National Historical Park Establishment Act - (Sec. 3) Establishes the Blackstone River Valley National Historical Park in Massachusetts and Rhode Island as a unit of the National Park System.

Requires the Secretary to prepare a general management plan for the Park that considers ways to use preexisting or planned visitor facilities and recreational opportunities developed in the John H. Chafee Blackstone River Valley National Heritage Corridor.

Dedicates the Park to former Senator John H. Chafee from Rhode Island in recognition of: (1) his role in the preservation of the resources of the Blackstone River Valley and the heritage corridor that bears his name, and (2) his decades of service to the people of Rhode Island and the United States.

Requires a memorial to be displayed at a location in the Park that recognizes Senator Chafee's role in the preservation of the resources of the Blackstone River Valley for the people of the United States.

Prohibits the use of condemnation to acquire land or interests in land under this Act. Prohibits anything in this Act from: (1) creating buffer zones outside the Park; or (2) restricting an activity because it can be seen, heard, or detected within the Park from being conducted outside its boundaries.</summary>
</bill>
