<bill session="113" type="h" number="2875" updated="2015-09-01T10:19:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Waterfront of Tomorrow Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize programs and activities for the improvement and protection of ports and harbors, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400416"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400366" joined="2013-08-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Financial Services, and Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Readiness.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW12" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW14" subcommittee="Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS03" subcommittee="Readiness" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Motor carriers"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="New York City"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Seashores and lakeshores"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2013--Introduced.
Waterfront of Tomorrow Act of 2013 - Directs the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, to study measures that provide the greatest flood protection and climate resilience for New York City coastal communities from a disaster such as Hurricane Sandy.

 Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to study the environmental impact of each major disaster that will have a significant environmental impact on U.S. waters.

Makes one of the goals of national freight policy to ensure that the socioeconomic and environmental impacts of moving cargo through a community are fully accounted for in establishing the national freight network (composed of highways, railways, navigable waterways, seaports, airports, freight intermodal connectors, and aerotropolis transportation systems most critical to the multimodal movement of freight).

Directs the Secretary of Transportation (DOT) to ensure that ports and harbors are incorporated into the national freight network.

Authorizes the Secretary of the Army to make grants to states and local governments for projects to improve port infrastructure and intermodal rail and highway networks.

Directs the Administrator of the Maritime Administration, acting jointly with the EPA Administrator, to establish a green port designation for ports that meet certain environmental standards.

Authorizes the Administrator of the Maritime Administration to provide grants and technical assistance to a designated green port to implement innovations that minimize the environmental impacts of port operations.

Directs the Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Administrator of the Economic Development Administration (EDA), to make grants to states and local governments for projects to establish environmentally sustainable waterfront areas. Sets the federal share of project costs at 75%.</summary>
</bill>
