<bill session="113" type="s" number="1778" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-12-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-12-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-12-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Kilah Davenport Child Protection Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Attorney General to report on State law penalties for certain child abusers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400054"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2014-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412324" joined="2014-01-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-12-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3627"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/9/2013--Introduced.
Kilah Davenport Child Protection Act of 2013 - Directs the Attorney General to report every 3 years to the House and Senate Judiciary Committees on the penalties for violations of laws prohibiting child abuse in each state (defined as each of the 50 states, the District of Columbia, and each U.S. territory), including whether the laws of each state provide for enhanced penalties when a victim suffers serious bodily injury or permanent or protracted loss or impairment of any mental or emotional function.

Amends the federal criminal code to apply certain increased criminal penalties against any person who commits domestic assault and who has a final conviction on at least two separate prior occasions under state, federal, or tribal court proceedings (an habitual offender) for offenses that would be, if subject to federal jurisdiction, assault, sexual abuse, or a serious violent felony against a spouse or intimate partner (as under current law) or against a child of, or in the care of, the person committing the offense.</summary>
</bill>
