<bill session="113" type="h" number="4764" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-05-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Verify It Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require Federal agencies to provide notice and consideration of evidence before submitting debts to the Secretary of the Treasury for collection through reduction of tax refunds, and to restore the 10-year statute of limitations applicable to collection of debt by administrative offset.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412479"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E865"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-29">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-29">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU05" subcommittee="Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4491"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Debt collection"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/29/2014--Introduced.
Verify It Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to prohibit a federal agency from notifying the Secretary of the Treasury of any past-due legally enforceable debt until such agency: (1)&#160;notifies by certified mail the person owing such debt that the agency proposes to notify the Secretary of the debt and gives such person at least 60 days to present evidence that such debt is not past-due or legally enforceable, (2) considers&#160;such evidence and determines that an amount of such debt is past-due and legally enforceable, and (3) satisfies any other conditions the Secretary may prescribe to ensure that the debt is valid and that the agency has made reasonable efforts to collect such debt.

Prohibits any administrative offset of a claim asserted by the federal government that has been outstanding for more than 10 years.</summary>
</bill>
