<bill session="113" type="h" number="4063" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-02-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-02-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-02-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Growing Small Businesses Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 to direct the Secretary of Labor to develop performance measures for individuals who receive entrepreneurial training as a part of any workforce investment activity, to create requirements for providers of workforce investment activities that offer entrepreneurial training, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412506"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412536" joined="2014-02-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-02-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Training" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Self-employed"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/14/2014--Introduced.
Growing Small Businesses Act of 2014 - Amends the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 to revise performance accountability system requirements for statewide and local workforce investment programs.

Directs the Secretary of Labor to develop separate performance measures for individuals who receive entrepreneurial training under such programs.

Requires providers of training services who offer entrepreneurial training services under a local workforce investment program for adults and dislocated workers to: (1) use intake tools that assess an individual's suitability for referral to entrepreneurial training services; (2) report to the local workforce investment board that includes the number of individuals who express interest in self-employment or starting a business and enroll entrepreneurial training services; and (3) develop partnerships with microbusiness development organizations that can provide education, training, counseling, and coaching focused on helping new and low and moderate income entrepreneurs succeed.</summary>
</bill>
