<bill session="113" type="h" number="3324" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-10-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-10-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Lacey Act Paperwork Reduction Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Lacey Act Amendments of 1981 to reduce burdensome paperwork, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412434"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412275" joined="2013-10-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-27">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII22" subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Horticulture and plants"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/23/2013--Introduced.
Lacey Act Paperwork Reduction Act - Amends the Lacey Act Amendments of 1981 to require any person, upon importation of any plant, to possess and have available for inspection by the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service (USFWS) a declaration that contains: (1) the scientific name of any plant (including the genus and species of the plant) contained in the importation; and (2) a description of the declared value of the plant or the merchandise containing the plant, the quantity of the plant, and the name of the country from which the plant was taken. (Currently, a person is required to file such a declaration that describes the value of the importation.)

Revises the rulemaking procedure applicable to such importation to authorize the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the USFWS and in consultation with the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service, to issue such regulations as may be necessary to carry out this Act. Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) distinguish among different species; and (2) limit the applicability of the Act to a particular class or type of species if the Secretary determines that application of this Act would not be feasible, practicable, or effective.</summary>
</bill>
