<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="HEB51CF914B9143DEA9B46ADA67A6D2AC" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HRES 759 IH: Recognizing Survivors Victory Day to celebrate and honor the victims and survivors of trauma.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2014-11-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 759</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20141119">November 19, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001051">Mr. Carter</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Recognizing Survivors Victory Day to celebrate and honor the victims and survivors of trauma.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas><text>Whereas, on November 19, 2002, Jessica Huber from Leander, Texas, was nearly killed after her
			 mother, while under the influence of prescription pain killers, narcotics,
			 and marijuana, ran a red light and crashed;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Jessica, as a result of her injuries, underwent multiple blood transfusions and surgeries;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, despite the extraordinary odds against her survival, Jessica is living a happy, healthy,
			 and productive life;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Jessica’s story is a poignant reminder of the thousands who have been victims and survivors
			 of trauma;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas stories of survivors of trauma remind us all of the indomitable nature of the human spirit
			 and our basic desire to persevere in the face of adversity; and</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in honor of Jessica Huber, November 19 is recognized as Survivors Victory Day: Now,
			 therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body id="HCD27817903BB4B73BA3640A1EDA58A6A" style="traditional">
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H75BFCA496B764FFCA0FBE65ED31C20BF" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives recognizes Survivors Victory Day to celebrate and honor the
			 victims and survivors of trauma.</text>
		</section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


