<bill session="113" type="h" number="3692" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-12-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-12-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-12-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Schools of the Future Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize a competitive grant program to implement and evaluate digital learning in rural locales.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412209"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-12-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/10/2013--Introduced.
Schools of the Future Act - Authorizes the Secretary of Education to award competitive three- to five-year grants to eligible partnerships to implement and evaluate the results of technology-based learning practices, strategies, tools, or courses at rural schools.

Defines "eligible partnerships" as those composed of a school partner, a digital learning partner, and an evaluation partner.

Describes a "school partner" as a: (1) local educational agency, (2) charter school network that does not include virtual schools, (3) consortium of public elementary or secondary schools, (4) regional educational service provider, or (5) consortium of such entities.

Describes a "digital learning partner" as an institution of higher education, a nonprofit organization, or an organization with school development or turnaround experience.

Includes among the grant-funded technology-based learning practices, strategies, tools, or courses, those that: (1) personalize the learning experience, (2) aid and inform instruction, (3) meet the needs of students with specific educational needs, (4) help students develop 21st century skills, and (5) give students access to courses that would otherwise be unavailable to them.

Requires each partnership's evaluation partner, after the third year of the grant, to evaluate the effect of the technology-based learning practices, strategies, tools, or courses on student achievement and its school partner's costs and savings.

Directs the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Institute of Education Sciences, to: (1) evaluate the implementation and impact of the activities supported by this Act's grants, (2) identify best practices, and (3) disseminate research on best practices in school leadership.</summary>
</bill>
