<bill session="113" type="h" number="3924" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-01-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-01-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-01-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Helping Owners Mitigate Effectively Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HOME Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To delay increases in premium rates for flood insurance coverage under the National Flood Insurance program, establish a refundable tax credit for flood mitigation expenses, and authorize increased funding for flood damage mitigation programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412530"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412385" joined="2014-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412529" joined="2014-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2014-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412527" joined="2014-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412412" joined="2014-05-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-01-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-17">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-17">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-17">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1268"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/17/2014--Introduced.
Helping Owners Mitigate Effectively Act of 2014 or the HOME Act of 2014 - Delays any change in risk premium rates for flood insurance under the National Flood Insurance Program resulting from amendments made by the Biggert-Waters Flood Insurance Reform Act of 2012 (Biggert-Waters Act)&#160;until five years after the enactment date&#160;of such Act.

Amends the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 to provide that the maximum annual chargeable flood insurance premium rate for a property shall be the appraised value of the property when purchased by its current owner divided by 30.

Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a tax credit of up to $7,500 for flood mitigation expenses in a taxable year for policy holders of flood insurance coverage and small businesses. Terminates such credit after December 31, 2022

Amends the Biggert-Waters Act to authorize the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to use any other amounts available to the Administrator to carry out the the study of participation in the National Flood Insurance Program and of the affordability of risk-based premiums under such Program.

Amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance&#160;Act to authorize increased appropriations for predisaster hazard mitigation for FY2014-FY2018.&#160; Authorizes appropriations for flood risk mitigation assistance for FY2014-FY2018.</summary>
</bill>
