<bill session="113" type="h" number="3736" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-12-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-12-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-12-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PACES Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protect Advanced Communications for Emergency Services Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide that certain uses of a patent or copyright in compliance with an order of the Federal Communications Commission for emergency communications services shall be construed as use or manufacture for the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400101"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412482" joined="2013-12-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-12-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, Intellectual Property, and the Internet.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts, Intellectual Property, and the Internet" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="s" number="1478"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/12/2013--Introduced.
Protect Advanced Communications for Emergency Services Act of 2013 or the PACES Act - Requires any patent infringement action against certain wireless carriers (excluding mobile satellite service operators) or IP-enabled voice service providers based on their use of technologies&#160;complying&#160;with&#160;requirements of the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to provide 9-1-1, enhanced 9-1-1, or other emergency communication services (such as the delivery of 9-1-1 calls with&#160;next generation text, picture, and video technologies capable of&#160;automatically&#160;identifying number and location information to emergency service personnel) to be filed in accordance with federal judicial code procedures under which a patent or copyright owner's remedy is by an action against the United States in the U.S. Court of Federal Claims. (Thus, specifies that such 9-1-1 services are provided by&#160;or for the United States with authorization or consent of the United States.)</summary>
</bill>
