<bill session="113" type="h" number="3316" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-10-29">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-10-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">GRANT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Grant Reform and New Transparency Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 31, United States Code, to provide transparency and require certain standards in the award of Federal grants, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412464"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400196" joined="2013-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412466" joined="2013-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412213" joined="2013-10-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-29">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-10-29" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 19 - 15.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, Markup"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Humanities programs funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Office of Management and Budget (OMB)"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/23/2013--Introduced.
Grant Reform and New Transparency Act of 2013 or the GRANT Act - Establishes new standards for awarding federal grants. Requires executive agencies to use merit-based selection procedures in awarding grants and to conduct an evaluation of the ability of a prospective grantee to successfully carry out a grant before awarding it.

Requires the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to: (1) upgrade any public website for finding federal grant opportunities so that such website serves as a central point of information for competitive grants, (2) issue and disseminate guidance to aid agencies in establishing merit-based selection procedures for grant programs and in identifying amounts of undisbursed funding remaining in grant accounts, and (3) submit a plan to improve the single audit process for auditing the financial statements and federal awards of a non-federal entity. Sets forth the information required to be included in the public grant website, including grant funds availability and grant award information. Requires agencies to explain to grant applicants the basis for award decisions involving grants exceeding $100,000.</summary>
</bill>
