<bill session="113" type="h" number="3559" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-11-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-11-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-11-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Entrepreneur-in-Residence Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a program to accelerate entrepreneurship and innovation by partnering world-class entrepreneurs with Federal agencies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400185"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2013-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412464" joined="2013-11-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-11-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/20/2013--Introduced.
Entrepreneur-in-Residence Act of 2013 - Directs the Director of the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) to establish an entrepreneur-in-residence program to appoint in-house entrepreneurs who have demonstrated success in working with business concerns and entrepreneurs to: (1) assist federal agencies in improving outreach to business concerns and entrepreneurs, (2) provide recommendations on inefficient or duplicative agency programs and on methods to improve agency efficiency, (3) facilitate meetings and forums to educate business concerns and entrepreneurs on agency programs and initiatives, and (4) provide technical assistance or mentorship. Limits to 10 the number of entrepreneurs-in-residence that the Director may appoint in any year.

Authorizes the Director to establish an informal working group to allow entrepreneurs-in-residence to meet to discuss best practices, experiences, and recommendations in order to create an informal knowledge base for current and future entrepreneurs-in-residence.

Terminates such program after FY2017.</summary>
</bill>
