<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 S230 IS: To authorize the Peace Corps Commemorative Foundation to establish a commemorative work in the District of Columbia and its environs, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2013-02-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 230</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20130207">February 7, 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S349">Mr. Portman</sponsor> (for himself
			 and <cosponsor name-id="S325">Mr. Udall of Colorado</cosponsor>) introduced the
			 following bill; which was read twice and referred to the
			 <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural
			 Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To authorize the Peace Corps Commemorative Foundation to
		  establish a commemorative work in the District of Columbia and its environs,
		  and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HBB775EACB419442CBF14CC45675B4981" style="OLC">
		<section id="H48F9C773B50045AD84ECECFA87C785C4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Memorial to Commemorate
			 America’s Commitment to International Service and Global Prosperity</header>
			<subsection id="ID7f5af39356364d9eb977d63dfc63e6d5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization
			 To establish commemorative work</header><text>The Peace Corps Commemorative
			 Foundation may establish a commemorative work on Federal land in the District
			 of Columbia and its environs to commemorate the mission of the Peace Corps and
			 the ideals on which the Peace Corps was founded.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H829BC2C92311467B9DC408E26FBF7022"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Compliance with
			 standards for Commemorative Works Act</header><text>The establishment of the
			 commemorative work under this section shall be in accordance with chapter 89 of
			 title 40, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Commemorative Works
			 Act</quote>).</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HC813DFFC6E06486C8C30DBED380F80EF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of Federal
			 funds prohibited</header>
				<paragraph id="id286F4B806EB24E7D996D5F5365FC1F2D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In
			 general</header><text>Federal funds may not be used to pay any expense of the
			 establishment of the commemorative work under this section.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="id8F61664F59CC4F34A7ED7F2924CAC6FF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Responsibility
			 of Peace Corps</header><text>The Peace Corps Commemorative Foundation shall be
			 solely responsible for acceptance of contributions for, and payment of the
			 expenses of, the establishment of the commemorative work under this
			 section.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1DC88B4BC8C74AA4BE59A3EFD8B6C779"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Deposit of
			 excess funds</header><text>If, on payment of all expenses for the establishment
			 of the commemorative work under this section (including the maintenance and
			 preservation amount required by <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/40/8906">section 8906(b)(1)</external-xref> of title 40, United States
			 Code), or on expiration of the authority for the commemorative work under
			 <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/40/8903">section 8903(e)</external-xref> of title 40, United States Code, there remains a balance of
			 funds received for the establishment of the commemorative work, the Peace Corps
			 Commemorative Foundation shall transmit the amount of the balance to the
			 Secretary of the Interior for deposit in the account provided for in section
			 8906(b)(3) of title 40, United States Code.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H62D45CC518B14D27922DCEAF83B796F7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Budgetary
			 effects</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The budgetary effects
			 of this Act, for the purpose of complying with the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act
			 of 2010, shall be determined by reference to the latest statement titled
			 <quote>Budgetary Effects of PAYGO Legislation</quote> for this Act, submitted
			 for printing in the Congressional Record by the Chairman of the Senate Budget
			 Committee, provided that such statement has been submitted prior to the vote on
			 passage.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


