<bill session="113" type="h" number="5791" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-12-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-12-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-12-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FINER Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fines in Need of Extensive Reform Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To increase transparency and provide for judicial review of administrative fines, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412568"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412508" joined="2014-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412388" joined="2014-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412550" joined="2014-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400247" joined="2014-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412475" joined="2014-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412569" joined="2014-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400320" joined="2014-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412489" joined="2014-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400341" joined="2014-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412426" joined="2014-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412314" joined="2014-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412596" joined="2014-12-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-12-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-04">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-04">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU05" subcommittee="Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Alternative dispute resolution, mediation, arbitration"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/4/2014--Introduced.
Fines in Need of Extensive Reform Act of 2014 or the FINER Act of 2014 - Prohibits federal agency rules that provide for an assessment of an administrative fine from taking effect until 90 days after the rule and relevant rule guidance is made available on the agency's website.

Establishes procedures for enforcement of, and challenges to, administrative fines to: (1) prohibit fine assessments unless a particular officer or employee of the agency is responsible for assessing the fine, (2) allow persons to challenge the imposition of a fine in federal court or through alternative dispute resolution by a neutral third party, and (3) require rule violations to be dismissed if the agency officer or employee who assessed the fine is not present in court for any proceedings contesting the fine.

 Requires agencies to publish annually in the Federal Register guidance for any rules for which they may assess an administrative fine.

Allows a person who prevails in contesting a fine to recover reasonable court costs and attorney's fees.

Provides for fine amounts to be deposited into the Treasury. Prohibits fines from being used to supplement or offset the appropriations of the agency that assessed the fine.

Excludes user fees, criminal fines or penalties, or court-imposed fines from the requirements applicable to administrative fines.</summary>
</bill>
