<bill session="113" type="h" number="3415" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-10-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-10-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pinyon-Juniper Related Projects Implementation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To facilitate planning, permitting, administration, implementation, and monitoring of pinyon-juniper dominated landscape restoration projects within Lincoln County, Nevada, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412559"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412500" joined="2013-10-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="Public Lands and Environmental Regulation" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="s" number="1640"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/30/2013--Introduced.
Pinyon-Juniper Related Projects Implementation Act - Amends the Lincoln County Land Act of 2000 (the Act) to require implementation of a multispecies habitat conservation plan in Lincoln County, Nevada.

Amends the Act and the Lincoln County Conservation, Recreation, and Development Act of 2004 to make certain amounts available for: (1) pinyon-juniper dominated landscape restoration projects within the county, consistent with the Ely Resource Management Plan; and (2) completing specified plans and activities.

Declares that establishment and funding of cooperative agreements between the BLM and Lincoln County shall be required for certain county-provided law enforcement and planning related activities.

Requires the use of a portion of proceeds from land sales under both Acts for economic development in Lincoln County.

Excludes specified public land within certain utility corridors in Lincoln and Clark Counties, Nevada, from being withdrawn from public land, mining, and mineral leasing and geothermal leasing laws.</summary>
</bill>
