<bill session="113" type="h" number="5149" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Smart Water Management Conservation and Efficiency Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for a smart water management pilot program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412189"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412421" joined="2014-07-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Science, Space, and Technology, Natural Resources, and Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-17">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-17">
      <text>Referred to House Science, Space, and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-17">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-17">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and the Economy.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF18" subcommittee="Environment and the Economy" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY20" subcommittee="Energy" name="House Science, Space, and Technology"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2225"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/17/2014--Introduced.
Smart Water Management Conservation and Efficiency Act of 2014 - Directs the Secretary of Energy (DOE) to establish and carry out a smart water management pilot program to award grants to three to five eligible entities (authorities that provide drinking water, wastewater treatment, or water reuse services) to demonstrate and deploy novel and innovative technology-based solutions that will: (1) increase the energy and water efficiency of drinking water, wastewater treatment, and water reuse systems; (2) improve such systems to help communities make significant progress in conserving water, saving energy, and reducing costs; and (3) support the implementation of innovative processes and the installation of advanced automated systems that provide real-time data on energy and water.

Directs the Secretary, in selecting grant recipient, to consider:

 energy and cost savings; the novelty of the technology to be used; the degree to which the project integrates next-generation sensors, software, analytics, and management tools; the anticipated cost-effectiveness of the pilot project in terms of energy efficiency savings, water savings or reuse, and infrastructure costs averted; whether the technology can be deployed in a variety of geographic regions and the degree to which the technology can be implemented on a smaller or larger scale; and whether the project will be completed in five years or less. Requires the Secretary to evaluate, annually, each project for which a grant is provided and make best practices identified available to the public.</summary>
</bill>
