<bill session="113" type="h" number="4591" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-05-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Workforce Investment and Job Creation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a national strategy for identifying job training needs to increase opportunities for technical school training and promote hiring.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400628"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-07">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-07">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Training" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4541"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1619"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/7/2014--Introduced.
Workforce Investment and Job Creation Act - Directs the Secretary of Labor to develop a strategy report to address the skills gap by providing analysis and recommendations to increase on-the-job training and apprenticeship opportunities, identify industry-recognized postsecondary credentials that are nationally portable and aligned with in-demand occupations in industries such as construction, manufacturing, and others that are emerging, and increase employer participation in education and workforce training.

Defines the term "skills gap" as the difference, or gap, between the current supply of labor and skills of the workforce and that which is desired by employers.

Amends the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 to require the Secretary of Labor to award competitive grants to states to provide funds to local boards for provision of technical school training subsidies in local areas through one-stop delivery systems to pay tuition costs for the career and technical education of unemployed individuals enrolled or accepted at a technical school. Limits the aggregate amount of subsidies to an individual to $2,000.

Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow employers a refundable tax credit for: (1) 60% of the excess of the aggregate wages paid to their employees in 2014 over the aggregate wages paid them in 2013, and (2) 40% of the excess of such wages paid during 2015 over the aggregate inflation-adjusted wages paid during 2014. Limits the maximum amount of such credit to $500,000 in any calendar year.</summary>
</bill>
