<bill session="113" type="hr" number="591" updated="2015-09-01T10:18:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Commending the Government of Afghanistan for certifying the results of the national election held on April 5, 2014, and urging the Government of Afghanistan to continue to pursue a "transparent, credible, and inclusive" run-off presidential election on June 14, 2014, while ensuring the safety of voters and candidates.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412276"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Political movements and philosophies"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="Voting rights"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/21/2014--Introduced.
Commends the government of Afghanistan for holding the first round of a presidential election on April 5, 2014, and for preparing for the peaceful transition to a new government.

Encourages the government of Afghanistan to implement measures that will increase voter participation, particularly among the Afghan female population.

Salutes the bravery of the Afghan citizenry in facing violence and death to exercise their right to vote.

Encourages all elements of Afghan society to restrain themselves and their supporters from fomenting disturbances in voting areas.

Advises that the Ministry of Communications leave texting capabilities functional on election day.

Commends the Afghan government for reducing the number of casualties on election day, and urges the Afghan National Security Forces (ANSF) to continue efforts to ensure the safety of voters and candidates.

Remembers those members of the ANSF who gave their lives protecting their democracy on April 5, 2014, and honors service members from U.S., coalition, and Afghan forces who have been killed or injured in defense of the democratic rights of the Afghan people.

Supports the U.N. mandate to assist Afghan electoral bodies and other stakeholders with technical preparations and the promotion of an inclusive democratic process.

Recommends a pause in the drawdown of U.S. and International Security Assistance Force security, intelligence, and diplomatic assets until June 14, 2014.

Recognizes the substantial investments made by U.S. taxpayers in support of democracy in Afghanistan.

Reaffirms the U.S. policy position that successful political transition is an essential prerequisite for sustainable security in Afghanistan.

Concurs in the Senate's urging of the Secretary of State to condition financial and logistical support for future Afghanistan elections on the implementation of reforms that would increase female participation and combat fraud throughout the electoral process.</summary>
</bill>
