<bill session="113" type="h" number="4339" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-03-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-03-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-03-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pipeline Revolving Fund and Job Creation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish State revolving loan funds to repair or replace natural gas distribution pipelines.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400333"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2014-03-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-03-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-27">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-27">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW14" subcommittee="Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="s" number="1768"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1768"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Buy American requirements"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/27/2014--Introduced.
Pipeline Revolving Fund and Job Creation Act - Directs the Administrator of the Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration to offer to enter into agreements to make capitalization grants, including letters of credit, to eligible states for the repair or replacement of natural gas distribution pipelines.

Requires grant funds to be deposited into state revolving loan funds to provide loans or loan guarantees to: (1) facilitate compliance with an intended use plan, or (2) repair or replace those pipelines that have been identified as leak-prone.

Prohibits the use of funds from loans or loan guarantees made by a state to repair or replace natural gas distribution pipelines unless all of the iron, steel, plastic, and manufactured goods used in the repair or replacement are produced in the United States (Buy America).</summary>
</bill>
