<bill session="113" type="h" number="4804" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-11">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-06-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bureau Examination Fairness Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010 to provide requirements that must be followed by the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection when carrying out certain examinations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412474"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-06-11" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 33 - 26.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, Markup"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Consumer Financial Protection Bureau"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/5/2014--Introduced.
Bureau Examination Fairness Act - Amends the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010 to prohibit the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB) from including enforcement attorneys when examining entities under its jurisdiction.

Requires the CFPB, when requesting data from such entities, to: (1) ensure that the different divisions of the CFPB coordinate with each other before the data is requested, (2) accompany each request with a written statement of its intended use, and (3) use peer-reviewed data sampling based upon limited data sets rather than requesting full data sets (unless the Director determines, in writing, that requesting full data sets is necessary).

Directs the CFPB also, with respect to a data request whose cost of compliance is anticipated to exceed $50,000 per company, to give the entity the Director's written approval for the request.

Requires the CFPB to: (1) complete examination field work and conduct an exit interview with the entity being examined within 60 days after the examination begins, and (2) produce a report of examination or supervisory letter within 120 days after the examination is completed.

Restricts the CFPB to performing only one limited-scope examination of an entity at any one time.</summary>
</bill>
