<bill session="113" type="s" number="1593" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-11-19">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-11-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Servicemember Housing Protection Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act to enhance the protections accorded to servicemembers and their spouses with respect to mortgages, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300081"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2013-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2013-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2013-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2013-10-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7579-7580"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-30">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 113-280.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-11-19" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1982"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2413"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/28/2013--Introduced.
Servicemember Housing Protection Act of 2013 - Amends the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act to protect a surviving spouse who is the successor in interest to a servicemember who dies from a service-connected cause while in military service against a mortgage foreclosure or residential lease termination. Extends such protection for the one-month period following the death of the servicemember.

Allows the termination of an existing lease by the lessee, without penalties, when the lessee is assigned to or otherwise relocates to federal quarters or military housing. Requires, in such case, the lessee to deliver to the lessor written notice of such termination and a letter from the servicemember's commanding officer indicating such relocation.</summary>
</bill>
