<bill session="113" type="s" number="2380" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Freight Priorities Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 49, United States Code, to improve the national freight policy of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412598"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3241"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Motor carriers"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Urban and suburban affairs and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/21/2014--Introduced.
Freight Priorities Act - Declares the policy, objectives, and goals of the United States for improving the efficiency, operation, and security of the national freight network by leveraging investments and promoting partnerships that accomplish specified results.

Requires metropolitan planning organizations to involve public port authorities in metropolitan freight transportation planning.

Authorizes the Secretary of Transportation (DOT) to establish: (1) measures to assess the performance of a multimodal freight network in accordance with the national freight strategic plan, and (2) a pilot program for up to five urbanized areas to develop and deploy one or more pilot measures and targets to improve multimodal freight movement in densely populated and congested urban areas.

Directs the Secretary to: (1) establish and support a national cooperative freight transportation research program, and (2) offer to enter into an agreement with the Transportation Research Board of the National Research Council of the National Academies to support and carry out administrative and management activities relating to governance of the research program.

Requires the National Academies to select an advisory committee consisting of a representative cross-section of freight stakeholders, which shall recommend a national research agenda for the program.</summary>
</bill>
