<bill session="113" type="h" number="4024" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-02-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-02-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-02-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ensuring Access to Clean Water Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To protect navigable waters from contamination by chemical storage facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400061"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-02-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1961"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/10/2014--Introduced.
Ensuring Access to Clean Water Act of 2014 - Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act) to direct the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) or a state exercising primary enforcement responsibility for National Pollutant Discharge Elimination System permit programs to carry out a state chemical storage facility source water protection program.

Requires such a program to provide for oversight and inspection of each covered chemical storage facility in accordance with minimum requirements, described in this Act, to prevent the release of chemicals into a navigable water that is designated for use as a domestic water source. Defines "covered chemical storage facility" as a facility at which a chemical is stored and from which a release is determined to pose a risk of harm to such source.

Prohibits this Act from precluding or denying the right of any state to adopt or enforce standards for the oversight and inspection of covered chemical storage facilities that are more stringent than this Act's minimum requirements.

Requires the Administrator to report on a survey of states' best practices in oversight and inspection programs and applicable regulations implementing the programs.

Authorizes the issuance of orders by the Administrator to carry out this Act.

Authorizes an owner or operator of a public water system to commence, or to petition the Administrator to commence, a civil action for equitable relief to address possible imminent and substantial endangerment to the health of persons supplied by the water system. Provides a special rule to expedite the Administrator's response to a petition in emergency situations.

Sets forth requirements concerning: (1) liability of a facility owner or operator for costs of response actions, (2) pre-transfer inspections of facilities, and (3) information for operators of domestic water systems on navigable waters regarding emergency response plans and chemical inventories.

Establishes a civil penalty of up to $15,000 for each day in which an owner or operator of a covered facility violates this Act.</summary>
</bill>
