<bill session="113" type="s" number="2408" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-05-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">No Surface Occupancy Western Arctic Coastal Plain Domestic Energy Security Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the exploration, leasing, development, and production of oil and gas in and from the western portion of the Coastal Plain of the State of Alaska without surface occupancy, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300075"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2014-06-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3298-3299"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="49"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2674"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3033"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4286"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2170"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2409"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Arctic Ocean"/>
    <term name="Arctic and polar regions"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Energy revenues and royalties"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Labor-management relations"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/22/2014--Introduced.
No Surface Occupancy Western Arctic Coastal Plain Domestic Energy Security Act - Authorizes the exploration, leasing, development and production of oil and gas on the Western Coastal Plain of Alaska.

Directs the Secretary of the Interior to: (1) establish a competitive oil and gas leasing program for oil and gas exploration, development, and production on the Western Coastal Plain; and (2) prohibit surface occupancy of the Western Coastal Plain during any oil and gas development and production

States that, in connection with specified environmental protection laws, the Secretary shall neither: (1) identify nonleasing alternative courses of action, nor (2) analyze the environmental effect of those courses of action.

Requires the Secretary, within one year after the first lease sale is conducted under this Act, to conduct a second lease sale (and additional sales if sufficient interest in exploration or development exists).

Sets forth procedures for: (1) lease sales and lease grants on the Western Coastal Plain, and (2) Western Coastal Plain environmental protection.

Prescribes a revenue allocation scheme derived from bonus, rental, and royalty revenues from federal oil and gas leasing and operations authorized under this Act, including monthly payments to the state of Alaska.

Requires the Secretary to convey to: (1) the Kaktovik Inupiat Corporation the surface estate of certain land, and (2) the Arctic Slope Regional Corporation the remaining subsurface estate to which that Corporation is entitled under a specified agreement.</summary>
</bill>
