<bill session="113" type="h" number="2158" updated="2015-09-01T10:19:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-16">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-07-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Expedited Departure of Certain Snake Species Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Expedited Departure of Certain Snake Species Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To exempt from the Lacey Act Amendments of 1981 the expedited removal from the United States of certain snake species, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412275"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-25">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-16">
      <text>Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-16">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-07-16" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-09-15T16:39:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 113-596.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-09-15T16:40:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="443">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 443.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII22" subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Pest management"/>
    <term name="Reptiles"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/23/2013--Introduced.
Expedited Departure of Certain Snake Species Act - Eases restrictions on transporting invasive animals under the Lacey Act Amendments of 1981 for the transport of the Burmese python, Indian python, Northern African python, Southern African python, and Yellow anaconda. Allows an intermediate stop during the transport of those snakes if: (1) the stop is made in a designated airport in the course of transport that begins at a designated airport and ends at a place outside of the United States no later than 48 hours after the transport begins, (2) the transport does not include a stop in Hawaii, and (3) the snake is in a secure container during transport.

Allows the stop to include a: (1) stop at an airport that is not a designated airport to refuel or take on additional cargo or passenger, or (2) a transfer of the container in an airport between aircraft used to transport of the snake outside of the United States.</summary>
</bill>
