<bill session="113" type="s" number="1921" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-01-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-01-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-01-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Taxpayer Transparency Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require a Federal agency to include language in certain educational and advertising materials indicating that such materials are produced and disseminated at taxpayer expense.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400034"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2014-01-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412496" joined="2014-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400222" joined="2014-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412491" joined="2014-01-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-01-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3308"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/14/2014--Introduced.
Taxpayer Transparency Act of 2013 - Requires each communication funded by a federal agency for advertising or educational purposes to clearly state: (1) in the case of a printed communication, including mass mailings, signs, and billboards, that the communication is printed and published at taxpayer expense; and (2) in the case of a communication transmitted through radio, television, or the Internet, that the communication is produced and disseminated at taxpayer expense. Requires any such printed communication, including e-mails, to be of sufficient size to be clearly readable, to be set apart from the other contents of the communication, and to be printed with a reasonable degree of color contrast between the background and the printed statement. Exempts from such requirements: (1) information in or relating to a solicitation for offers for a federal contract or applications or submissions of a bid or proposal for a federal grant or other means of funding under a federal program; and (2) advertisements for employment opportunities, not including advertising materials developed for use in recruiting and retaining personnel for the Armed Forces.</summary>
</bill>
