<bill session="113" type="h" number="3956" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-01-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-01-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-01-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Community Investment and Empowerment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 to authorize the Small Business Administrator to make grants for economic growth, business retention and business recruitment to economically underserved communities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412535" joined="2014-03-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-01-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Property tax"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/28/2014--Introduced.
Community Investment and Empowerment Act - Amends the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 to authorize the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) to make grants on a competitive basis to communities for: the creation of a grant and/or revolving loan fund program that helps develop financing packages for Class 1 commercial investment (defined as retail grocery chains, food service retailers, restaurants and franchises, retail stores, cafes, shopping malls, and other shops); lowering real estate property tax rates; conducting community-wide market analysis to help recruit and/or retain Class 1 commercial investment; creating employment training programs for Class 1 business customer service, sales, and managerial positions; retail marketing strategies to solicit new Class 1 commercial investment starts in the community; program allowances for activities such as the publication of marketing materials, development of economic development web pages, and educational outreach activities with retail trade associations; and hiring business recruitment specialists. Authorizes the Administrator to only make such a grant to communities: (1) whose demographics include a median per capita income no higher than $35,000 and a lack of Class 1 commercial investment; (2) that submit an application that describes the activities the community carries out, and the difficulty the community has faced, to recruit, retain and grow their economy through Class 1 commercial investment; and (3) that agree to match 10% of grant funds with certain non-federal contributions. Allows the Administrator to waive or reduce the non-federal contribution if the community involved demonstrates that it cannot meet the contribution requirement due to financial hardship.</summary>
</bill>
