<bill session="113" type="s" number="2274" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-04-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-04-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to expedite decisions on applications for authorization to export natural gas, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400412"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2014-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412554" joined="2014-04-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="6"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2494"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2638"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/30/2014--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of Energy (DOE) to issue a decision on an application for authorization to export natural gas within 90 days after the later of: (1) the end of the comment period for that decision as set forth in the Federal Register, or (2) the date of enactment of this Act.

Grants original and exclusive jurisdiction to the U.S. Court of Appeals for the circuit in which the export facility under an application will be located over any civil action for the review of: (1) an order by the Secretary about the application, or (2) the&#160; failure of the Secretary to issue a decision on the application.

Requires the Court, if it finds in a civil action that the Secretary has failed to issue a decision on an application, to order the Secretary to issue one within 30 days.

Requires the Court to set any civil action brought under this Act on the docket, for expedited consideration, as soon as practical after the filing date of the initial pleading.</summary>
</bill>
