<bill session="113" type="h" number="3750" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-12-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-12-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-12-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Telehealth Modernization Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To promote the provision of telehealth by establishing a Federal standard for telehealth, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400663"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412563" joined="2014-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2014-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412257" joined="2014-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412460" joined="2013-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412583" joined="2014-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412293" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412308" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412315" joined="2014-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412319" joined="2014-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412538" joined="2014-11-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-12-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/12/2013--Introduced.
Telehealth Modernization Act of 2013 - Calls for states to authorize health care professionals to deliver health care to individuals through telehealth and to consider adopting conditions under which such a professional should:

 have access to the individual's medical history and should review it with the individual as if delivering the health care in person; attempt to identify any conditions underlying the symptoms reported by the individual before providing any diagnosis or treatment and, if recommending a treatment, should review with the individual the contraindications to such treatment; have a conversation with the individual adequate to establish any diagnosis rendered; document any evaluation and treatment delivered to the individual for the purpose of generating a medical record of the encounter; provide to the individual information regarding the professional's health care education, certification, and credentials; offer no assurance to the individual that any item or service will be issued or provided in exchange for the payment of the consultation fee or solely in response to the individual completing a form or questionnaire; and issue, as part of the health care delivered, only a prescription that is issued for a legitimate medical purpose in the usual course of professional practice, that is issued by a health care professional who has obtained a medical history and conducted an evaluation adequate to establish a diagnosis, that is not for a drug or substance in schedule II, III, or IV of the Controlled Substances Act, and that is filled by a licensed dispensing entity.</summary>
</bill>
