<bill session="113" type="h" number="4065" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-02-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-02-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-02-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Smartphone Theft Prevention Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require mobile service providers and mobile device manufacturers to give consumers the ability to remotely delete data from mobile devices and render such devices inoperable.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400366"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400031" joined="2014-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="2014-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400130" joined="2014-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412276" joined="2014-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2014-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400163" joined="2014-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400641" joined="2014-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400230" joined="2014-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412297" joined="2014-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2014-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400271" joined="2014-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400309" joined="2014-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2014-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="2014-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="2014-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412522" joined="2014-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400416" joined="2014-03-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-02-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF16" subcommittee="Communications and Technology" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="s" number="2032"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Crimes against property"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission (FCC)"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/14/2014--Introduced.
Smartphone Theft Prevention Act - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to require commercial mobile service providers to make available on mobile devices a function that an account holder may use remotely to: (1) delete or render inaccessible all information relating to the account holder that has been placed on the device; (2) render the device inoperable on the global networks of such service providers, even if the device is turned off or has the data storage medium removed; (3) prevent the device from being reactivated or reprogrammed without a passcode or similar authorization after the device has been rendered inoperable or has been subject to an unauthorized factory reset; and (4) reverse any such actions if the device is recovered by the account holder.

Prohibits a mobile device from being manufactured in the United States or imported into the United States for sale or resale to the public, unless the device is configured in such a manner that a service provider may make such remote deletion and inoperability functions available on the device.

Allows the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to waive such requirements with respect to any low-cost mobile device that: (1) is intended primarily for voice-only mobile service, and (2) may have limited data consumption functions focused on text messaging or short message service.

Prohibits service providers from charging a fee for making such remote deletion and inoperability functions available.</summary>
</bill>
