<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HFBA7EE54A5874E9B8EBB8C63A1351E3F" public-private="public" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>90 HR 1241 : To facilitate a land exchange involving certain National Forest System lands in the Inyo National Forest, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2013-12-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code><congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>H. R. 1241</legis-num><current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20131209">December 9, 2013</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To facilitate a land exchange involving certain National Forest System lands in the Inyo National Forest, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H894AF54D86554C5880339FFFA94549EE" style="OLC"><section id="HFF0720BA8C014555A2781CA9E3B54FC4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Special rules for Inyo National Forest land exchange</header><subsection id="H69CE744D1D084048B29593A978760359"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority To accept lands outside boundaries of Inyo National Forest</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any land exchange involving the conveyance of certain National Forest System land located within the boundaries of Inyo National Forest in California, as shown on the map titled <quote>Federal Parcel</quote> and dated June 2011, the Secretary of Agriculture may accept for acquisition in the exchange certain non-Federal lands in California lying outside the boundaries of Inyo National Forest, as shown on the maps titled <quote>DWP Parcel – Interagency Visitor Center Parcel</quote> and <quote>DWP Parcel – Town of Bishop Parcel</quote> and dated June 2011, if the Secretary determines that acquisition of the non-Federal lands is desirable for National Forest System purposes.</text></subsection><subsection id="H60E0768994E74A0CAF3462ACF6D0E229"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Cash equalization payment; use</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In an exchange described in subsection (a), the Secretary of Agriculture may accept a cash equalization payment in excess of 25 percent. Any such cash equalization payment shall be deposited into the account in the Treasury of the United States established by <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/90/171">Public Law 90–171</external-xref> (commonly known as the Sisk Act; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/484a">16 U.S.C. 484a</external-xref>) and shall be made available to the Secretary for the acquisition of land for addition to the National Forest System.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2D26640C8EE5403CA2D465671A6E8AA4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to grant the Secretary of Agriculture new land exchange authority. This section modifies the use of land exchange authorities already available to the Secretary as of the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date chamber="House" date="20131203">Passed the House of Representatives December 3, 2013.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk</role></attestation-group></attestation></bill>


