<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 S2928 IS: To prohibit the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission from issuing certain decisions that will raise costs for ratepayers, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2014-11-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>113th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 2928</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20141113">November 13, 2014</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S270">Mr. Schumer</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To prohibit the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission from issuing certain decisions that will raise
			 costs for ratepayers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HEB7757C927A14644B0FD181F09F9E2BA" style="OLC"><section id="H62039B09C960445BBB4041F32F16257A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Prohibition against certain FERC decisions that will raise costs for ratepayers</header><subsection id="HAB2C6AF846934E08B682010B253DFAFA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Cost-Benefit analysis</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prior to issuing a decision described in subsection (b), the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission
			 shall publish a cost-benefit analysis of such decision, including the
			 likely financial impact of such decision on ratepayers.</text></subsection><subsection id="HAED5521F6EEE45D484B6F673FB94147C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Decisions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section applies to any decision by the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission that will—</text><paragraph id="HB371EDE60BC94199BA02591E5597A79D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>authorize the creation of a new capacity zone; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H81A7C85C0120427EAA5C8EC24D8608D7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>affect the supply and demand curves or models used to determine prices at points in a capacity
			 zone.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3E020AD789EA4F1CA2A7804B278ABA51"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission determines, through a cost-benefit analysis published
			 under subsection (a), that a decision described in subsection (b) will
			 raise costs for ratepayers, then the Commission may not issue such
			 decision.</text></subsection><subsection id="idDA572962213A40AFA08CBA4ED2AE172E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section takes effect on January 1, 2014.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


