<bill session="113" type="s" number="2703" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Military SAFE Standards Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish eligibility, assignment, training, and certification requirements for sexual assault forensic examiners for the Armed Forces, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300011"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2014-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/2014--Introduced.
Military SAFE Standards Act - Requires sexual assault forensic examiners (SAFEs) for the Armed Forces to be members of the Armed Forces and civilian personnel of the Department of Defense (DOD) or the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) who are physicians, nurse practitioners, nurse midwives, physician assistants, or registered nurses. Permits an independent duty corpsman or equivalent to be assigned as a SAFE if the assignment of such a physician, assistant, or nurse is impracticable.

Directs the DOD and DHS Secretaries to: (1) assign at least one SAFE at each military medical treatment facility in the United States and overseas; or (2) enter into agreements with facilities with appropriate resources for the provision of sexual assault forensic examinations for the Armed Forces. Requires at least one SAFE to be assigned to each naval vessel.

Requires the Secretary concerned to establish a SAFE certification program that includes training in sexual assault forensic examinations.</summary>
</bill>
