<bill session="113" type="h" number="4077" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-02-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-02-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-02-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Quality Health Care Coalition Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure and foster continued patient safety and quality of care by clarifying the application of the antitrust laws to negotiations between groups of health care professionals and health plans and health care insurance issuers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400080"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412436" joined="2014-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412276" joined="2014-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412511" joined="2014-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400626" joined="2014-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412314" joined="2014-06-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-02-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU05" subcommittee="Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2300"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1851"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Competition and antitrust"/>
    <term name="Contracts and agency"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/25/2014--Introduced.
Quality Health Care Coalition Act of 2014 - Exempts health care professionals, including individuals and entities, from federal and state antitrust laws in connection with negotiations with a health plan regarding contract terms under which the professionals provide health care items or services for which plan benefits are provided.

Declares that this Act: (1) applies only to health care professionals excluded from the National Labor Relations Act; and (2) does not apply to such negotiations relating to Medicare or Medicaid programs, the Children's Health Insurance Program (CHIP, formerly known as SCHIP), medical and dental care for members of the uniformed services, veterans' medical care, the federal employees health benefits program, or the Indian Health Care Improvement Act.</summary>
</bill>
