<bill session="113" type="s" number="2650" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Iran Nuclear Negotiations Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for congressional review of agreements relating to Iran's nuclear program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412248"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412251" joined="2014-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2014-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="2014-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="2014-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412494" joined="2014-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412496" joined="2014-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="2014-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400284" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412322" joined="2014-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="2014-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412491" joined="2014-07-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-23">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4767, S4768-4769, S4769-4770"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/23/2014--Introduced.
Iran Nuclear Negotiations Act of 2014 - Directs the President, within three days after entering into a U.S.-Iran agreement relating to Iran's nuclear program, to submit such agreement to Congress.

Provides for: (1) a 15-day review period by the Senate Committee on Foreign Relations and the House Committee on Foreign Affairs, and (2) a subsequent 15-day period in which a joint resolution of disapproval may be introduced in the House and in the Senate for expedited consideration.

Prohibits the use of any Department of State funds available for obligation to implement a nuclear program agreement with Iran, including any related sanctions reduction, if: (1) the President fails to submit the agreement to Congress, or (2) a joint resolution of disapproval is enacted into law.

Provides that:

 if any element of the intelligence community receives information from a reputable source that Iran has failed to comply with the terms of the Joint Plan of Action, or any other agreement related to Iran's nuclear program, the Director of National Intelligence shall determine within 10 days whether the information is credible and accurate, and submit it to Congress; and upon the Director's determination of the information's credibility and accuracy, any sanctions on Iran that have been waived, suspended, or otherwise reduced in connection with Iran's nuclear program shall be reinstated within five days. Reinstates by action of law on November 28, 2014, any sanctions on Iran that have been waived, suspended, or otherwise reduced in connection with Iran's nuclear program, unless before that date the President submits to Congress a comprehensive and long-term agreement that: (1) addresses all key aspects of Iran's nuclear program, and (2) is significantly longer in duration than any previous U.S.-Iran nuclear agreement.</summary>
</bill>
