<bill session="113" type="s" number="2786" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Corporate Inverters Earnings Stripping Reform Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to prevent earnings stripping of domestic corporations which are members of a worldwide group of corporations which includes an inverted corporation and to require agreements with respect to certain related party transactions with those members.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300087"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400013" joined="2014-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2014-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2014-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412390" joined="2014-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2014-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="2014-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2014-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2014-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2014-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300078" joined="2014-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300081" joined="2014-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2014-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2014-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412542" joined="2014-09-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/10/2014--Introduced.
Corporate Inverters Earnings Stripping Reform Act of 2014 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to impose limitations on the tax deduction for interest paid by corporations which are designated as applicable entities (i.e., members of an expanded affiliated group which includes a surrogate foreign corporation which is not treated as a domestic corporation). Prohibits such an entity from claiming a tax deduction for interest that exceeds 25% of its adjusted taxable income and from carrying forward interest which is paid or accrued during the first year in which such entity becomes an applicable entity.

Requires an applicable entity to file an annual application for an approval agreement (i.e., a prefiling, advance pricing, or other agreement involving a related-party transaction) with the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) during the 10-year period after it becomes an applicable entity.</summary>
</bill>
