<bill session="113" type="h" number="5710" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-11-20">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-11-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-11-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ebola Emergency Response Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the provision of assistance on an emergency basis for countries affected by or at risk of being affected by the outbreak of the Ebola virus disease to effectively address such outbreak at its source, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400380"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412404" joined="2014-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412512" joined="2014-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400130" joined="2014-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412552" joined="2014-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400371" joined="2014-11-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-11-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-19">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1632"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-20">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-11-20" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans and debt"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Guinea"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Homelessness and emergency shelter"/>
    <term name="Immunology and vaccination"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Liberia"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Reconstruction and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Sierra Leone"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/14/2014--Introduced.
Ebola Emergency Response Act - Expresses the sense of Congress that:

 the Ebola virus outbreak in West Africa poses severe health, economic, and security threats to the affected countries, the United States, and the broader international community; and the whole-of-government response taken by the United States provides capabilities critical to helping contain Ebola in West Africa; yet the United States alone will not succeed in containing it. Directs the President to:

 coordinate with the governments of affected African countries, the private sector, regional and international financial institutions and international organizations, civil society, and nongovernmental organizations to implement a comprehensive Ebola control strategy and assist affected populations; and use U.S. influence at the United Nations (U.N.) to ensure that the U.N. Mission in Liberia is protecting individuals under its care and playing an active emergency response role, and ensuring that the U.N. Mission for the Ebola Emergency Response (UNMEER) is playing an effective role in aligning donors around a plan to detect, contain, treat, and deter Ebola's further spread. Authorizes the President to provide specified emergency assistance to countries directly affected by or at imminent risk of being affected by the Ebola outbreak.

Expresses the sense of Congress that the President should work with other donors, including international financial institutions, to encourage them to: (1) help the governments of Guinea, Liberia, and Sierra Leone mitigate the risks of economic collapse and related civil unrest by providing access to emergency grants and financing tools to address fiscal issues that are the direct result of the Ebola crisis; and (2) assist with post-crisis economic recovery.</summary>
</bill>
