<bill session="113" type="sr" number="375" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-03-13">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-03-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution concerning the crisis in the Central African Republic and supporting United States and international efforts to end the violence, protect civilians, and address root causes of the conflict.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412390"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400134" joined="2014-03-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-03-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1325" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-03-11" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-03-11">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Menendez with an amendment and with an amended preamble. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-03-11" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="324">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 324.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2014-03-13" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>Resolution agreed to in Senate with an amendment and an amended preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1668-1669" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S1668-1669" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Central African Republic"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="France"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/13/2014--Passed Senate amended.
Condemns the violence, atrocities, and human rights violations committed by all parties to the conflict in the Central African Republic.

 Commends the conflict resolution efforts of religious and community leaders in the Central African Republic.

 Welcomes the mobilization of international peacekeeping, humanitarian, and diplomatic resources, and encourages continued efforts to address humanitarian needs, bring an end to the violence, and develop sustainable democratic institutions in the Central African Republic.

Welcomes the January 2014 decision of the Transitional National Council on the election of Catherine Samba-Panza as the Central African Republic's new transitional president.

Commends the African Union and its contributing countries for their efforts.

Recognizes the Economic Community of Central African States for its leadership in the political transition process.

Commends France for its stabilization efforts and other assistance.

Calls on the President to: (1) work with international partners to support a cessation of armed conflict in the Central African Republic, and (2) develop a long-term U.S. strategy for a durable peace and greater security for the Central African Republic and to enhance regional stability.

Urges the Secretary of State to consider the reestablishment of a U.S. diplomatic presence in the Central African Republic.</summary>
</bill>
