<bill session="113" type="h" number="3896" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-29T13:55:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-07-29T13:55:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-01-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Longshore and Harbor Workers' Compensation Clarification Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Longshore and Harbor Workers' Compensation Act to provide a definition of recreational vessel for purposes of such Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400623"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412385" joined="2014-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400108" joined="2014-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412529" joined="2014-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412283" joined="2014-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412527" joined="2014-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400318" joined="2014-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2014-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412412" joined="2014-01-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-01-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-29T13:45:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Walberg moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-29T13:45:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6995-6997" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-29T13:45:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3896.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2014-07-29T13:55:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6995-6996" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-07-29T13:55:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-30">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED10" subcommittee="Workforce Protections" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/29/2014--Passed House amended.
Longshore and Harbor Workers' Compensation Clarification Act of 2014 - Amends the Longshore and Harbor Workers' Compensation Act to define "recreational vessel" as a vessel:

 being manufactured or operated primarily for pleasure; or leased, rented, or chartered to another for the latter's pleasure. Prescribes the following rules in applying the definition:

 a vessel being manufactured or built, or being repaired under warranty by its manufacturer or builder, is a recreational vessel if the vessel appears intended, based on its design and construction, to be for ultimate recreational uses. Requires the manufacturer or builder to bear the burden of establishing that a vessel is recreational under this standard; a vessel being repaired, dismantled for repair, or dismantled at the end of its life will be treated as recreational at the time of repair, dismantling for repair, or dismantling, provided that such vessel shares elements of design and construction of traditional recreational vessels and is not normally engaged in a military, commercial or traditionally commercial undertaking; and a vessel will be treated as a recreational vessel if its a public vessel, such as a vessel owned or chartered and operated by the United States, or by a state or local government, at the time of repair, dismantling for repair, or dismantling, provided that such vessel shares elements of design and construction with traditional recreational vessels and is not normally engaged in a military, commercial, or traditionally commercial undertaking. Requires the Secretary of Labor to amend a certain federal regulation to replace its definition of "recreational vessel" with the definition specified in this Act.</summary>
</bill>
