<bill session="113" type="h" number="5652" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fiscal Responsibility Using Government Accountability Laws Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FRUGAL Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for fiscal responsibility by the Federal Government through the use of accountability laws.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412519"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412577" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412557" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412527" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412509" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412514" joined="2014-09-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Government Reform, and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Currency"/>
    <term name="Foreign property"/>
    <term name="General Services Administration"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Taxation of foreign income"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/18/2014--Introduced.
Fiscal Responsibility Using Government Accountability Laws Act of 2014 or the FRUGAL Act - Requires the Treasury Inspector General for Tax Administration to analyze the extent to which taxpayers are reporting existing foreign accounts and are circumventing or properly utilizing offshore voluntary disclosure initiatives and programs. Requires the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) to: (1) increase educational outreach concerning taxpayer offshore tax obligations, and (2) report to Congress on closing offshore tax loopholes and increasing revenue collection from offshore sources.

Requires the Federal Acquisition Regulation to be revised to include guidelines for federal agencies to use reverse auctions, an electronic auction in which offerors compete by submitting bids or revised bids for a contract, task, or delivery order until the award is made to the offeror with the lowest bid. States that the guidelines should ensure that reverse auctions uphold high quality standards and that small businesses can continue to participate in the procurement process.

Requires the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System to develop and implement a plan to reduce spending on coin inventory management.</summary>
</bill>
