<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H4021E8248AC6416CB3736A453F0D1C8D" key="H" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HR 5884 IH: Don’t Track Me Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2014-12-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 5884</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20141211">December 11, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000937">Mr. Stockman</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name> and <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To prohibit the replacement of the gasoline excise tax with a GPS, location or distance-based tax
			 and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HBD0223E5CCF54BB4B0E21253090740C2" style="OLC">
		<section id="HDC2953C94DDB41A690FB4CA44A3004E9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
			<text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Don’t Track Me Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id77F99E11B5704EADB6B1EF6D7C7D8CE2" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings and purpose</header><subsection id="idBF320E483E64444B867583E5407F7F77"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds as follows:</text><paragraph id="idBC450F06B5F2442481E867D02DAB21DF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Tracking the location of vehicles and the identities of owners for the purpose of taxation, fines
			 or fees has the potential to be misused, and such collected data could be
			 hacked or used for privacy-invading purposes.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id16F86EF44C8C478AAFF4BDA510209E2E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Government and corporate websites are frequently hacked, and driver-tracking databases may be no
			 more invulnerable to hacking; to the advantage of criminals, stalkers, and
			 identity thieves.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idD37A2DD713724273B2938828A2F55919"><enum>(3)</enum><text>GPS tracking enables the technology for automatic speeding, parking and other traffic tickets,
			 charging variable tax rates due to the time of day or other factors,
			 including characterizing driving behavior from acceleration and braking
			 speed, evasive maneuvers such as swerving to avoid a child or deer in the
			 road, or driving in what the Government may believe is a <quote>fuel-wasting</quote> manner.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idEE5E837C94E54305A6BBAD6CCC872BA1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>GPS tracking schemes may require vehicle owners to maintain bank accounts for the debiting of
			 resultant fees. This may be a hardship for many low-income vehicle owners,
			 as well as opening new hacking vulnerabilities for bank accounts of
			 vehicle owners.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id871E63EECE834AFFBBE7E14853A7E26A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The existing gas tax is a rare example of a user fee, whereby vehicle owners pay for the roads they
			 use when purchasing fuel. The tax has successfully provided necessary
			 funding for many decades.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6B5CB91A2F1543FDACEB211F9015DF48"><enum>(6)</enum><text>There are far less intrusive ways than location-based tracking to get electric vehicle and hybrid
			 owners to pay for their road usage.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0EBEC304670E48FFACAE353CEB9142D6"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Vehicle owners must not be required to surrender their Fourth Amendment rights and be tracked
			 everywhere as a condition of driving on public roads.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4F2487A158B843608A32FF1B0D35F059"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Amendment IV of the United States Constitution states <quote>The right of the people to be secure in their persons, houses, papers, and effects, against
			 unreasonable searches and seizures, shall not be violated, and no warrants
			 shall issue, but upon probable cause, supported by oath or affirmation,
			 and particularly describing the place to be searched, and the persons or
			 things to be seized.</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id02F2856A3ABF4C32908E8799CE9E667D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>It is the purpose of this Act to prohibit the replacement or supplementation of the Federal
			 gasoline excise tax with any tax or fee based upon vehicle location or
			 distance traveled, whether determined by global positioning satellite
			 (GPS), license plate reading cameras or any other method of determining
			 owner registration or identity information, and vehicle location or
			 distance traveled.</text></subsection></section><section id="id474336A56C824B06A06A06125C1C5982"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition of a GPS, location or mileage based tax</header><subsection id="idB03C5FA789164DC284AB6B1E2D06418E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>It is contrary to the public policy of the United States to require the placement or use of any
			 GPS, location, distance tracking system, or any other system to collect
			 identities of vehicle owners by any remote means such as license plate
			 reading cameras, radio frequency identification (RFID) devices or by any
			 other means.</text></subsection><subsection id="idC70F6F00FAD34B11898D8CBCF3273194"><enum>(b)</enum><text>The Federal gasoline excise tax may not be replaced or supplemented with any tax, fee or fine based
			 upon vehicle location or distance traveled, whether determined by global
			 positioning satellite (GPS), cameras that read license plates or any other
			 method of determining vehicle location, distance traveled or registration
			 and identity data.</text></subsection><subsection id="idCA9A779F233547198EAA27B131E76A0C"><enum>(c)</enum><text>No motor vehicle may be required to have any device on board the vehicle or to transmit data to any
			 off board device which tracks or records, collects, stores, transmits and
			 location, distance, or registration or driver identity information.</text></subsection></section><section id="id35DC4AA72E7343F8B2CA9BC7E473A535"><enum>4.</enum><header>Limitations on vehicle-to-vehicle and vehicle-to-infrastructure communications</header><subsection id="id207AB7528D8A4F38BD8079BA38B2697C"><enum>(a)</enum><text>No public funds may be used to study or implement or require the use of any method of tracking or
			 reporting vehicle movement or location for the purpose of taxes, user
			 fees, traffic fines, accident investigation, or to communicate with other
			 vehicles or infrastructure.</text></subsection><subsection id="id4A87A13308494AA2900959636242AD49"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Vehicle-to-vehicle or vehicle-to-infrastructure communication systems for the purposes of recording
			 or transmitting or storing for later retrieval location, registration,
			 identity, or speed data are prohibited, except for those vehicles owned or
			 leased by Federal Government agencies in question.</text></subsection><subsection id="id4FD6C60FDA654B978739BF938EAF5A74"><enum>(c)</enum><text>Any such transmissions may only be used for momentary accident avoidance or completely anonymized
			 traffic reporting.</text></subsection></section><section id="idC1ED97CC350E4F76B8D9D29197B65CC3"><enum>5.</enum><header><quote>Black box</quote> data recorders</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No motor vehicle shall be required by any Federal agency to have installed and operational any <quote>black box</quote> accident data recorder that records any vehicle data for a period longer than the last five
			 minutes of vehicle operation, and such devices may never be capable of
			 recording audio, images, or video from inside the vehicle. Any such device
			 may not broadcast or transmit any data in any way, except by a direct
			 cable connection to a computer.</text></section><section id="idCC635DB64D794AD59412F338CEBE276A"><enum>6.</enum><header>Vehicle owners exempted</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No provisions of this Act shall prohibit the use by vehicle owners of GPS or other technologies for
			 tracking the location of their own vehicle.</text></section><section id="id5268635761FE4E9D96068D37EE9F6F36"><enum>7.</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of the Department of Transportation shall submit to Congress, not later than 90 days
			 after the date of the enactment of this Act, a report describing the
			 actions taken to ensure permanent compliance with this Act.</text></section></legis-body>
</bill>


