<bill session="113" type="h" number="5567" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Education and Workforce Innovation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To carry out pilot programs to improve skills and job training, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412407"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412396" joined="2014-09-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Training" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/18/2014--Introduced.
Education and Workforce Innovation Act - Directs the Secretary of Education to carry out a five-year pilot program to award grants to eligible entities to carry out programs that provide direct skills and job training for individuals to enter and advance in high-growth, emerging, and in-demand industries, such as skilled labor and trade industries.

Defines an "eligible entity" as a private company involved in the manufacturing, production, or technology industries, in partnership with a junior or community college, postsecondary vocational institution, or secondary school.

Authorizes such an entity to use such a grant to develop and carry out a multiyear program to provide students enrolled in such a college, institution, or school with education and training to enter and advance in such industries, by providing: (1) customized training, (2) increased productivity and knowledge transfer, (3) a stable and predictable pipeline to a high-standard of employment upon graduation, (4) a proven model of success, and (5) an opportunity for career advancement.

Requires an eligible entity that is awarded a grant to provide matching funds from non-federal sources.

Directs the Secretaries of Education and the Treasury to administer a five-year pilot program under which qualified investors enter into a pay-for-performance agreement under which they will provide funds to service providers to carry out workforce training programs that increase trade certifications or apprenticeships for unemployed individuals or dislocated workers.</summary>
</bill>
