<bill session="113" type="h" number="5224" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">RDOCS-VA Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Restoring the Doctors of Our Country through Scholarships Veterans Affairs Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to establish a scholarship program to increase the availability of physicians who provide primary health care services at medical facilities of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400262"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1251"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-08-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR03" subcommittee="Health" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/28/2014--Introduced.
Restoring the Doctors of Our Country through Scholarships Veterans Affairs Act of 2014 or the RDOCS-VA Act of 2014 - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, as part of the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) Health Professionals Educational Assistance Program, to carry out a scholarship program to provide for the increased availability of physicians who provide primary health care services at VA medical facilities, which shall be known as the Restoring the Doctors of Our Country through Scholarships-Veterans Affairs (RDOCS-VA) program.

Directs the Secretary, under such program, to award not less than 400 scholarships covering all tuition and costs for an undergraduate medical education for a period of study not exceeding 48 consecutive months, and a cost-of-living stipend, to selected individuals who agree to:

 be admitted into and maintain enrollment in a participating undergraduate medical program in the scholar's state of residence, maintain a minimum level of academic standing, complete an accredited residency training program in a primary care specialty, become licensed to practice medicine in the scholar's state of residence, receive and maintain board certification in a primary care specialty, and complete a five-year post-graduate period of employment by the VA performing primary care services. Directs the Secretary to give preference to applicants who: (1) are enrolled in an accelerated track family-medicine program, or (2) elect to complete the five-year period of employment at a VA facility that the Secretary designates as having an urgent need for primary care physicians.

Sets forth provisions regarding such scholar's liability for breach of agreement.</summary>
</bill>
