<bill session="113" type="s" number="2384" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-05-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Deter Cyber Theft Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the President to develop a watch list and a priority watch list of foreign countries that engage in economic or industrial espionage in cyberspace with respect to United States trade secrets or proprietary information, to provide for the imposition of sanctions with respect to foreign persons that knowingly benefit from such espionage, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300066"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2014-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="2014-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2014-05-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3297-3298"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3979"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="884"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Customs enforcement"/>
    <term name="Foreign property"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Trade secrets and economic espionage"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/22/2014--Introduced.
Deter Cyber Theft Act of 2014 - Requires the President to report annually to Congress on foreign countries that engage in economic and industrial espionage in cyberspace with respect to U.S. trade secrets or proprietary information. Requires each report to: (1) identify countries that engage in such espionage, including countries that facilitate, support, fail to prosecute, or otherwise permit such espionage; (2) specify the countries that engage in the most egregious forms of such espionage; and (3) describe actions taken and progress made by the President to decrease the prevalence of such espionage.

Authorizes the President to block and prohibit transactions in property, and interests in property, of a foreign person the President determines knowingly requests, engages in, supports, facilitates, or benefits from the significant appropriation, through economic or industrial espionage in cyberspace, of technologies or proprietary information developed by U.S. persons if such property and interests in property: (1) are in the United States; (2) come within the United States; or (3) are, or come within, the possession or control of a U.S. person. Prohibits the President from imposing sanctions on the importation of goods under such authority.</summary>
</bill>
