<bill session="113" type="h" number="2824" updated="2015-09-01T10:19:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-03-25T15:07:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-03-25T15:07:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preventing Government Waste and Protecting Coal Mining Jobs in America</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Preventing Government Waste and Protecting Coal Mining Jobs in America</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Preventing Government Waste and Protecting Coal Mining Jobs in America</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 to stop the ongoing waste by the Department of the Interior of taxpayer resources and implement the final rule on excess spoil, mining waste, and buffers for perennial and intermittent streams, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412460"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412555" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412549" joined="2013-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412397" joined="2013-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412191" joined="2013-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412294" joined="2013-08-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-02">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-14">
      <text>Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-14">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-11-14" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 24 - 15.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-02-28T11:58:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 113-364.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-02-28T11:58:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="270">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 270.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-03-05T18:03:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 501 Reported to House. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 2824 and H.R. 2641. The resolution provides one hour of general debate for each bill and makes in order specified amendments printed in the Rules Committee Report 113-374. The resolution provides one motion to recommit.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-25T12:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 501.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2621-2634, H2634-2635" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-25T12:31:00-04:00">
      <text>The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 2824 and H.R. 2641. The resolution provides one hour of general debate for each bill and makes in order specified amendments printed in the Rules Committee Report 113-374. The resolution provides one motion to recommit.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-25T12:32:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 501 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-25T12:32:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Rob Woodall to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-25T12:32:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 2824.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-25T13:41:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 501, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Lowenthal Part B amendment no. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-25T13:51:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Lowenthal Part B amendment No. 1, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Lowenthal demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-25T13:52:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisons of H.Res. 501, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Cartwright Part B amendment no. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-25T14:00:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Cartwright Part B amendment No. 2, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Cartwright demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-25T14:00:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question on adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-25T14:37:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2824.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-25T14:38:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2629" label="text of amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-25T14:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Bera (CA) moved to recommit with instructions to the Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2633-2634" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2633" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-25T14:41:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Bera motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to report the same back to the House forthwith with an amendment to clarify that the underlying bill does not limit the right of the Department of the Interior or of any state to prioritize (1) the hiring of unemployed workers, including veterans, or (2) the use of US-made equipment and materials in mining operations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-25T14:47:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2633" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-25T14:55:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 197 - 224 (Roll no. 140).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2633-2634" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="141" datetime="2014-03-25T15:07:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 229 - 192 (Roll no. 141).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-03-25T15:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-26">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-07">
      <text>Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-05-08" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="373">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 373.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hr" number="501"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="113" type="hr" number="501"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4304"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4304"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h599"/>
    <amendment number="h600"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>3/25/2014--Passed House amended.
Preventing Government Waste and Protecting Coal Mining Jobs in America - Amends the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 to require state programs for regulation of surface coal mining to incorporate the necessary rule concerning excess spoil, coal mine waste, and buffers for perennial and intermittent streams published by the Office of Surface Mining Reclamation and Enforcement on December 12, 2008.

Requires the Secretary of the Interior to: (1) publish notice of a determination when all states that wish to assume exclusive jurisdiction of such mining regulation have incorporated the rule in their programs; (2) assess the effectiveness of the rule's implementation during the five-year period following such notice; (3) carry out all required consultation on the benefits and other impacts of the implementation of the rule to any threatened or endangered species, with the participation of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service and the United States Geological Survey (USGS); and (4) report to Congress an evaluation of the rule's effectiveness, any ways in which it inhibits energy production, and any proposed changes to the rule. Prohibits issuance of any regulations regarding stream buffer zones or protection before publication of the report, other than a rule necessary to implement incorporation of the December 2008 rule described in this Act. Requires each state with an approved program for regulation of surface coal mining to submit program amendments incorporating such rule within two years of enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
