<bill session="113" type="h" number="4343" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-03-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-03-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-03-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Write the Laws Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To end the unconstitutional delegation of legislative power which was exclusively vested in the Senate and House of Representatives by article I, section 1 of the United States Constitution, and to direct the Comptroller General of the United States to issue a report to Congress detailing the extent of the problem of unconstitutional delegation to the end that such delegations can be phased out, thereby restoring the constitutional principle of separation of powers set forth in the first sections of the United States Constitution.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410396"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-03-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU10" subcommittee="Constitution and Civil Justice" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1663"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional-executive branch relations"/>
    <term name="Constitution and constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/27/2014--Introduced.
Write the Laws Act - Prohibits: (1)&#160;the inclusion of a delegation of legislative powers clause in any bill passed by Congress, whether such delegation is to a branch of government, a federal or quasi-public agency, a state or instrumentality thereof, or any other organization or individual; or (2) any new presidential directive, adjudicative decision, rule, or regulation governing, limiting, imposing a penalty on, or otherwise regulating any activity of, any person or entity, other than a U.S. officer or employee, unless such directive, decision, rule, or regulation is authorized by&#160;a duly-enacted&#160;bill. Directs the Comptroller General (GAO) to report to Congress identifying all previously-enacted&#160;statutes that contain a delegation of powers clause to assist Congress in&#160;repealing or amending any such statutes.</summary>
</bill>
