<bill session="113" type="h" number="4423" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-04-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-04-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Acre in, Acre Out Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for no net increase in the total acreage of certain Federal land under the jurisdiction of the Bureau of Land Management, the National Park Service, the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, or the Forest Service, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412485"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412252" joined="2014-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400141" joined="2014-05-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412397" joined="2014-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2014-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412487" joined="2014-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412399" joined="2014-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412581" joined="2014-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="2014-05-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-08">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-08">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Energy, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="Public Lands and Environmental Regulation" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII22" subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG15" subcommittee="Conservation, Energy, and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="General public lands matters"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/8/2014--Introduced.
Acre in, Acre Out Act - Prescribes a new requirement for the acquisition of land by the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) that would result in a net increase of total land acreage under the jurisdiction of the National Park Service, the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, the Bureau of Land Management (BLM), or the Forest Service. Requires the Secretary concerned to offer for sale an equal number of acres of federal land that is under the same jurisdictional status.

Exempts from this requirement any easements acquired to facilitate management of federal lands.

Requires land sold pursuant to this Act to be offered for sale: (1) at fair market value (based on local comparable sales); and (2) at a price reduced by 10% each month if the land is not sold or under contract six months after it was first offered for sale.

Declares that time periods during which such land is under contract or withdrawn from the market shall not be counted for price reduction purposes.

Requires all net proceeds from the sale of federal lands pursuant to this Act to be deposited directly into the Treasury for reduction of the public debt.</summary>
</bill>
