<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Enrolled-Bill" dms-id="H4905CBCC35534D7A9E7BEA8239CCED29" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title> HR 2952 ENR: Cybersecurity Workforce Assessment Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>One Hundred Thirteenth Congress of the United States of America</congress> <session>At the Second Session</session><enrolled-dateline>Begun and held at the City of Washington on Friday, the third day of January, two thousand and fourteen</enrolled-dateline> 
<legis-num>H. R. 2952</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no"></current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Homeland Security to assess the cybersecurity workforce of the Department of Homeland Security and develop a comprehensive workforce strategy, and for other purposes. </official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H429A1732E08C41989B417EE5B15AEDF6" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA7182B14FF6244B0867A7B2305F8BAAF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Cybersecurity Workforce Assessment Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section>
<section id="H20E6C3E9DD6A4E728565EA61A0B833FE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act—</text>
<paragraph id="H5815683DF0B84810B1CD96956F719838"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>Cybersecurity Category</term> means a position’s or incumbent’s primary work function involving cybersecurity, which is further defined by Specialty Area;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEB7847BC0D6A42B18CC08C936EFA56CE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>Department</term> means the Department of Homeland Security;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC3D793EA07A14EF99B34D42E20E2918F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Homeland Security; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1A9762E7776C4BC199FD7917DDC81C6E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>Specialty Area</term> means any of the common types of cybersecurity work as recognized by the National Initiative for Cybersecurity Education’s National Cybersecurity Workforce Framework report.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="H8F5F7D96263C43B399DDE0C7008EF59B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Cybersecurity workforce assessment and strategy</header>
<subsection id="H01D2BFC349D5498694C5091863CA1493"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Workforce assessment</header>
<paragraph id="H4E30308E8D624CD18D317D3AE46D7F43"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for 3 years, the Secretary shall assess the cybersecurity workforce of the Department.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H94FFA64DBCF64D0EB6AA97EFB9ECB504"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The assessment required under paragraph (1) shall include, at a minimum—</text>
<subparagraph id="H667B214DBB9C448D88948B0B2740FFE9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an assessment of the readiness and capacity of the workforce of the Department to meet its cybersecurity mission;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H0C09D5B231EB4F8390A10250F356194B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>information on where cybersecurity workforce positions are located within the Department;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H04439D0867FF411D8556E77FE9FAECC0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>information on which cybersecurity workforce positions are—</text>
<clause id="HEAF7DD9B990843B4B08E495FE7CEDDA5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>performed by—</text>
<subclause id="H9036A7735DB240E3BB5D4C3A19EEDD21"><enum>(I)</enum><text>permanent full-time equivalent employees of the Department, including, to the greatest extent practicable, demographic information about such employees;</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H9D09E75D44604D55BB34B9159CFC39B6"><enum>(II)</enum><text>independent contractors; and</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HD1896561B4D0484A91B44E17C0EC0A19"><enum>(III)</enum><text>individuals employed by other Federal agencies, including the National Security Agency; or</text></subclause></clause>
<clause id="H597BE203CB4E4B7E802A8D8364777B09"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>vacant; and</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HBF46F2EF33B94C318DD61461C8C92AD3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>information on—</text>
<clause id="H57C10BE856B144ACA2E5B811A3587947"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the percentage of individuals within each Cybersecurity Category and Specialty Area who received essential training to perform their jobs; and</text></clause>
<clause id="HC2D096FE200A41769174C7964562E870"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in cases in which such essential training was not received, what challenges, if any, were encountered with respect to the provision of such essential training.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H11B6F725369E4213804A37250DD7E055"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Workforce strategy</header>
<paragraph id="HC02491E3D65B46B3AAEBD6169835FED9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text>
<subparagraph id="HFBFC942E1B3D419987510C46AC6369F7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, develop a comprehensive workforce strategy to enhance the readiness, capacity, training, recruitment, and retention of the cybersecurity workforce of the Department; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2367108925BA42C5B820C3A0F364A182"><enum>(B)</enum><text>maintain and, as necessary, update the comprehensive workforce strategy developed under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4E80D4837F7D4EB7B4D2D690A779A580"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The comprehensive workforce strategy developed under paragraph (1) shall include a description of—</text>
<subparagraph id="H56BB1003E9804253BFDCED80E52A9A11"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a multi-phased recruitment plan, including with respect to experienced professionals, members of disadvantaged or underserved communities, the unemployed, and veterans;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4A4411EC63354C73A3AAD6EA19BC3E64"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a 5-year implementation plan;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD76717E23F89447BB665F3CE80AFA1C1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a 10-year projection of the cybersecurity workforce needs of the Department;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H937C6E6A4A894656881DE67C1E745437"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any obstacle impeding the hiring and development of a cybersecurity workforce in the Department; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HBCD65789E97343A599BBD931363C4631"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any gap in the existing cybersecurity workforce of the Department and a plan to fill any such gap.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H9E6680598A8544AE8F56F914345EAE0F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Updates</header><text>The Secretary submit to the appropriate congressional committees annual updates on—</text>
<paragraph id="H3D0D09270A544575A02E855B91D049B0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the cybersecurity workforce assessment required under subsection (a); and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDBEAB546C6654BDCA7E5B2A4A399F8E7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the progress of the Secretary in carrying out the comprehensive workforce strategy required to be developed under subsection (b).</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="HEE25740CCB9946DA870F91AF4D1F5E5F"><enum>4.</enum><header>Cybersecurity Fellowship Program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the feasibility, cost, and benefits of establishing a Cybersecurity Fellowship Program to offer a tuition payment plan for individuals pursuing undergraduate and doctoral degrees who agree to work for the Department for an agreed-upon period of time.</text></section> 
</legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><role>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</role></attestation-group><attestation-group><role>Vice President of the United States and President of the Senate.</role></attestation-group></attestation>
</bill> 


