<bill session="113" type="s" number="2241" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-04-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-04-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Drug-Free Playgrounds Safety Enhancement Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to enhance the safety of drug-free playgrounds.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412326"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412602" joined="2014-09-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Games and hobbies"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation facilities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/10/2014--Introduced.
Drug-Free Playgrounds Safety Enhancement Act of 2014 - Amends provisions of the Controlled Substances Act prescribing enhanced penalties for distributing or manufacturing drugs in or near certain facilities, such as schools, playgrounds, youth centers, and swimming pools, to: (1) include among such facilities a video amusement game facility (currently, a video arcade facility); (2) define a "video amusement game facility" as any facility that is legally accessible to persons under 18 years of age, that is intended primarily for amusement, and that contains video game machines or other similar youth games; and (3) revise the definition of "playground" to mean any outdoor area that is intended for recreation, that is open to the public, and that contains one or more apparatus intended for the recreation of children, including play structures, sliding boards, swingsets, seesaws, merry-go-rounds, slides, jungle gyms, chin-up bars, sandboxes, spring riders, monkey bars, overhead ladders, trapeze rings, playhouses, rope bridges, and mazes.</summary>
</bill>
