<bill session="113" type="s" number="2475" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Children in Families First Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to realign structure and reallocate resources in the Federal Government, in keeping with the core American belief that families are the best protection for children and the bedrock of any society, to bolster United States diplomacy and assistance targeted at ensuring that every child can grow up in a permanent, safe, nurturing, and loving family, and to strengthen intercountry adoption to the United States and around the world and ensure that it becomes a viable and fully developed option for providing families for children in need, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300063"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2014-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2014-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2014-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="2014-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412390" joined="2014-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2014-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2014-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412545" joined="2014-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400222" joined="2014-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2014-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="2014-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2014-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412243" joined="2014-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300080" joined="2014-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2014-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2014-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2014-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2014-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2014-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412542" joined="2014-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2014-06-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3323"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4143"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1530"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/17/2014--Introduced.
Children in Families First Act of 2014 - Establishes within the Department of State the Office of Vulnerable Children and Family Security which shall: (1) support the implementation in foreign countries of child welfare laws and policies; and (2) address the gap in U.S. diplomacy, policy, and operations with respect to promoting appropriate, protective, and permanent family care for children living without families.

States that the Office shall be headed by an Ambassador-at-Large who shall: (1) serve as a primary advisor to the Secretary of State and the President in all matters related to vulnerable children and family security in foreign countries; and (2) represent the United States in matters relevant to international child welfare, family preservation and reunification, and provision of permanent, safe parental care through kinship and domestic and intercountry adoption.

	Amends the Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000 to direct the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS), through U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services (USCIS), to carry out the functions prescribed by the Convention regarding the accreditation of U.S. adoption services providers.

Establishes databases for internationally adopted children and adoption service providers.

Transfers from the Secretary of State to the Field Operations Directorate of USCIS specified adoption-related functions, including accreditation of agencies and approval of persons to provide adoption services and oversight of provider investigations.

Requires the Secretary of Homeland Security, through USCIS, to: (1) be responsible for processing and case-specific decision making on all intercountry adoption cases, (2) ensure that all intercountry adoption suitability and eligibility determinations of prospective adoptive parents are made in compliance with the Hague Adoption Convention, (3) ensure that all non-Convention adoption cases undergo specified preprocessing, and (4) be responsible for all case processing steps in Convention and non-Convention adoption petitions on behalf of children whom U.S. parents propose to immigrate to the United States.

Establishes within the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) a Center of Excellence on Children in Adversity.

Authorizes the President to provide assistance for programs in developing countries for nutrition, education, care, and protection of children.

Requires: (1) the President to establish a system to monitor and evaluate the effectiveness of U.S. aid to children in adversity, and (2) USAID to carry out a priority country demonstration program implementing the (December 2012) Action Plan for Children in Adversity over a period of five years in at least six countries.</summary>
</bill>
