<bill session="113" type="h" number="3615" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-11-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-11-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-11-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Careers for Heroes Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the hiring of veterans by the Federal Government.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400660"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-11-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-21">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-21">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR10" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="495"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="944"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1950"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1982"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2413"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/21/2013--Introduced.
Careers for Heroes Act - Directs the head of each federal agency other than the Department of Defense (DOD) and the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to develop a plan for exercising, during the five-year period beginning on the enactment of this Act, authority to make veterans recruitment appointments and authority under the Veterans Employment Opportunities Act of 1998.

Requires the Director of the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) to ensure that, under such plans, agencies shall appoint no less than 15,000 qualified covered veterans during such period. (Covered veterans include those who: (1) are disabled or recently separated; (2) served on active duty during a war or in a campaign or expedition for which a campaign badge has been authorized; or (3) while serving on active duty, participated in a military operation for which an Armed Forces service medal was awarded.)</summary>
</bill>
