<bill session="113" type="sr" number="343" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-02-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-02-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-02-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution establishing a Select Committee of the Senate to make a full and thorough investigation of the unauthorized disclosures of apparently classified information concerning the National Security Agency intelligence-collection programs, operations, and activities, including programs affecting Americans, to make findings based upon the investigation, and to make recommendations based on the investigation and findings.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300071"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-02-04">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S767"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S765-767" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="National Security Agency"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/4/2014--Introduced.
Establishes in the Senate the Select Committee on the Investigation of leaks concerning certain activities of the National Security Agency (NSA) to:

 make a full and thorough investigation of the unauthorized disclosures that have occurred since June 2013 of apparently classified information concerning the NSA intelligence-collection programs, operations, and activities, including intelligence-collection programs affecting Americans; make findings based upon the investigation; submit to Congress and the President recommendations based on it and such findings; and take any actions necessary and appropriate to carry out these requirements.</summary>
</bill>
