<bill session="113" type="h" number="3666" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-12-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-12-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-12-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sequester Delay and Stop Tax Haven Abuse Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To alleviate the sequestration and to end offshore tax abuses, to preserve our national defense and protect American families and businesses from devastating cuts, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400103"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412571" joined="2014-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412470" joined="2014-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2013-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400111" joined="2013-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2014-01-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-12-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Financial Services, and the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-05">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-05">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-05">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1554"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1555"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3793"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="268"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1533"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1844"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Commodities markets"/>
    <term name="Commodity Futures Trading Commission"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Credit and credit markets"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international banking"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction and venue"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Taxation of foreign income"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/5/2013--Introduced.
Sequester Delay and Stop Tax Haven Abuse Act - Title I: Extension of Sequestration - Amends the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 to: (1) repeal the&#160;across-the-board reductions in discretionary spending mandated by such Act in FY2014 and FY2015, and (2) increase the budget authority in FY2016 for the security and nonsecurity budget categories.

Title II: Deterring the Use of Tax Havens for Tax Evasion - Authorizes the Secretary of the Treasury to impose restrictions on foreign jurisdictions or financial institutions operating in the United States that are of primary money laundering concern or that significantly impede U.S. tax enforcement.

Amends the Internal Revenue Code to:

 expand reporting requirements for U.S. persons who hold an interest in a passive foreign investment company; establish a rebuttable presumption against the validity of transactions by institutions that do not comply with reporting requirements under the Foreign Account Tax Compliance Act; treat certain foreign corporations managed and controlled primarily in the United States as domestic corporations for U.S. tax purposes; require tax withholding agents and financial institutions to report certain information about beneficial owners of foreign-owned financial accounts; treat swap payments sent offshore as taxable U.S. source income; and impose additional requirements for third party summonses used to obtain information in tax investigations that do not identify the person with respect to whose liability the summons is issued (i.e., John Doe summons). Title III: Other Measures to Combat Tax Haven Abuses - Amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to: (1) require corporations registered with the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to report annually, on a country-by country basis, on employees, gross revenues, payments made to governments, and other financial information; and (2) impose a fine for failure to disclose any holdings or transactions involving equity or debt instruments known to involve a foreign entity that would otherwise be subject to disclosure requirements.

Makes investment advisers and persons engaged in forming new business entities subject to anti-money laundering requirements.

Title IV Ending Corporate Offshore Tax Avoidance - Imposes new restrictions on U.S. corporations and other entities with foreign income with respect to: (1) tax deductions allocable to deferred foreign income, (2) the recalculation of foreign income taxes, (3) intangible property transferred overseas, (4) tax evasion activities by U.S. corporations reincorporating in a foreign country, and (5) loans to U.S. shareholders from controlled foreign corporations.</summary>
</bill>
