<bill session="113" type="h" number="5042" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Jumpstart VA Construction Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out a pilot program under which the Secretary enters into partnership agreements with non-Federal entities for the construction of major medical facility projects.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412189"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR03" subcommittee="Health" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/9/2014--Introduced.
Jumpstart VA Construction Act - Requires the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out a 10-year pilot program of entering into partnership agreements on a competitive basis with appropriate non-federal entities for major authorized construction projects. Directs the Secretary to select 10 major medical facility projects authorized for the construction of a new facility for which: (1) Congress has appropriated funds, (2) the design and development phase is complete, and (3) construction has not begun as of the date of enactment of this Act. Requires four of such projects to be seismic-related projects and four to be community based outpatient clinic-related projects.

Directs the Secretary to: (1) appoint a non-Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) entity as the project manager of each project; (2) ensure that the project manager implements a project management plan to ensure concise and consistent communication of all parties involved; (3) work in cooperation with each participating non-federal entity to minimize multiple change orders; (4) develop metrics to monitor change order process times, with the intent of expediting any change order; and (5) monitor construction to ensure that it is in compliance with the Federal Acquisition Regulations and VA acquisition regulations and that the costs are reasonable.</summary>
</bill>
