<bill session="113" type="s" number="1955" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-01-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-01-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-01-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Knife Owners' Protection Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to protect the right of law-abiding citizens to transport knives interstate, notwithstanding a patchwork of local and State prohibitions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300041"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300030" joined="2014-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412495" joined="2014-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412322" joined="2014-07-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-01-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3478"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/16/2014--Introduced.
Knife Owners' Protection Act of 2014 - Allows any individual who is not otherwise prohibited by federal law from possessing, transporting, shipping, or receiving a knife to transport a knife from any state or place where such individual may lawfully possess, carry, or transport such a knife to any other state or place where such individual may lawfully do so: (1) by motor vehicle if the knife is not directly accessible from the passenger compartment or is in a locked container, glove compartment, or console; or (2) by other means over land or through water or the air if the knife is in a locked container. Excludes the transport of a knife with the intent to commit an offense punishable by imprisonment for a term exceeding one year involving the use or threatened use of force against another person or with knowledge, or reasonable cause to believe, that such an offense is to be committed in the course of, or arising from, the journey.

Authorizes an individual transporting a knife in accordance with such requirements to have a knife accessible while staying in any form of temporary lodging.

Allows an individual to carry a knife or tool that is designed for enabling escape in an emergency and that incorporates a blunt tipped safety blade or a guarded blade or both for cutting safety belts in the passenger compartment of a motor vehicle without being secured in a locked container, glove compartment, or console, except in the passenger cabin of aircraft whose passengers are subject to airport screening procedures of the Transportation Security Administration (TSA).

Establishes a cause of action by individuals subjected to deprivation of rights provided under this Act. Requires the court to award reasonable attorney's fees to the prevailing party if an individual asserts this Act as a claim or defense.</summary>
</bill>
