<bill session="113" type="hr" number="676" updated="2015-09-01T10:18:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-30T18:29:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-07-30T18:29:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for authority to initiate litigation for actions by the President or other executive branch officials inconsistent with their duties under the Constitution of the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400367"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Rules, and in addition to the Committee on House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-22">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-22">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-28T16:43:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Rules. H. Rept. 113-561, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-28T16:43:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on House Administration discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-07-28T16:43:00-04:00" state="REPORTED" calendar="House" number="129">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 129.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-07-29T17:58:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 694 Reported to House. The resolution provides for consideration of both H. Res. 676 and H.R. 935 in the House. Both measures are debatable for one hour.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-30T16:45:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 694.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7087-7099" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-30T16:45:00-04:00">
      <text>The resolution provides for consideration of both H. Res. 676 and H.R. 935 in the House. Both measures are debatable for one hour.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-30T16:45:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 676.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-30T18:01:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7099" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="468" datetime="2014-07-30T18:29:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 225 - 201 (Roll no. 468).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7087" label="text"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hr" number="694"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="113" type="hr" number="694"/>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="113" type="hr" number="694"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
    <term name="Congressional-executive branch relations"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h1131"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>7/30/2014--Passed House amended.
Authorizes the Speaker of the House of Representatives to initiate or intervene in one or more civil actions, on behalf of the House, in a federal court of competent jurisdiction to seek any appropriate relief regarding the failure of the President, the head of any department or agency, or any other executive branch officer or employee, to act in a manner consistent with that official's duties under the U.S. Constitution and federal laws with respect to implementation of requirements of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (PPACA), certain PPACA-related requirements in the Health Care and Education Reconciliation Act of 2010, including any amendment made by them, or any other related provision of law, including a failure to implement it.

Requires the Speaker to notify the House of a decision to initiate or intervene in any such civil action.

Requires the Office of the General Counsel of the House, at the direction of the Speaker, to represent the House in the civil action initiated, or in which the House intervenes. Authorizes the Office to employ the services of outside counsel and other experts for this purpose.

Requires: (1) the chair of the Committee on House Administration to cause to be printed in the Congressional Record a statement setting forth the aggregate amounts expended by the Office on the outside counsel and other experts on a quarterly basis, and (2) the statement to be submitted for printing within 30 days after the expiration of each quarter.</summary>
</bill>
