<bill session="113" type="s" number="2680" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Buy it in America Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of Commerce to establish a voluntary program under which manufacturers may have products certified as meeting the standards of labels that indicate to consumers the extent to which the products are manufactured in the United States, to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow a credit against income tax for equity investments in small business concerns, to establish small business savings accounts, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300080"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412602" joined="2014-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4931"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2497"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Buy American requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/29/2014--Introduced.
Buy it in America Act - Directs the Secretary of Commerce to establish the America Star Program as a voluntary program under which manufacturers may have products certified&#160;as meeting the standards of a&#160;label (i.e., America Star label) that indicates to consumers the extent to which such products are manufactured in the United States.

Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) allow a new tax credit (angel investment tax credit) for up to 25% of equity investment in a&#160;small business entity that is located in the United States and engages in a qualified high technology trade or business; (2) make permanent the 100% exclusion from gross income of gain from the sale or exchange of qualified small business stock; and (3) establish tax-exempt small business startup savings accounts to&#160;make distributions for small business operating capital, the purchase of equipment or facilities, marketing, training, incorporation, and accounting fees.</summary>
</bill>
