<bill session="113" type="h" number="3371" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-10-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-10-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">State Loan Access and Student Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To exempt certain education loans made by States from certain preferred lender requirements under the Higher Education Act of 1965.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400179"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412571" joined="2014-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412576" joined="2013-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400111" joined="2014-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412482" joined="2014-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="2013-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2013-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412575" joined="2013-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412579" joined="2013-12-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Training" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/29/2013--Introduced.
State Loan Access and Student Protection Act - Amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to exempt certain state education loans from the requirement that when an institution of higher education (IHE) recommends, promotes, or endorses such loans, there need to be at least two unaffiliated lenders of those loans on the school's preferred lender list.

Conditions that exemption on the IHE:

 only recommending, promoting, or endorsing such loans by providing students and families with information about the loans and providing financial aid packages that include such loans to students who have previously been awarded such loans; using a form, to be developed by the Secretary of Education, to disclose the terms and conditions of such loans to borrowers and compare them to the terms and conditions of Direct loans under part D (William D. Ford Federal Direct Loan Program) of title IV; placing such loans on their preferred list only if the loans' terms and conditions are at least as favorable as the terms and conditions on Direct loans; and prominently disclosing to borrowers the methods and criteria it used in deciding to recommend, promote, or endorse such loans.</summary>
</bill>
