<bill session="113" type="s" number="2742" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improving Access to Social Security Services Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for public notice and input prior to the closure, consolidation, or public access limitation of field or hearing offices of the Social Security Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300087"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2014-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2014-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2014-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300078" joined="2014-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Social Security Administration"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2014--Introduced.
Improving Access to Social Security Services Act - Amends title VII (Administration) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to prohibit the Commissioner of Social Security from imposing any reduction in public access on a Social Security Administration field or hearing office without a public comment period meeting specified deadlines, including at least one public hearing.

Requires each field office to provide services necessary for: (1) Social Security number printout services until August 1, 2015, and (2) benefit verification letter services until October 1, 2015.

Directs the Commissioner to conduct an outreach campaign to notify Social Security beneficiaries and other interested parties of plans to phase out such services and their online availability.

Requires each office that ceases to offer, or reduces the availability of, such services to give notice to key local organizations whose members or patrons may be affected by such cessation or reduction.

Requires the Commissioner to establish a system providing live-chat assistance for online users of the Administration website.

Directs the Commissioner to establish: (1) a process whereby an eligible individual may apply for a reduction or waiver of Administration service fees, and (2) an automated notification system to alert Social Security beneficiaries of changes made to their information for direct deposit to a financial institution of their Social Security benefits.

Prohibits any person from displaying another individual's Social Security number to the general public without the individual's affirmatively expressed consent, or selling or purchasing that number without such consent.

Directs the Attorney General to study all uses of Social Security numbers permitted, required, authorized, or excepted under any federal law.

Prohibits any person from obtaining an individual's Social Security number for purposes of locating or identifying the individual with the intent to physically injure, harm, or use the identity of the individual for any illegal purpose.

Amends SSA title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) to prescribe criminal sanctions for the knowing and willful display, sale, or purchase of a Social Security number without meeting the prerequisites for consent.

Extends to any electronic communication the prohibitions, subject to criminal penalties, relating to references to Social Security or Medicare.

Authorizes a private cause of action in state court for injunctive relief or up to $500 in actual damages by any individual aggrieved by a violation of this Act or any of its amendments.

Subjects any person the Attorney General determines has violated any provisions of this Act to a civil penalty of up to: (1) $5,000 for each violation, and (2) $50,000 if the violation has occurred with such frequency as to constitute a general business practice.</summary>
</bill>
