<bill session="113" type="s" number="2976" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-12-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-12-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-12-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Derivatives End-Users Clarification Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Commodity Exchange Act and the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to specify how clearing requirements apply to certain affiliate transactions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300025"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2014-12-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-12-04">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6351-6352"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4413"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="5405"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="5471"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Commodities markets"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/4/2014--Introduced.
Derivatives End-Users Clarification Act - Amends the Commodity Exchange Act and the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to revise the treatment of affiliate transactions that may be exempt from clearing requirements to authorize such an exemption only if the affiliate enters into the swap to hedge or mitigate the commercial risk of the person that is not a financial entity (as under current law), on the condition that an appropriate credit support measure or other mechanism shall be used if the hedge or mitigation of commercial risk is addressed by entering into: (1) a swap with either a swap dealer or major swap participant, or (2) a security-based swap with a security-based swap dealer or major security-based swap participant.

 Applies this subtitle only to swaps or security-based swaps entered into after enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
