<bill session="113" type="h" number="3886" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-01-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-01-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-01-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Secure Rural Schools and Community Self-Determination Act of 2000 to exempt payments made to States and counties under such Act from any reduction pursuant to a sequestration order and to reimburse those States and counties that returned a portion of their January 2013 payment because of sequestration, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400100"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-01-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committees on Natural Resources, and the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-15">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-15">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-15">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Energy, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG15" subcommittee="Conservation, Energy, and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="Public Lands and Environmental Regulation" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/15/2014--Introduced.
Amends the Secure Rural Schools and Community Self-Determination Act of 2000 (the Act) to exempt from any presidential sequestration order issued under the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 (Gramm-Rudman-Hollings Act) funds made available under the Act or derived from the other authorized funding sources for the purpose of making payments to eligible states and counties containing certain federal lands (payments in lieu of federal payment of state property taxes).

Directs the Secretary of the Treasury, using authorized payment sources, to reimburse each state or county that, in response to a presidential sequestration order issued during FY2013, repaid some of the payment it received during FY2013 either by: (1) returning a portion of it to the Secretary, (2) having funds deducted from other amounts due the state or county under the Act, or (3) providing some combination of returning and deducting funds. Requires the Secretary to waive the repayment requirement for any state or county that did not repay the required portion of the payment it received during FY2013 despite such order.</summary>
</bill>
