<bill session="113" type="s" number="1674" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-11-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-11-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-11-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Parent Education and Family Engagement in Early Childhood Care and Education Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to help establish, enhance, and increase access to early childhood parent education and family engagement programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412378"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2014-11-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-11-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/7/2013--Introduced.
Parent Education and Family Engagement in Early Childhood Care and Education Act - Authorizes the Secretary of Education and the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to award competitive matching grants to states and, through them, competitive subgrants to local agencies to establish, expand, or enhance early childhood and elementary school parent education and family engagement programs.

Requires a state to use: (1) at least 83% of its grant for subgrants to programs serving children from birth through age 5 and their parents, and (2) no more than 15% of its grant for subgrants to programs assisting children between age 5 and 8 and their parents with the transition to elementary school.

Requires the programs to include:

 support for activities that enhance the skills of parents in providing for and understanding their children's learning processes and intellectual, social, emotional, and physical development; training and professional development for early childhood educators in engaging parents in parent education and discussing parenting, behavior management, and healthy child development; training for parent educators and early childhood educators in detecting challenges to children's development and improving child and family health, safety, and stability; and coordination between early childhood educators and instructional staff at elementary schools in the same geographic area as the local agency. Prohibits subgrantees from using their subgrants for routine child care or early childhood education program services that are not directly related to parent education or family engagement programs.

Directs the Secretaries to arrange for the National Academy of Sciences (NAS) to evaluate early childhood parent education and family engagement programs and disseminate information on the best practices of those programs.

Prohibits this Act's funding from supplanting other federal, state, and local funds for such programs.</summary>
</bill>
