<bill session="113" type="s" number="2951" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-11-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-11-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-11-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Dignified Burial Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to ensure that the Secretary of Veterans Affairs is informed of the interment of deceased veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412218"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-11-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="5369"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Veterans' organizations and recognition"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/20/2014--Introduced.
Veterans Dignified Burial Act - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA): (1) upon confirming the veteran status of a deceased veteran in the custody of a local medical examiner, funeral director, county service group, or other similar entity, to request from such entity the specific date of the scheduled interment of such veteran; and (2) during each 30-day period following such request, to repeat the request until such entity confirms that such veteran has been interred.

Requires the Secretary, by January 31 of each year, to submit to the House and Senate Veterans' Affairs Committees a report on deceased veterans who were interred after the 30-day period following the date on which the Secretary made such request. Requires the report to include: (1) the number of deceased veterans who were not interred in such 30-day period during the prior year, (2) the number of such deceased veterans who are not interred as of the date of the report, and (3) the entity with custody of each such deceased veteran.</summary>
</bill>
