<bill session="113" type="h" number="5167" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-11-13T12:28:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-11-13T12:28:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Administrator of General Services, on behalf of the Secretary of the Interior, to convey certain Federal property located in the National Petroleum Reserve in Alaska to the Olgoonik Corporation, an Alaska Native Corporation established under the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act.</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by house">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to convey certain Federal property located in the National Petroleum Reserve in Alaska to the Olgoonik Corporation, an Alaska Native Corporation established under the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400440"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee Indian and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-09">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18">
      <text>Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18">
      <text>Subcommittee Indian and Alaska Native Affairs Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-09-18" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-11-12T19:45:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 113-618.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-11-12T19:46:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="459">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 459.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-11-13T12:25:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Young (AK) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-13T12:25:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7948-7949" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-13T12:25:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5167.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2014-11-13T12:28:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7948" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-11-13T12:28:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-13T12:28:00-05:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-17">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSII24" subcommittee="Indian and Alaska Native Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII10" subcommittee="Public Lands and Environmental Regulation" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="s" number="2684"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Strategic materials and reserves"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/22/2014--Introduced.
Directs the Administrator of General Services (GSA), on behalf of the Secretary of the Interior, to convey to the Olgoonik Corporation, an Alaska Native Corporation, approximately 1,518 acres of real property and improvements that comprise a former Distant Early Warning Line site in the National Petroleum Reserve near Wainwright, Alaska.

Requires the Corporation to pay the fair market value of the property.

Permits the Secretary to authorize the Corporation to enter the property at no charge for pre-construction and construction activities.

Exempts this conveyance from certain provisions of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969.</summary>
</bill>
