<bill session="113" type="s" number="2684" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Administrator of General Services, on behalf of the Secretary of the Interior, to convey certain Federal property located in the National Petroleum Reserve in Alaska to the Olgoonik Corporation, an Alaska Native Corporation established under the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300075"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2014-09-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="5167"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Strategic materials and reserves"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/29/2014--Introduced.
Directs the Administrator of General Services (GSA), on behalf of the Secretary of the Interior, to convey to the Olgoonik Corporation, an Alaska Native Corporation, approximately 1,518 acres of real property and improvements that comprise a former Distant Early Warning Line site in the National Petroleum Reserve near Wainwright, Alaska.

Requires the Corporation to pay the fair market value of the property.

Permits the Secretary to authorize the Corporation to enter the property at no charge for pre-construction and construction activities.

Exempts this conveyance from certain provisions of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969.</summary>
</bill>
