<bill session="113" type="h" number="5460" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medicare Ambulance Access, Fraud Prevention, and Reform Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to increase access to ambulance services under the Medicare program and to reform payments for such services under such program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400419"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2014-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412501" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412482" joined="2014-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412401" joined="2014-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412566" joined="2014-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400219" joined="2015-01-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400291" joined="2014-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400297" joined="2014-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2014-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412254" joined="2015-01-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412239" joined="2014-09-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-11">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-11">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Digestive and metabolic diseases"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/11/2014--Introduced.
Medicare Ambulance Access, Fraud Prevention, and Reform Act of 2014 - Amends part B (Supplementary Medical Insurance Benefits) of title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act with respect to the ambulance fee schedule to: (1) increase the conversion factor for ground ambulance services in the formula for determining the appropriate fee, and (2) increase the mileage rate for such services.

Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to study how the conversion factor should be modified, if at all, to take into account the cost of providing ambulance services in urban, rural, and super-rural areas.

Directs the Secretary to establish a process to determine, in advance of furnishing end stage rental disease (ESRD) ambulance services, whether payment for them may not be made because they are not covered or because they are excluded from coverage. Prohibits any payment unless the Secretary determines, pursuant to this process, that the service meets coverage requirements.

Directs the Secretary to develop a data collection system for providers and suppliers of ambulance services to collect cost, revenue, utilization, and other appropriate information.</summary>
</bill>
