<bill session="113" type="sr" number="482" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate that the area between the intersections of International Drive, Northwest Van Ness Street, Northwest International Drive, Northwest and International Place, Northwest in Washington, District of Columbia, should be designated as "Liu Xiaobo Plaza".</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412573"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400408" joined="2014-07-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3944" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/24/2014--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of the Senate that:

 the area between the intersections of International Drive, NW and Van Ness Street, NW and International Drive, NW and International Place, NW in Washington, DC, should be known and designated as "Liu Xiaobo Plaza," and any reference in a federal law, map, regulation, document, paper, or other record to that area should be deemed to be a reference to "Liu Xiaobo Plaza"; the address of 3505 International Place, NW, Washington, DC, should be redesignated as "1 Liu Xiaobo Plaza," and any reference in a federal law, map, regulation, document, paper, or other record to that address should be deemed to be a reference to "1 Liu Xiaobo Plaza"; and the Administrator of General Services (GSA) should construct street signs that: (1) contain the phrase "Liu Xiaobo Plaza"; (2) are similar in design to the signs used by Washington, DC to designate the location of Metro stations; and (3) should be placed on the parcel of federal property that is closest to "1 Liu Xiaobo Plaza" and the street corners of International Drive, NW and Van Ness Street, NW, and International Drive, NW and International Place, NW, Washington, DC.</summary>
</bill>
