<bill session="113" type="h" number="4037" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-02-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-02-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-02-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improving Veterans' Access to Vocational Rehabilitation and Employment Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to make certain improvements in the laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs relating to training and rehabilitation for veterans with service-connected disabilities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412480"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-02-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-25">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSVR10" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Housing for the elderly and disabled"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/11/2014--Introduced.
Improving Veterans' Access to Vocational Rehabilitation and Employment Act of 2014 - Requires the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA), when calculating the rate of veterans determined to be rehabilitated to the point of employability, to divide the number of veterans who participated in VA vocational rehabilitation programs whom the Secretary determines to have been so rehabilitated by the total number of veterans who: (1) participated in such programs during that fiscal year, and (2) were entitled to participate in such programs during such fiscal year but who did not complete a program.

Allows a course of education and training to be pursued by a veteran as part of a rehabilitation program only if the course is approved under VA vocational rehabilitation requirements.

Makes veterans enrolled in a VA vocational rehabilitation program eligible for VA specially adapted housing, when appropriate.

Authorizes the Secretary to prioritize VA vocational rehabilitation services based on need upon consideration of disability ratings, the severity of employment handicaps, qualification for a program of independent living, income, and other factors determined appropriate.</summary>
</bill>
