<bill session="113" type="h" number="3781" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-12-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-12-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-12-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Unemployed Worker Investment Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow small employers a credit against income tax for hiring individuals receiving unemployment compensation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412521"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412379" joined="2014-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412498" joined="2014-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412511" joined="2014-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412557" joined="2014-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412189" joined="2014-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400290" joined="2014-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412518" joined="2014-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412522" joined="2014-01-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-12-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/16/2013--Introduced.
American Unemployed Worker Investment Act of 2013 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a small business employer (i.e., an employer that employs more than 10 but fewer than 25 full-time employees throughout the taxable year) a work opportunity tax credit for hiring a qualified unemployment compensation recipient. Allows the first $10,000 of wages paid to such a recipient to be taken in account for purposes of such credit.

Defines "qualified unemployment compensation recipient" as any individual who is certified as: (1) not being a student for at least six months during the one-year period ending on the hiring date, (2) being in receipt of unemployment compensation on the hiring date, and (3) having a hiring date during the two-year period which begins on the enactment of this Act.

Denies such credit unless: (1) the&#160;qualified unemployment compensation recipient is employed for not&#160;less than 35 hours per week for not&#160;less than 1 year, and (2) the number of full-time employees of the employer receiving such credit is increased by 1 for at least 1 year.</summary>
</bill>
