<bill session="113" type="h" number="3602" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-11-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-11-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-11-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Filipino Temporary Protected Status Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To designate the Philippines under section 244 of the Immigration and Nationality Act to permit nationals of the Philippines to be eligible for temporary protected status under such section.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400653"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400021" joined="2014-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400041" joined="2014-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412379" joined="2014-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412418" joined="2014-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2013-11-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412521" joined="2014-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412560" joined="2014-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400364" joined="2013-11-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="2014-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412514" joined="2014-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="2014-03-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-11-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Border Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Philippines"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/21/2013--Introduced.
Filipino Temporary Protected Status Act of 2013 - Expresses the sense of Congress that the extraordinary and temporary conditions caused by flooding and other catastrophic damage wrought by Typhoon Haiyan in the Philippines qualifies the Philippines for designation under section 244 of the Immigration and Nationality Act, pursuant to which nationals of the Philippines would be eligible for temporary protected status in the United States.

Provides 18-month temporary protected status for a national of the Philippines who: (1) has been continuously physically present in the United States since November 8, 2013, (2) is admissible as an immigrant and not ineligible for temporary protected status, and (3) registers for temporary protected status in a manner that the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) shall establish.

Permits such an alien to travel abroad if the alien establishes to the satisfaction of the Secretary that emergency and extenuating circumstances beyond the alien's control require his or her departure for a brief, temporary trip abroad.</summary>
</bill>
