<bill session="113" type="h" number="4500" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve the management of cyber and information technology ranges and facilities of the Department of Defense, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412583"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2014-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412254" joined="2014-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Intelligence, Emerging Threats &amp; Capabilities.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS26" subcommittee="Intelligence, Emerging Threats &amp; Capabilities" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3304"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/28/2014--Introduced.
Amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2014 to require the Principal Cyber Advisor (PCA) (the principal advisor to the Secretary of Defense on military cyber forces) to establish and submit to Congress a comprehensive list of cyber and information technology ranges and facilities of the Department of Defense (DOD).

Defines "cyber and information technology ranges and facilities" as cyber ranges, test facilities, test beds, and other DOD means for testing, training, and developing software, personnel, and tools for accommodating DOD's mission.

Requires the PCA to determine, on a case-by-case basis, whether listed ranges and facilities should be managed centrally to increase efficiency, should provide capability or capacity to more DOD elements, or both.

Directs the Secretary to establish or designate an entity to coordinate such ranges and facilities that the PCA determines should be centrally managed. Requires the head of such entity to: (1) manage and identify opportunities for integration of such ranges and facilities; and (2) assist the military departments, the National Guard, and elements of DOD to gain access to such ranges and facilities.

Requires the PCA to establish and maintain a list of commonly used terms relating to cyber matters to improve the coordination and cooperation among the military departments and other federal agencies.

Directs the head of the coordination entity to carry out one or more pilot programs to demonstrate commercially available, cloud-based cyber training, exercise, and test environments that are accessible to defense laboratories, the National Guard, academia, and the private sector.</summary>
</bill>
