<bill session="113" type="h" number="5272" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-08-01T21:56:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-08-01T21:56:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit certain actions with respect to deferred action for aliens not lawfully present in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400032"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-30T23:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 696 Reported to House. The rule makes in order one hour of debate each for H.R. 5230 and H.R. 5272. The rule also makes in order for one hour debate on a motion that the House disagree to the Senate amendment to H.R. 5021. Any motion pursuant to clause 4 of rule XXII relating to H.R. 5021 may be offered only by the Majority Leader or his designee. It shall be in order at any time on the legislative day of July 31, 2014 for the Speaker to entertain motions to suspend the rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-08-01T17:40:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 710 Reported to House. Provides for further consideration of H.R. 5230 and for consideration of H.R. 5272. Both bills are debatable for 1 hour. The amendments to H.R. 5230printed in part A of the report shall be considered as adopted. The amendment to H.R. 5272 printed in Part B of the report shall be considered as adopted. The rule provides for one motion to recommit with or without instructions for each measure. The rule amends section 2 of H.Res. 700 to allow for motions to suspend the rules with respect to a measure addressing missile defense of Israel.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-08-01T19:08:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 710 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-08-01T20:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 710.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7228-7236" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-08-01T20:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Provides for further consideration of H.R. 5230 and for consideration of H.R. 5272. Both bills are debatable for 1 hour. The amendments to H.R. 5230printed in part A of the report shall be considered as adopted. The amendment to H.R. 5272 printed in Part B of the report shall be considered as adopted. The rule provides for one motion to recommit with or without instructions for each measure. The rule amends section 2 of H.Res. 700 to allow for motions to suspend the rules with respect to a measure addressing missile defense of Israel.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-08-01T20:42:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 5272.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-08-01T21:32:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7235" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="479" datetime="2014-08-01T21:56:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 216 - 192, 1 Present (Roll no. 479).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7228-7229" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-08-01T21:56:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-08-05">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-09-08" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="551">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 551.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Border Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hr" number="696"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="113" type="hr" number="696"/>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="113" type="hr" number="696"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="113" type="hr" number="710"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h1133"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>8/1/2014--Passed House amended.
Prohibits a federal agency or instrumentality from using federal funding or resources after July 30, 2014, to:

 consider or adjudicate any new or previously denied application of any alien requesting consideration of deferred action for childhood arrivals, as authorized by Executive memorandum dated June 15, 2012, or by any other succeeding Executive memorandum or policy authorizing a similar program; newly authorize deferred action for any class of aliens not lawfully present in the United States; or authorize any alien to work in the United States who was not lawfully admitted into the United States and who is not in lawful U.S. status on the date of enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
