<bill session="113" type="s" number="2498" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HALOS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Helping Angels Lead Our Startups Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to clarify the definition of general solicitation under Federal securities law.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412194"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412545" joined="2014-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2014-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412507" joined="2014-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2014-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400408" joined="2014-06-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="4915"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/19/2014--Introduced.
Helping Angels Lead Our Startups Act or the HALOS Act - Directs the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to amend Regulation D (governing the limited offer and sale of securities without registration under the Securities Act of 1933) to make the prohibition against general solicitation or general advertising inapplicable to events with specified kinds of sponsors (including angel investor groups not connected to broker-dealers or investment advisers) where:

 presentations or communications are made by or on behalf of an issuer, the advertising does not refer to any specific offering of securities by the issuer, the sponsor does not engage in certain activities (such as offering investment recommendations or advice to attendees), and no specific information regarding a securities offering is communicated (other than that the issuer is in the process of offering or planning to offer securities, including the type and amount of securities being offered).</summary>
</bill>
