<bill session="113" type="h" number="4229" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-03-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-03-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-03-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Venezuelan Liberty and Democratic Solidarity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To seek international sanctions against the Government of Venezuela with respect to foreign persons responsible for or complicit in ordering, controlling, or otherwise directing, the commission of serious human rights abuses against citizens of Venezuela, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400344"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412250" joined="2014-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="2014-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412526" joined="2014-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412385" joined="2014-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400108" joined="2014-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412479" joined="2014-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412529" joined="2014-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412532" joined="2014-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412530" joined="2014-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412276" joined="2014-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412451" joined="2014-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400654" joined="2014-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412527" joined="2014-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400606" joined="2014-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412186" joined="2014-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="2014-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400623" joined="2014-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412412" joined="2014-03-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-03-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, Ways and Means, and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-13">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-13">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-13">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-13">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Africa, Global Health, Global Human Rights and International Organizations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Western Hemisphere.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA16" subcommittee="Africa, Global Health, Global Human Rights and International Organizations" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA07" subcommittee="Western Hemisphere" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Border Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international banking"/>
    <term name="Foreign property"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International exchange and broadcasting"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Organization of American States"/>
    <term name="Political movements and philosophies"/>
    <term name="Property rights"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="Venezuela"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/13/2014--Introduced.
Venezuelan Liberty and Democratic Solidarity Act - Directs the Secretary of State to require the U.S. Permanent Representative to the Organization of American States (OAS) to use U.S. influence at the OAS to protect the Inter-American Democratic Charter, and strengthen the independent Inter-American Commission on Human Rights to protect human rights throughout the Western Hemisphere, especially in Venezuela.

Directs the President to transmit to Congress a list of Venezuelan government officials or persons acting on behalf of that government who are responsible for or complicit in serious human rights abuses against citizens of Venezuela or their family members.

Directs the President to transmit to Congress a list of persons who: (1) transfer or facilitate the transfer of goods or technologies that are likely to be used to commit serious rights abuses to Venezuela, to any entity organized under the laws of Venezuela, or to any national of Venezuela, for use in Venezuela; or (2) provide services with respect to such goods or technologies after their transfer to Venezuela.

Directs the President to transmit to Congress a list of persons who have engaged in censorship or other activities with respect to Venezuela that: (1) prohibit, limit, or penalize the exercise of freedom of expression or assembly; or (2) limit access to print or broadcast media, including facilitation of intentional frequency manipulation.

Imposes property, financial, and visa sanctions against a person listed pursuant to this Act.

States that it should be U.S. policy to reduce petroleum imports from Venezuela to prevent its leader Nicolas Maduro from using petroleum profits to fund his regime's oppression and human rights violations.

Directs the Secretary of State to submit comprehensive strategies to Congress to: (1) promote internet and information access freedom in Venezuela, and (2) ensure that the government of Venezuela will uphold democratic principles and is moving toward market-oriented economic systems.

States that it shall be U.S. policy to: (1) support efforts to identify prisoners of conscience and cases of human rights abuses in Venezuela, and (2) offer refugee status or political asylum in the United States to political dissidents in Venezuela or assist in their relocation to other countries.

Obligates specified amounts for assistance to civil society in Venezuela.</summary>
</bill>
