<bill session="113" type="h" number="5192" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">THRIFT Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">To Help Reduce Inefficient Federal Tendencies Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for incentives for agencies and the judiciary to increase operating efficiency.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412410"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-24">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-24">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, Intellectual Property, and the Internet.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts, Intellectual Property, and the Internet" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU05" subcommittee="Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal appellate courts"/>
    <term name="Federal district courts"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/24/2014--Introduced.
To Help Reduce Inefficient Federal Tendencies Act of 2014 or&#160;the THRIFT Act of 2014 - Allows federal agencies, including judicial branch agencies, to: (1) retain up to 25% of annual savings from the implementation of plans developed by such agencies to create efficiencies and cost savings in agency operations, and (2) use such savings for specified purposes, including salary increases and employee awards for cost savings disclosures. Requires an agency to&#160;submit to the appropriate congressional committees a plan and an associated request to amend its approved operating budget specifying how such savings will be achieved and the amount and source of such savings.</summary>
</bill>
