<bill session="113" type="h" number="5436" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">AGE-IN Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Assistance in Gaining Experience, Independence, and Navigation Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Services Act to provide research, training, and navigator services to youth and young adults on the verge of aging out of the secondary educational system, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412453"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1259"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Hereditary and development disorders"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
    <term name="Youth employment and child labor"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/10/2014--Introduced.
Assistance in Gaining Experience, Independence, and Navigation Act of 2014 or the AGE-IN Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to award a grant to: (1) analyze existing research on youth and young adults with an autism spectrum disorder or other developmental disabilities as they transition out of the school-based support system; (2) research existing infrastructure for transitioning youth, including access to health care, continuing education programs, and community integration programs; and (3) develop a strategic plan for a Transition Navigator Grant Program to provide transitioning youth with support services.

Requires the Secretary to establish a Transition Navigator Grant Program to award grants to provide services based on the strategic plan. Directs the Secretary to contract a third party to evaluate the effectiveness of grantees in meeting the goals of the strategic plan.</summary>
</bill>
