<bill session="113" type="s" number="1745" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-11-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-11-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-11-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Somalia Stabilization Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to promote security, stability and good governance in Somalia through a coordinated interagency strategy that supports the consolidation of recent security and political gains in Somalia.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412390"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-11-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Somalia"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/20/2013--Introduced.
Somalia Stabilization Act of 2013 - Expresses the sense of Congress that the United States should: (1) support the Somali Federal Government, regional administrations, federal units, and people in their efforts to consolidate political gains and develop credible and representative government systems and institutions; (2) support African-led regional efforts to improve security and stability in Somalia; (3) support the development of professional and regionally and ethnically representative Somali security forces; (4) provide humanitarian assistance as needed while building a foundation for Somalia's development; and (5) carry out all diplomatic, economic, intelligence, military, and development activities in Somalia within the context of a comprehensive strategy coordinated through an interagency process.

Directs the President to submit to Congress a strategy to guide future U.S. action in support of the government and people of Somalia to foster economic growth, counter armed threats to stability, and develop credible and representative government systems and institutions.</summary>
</bill>
