<bill session="113" type="h" number="4876" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Emerging Business Encouragement Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Small Business Act to provide for contracting preferences and other benefits for emerging business enterprises, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412258"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400041" joined="2014-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="2014-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2014-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412263" joined="2014-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412535" joined="2014-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2014-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412312" joined="2014-06-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/17/2014--Introduced.
Emerging Business Encouragement Act of 2014 - Amends the Small Business Act to direct the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA), for each industry category for which the Administrator established a size standard, to establish procedures, by rule, for designating a small business in that industry category as an emerging business enterprise (EBE).

Requires the procedures to include specified criteria and a process for appealing the Administrator's decisions on designations.

Requires the designation to expire when the small business is no longer in compliance with the criteria, except that:

 in the case of an EBE which existed as a business entity before its EBE designation, the designation shall not expire until five years after it was made; and if the EBE exceeds the required size limitation its designation shall expire only if the size is 50% or more of the maximum size of a small business within that industry category. Directs the Administrator to establish criteria for designation of an EBE, including:

 a maximum number of employees determined according to a certain formula, an age of not more than five years, and a specified salary limitation for any individual who owns any part of the small business or who is in a management position. Requires the head of each federal agency to establish goals for participation by the designated EBEs in at least 5% of all contracts, including prime contracts and subcontracts, for each fiscal year.

Authorizes the Administrator to make a loan to a designated EBE under the SBA Express Loan Program, but only in accordance with specified terms.

Requires the Administrator, by rule, to establish a process for initial self-certification of EBEs for purposes of participation in federal contracts and eligibility for the Express Loans.</summary>
</bill>
