<bill session="113" type="h" number="4993" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To clarify the effect of State statutes of repose on the required commencement date for actions under the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400616"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400110" joined="2014-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400326" joined="2014-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412319" joined="2014-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="2014-06-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Transportation and Infrastructure, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-26">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-26">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-26">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU10" subcommittee="Constitution and Civil Justice" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="s" number="2542"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/26/2014--Introduced.
Amends the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (CERCLA) to preempt a state statute of repose for actions brought under state law for personal injury or property damages caused from or contributed to by exposure to any hazardous substance, pollutant, or contaminant, if the state statute provides a commencement date that is earlier than the federally required commencement date. (Currently, CERCLA preempts state statutes of limitations, which limit the amount of time a lawsuit can commence from the time the contamination is discovered. The Supreme Court ruled in CTS Corp. v. Waldburger that North Carolina's statute of repose was not preempted by CERCLA. That statute of repose limits the amount of time a lawsuit can commence to 10 years from the defendant's last action, regardless of when the contamination is discovered.)</summary>
</bill>
