<bill session="113" type="h" number="4088" updated="2015-09-01T17:49:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-02-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-02-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-02-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Help Communities Fight Violent Crime Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide funding for Violent Crime Reduction Partnerships in the most violent communities in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412546"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-02-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Appropriations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-25">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-25">
      <text>Referred to House Appropriations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Urban and suburban affairs and development"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/25/2014--Introduced.
Help Communities Fight Violent Crime Act - Authorizes appropriations for FY2014-FY2018 to the Director of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives (ATF) for the conduct of Violent Crime Reduction Partnerships in: (1) the 10 most violent cities in the United States with a population of more than 100,000 individuals, and (2) any community that is in close proximity to any such city.

Authorizes the Director to transfer such appropriated funds to any other federal agency or instrumentality for conducting activities under such a Partnership.</summary>
</bill>
