<bill session="113" type="s" number="2287" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-05-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Carbon Capture and Sequestration Deployment Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to facilitate the development and commercial deployment of carbon capture and sequestration technologies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300084"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412602" joined="2014-05-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2648-2649"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/5/2014--Introduced.
Carbon Capture and Sequestration Deployment Act of 2014 - Directs the Department of Energy (DOE) to establish a cooperative industry-government research and development program to demonstrate innovative technologies to capture, prevent, or store carbon dioxide (CO2) emissions from carbon-based fuels or to enable the beneficial use of CO2.

Requires DOE to conduct an annual assessment of existing programs supporting carbon capture and sequestration (CCS) technology until that technology is available in commerce. (CCS is a three-step process: the capture, transport, and underground injection and geologic sequestration of CO2.)

Amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to the tax credit for CO2 sequestration, to: (1) impose limitations on the allocation of credit amounts for carbon capture projects, including a 10-year limitation on CO2 capture at a qualified facility (defined as an industrial facility which captures not less than 500,000 metric tons of CO2 in a taxable year); (2) require the Secretary of the Treasury to establish procedures for allocating the national limitation on such credit to projects for placing carbon capture equipment (i.e., equipment to capture and pressurize qualified CO2) in service at qualified facilities and for certifying projects for which an allocation has been made; and (3) identify as eligible for such credit the taxpayer who captures and disposes of the qualified CO2.

Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to authorize DOE to make loan guarantees to: (1) construct or retrofit coal- or petroleum coke-fired industrial facilities or electric generation facilities to utilize CCS technology, and (2) construct pipelines for the transport of CO2 to sequestration sites or to sites where the C02 will be used for hydrocarbon recovery. Expands the qualifying advanced coal project investment tax credit to include an additional amount for the costs of constructing and retrofitting such facilities.</summary>
</bill>
