<bill session="113" type="s" number="2506" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Correctly Recognizing Educational Achievements To Empower Graduates Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CREATE Graduates Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to award grants to States to support efforts at institutions of higher education to increase degree attainment, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412324"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2014-06-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2954"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/19/2014--Introduced.
Correctly Recognizing Educational Achievements To Empower Graduates Act or the CREATE Graduates Act - Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to direct the Secretary of Education to award competitive grants to states and, through them, subgrants to institutions of higher education (IHEs) or systems of higher education to:

 identify current or former students who have earned at least 60 postsecondary credit hours (or the state-required minimum for earning an associate's degree) at the IHE or at an IHE within the system but have not been issued a postsecondary degree by such IHE or an associate's or bachelor's degree elsewhere; perform a degree audit on each of those students to identify those who are eligible to obtain an associate's degree and those who are eligible to obtain such a degree upon the completion of 12 or fewer postsecondary credit hours (or the equivalent); provide outreach and award an associate's degree to each of those students identified as eligible to obtain an associate's degree unless the student declines the degree; and provide outreach to those students identified as eligible to obtain such a degree upon the completion of 12 or fewer postsecondary credit hours, including guidance on the steps they can take to attain such a degree. Allows states to use up to: (1) 15% of their grant for administrative purposes, including the purchase of the technology to carry out grant requirements; and (2) 5% of their grant to create articulation agreements between 2-year and 4-year IHEs to facilitate the transfer of students between such schools.</summary>
</bill>
