<bill session="113" type="h" number="3782" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-12-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-12-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-12-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Native American Seeds Protection Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Agriculture, in consultation with Indian tribes, to make grants, competitive grants, and special research grants to, and enter into cooperative agreements and other contracting instruments with, eligible entities to conduct research and education and training programs to protect and preserve Native American seeds, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412558"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400077" joined="2014-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412505" joined="2014-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412403" joined="2014-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2014-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412511" joined="2014-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412293" joined="2013-12-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400259" joined="2014-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412527" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400313" joined="2014-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400316" joined="2014-03-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-12-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Horticulture, Research, Biotechnology, and Foreign Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG14" subcommittee="Horticulture, Research, Biotechnology, and Foreign Agriculture" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2116"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural education"/>
    <term name="Agricultural practices and innovations"/>
    <term name="Agricultural research"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Horticulture and plants"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/16/2013--Introduced.
Native American Seeds Protection Act of 2013 - Amends the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977 to authorize the Secretary of Agriculture to award grants to, and enter into agreements with, Indian tribes and 1994 Institutions to conduct research and education and training programs concerning the purity of Native American seeds. (1994 Institutions are Native American tribally-controlled colleges and universities that were granted land-grant status in 1994.)

Requires grant applicants to certify that any research conducted will be performed under a cooperative agreement with at least one other entity that has the capacity and infrastructure necessary to carry out agricultural research projects.

Authorizes the use of the grants to fund research to assess the impact of: (1) public law and policies on traditional ways of life and cultural practices relating to the harvesting and cultivating of Native American seeds, and (2) contaminants that compromise the integrity and purity of those seeds.

Authorizes the use of the grants to fund education and training programs on: (1) the methods necessary to conduct such research; and (2) the best methods to continuously test, monitor, and otherwise protect the purity of Native American seeds.

Amends the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act to authorize the use of grants under the community facilities grant program to expand, construct, and develop seed storage facilities that are used to protect and preserve Native American seeds.</summary>
</bill>
