<bill session="113" type="s" number="2076" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-26">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-06-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-03-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">U.S. Merchant Marine Academy Board of Visitors Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">U.S. Merchant Marine Academy Board of Visitors Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">U.S. Merchant Marine Academy Board of Visitors Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the provisions of title 46, United States Code, related to the Board of Visitors to the United States Merchant Marine Academy, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400040"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2014-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412321" joined="2014-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2014-03-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-03-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-04-09" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-05-14">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Rockefeller without amendment. With written report No. 113-158.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-05-14" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="375">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 375.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-06-26">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4188-4189" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2014-06-26" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with amendments by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4188-4189" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-06-30">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-03T12:32:00-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="4144"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s3442"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>6/26/2014--Passed Senate amended.
U.S. Merchant Marine Academy Board of Visitors Enhancement Act - Amends federal shipping law to: (1) expand the membership of the Board of Visitors to the U. S. Merchant Marine Academy, and (2) specify requirements for the presidential appointees.

Authorizes certain Board members to designate another individual to serve as a substitute member of the Board, on a temporary basis, to attend or participate in any activity the Board member is unable to attend or participate in. Prescribes requirements for designated substitute Board members.

Requires the Board to select biennially from among its members a member of the House of Representatives or a Senator to serve as Board Chairperson.

Directs the Secretary of Transportation (DOT) to select a Designated Federal Officer to support the performance of the Board's functions.

Directs the Board to report annually to the President on its actions, views, and recommendations with respect to the Academy.</summary>
</bill>
