<bill session="113" type="h" number="5428" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Return of Certain Lands At Fort Wingate to The Original Inhabitants Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the implementation of the negotiated property division regarding Former Fort Wingate Depot Activity in McKinley County, New Mexico, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400313"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee Indian and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII24" subcommittee="Indian and Alaska Native Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="Public Lands and Environmental Regulation" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3822"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/9/2014--Introduced.
Return of Certain Lands At Fort Wingate to The Original Inhabitants Act - Requires all U.S. interest in and to specified lands of the former Fort Wingate Depot Activity in McKinley County, New Mexico (Activity), transferred to the Secretary of the Interior to be held in trust for: (1) the Zuni Tribe as part of the Zuni Reservation, unless the Tribe elects to have the parcel conveyed to it in restricted fee status; and (2) the Navajo Nation as part of the Navajo Reservation, unless the Navajo Nation elects to have the parcel conveyed to it in restricted fee status.

Subjects the lands of the Activity held in trust or conveyed in restricted fee status to reservation by the United States of such easements as the Secretary of the Army determines are reasonably required to permit access to Activity lands for administrative, environmental cleanup, and environmental remediation purposes.

Requires the lands of the Activity identified as parcel 1 to be held in trust subject to a shared easement for cultural and religious purposes only.

Requires the access road for the Activity that originates at the frontage road for Interstate 40 and leads to the parcel of the administration area to be held in common by both the Zuni Tribe and the Navajo Nation to provide for equal access to the Activity.

Subjects lands held in trust or conveyed in restricted fee status to easements reasonably required to permit access to the Missile Defense Agency facility as needed by the Department of Defense (DOD).

Requires the Zuni Tribe or the Navajo Nation, after a parcel of land has been transferred or conveyed, to notify the Secretary of the Army of the existence or discovery of any contamination or hazardous material on it.</summary>
</bill>
