<bill session="113" type="s" number="1014" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-04-09">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-04-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Youth Sports Concussion Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Youth Sports Concussion Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reduce sports-related concussions in youth, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400413"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2014-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2014-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2013-05-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-04-09" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-12-08">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Rockefeller with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-12-08" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="618">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 618.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-12-12">
      <text>By Senator Rockefeller from Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation filed written report. Report No. 113-310.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2118"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Athletes"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer Product Safety Commission"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="School athletics"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/8/2014--Reported to Senate amended.
Youth Sports Concussion Act - Expresses the sense of Congress that the Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC) and the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) should review the National Academies' report on sports-related concussions in youth, and future research in this area, for any matter that may impact products under the CPSC's jurisdiction or inform the FTC's efforts to protect consumers.

Makes it unlawful to sell or offer for sale in interstate commerce, or import into the United States for such purposes, athletic sporting equipment for which the seller or importer makes any deceptive claim with respect to the safety benefits of such item.

Requires violations to be treated as unfair or deceptive acts or practices under the Federal Trade Commission Act.

Sets forth the enforcement authority of the FTC. Authorizes the FTC to promulgate regulations to carry out this Act.

Authorizes states to bring civil actions in federal court to obtain injunctive relief on behalf of state residents unless a civil or administrative action has already been instituted by the FTC. Allows the FTC to intervene and appeal in state actions.</summary>
</bill>
