<bill session="113" type="s" number="1877" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-12-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-12-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-12-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Child Support Improvement and Work Promotion Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to increase the reliability of child support for children, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300005"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="2013-12-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="2013-12-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2013-12-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2013-12-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2013-12-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-12-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1896"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1870"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction and venue"/>
    <term name="Separation, divorce, custody, support"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/19/2013--Introduced.
Child Support Improvement and Work Promotion Act - Amends part D (Child Support and Establishment of Paternity) of title IV of the Social Security Act (SSA) to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to utilize federal and state enforcement mechanisms and take necessary steps to ensure compliance with the U.S. treaty obligations under any multilateral child support convention in the event that a state plan does not comply with those obligations.

Authorizes a Central Authority for child support enforcement in a foreign reciprocating country or a foreign treaty country to obtain information from the Federal Parent Locator Service for the purpose of establishing parentage or child support obligations, and enforcing them.

Authorizes a state to require residents of a foreign reciprocating country or foreign treaty country who apply for services relating to establishment of paternity or child support obligations to make such an application through the foreign country's Central Authority for child support enforcement. Allows the state to accept or reject the application of any individual residing in a foreign country that is not a foreign reciprocating country or a foreign treaty country.

Allows collection of past-due support from federal tax refunds in response to a request from a foreign reciprocating country or a foreign treaty country.

Amends the federal judicial code with respect to full faith and credit for child support orders to revise requirements for state tribunals with appropriate jurisdiction to modify child support orders including an order issued in that state if one party resides in another state. Allows individual contestants to a child support order to consent to allow a state tribunal to continue to exercise jurisdiction to modify the order, or to change the tribunal and jurisdiction, in certain circumstances, to those of another state.

Allows issuance of passports to certain individuals with annual incomes of under $100,000 who owe arrearages of child support but have been making such payments over a period of time.

Authorizes child support enforcement programs operated by Indian tribes to conduct an experimental, pilot, or demonstration project to assist in promoting the SSA title IV part D objectives.

Authorizes establishment of voluntary parenting time arrangements under state part D plans.

Increases from 24 to 48 months the length of time information entered into the data base maintained by the National Directory of New Hires shall remain before being deleted.

Authorizes the Secretary to provide access to data in each component of the Federal Parent Locator Service for certain related federal or state research as well as assessments of the effectiveness of a federal program in achieving positive labor market outcomes.

Establishes in the executive branch a Child Support Enforcement Task Force.</summary>
</bill>
