<bill session="113" type="h" number="3432" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-10-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-10-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">New Mexico Wildland Fire Emergency Salvage Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To expedite the planning and implementation of salvage timber sales as part of Forest Service and Department of the Interior restoration and rehabilitation activities for lands within the Gila and Lincoln National Forests and for Bureau of Land Management lands in New Mexico adversely impacted by the 2012 and 2013 fire seasons, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400313"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-30">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-30">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Energy, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG15" subcommittee="Conservation, Energy, and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="Public Lands and Environmental Regulation" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/30/2013--Introduced.
New Mexico Wildland Fire Emergency Salvage Act of 2013 - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA), with respect to affected National Forest System lands, and the Secretary of the Interior, with respect to affected Bureau of Land Management (BLM) lands, as part of the restoration and rehabilitation activities undertaken on lands within the Gila National Forest and Lincoln National Forest and on BLM lands adversely impacted by the 2012 Little Bear and Whitewater-Baldy Complex Fires and the 2013 Silver Fire in New Mexico, to promptly plan and implement salvage timber sales of dead, damaged, or downed timber resulting from such wildfires.

Requires such salvage timber sales to proceed immediately and to completion.

Declares the such sales shall not be subject to administrative or judicial review in any U.S. court.</summary>
</bill>
