<bill session="113" type="s" number="2584" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Educating Tomorrow's Workforce Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 to raise the quality of career and technical education programs and to allow local eligible recipients to use funding to establish high-quality career academics.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412582"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400325" joined="2014-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412321" joined="2014-07-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4406-4408"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4408-4409" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/10/2014--Introduced.
Educating Tomorrow's Workforce Act of 2014 - Amends the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 to revise the requirements for the plan of a state seeking federal assistance for career and technical education programs. Requires the state plan to describe how the eligible state agency will ensure the quality of any program of study culminating in an industry-recognized certificate, credential, or license.

Requires state agency leadership activities to support career academies which:

 implement a college and career ready curriculum at the secondary education level integrating rigorous academic, technical, and employability contents; include experiential or work-based learning for secondary school students, in collaboration with local and regional employers; include opportunities for secondary school students to earn postsecondary credit while in secondary school; and establish and maintain ongoing partnerships between the local educational agency, business and industry, and institutions of higher education, or postsecondary vocational institutions, including local government. Requires the local plan for career and technical education programs to describe: (1) how the eligible recipient of assistance will assess local needs related to career and technical education as part of the local plan development process, and (2) how this needs assessment will be updated annually, especially on progress toward specific elements leading to high-quality implementation of career and technical education programs of study.

Authorizes the local use of funds for improving such programs to support career academies.</summary>
</bill>
