<bill session="113" type="h" number="5696" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-11-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-11-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-11-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Hong Kong Human Rights and Democracy Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reinstate reporting requirements related to United States-Hong Kong relations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400380"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400630" joined="2014-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400314" joined="2014-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400343" joined="2014-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412214" joined="2014-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="2014-11-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-11-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="s" number="2922"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Hong Kong"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International exchange and broadcasting"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="Political movements and philosophies"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="United Kingdom"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/13/2014--Introduced.
Hong Kong Human Rights and Democracy Act - Amends the United States-Hong Kong Policy Act of 1992 to direct the Secretary of State to report to Congress on conditions in Hong Kong that are of U.S. interest by March 31, 2015, and annually thereafter for 10 years or until the Secretary certifies that Hong Kong has held free and fair elections for 2 consecutive Chief Executive and 2 consecutive Legislative Council periods.

States that it is U.S. policy to:

 reaffirm the principles set forth in the United States-Hong Kong Policy Act of 1992; support the democratic aspirations of the people of Hong Kong; urge China's government to uphold its commitments to Hong Kong; support the establishment by 2017 of a democratic option to nominate and elect the Chief Executive of Hong Kong, and the establishment by 2020 of democratic elections for all members of the Hong Kong Legislative Council; and support freedom of the press. States that Hong Kong is ineligible for treatment different from that accorded to China under U.S. laws or agreements unless the President certifies to Congress that Hong Kong is sufficiently autonomous to justify different treatment.

Authorizes the President to waive such ineligibility if waiver is in the U.S. national interest and Congress is given a justification of the waiver on or before the date it takes effect.</summary>
</bill>
