<bill session="113" type="h" number="5707" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-11-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-11-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-11-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ebola Response Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the President to take action to protect against the transmission of Ebola virus from individuals traveling to the United States from abroad, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412525"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412309" joined="2014-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="410396" joined="2014-11-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-11-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Immigrant health and welfare"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/13/2014--Introduced.
Ebola Response Act of 2014 - Requires the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) and the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to prohibit any individual from entering the United States for 30 days following the individual's presence in a country experiencing an Ebola outbreak.

Directs DHS and HHS to ensure that individuals who are nationals of or have recently been in a country experiencing an Ebola outbreak are certified by a medical professional as testing negative for Ebola and having a normal body temperature before they enter the United States and submit to 21 days of monitoring for Ebola symptoms.

Allows the President to exempt officials, employees, and contractors of the Department of State and the Department of Defense (DOD) from the requirements of this Act if there are sufficient measures in place to protect against the transmission of Ebola by these individuals.</summary>
</bill>
