<bill session="113" type="h" number="5803" updated="2015-09-01T17:50:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-12-11T21:56:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-12-11T21:56:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-12-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of the Interior to assemble a team of technical, policy, and financial experts to address the energy needs of the insular areas of the United States and the Freely Associated States through the development of energy action plans aimed at promoting access to affordable, reliable energy, including increasing use of indigenous clean-energy resources, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400073"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400041" joined="2014-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400128" joined="2014-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412306" joined="2014-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412312" joined="2014-12-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-12-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-11T21:55:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Whitfield asked unanimous consent to discharge from committee and consider.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-11T21:55:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Commerce discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-11T21:55:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9292" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="without objection" type="vote" datetime="2014-12-11T21:56:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9292" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-12-11T21:56:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-12">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="83"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="s" number="2986"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="American Samoa"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Marshall Islands"/>
    <term name="Micronesia"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="Palau"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="U.S. territories and protectorates"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/8/2014--Introduced.
Requires the Department of the Interior to establish within the Empowering Insular Communities activity a team of technical, policy, and financial experts to: (1) develop an energy action plan addressing the energy needs of each of the insular areas (American Samoa, the Northern Mariana Islands, Puerto Rico, Guam, and the Virgin Islands) and Freely Associated States (Micronesia, the Marshall Islands, and Palau); and (2) assist each of the insular areas and Freely Associated States in implementing the plan.

Requires the plan to include: (1) recommendations to reduce reliance and expenditures on fuel shipped to the insular areas and Freely Associated States from ports outside the United States, to develop and utilize domestic fuel energy sources, and to improve performance of energy infrastructure and overall energy efficiency; (2) a schedule for implementation of the recommendations and identification and prioritization of specific projects; (3) a financial and engineering plan for implementing and sustaining projects; and (4) benchmarks for measuring progress toward implementation.

Requires Interior to approve the plan before it is implemented.

Extends the federal immigration law transition period for the Northern Mariana Islands through December 31, 2019, including the annual reduction of nonimmigrant workers who may be admitted during such period.</summary>
</bill>
