<bill session="113" type="h" number="4522" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-04-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-04-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the Green Bank to assist in the financing of qualified clean energy projects and qualified energy efficiency projects.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400415"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2014-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412571" joined="2014-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2014-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412193" joined="2014-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412524" joined="2014-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412282" joined="2014-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400230" joined="2014-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2014-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2014-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400364" joined="2014-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="2014-04-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-30">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-30">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="s" number="2271"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Government corporations and government-sponsored enterprises"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Lighting and heating"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Taxation of foreign income"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/30/2014--Introduced.
Establishes the Green Bank as a federally-owned independent corporation with a 20-year charter. Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to issue Green Bonds in order to provide the Bank with an initial capitalization of $10 billion and to provide additional capitalization of up to $50 billion upon request of the Bank.

Requires the Bank to establish a program to provide financial support or risk management for qualifying clean energy or energy efficiency projects.

Authorizes the Bank to provide funding for low-interest loans to establish state clean energy financing institutions and to co-fund the projects with an institution.

Gives the Bank immunity from impairment, limitations, or restrictions under laws. Authorizes the Bank to conduct its business without regard to state law relating to incorporation.

Exempts the Bank from all state or local taxation except real property taxation.

Requires the Chief Executive Officer of the Bank to set forth spending safeguards, including: (1) deobligating financial support to entities that demonstrate an insufficient level of performance or wasteful or fraudulent spending, and (2) creating a publicly available online database with information about financing support or risk management.

Amends the Internal Revenue Code to limit and defer tax deduction amounts for foreign-related interest expense (i.e., interest expense allocated and apportioned to income from sources outside the United States).</summary>
</bill>
