<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="HD4669A41F1C44D7587966C9E407DCC2D" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HRES 652 IH: Condemning the President of the United States and the executive branch of Government for continuous actions that violate the laws and Constitution of the United States.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2014-06-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 652</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20140626">June 26, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001048">Mr. Culberson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000168">Mr. Olson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000067">Mr. Hall</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001248">Mr. Burgess</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000033">Mr. Young of Alaska</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001183">Mr. Schweikert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000250">Mr. Sessions</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000182">Mr. Neugebauer</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Condemning the President of the United States and the executive branch of Government for continuous
			 actions that violate the laws and Constitution of the United States.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas><text>Whereas the President violated the Constitution by unilaterally changing sections of the Affordable
			 Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/148">Public Law 111–148</external-xref>) 23 times without congressional approval;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the President and the Department of Justice, in direct violation of their constitutional
			 responsibility, decided to not enforce Federal law with regards to the
			 Defense of Marriage Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/199">Public Law 104–199</external-xref>);</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the President and the Department of Justice continues to choose not to enforce Federal drug
			 laws (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/91/513">Public Law 91–513</external-xref>, the Controlled Substances Act, and Public Law
			 100–690, the Anti-Drug Abuse Act of 1986);</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the President violated the Constitution by making presidential appointments to the National
			 Labor Relations Board and the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau while
			 Congress was not in session;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the President and the Department of Justice abused executive privilege with regards to the
			 Operation Fast and Furious scandal, by refusing to comply with a subpoena
			 issued by
			 the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of
			 Representatives in violation of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/192">section 192</external-xref> of title 2, United States
			 Code;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the President violated the law (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/89/236">Public Law 89–236</external-xref>) when he unilaterally changed our
			 Nation’s immigration laws with regards to Deferred Action;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the President and the Department of Health and Human Services failed to enforce Federal law
			 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/5">Public Law 111–5</external-xref>) by illegally waiving the work requirement for welfare
			 recipients;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Internal Revenue Service violated the First Amendment to the United States Constitution
			 by targeting non-profit organizations because of their religious or
			 political beliefs;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the President and the Department of Defense knowingly violated the National Defense
			 Authorization Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/66">Public Law 113–66</external-xref>) by not providing a 30-day
			 notice to Congress prior to transporting five Guantanamo detainees to
			 Qatar in a prisoner swap;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas article II, section 3 of the United States Constitution states in pertinent part that the
			 President <quote>shall take care that the Laws be faithfully executed.</quote>; and</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the House of Representatives reiterates its authority to impeach any president for failing
			 to faithfully enforce the laws of the land or for violating the law: Now,
			 therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body id="H481F05A75CDB4B6389987A1B9D78A825" style="traditional">
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H254A55B33BE742E083F961EE9C13FDA9" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text>
			<paragraph id="H874511A2360D427B8CAF985C1F5872E6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>condemns the President and the executive branch of Government for actions and acts that are beyond
			 the clearly defined laws of the United States;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HB4010CA2F95341F6A7136154BF578A35"><enum>(2)</enum><text>calls on the President and the executive branch of Government to adhere to the Constitution and
			 halt all unlawful and illegal actions which circumvent Congress and
			 violate the Constitution; and</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H3620444681E141E98442883D134103F4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>calls on the President and the executive branch of Government to respect the constitutionally
			 defined separation of powers.</text>
			</paragraph></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


