<bill bill-stage="Enrolled-Bill" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H163415F77B354807B4660942D0F68354" public-private="public" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"> HR 2611 ENR: To designate the headquarters building of the Coast Guard on the campus located at 2701 Martin Luther King, Jr., Avenue Southeast in the District of Columbia as the “Douglas A. Munro Coast Guard Headquarters Building”, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"/>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">One Hundred Thirteenth Congress of the United States of America</congress> <session display="yes">At the First Session</session>
    <enrolled-dateline>Begun and held at the City of Washington on Thursday, the third day of January, two thousand and thirteen</enrolled-dateline> 
<legis-num>H. R. 2611</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no"/> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To designate the headquarters building of the Coast Guard on the campus located at 2701 Martin Luther King, Jr., Avenue Southeast in the District of Columbia as the <quote>Douglas A. Munro Coast Guard Headquarters Building</quote>, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HB69FF0975B894632ADB2195E38C493FC" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC6CC660EB7A249718E38341FF5D8EBF0" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Designation</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The headquarters building of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7008" entity-type="federal-body">Coast Guard</cato:entity-ref> on the campus located at 2701 Martin Luther King, Jr., Avenue Southeast in the District of Columbia shall be known and designated as the <quote>Douglas A. Munro Coast Guard Headquarters Building</quote>.</text> </section> 
<section id="H6EF7CE9208174A5AAC49D9D9DE32E7B2">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>References</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Any reference in a law, map, regulation, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the building referred to in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="bill-by-number" value="113/hr/2611/s:1" proposed="true">section 1</cato:entity-ref> shall be deemed to be a reference to the <quote>Douglas A. Munro Coast Guard Headquarters Building</quote>.</text> </section> 
</legis-body> <attestation>
    <attestation-group>
      <role>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</role>
    </attestation-group>
    <attestation-group>
      <role>Vice President of the United States and President of the Senate.</role>
    </attestation-group>
  </attestation>
</bill>