<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="HB5C1F71BFC22423F8389200D2417E4B4" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HRES 488 IH: Supporting the people of Venezuela as they protest peacefully for democratic change and calling to end the violence.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2014-02-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 488</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20140225">February 25, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000435">Ms. Ros-Lehtinen</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S000018">Mr. Salmon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000600">Mr. Diaz-Balart</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001165">Mr. Sires</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000573">Mr. Garcia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000621">Mr. DeSantis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000556">Mr. Grayson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000610">Mr. Deutch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001191">Mr. Murphy of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000065">Mr. Yoho</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000937">Mr. Stockman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000615">Mr. Duncan of South Carolina</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000378">Mr. Kinzinger of Illinois</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Supporting the people of Venezuela as they protest peacefully for democratic change and calling to
			 end the violence.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas><text>Whereas the United States Government should support the free and peaceful exercise of
			 representative democracy in Venezuela, condemning violence and
			 intimidation against the country's political opposition, and calling for
			 dialogue between all political actors in the country;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on February 12, 2014, also known in Venezuela as the National Youth Day, students began
			 protesting in several cities against anti-democratic decisions and the
			 crippling economy made by Venezuelan leader Nicolas Maduro;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on February 12, 2014, a judge issued an arrest warrant for Leopoldo López, leader of the
			 opposition party Voluntad Popular, for baseless and unfounded allegations
			 in connection with the student protests;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on February 17, 2014, the Government of Venezuela notified the United States Department of
			 State that it had declared 3 consular officers at the United States
			 Embassy in Venezuela personae non gratae;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas over the last year, the Government of Venezuela has expelled a total of 8 United States
			 Government officials from Venezuela;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on February 18, 2014, opposition leader Leopoldo Lopez turned himself in to Venezuelan
			 authorities, was arrested, and charged with criminal incitement,
			 conspiracy, arson, and intent to damage property;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Leopoldo Lopez is currently being held in a prison at a military facility;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas according to Amnesty International, <quote>The charges brought against Venezuelan opposition leader Leopoldo López smack of a politically
			 motivated attempt to silence dissent in the country</quote>;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Venezuelan Government has blocked users’ online images as opposition groups marched
			 through Caracas;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Venezuelan people have been protesting economic, social, and political concerns facing
			 their country, including corruption, rising inflation rates, unemployment,
			 shortages of everyday products, increasing crime rates, and the erosion of
			 human rights and respect for political dissent;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on February 19, 2014, President Barack Obama criticized the Venezuelan Government for
			 arresting protesters, called for their release, and urged the government
			 to focus on the <quote>legitimate grievances of the Venezuelan people</quote>;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, as of February 20, 2014, there have been 13 people killed, over 100 injured, and many
			 persons unjustly detained due to pro-democracy demonstrations throughout
			 Venezuela;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Venezuelan leader Nicolas Maduro threatened to expel the United States news network CNN
			 from Venezuela and has taken off the air the Colombian news channel NTN
			 24, which transmits in Venezuela, after news outlets reported on the
			 nation-wide protests;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Inter-American Commission on Human Rights released a statement on February 14, 2014,
			 which <quote>expresses its concern over the serious incidents of violence that have taken place in the context
			 of protest demonstrations in Venezuela, as well as other complaints
			 concerning acts of censorship against media outlets, attacks on
			 organizations that defend human rights, and acts of alleged political
			 persecution</quote>; and</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas as a member of the Organization of American States and signatory to the Inter-American
			 Democratic Charter, the Government of Venezuela has agreed to abide by the
			 principles of constitutional, representative democracy, which include free
			 and fair elections and adherence to its own constitution: Now, therefore,
			 be it</text></whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body id="HCA38EF54A96445A697031A12A2863883" style="traditional">
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HBCCDDFE86DDF420DAA8643AFC66CA8C9" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the House of Representatives—</text>
			<paragraph id="H1EE36A68CBBC4FEB86FF603A629BABC1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports the people of Venezuela in their pursuit of freedom of expression and freedom of assembly
			 to promote democratic principles in Venezuela;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H9EE3A04CF0584B579FF80945998CFB54"><enum>(2)</enum><text>deplores the inexcusable violence perpetrated against opposition leaders and protesters in
			 Venezuela, and the growing efforts to use politically motivated criminal
			 charges to intimidate the country's political opposition;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HB2AF6821F3B14799848BBE3FF7EB5109"><enum>(3)</enum><text>urges responsible nations throughout the international community to stand in solidarity with the
			 people of Venezuela and to actively encourage a process of dialogue
			 between the Government of Venezuela and the political opposition to end
			 the violence;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H72F97C905CBA4489863A9EBD6A56D433"><enum>(4)</enum><text>urges the United States Department of State to work in concert with other countries in the Americas
			 to take meaningful steps to ensure that basic fundamental freedoms in
			 Venezuela are in accordance with the Inter-American Democratic Charter and
			 to strengthen the ability of the Organization of American States (OAS) to
			 respond to the erosion of democratic norms and institutions in member
			 states;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H6402AF1AAC204601B8D28B1F70ED8D2C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>urges the United States Department of State to insist that the Secretary General of the OAS
			 immediately convene the OAS’s Permanent Council to seek the most effective
			 way to expeditiously end the violence in Venezuela in accordance with the
			 Inter-American Democratic Charter; and</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H09BAA554F7CA4856B59A22B5AE0DA29A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>supports the Inter-American Commission on Human Rights in calling upon the Venezuelan Government to <quote>urgently adopt all measures that may be necessary to guarantee the rights to life, humane
			 treatment, and security, as well as the political rights, the right of
			 assembly, and the rights of freedom of association and freedom of
			 expression of everyone under its jurisdiction</quote>.</text>
			</paragraph></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


