<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-print="no" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-concurrent" stage-count="1" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 SCON 19 ATS: Providing for a conditional adjournment or recess of the Senate and an adjournment of the House of Representatives. </dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2013-06-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form display="yes">
		<distribution-code>III</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num display="yes">S. CON. RES. 19</legis-num>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED
		  STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20130627">June 27, 2013</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S198">Mr. Reid</sponsor> submitted the
			 following concurrent resolution; which was considered and agreed
			 to</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type display="yes">CONCURRENT RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Providing for a conditional adjournment or
		  recess of the Senate and an adjournment of the House of Representatives.
		  </official-title>
	</form>
	<resolution-body display-resolving-clause="yes-display-resolving-clause" style="traditional">
		<section commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That when the Senate recesses or adjourns
			 on any day from Thursday, June 27, 2013, through Friday, July 5, 2013, on a
			 motion offered pursuant to this concurrent resolution by its Majority Leader or
			 his designee, it stand recessed or adjourned until 12:00 noon on Monday, July
			 8, 2013, or such other time on that day as may be specified by its Majority
			 Leader or his designee in the motion to recess or adjourn, or until the time of
			 any reassembly pursuant to section 2 of this concurrent resolution, whichever
			 occurs first; and that when the House adjourns on any legislative day from
			 Friday, June 28, 2013, through Friday, July 5, 2013, on a motion offered
			 pursuant to this concurrent resolution by its Majority Leader or his designee,
			 it stand adjourned until 2:00 p.m. on Monday, July 8, 2013, or until the time
			 of any reassembly pursuant to section 2 of this concurrent resolution,
			 whichever occurs first.</text>
		</section><section id="id2A738FE7D9B945328FF3C838553A2F3E"><enum>2.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Majority Leader of the Senate and the
			 Speaker of the House, or their respective designees, acting jointly after
			 consultation with the Minority Leader of the Senate and the Minority Leader of
			 the House, shall notify the Members of the Senate and House, respectively, to
			 reassemble at such place and time as they may designate if, in their opinion,
			 the public interest shall warrant it.</text>
		</section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


