<bill session="113" type="hr" number="617" updated="2015-09-01T10:18:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-12T12:16:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-06-12T12:16:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Condemning the abduction of female students by armed militants from the terrorist group known as Boko Haram in northeastern provinces of the Federal Republic of Nigeria.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412412"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-12T09:15:00-04:00">
      <text>ORDER OF BUSINESS - Mr. Holding asked unanimous consent that it be in order at any time on the legislative day of June 12, 2014 to consider in the House, H.Res. 617; that the resolution be considered as read; and that the previous question be considered as ordered on the preamble and the resolution to final adoption without intervening motion. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-12T09:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered pursuant to the order of the House of June 12, 2014.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5323" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-12T09:15:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to a previous  order of the House.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5323" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-12T09:16:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - Pursuant to the order of the House of June 12, 2014, the Chair put the question on agreeing to H.Res. 617, and by voice vote, announced that the yeas had prevailed. Ms. Wilson (FL) demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-12T12:10:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5342" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="312" datetime="2014-06-12T12:16:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 411 - 2 (Roll no. 312).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5323" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-06-12T12:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hr" number="573"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="sr" number="433"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Nigeria"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/12/2014--Passed House without amendment.
Supports the people of Nigeria, especially the parents and families of the girls abducted by Boko Haram in Borno state, and calls for their immediate and safe return.

Condemns Boko Haram for its attacks on civilian targets, including schools, mosques, churches, villages, and agricultural centers.

Encourages the government of Nigeria to strengthen efforts to protect children seeking an education and to hold those who conduct such attacks accountable.

Commends U.S. efforts to hold terrorist organizations such as Boko Haram accountable, and supports U.S. offers to assist in the search for the abducted girls.

Recognizes that every individual, regardless of gender, should have the opportunity to pursue an education without fear of discrimination.

Encourages the Department of State and the U.S. Agency for International Development (USDA) to continue supporting initiatives that promote the human rights of women and girls in Nigeria.

Urges the President to strengthen U.S. security, law enforcement, and intelligence cooperation with Nigeria.

Calls on the President to provide Congress with a comprehensive strategy to counter the growing threat posed by radical Islamist terrorist groups in West Africa, the Sahel, and North Africa.</summary>
</bill>
