<bill session="113" type="h" number="2812" updated="2015-09-01T10:19:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Justice Exists for All of Us Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To encourage States to prohibit "stand your ground" laws and require neighborhood watch programs to register with local law enforcement agencies and the Department of Justice, to direct the Attorney General to study such laws, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400199"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412404" joined="2013-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412221" joined="2014-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400074" joined="2013-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2013-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="2013-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2013-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2013-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400163" joined="2013-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412498" joined="2013-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412418" joined="2013-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412561" joined="2013-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412199" joined="2013-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2013-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="2013-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412521" joined="2013-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2013-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400271" joined="2013-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2013-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="2013-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400363" joined="2013-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="2013-08-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/24/2013--Introduced.
Justice Exists for All of Us Act of 2013 - Prohibits a state, for each fiscal year beginning three years after enactment of this Act, from having in effect a law or policy that: (1) allows a person to use deadly force when such person is threatened and that does not impose a duty to retreat before using such force in any place where that person is lawfully present (commonly known as a "stand your ground law"), except where the person is a victim of domestic violence; or (2) allows the establishment, organization, or operation of, or participation in, a Neighborhood Watch program that is not registered with the local law enforcement agency and the Department of Justice (DOJ). Allows the Attorney General to authorize up to two one-year extensions of such deadline.

Provides that a state that fails to substantially implement this Act for any fiscal year shall not receive 20% of the funds that would otherwise be allocated to it under the Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grant program. Provides for alternative procedures for compliance by a state that is unable to substantially implement this Act because of a conflict with the state's constitution.

Directs the Attorney General to conduct a study of state stand your ground laws, including by examining: (1) the effect that such laws have on rates of violent deaths, and (2) whether women and minorities are targets of the force authorized by such laws at a higher rate than the general population.</summary>
</bill>
