<bill session="113" type="s" number="2217" updated="2015-09-01T17:50:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-04-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-04-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Military Mental Health Review Board Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 10, United States Code, to enhance the participation of mental health professionals in boards for the correction of military records and boards for the review of the discharge or dismissal of members of the Armed Forces.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412244"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2014-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2014-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412602" joined="2014-04-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3979"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4435"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2410"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/7/2014--Introduced.
Military Mental Health Review Board Improvement Act - Requires any medical advisory opinion issued to a civilian board for the correction of a military record, with respect to a current or former member of the Armed Forces diagnosed while serving in the Armed Forces as experiencing a mental health disorder, to include the opinion of a clinical psychologist or psychiatrist if the request for the correction of the records concerned relates to a mental health disorder.

Requires any physician on a board for review of a discharge or dismissal of certain former members of the Armed Forces, who after deployment were diagnosed as experiencing post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD) or traumatic brain injury, or as having a mental health disorder, to have training on mental health issues connected with PTSD or traumatic brain injury (as applicable), or special training on mental health disorders.</summary>
</bill>
