<bill session="113" type="s" number="1796" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-12-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-12-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-12-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">STEM Gateways Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to increase the participation of women, girls, and underrepresented minorities in STEM fields, to encourage and support students from all economic backgrounds to pursue STEM career opportunities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412223"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2014-01-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-12-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3690"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Women's education"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/10/2013--Introduced.
STEM Gateways Act - Directs the Secretary of Education to award competitive grants to eligible entities for science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM) elementary and secondary school programs for women and girls, underrepresented minorities, and individuals from all economic backgrounds.

Requires those programs to be directed toward at least one of the following goals:

 encouraging the interest of elementary and secondary school students in the STEM fields; motivating the engagement of those students in the STEM fields by providing them with relevant hands-on learning opportunities; supporting classroom success in the STEM disciplines by elementary and secondary school students; supporting STEM workforce training and career preparation for secondary school students; and improving the access of secondary school students to STEM career and continuing education opportunities. Defines an "eligible entity" as: (1) a local educational agency (LEA); (2) an educational service agency serving more than one LEA; (3) a consortium of LEAs; (4) a nonprofit organization that works with elementary schools, secondary schools, or institutions of higher education and has shown a commitment to achieving the goals listed above; or (5) a community college working in partnership with secondary schools to create dual enrollment, credit transfer, or accelerated postsecondary credentialing opportunities.</summary>
</bill>
