<bill session="113" type="h" number="4566" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-05-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Commission on the Accountability and Review of Federal Agencies Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a commission to conduct a comprehensive review over 6 years of Federal agencies and programs and to recommend the elimination or realignment of duplicative, wasteful, or outdated functions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412531"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400029" joined="2014-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400071" joined="2014-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412552" joined="2014-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412540" joined="2014-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="408211" joined="2014-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412489" joined="2014-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="410396" joined="2014-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412525" joined="2014-05-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-06">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-06">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/6/2014--Introduced.
Commission on the Accountability and Review of Federal Agencies Act - Establishes the Commission on the Accountability and Review of Federal Agencies. Requires such Commission to evaluate federal agencies and their programs each year for a six-year period&#160;to determine whether: (1) two or more agencies or programs are performing the same essential function and such function can be consolidated or streamlined; (2) any agency or program has wasted federal funds by egregious spending, mismanagement of resources and personnel, or&#160;use of funds for personal benefit or the benefit of a special interest group; and (3)&#160;any agency or program has completed its intended purpose, has become irrelevant, or has failed to meet its objectives. Requires the realignment or elimination of such agencies or programs.

Requires the Comptroller General (GAO) to report to Congress on the effectiveness of the Commission. Sets forth procedures for consideration and implementation by Congress of Commission recommendations.</summary>
</bill>
