<bill session="113" type="h" number="5703" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-11-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-11-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-11-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protect and Preserve International Cultural Property Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To protect and preserve international cultural property at risk of destruction due to political instability, armed conflict, or natural or other disasters, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400122"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="2014-11-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-11-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, Armed Services, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-13">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-13">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-13">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-13">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU10" subcommittee="Constitution and Civil Justice" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Archaeology and anthropology"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign property"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers"/>
    <term name="National Archives and Records Administration"/>
    <term name="National Science Foundation"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Smithsonian Institution"/>
    <term name="Smuggling and trafficking"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/13/2014--Introduced.
Protect and Preserve International Cultural Property Act - Directs the President to appoint a White House Coordinator for International Cultural Property Protection who shall coordinate and promote federal agency efforts to address international cultural property protection activities.

Directs the Secretary of State (Secretary in this Act), the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development (USAID), the Attorney General (DOJ), and the Secretary of Defense (DOD) to submit to the Coordinator information on efforts to protect international cultural property.

Authorizes the Department of State, DOD, USAID, the Department of Homeland Security (DHS), DOJ, the Department of the Interior, the National Archives, the National Science Foundation, and any other appropriate agency to enter into agreements with the Smithsonian Institution to engage temporarily Smithsonian personnel to assist in international cultural property protection activities.

Authorizes the Secretary to make grants to private individuals or organizations for international cultural property protection activities in areas at risk of destruction due to political instability, armed conflict, or natural or other disasters.

Directs the President to apply specified import restrictions with respect to any archaeological or ethnological material of Syria as if Syria were a State Party to the Convention on prohibiting and preventing the illicit import, export, and transfer of ownership of cultural property (adopted by the General Conference of the United Nations Educational, Scientific, and Cultural Organization).</summary>
</bill>
