<bill session="113" type="h" number="4248" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-03-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-03-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-03-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Education Outcomes Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require institutions of higher education to disseminate information with respect to the completion rates, employment rates, and retention rates of recipients of GI Bill funding.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412520"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412480" joined="2014-03-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-03-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Training" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/13/2014--Introduced.
Veterans Education Outcomes Act - Amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require institutions of higher education (IHEs) participating in title IV programs to inform prospective and enrolled students of the percentage of the IHE's full-time students who receive assistance under the All-Volunteer Force or Post 9/11 Educational Assistance programs or the program providing educational assistance for members of the Selected Reserve.

Requires those IHEs to disaggregate by the recipients of such assistance information, which they are required to provide to prospective and enrolled students, regarding:

 their costs of attendance, their completion or graduation rates, their graduates' placement in employment and type of employment, the types of graduate and professional education their graduating students pursue, and their retention rate for undergraduate students.</summary>
</bill>
