<bill session="113" type="h" number="3142" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-09-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-09-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-09-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">STEM Readiness Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve science, technology, engineering, and mathematics education, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412571" joined="2013-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412535" joined="2013-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412189" joined="2013-10-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412432" joined="2013-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="2013-10-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="2013-10-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412579" joined="2014-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412412" joined="2013-10-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-09-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Training" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/19/2013--Introduced.
STEM Readiness Act of 2013 - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to direct the Secretary of Education to award competitive merit-based scholarships to students who are pursuing bachelor's degrees in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM) with concurrent certification as kindergarten, elementary, and secondary school teachers.

Requires scholarship recipients to work for at least five academic years as a full-time STEM teacher at a public or private kindergarten or elementary or secondary school during the seven-year period beginning within one year after they complete their studies.

Awards scholarships for one academic year of study at a time, but makes them renewable on an annual basis if their recipients meet certain measures of academic progress.

Allows scholarship recipients to enter into agreements with the Secretary that provide them with a bonus in exchange for performing their service in a high-need local educational agency for a period equivalent to the period for which they receive the bonus.

Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to authorize the Secretary to award competitive matching grants to up to 50 institutions of higher education to establish, strengthen, and operate four-year undergraduate degree programs that enable students to concurrently: (1) earn a STEM bachelor's degree; and (2) be certified to teach kindergarten, elementary, or secondary school.

Awards those grants one fiscal year at a time, but makes them renewable on an annual basis for up to five years.</summary>
</bill>
