<bill session="113" type="hr" number="566" updated="2015-09-01T10:18:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-05-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Condemning Dalit untouchability, the practice of birth-descent discrimination against Dalit people, which is widely practiced in India, Nepal, the Asian diaspora, and other South Asian nations, and calling on these countries to recognize the human rights of the Dalit people and end all forms of untouchability within their borders.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400295"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Africa, Global Health, Global Human Rights and International Organizations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Asia and the Pacific.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA16" subcommittee="Africa, Global Health, Global Human Rights and International Organizations" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA05" subcommittee="Asia and the Pacific" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="India"/>
    <term name="Nepal"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/2/2014--Introduced.
Condemns the practice of untouchability and the discriminatory treatment of the Dalits in South Asia and the Asian diaspora.

 Calls on the governments of India, Nepal, the Asian diaspora, and other South Asian nations to: (1) end all forms of untouchability and discrimination of the Dalit people, and (2) ensure respect for internationally recognized human rights for these minority groups.

Demands that the international community put pressure on the governments of nations that still practice Dalit untouchability to end this practice and protect the fundamental rights of all Dalits within their borders.</summary>
</bill>
