<bill session="113" type="s" number="2114" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-03-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-03-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-03-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bond Transparency Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 with respect to disclosures to investors in municipal and corporate debt securities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412321"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2014-03-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-03-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/12/2014--Introduced.
Bond Transparency Act of 2014 - Amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to define a "riskless principal transaction" as any transaction the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) identifies as one, but primarily one in which a broker, dealer, or municipal securities dealer acts on a customer order to buy or sell either municipal securities or corporate debt securities while also acting as principal for its own account in order to complete the transaction.

Requires a broker or dealer, at or before completion of the transaction, to make a markup disclosure in writing to the customer of the difference between either: (1) the customer's purchase price and the broker or dealer's purchase price; or (2) the customer's sale price and the broker or dealer's sale price.

Subjects riskless principal transactions in corporate debt securities to the same markup disclosure requirements as those for riskless principal transactions in municipal securities.</summary>
</bill>
