<bill session="113" type="h" number="5332" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SAVE Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Serving America's Veterans Effectively Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To promote identification of veterans and their health needs in furnishing of items and services under the Medicare, Medicaid, and other programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400087"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-08-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2014--Introduced.
Serving America's Veterans Effectively Act of 2014 or the SAVE Act of 2014 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to:

 require the inclusion of a patient's status as a veteran in the patient information that the Secretary requires for meaningful use of electronic health records under the Medicare and Medicaid programs, include an inquiry into whether a patient is a veteran and any relevant circumstances relating to a veteran's service in the Armed Forces as part of the initial preventive examination of Medicare beneficiaries, and take such additional actions as may be appropriate to promote awareness among nongovernmental physicians of the special circumstances and health care needs of veterans. Authorizes the Secretary to make grants to organizations to educate health care providers on appropriate health care for veterans.</summary>
</bill>
