<bill session="113" type="h" number="3885" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-01-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-01-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-01-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Generating Real Opportunities for Workers and Transitional Help Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">GROWTH Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for a 12 month extension for certain Emergency Unemployment Compensation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400648"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400646" joined="2014-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412434" joined="2014-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412465" joined="2014-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412487" joined="2014-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412552" joined="2014-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412489" joined="2014-01-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-01-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Transportation and Infrastructure, Energy and Commerce, and Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-15">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-15">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-15">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-15">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW14" subcommittee="Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="Public Lands and Environmental Regulation" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="556"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="556"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1502"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1502"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1674"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1674"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2575"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2575"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3788"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3788"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="18"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="18"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1869"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1869"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
    <term name="Tax treatment of families"/>
    <term name="Temporary and part-time employment"/>
    <term name="Trade adjustment assistance"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/15/2014--Introduced.
Generating Real Opportunities for Workers and Transitional Help Act or GROWTH Act - Amends the Supplemental Appropriations Act, 2008 to declare that nothing in the Act shall prevent the commencement or continued payment of first-tier emergency unemployment compensation (EUC) to the extent that it:

 represents amounts established in an applicant's EUC account (EUCA); and is payable for a week ending on or before January 1, 2015. (Thus provides for a 12-month extension of EUC.) Revises the formula for crediting Tier-1 amounts to an applicant's EUCA to include a week ending after January 1, 2014. Decreases the percentages in the formula (the lesser of which shall be the amount credited): (1) from 80% to 54% of the total amount of regular compensation (including dependents' allowances) payable to the individual during the benefit year, and (2) from 20 to 14 times the individual's average weekly benefit amount for the benefit year.

Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to transfer necessary amounts from the Treasury general fund to the EUC account to make payments to states for this extension of EUC.

Makes a change in application of a certain requirement (nonreduction rule) to a state that has entered a federal-state EUC agreement, under which the federal government would reimburse the state's unemployment compensation agency making EUC payments to individuals who have exhausted all rights to regular unemployment compensation under state or federal law and meet specified other criteria.

 (Under the nonreduction rule such an agreement does not apply with respect to a state whose method for computing regular unemployment compensation under state law has been modified to make the average weekly unemployment compensation benefit paid on or after June 2, 2010, less than what would have been paid before June 2, 2010.)

 Declares that the nonreduction rule shall not apply to a state which has enacted a law before December 1, 2013, that, upon taking effect, would violate the nonreduction rule. Allows a state whose agreement was terminated, however, to enter into a subsequent federal-state EUC agreement on or after enactment of this Act if, taking into account this inapplicability of the nonreduction rule, it would otherwise meet the requirements for an EUC agreement. (Thus allows such a subsequent EUC agreement to permit payment of less than the average weekly unemployment compensation benefit paid on or after June 2, 2010.)

Authorizes the Secretary of Labor, for FY2014-FY2023, to use any available discretionary appropriations to conduct in-person reemployment and unemployment insurance eligibility assessments for unemployment insurance beneficiaries. Specifies limits in such amount for each fiscal year.

Amends the Internal Revenue Code (IRC) to repeal the excise tax on medical devices.

 Declares that no presidential permit shall be required for a specified application filed on May 4, 2012, by TransCanada Keystone XL pipeline, L.P., to the Department of State for the Keystone XL pipeline, as supplemented to include the Nebraska reroute featured in the Final Evaluation Report issued by the Nebraska Department of Environmental Quality in January 2013 and approved by the Nebraska governor.

Considers the final environmental impact statement regarding the pipeline issued by the Secretary of State on August 26, 2011, coupled with the Final Evaluation Report, to satisfy all requirements of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969.

Amends the IRC, as amended by the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act, to redefine "full-time employee," for purposes of the mandate requiring employers to provide health care coverage for their employees, as an employee who is employed on average at least 40 hours of service a week (currently, at least 30 hours of service a week).

Amends title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) of the Social Security Act to declare that for any month that an individual is entitled to unemployment compensation (UC) he or she shall be deemed to have engaged in substantial gainful activity and so be disqualified from receiving Social Security disability benefits after a certain period has elapsed.

States that, for purposes of determining services rendered by an individual during a period of trial work which will not disqualify the individual for disability benefits, the individual shall be deemed to have rendered services in a month if he or she is entitled to UC or trade adjustment assistance for that month.

Amends the IRC to require taxpayers who are claiming the refundable portion of the child tax credit to include their Social Security numbers on their tax returns..</summary>
</bill>
