<bill session="113" type="h" number="4668" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-11-19">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-11-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Point Spencer Coast Guard and Public-Private Sector Infrastructure Development Facilitation and Land Conveyance Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the retention and future use of certain land on Point Spencer in Alaska, to support the statutory missions and duties of the Coast Guard, to convey certain land on Point Spencer to the Bering Straits Native Corporation, to convey certain land on Point Spencer to the State of Alaska, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400440"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412283" joined="2014-05-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E756-757"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-15">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-15">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee Indian and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-10">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-19">
      <text>Subcommittee Indian and Alaska Native Affairs Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-19">
      <text>Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-19">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-11-19" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII24" subcommittee="Indian and Alaska Native Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSII10" subcommittee="Public Lands and Environmental Regulation" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW07" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/15/2014--Introduced.
Point Spencer Coast Guard and Public-Private Sector Infrastructure Development Facilitation and Land Conveyance Act - Designates certain land at Point Spencer in Alaska (a parcel of land on which a decommissioned long range radio navigation station was located) to be: (1) retained by the Coast Guard; (2) conveyed to, or leased by, the state of Alaska; and (3) conveyed to the Bering Straits Native Corporation (BSNC) (a corporation authorized to represent and manage land and resources from the settlement of aboriginal claims of indigenous Alaska Natives in the Bering Strait region).

Requires the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating to retain an easement authorizing public aircraft to use all existing and future airstrips, runways, and taxiways on a specified tract of such land at no cost.

Defines "public aircraft" as any aircraft owned by, operated by, or chartered by the United States or by a contractor of the United States for the performance of a federal contract on or from Point Spencer.

 Sets forth requirements concerning: (1) conveyed lands that are leased back to the Coast Guard upon the Secretary's request, (2) airspace easements, and (3) rights-of-way on roads to and from airstrips.

Requires the United States to retain the authority to enforce archaeological and historic preservation laws on certain land.

Directs the Secretary, the state of Alaska, and the BSNC to develop a joint management plan for the use and management of the lands retained, conveyed, or leased under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
