<bill session="113" type="s" number="2033" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-02-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-02-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-02-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">JOBS Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Jumpstart Our Businesses by Supporting Students Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 in order to allow the Secretary of Education to award job training Federal Pell Grants.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300063"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412582" joined="2014-07-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-02-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="4207"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/12/2014--Introduced.
Jumpstart Our Businesses by Supporting Students Act of 2014 or the JOBS Act of 2014 - Amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to direct the Secretary of Education, for the award years beginning on July 1, 2014, and ending on June 30, 2020, to award job training Federal Pell Grants to students in job training programs.

Makes students eligible for such Grants if they: (1) have not attained a baccalaureate or postbaccalaureate degree; (2) are attending an institution of higher education (IHE) that is eligible to participate in title IV programs; (3) are enrolled in, or accepted for enrollment in, a job training program at that IHE that does not lead to a baccalaureate degree; and (4) meet all the other eligibility requirements for a Federal Pell Grant.

Establishes a maximum amount, but no minimum amount, for such a Grant.

Defines an eligible "job training program" as a career and technical education program at an IHE that:

 provides at least 150 clock hours of instructional time over a period of at least 8 weeks, provides training that meets the needs of the local or regional workforce, provides students who complete the program with a recognized educational credential, and the IHE has determined is sufficient to meet the hiring requirements of multiple employers and allow students to apply for any licenses or certifications that may be required for employment in the field for which the job training is offered.</summary>
</bill>
