<bill session="113" type="h" number="4818" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Military Spouse Career Advancement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 10, United States Code, to codify the Military Spouse Career Advancement Account program conducted by the Department of Defense to assist spouses of members of the Armed Forces serving on active duty to pursue educational opportunities and career training, to ensure that such educational opportunities and training are available to all military spouses, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412527"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400031" joined="2014-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412516" joined="2014-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412571" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="2014-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412379" joined="2014-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2014-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412555" joined="2014-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412544" joined="2014-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412577" joined="2014-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2014-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2014-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2014-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412558" joined="2014-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2014-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412189" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412560" joined="2014-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412383" joined="2014-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400308" joined="2014-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2014-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="2014-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400363" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412579" joined="2014-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/9/2014--Introduced.
Military Spouse Career Advancement Act - Requires (current law authorizes) the Secretary of Defense (DOD) to establish programs to provide education and training opportunities for military spouses to expand employment and portable career opportunities.

Directs the Secretary to continue to carry out the Military Spouse Career Advancement Account (MyCAA) program, under which the spouse of a member of the armed forces who is serving on active duty may receive up to the amount that the Secretary determines is equal to the average amount of in-state tuition at public four-year colleges and universities located in the state in which the spouse resides in tuition assistance for education and training courses and licensing and credentialing fees.

Requires financial assistance provided under the program to be available to cover the costs of:

 state certifications for teachers, medical professionals, and other occupations; licensing exams and related preparation courses; continuing education classes; degree programs leading to employment in portable careers; and secondary education completion courses, GED tests, and English as a Second Language classes. Prohibits the Secretary from restricting participation in the program to spouses of members serving in particular grades.</summary>
</bill>
