<bill session="113" type="hr" number="477" updated="2015-09-01T10:18:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-02-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-02-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-02-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the former Yugoslav Republic of Macedonia should work within the framework of the United Nations process and in good faith with Greece to achieve longstanding United States and United Nations policy goals by finding a mutually acceptable name that must apply for all internal and international uses (erga omnes), for the former Yugoslav Republic of Macedonia.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400251"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412250" joined="2014-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412282" joined="2014-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412331" joined="2014-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412212" joined="2014-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400371" joined="2014-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400407" joined="2014-03-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-02-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E197"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="European Union"/>
    <term name="Greece"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Macedonia"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/11/2014--Introduced.
Urges the former Yugoslav Republic of Macedonia to: (1) work within the United Nations (U.N.) framework and with Greece to achieve longstanding U.S. and U.N. policy goals by finding a mutually acceptable name that must apply for all internal and international uses for the former Yugoslav Republic of Macedonia, and (2) abstain from all hostile activities and stop violating the U.N.-brokered Interim Agreement between the former Yugoslav Republic of Macedonia and Greece regarding hostile activities or propaganda.

 Urges the United States to work in partnership with North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) allies to uphold certain NATO decisions and extend an invitation to the former Yugoslav Republic of Macedonia as soon as a mutually acceptable solution to the name issue has been reached within the U.N. framework.

 Expresses the view of the House of Representatives that the former Yugoslav Republic of Macedonia can be considered for accession into the European Union (EU) only after a mutually acceptable solution to the name issue has been reached within the U.N. framework.</summary>
</bill>
