<bill session="113" type="h" number="5675" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SAFE TOWERS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Standards Addressing Federal Transparency and Oversight With Evolving Recruitment Specifications Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration to revise hiring practices for air traffic controller positions, to establish an Air Traffic Control Education and Training Advisory Committee, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412422"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400031" joined="2014-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412537" joined="2014-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412524" joined="2014-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412485" joined="2014-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412444" joined="2014-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412566" joined="2014-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400630" joined="2014-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400352" joined="2014-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="2014-12-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW05" subcommittee="Aviation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/19/2014--Introduced.
Standards Addressing Federal Transparency and Oversight With Evolving Recruitment Specifications Act or the SAFE TOWERS Act - Revises Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) requirements for the hiring of air traffic controllers.

Directs the FAA Administrator to give preferential consideration in the hiring of air traffic controllers to:

 individuals who have successfully completed air traffic controller training and graduated from an institution participating in the FAA's Collegiate Training Initiative program, and have received a recommendation from the institution; and qualified individuals eligible for a veterans recruitment appointment or qualified eligible veterans who maintain aviation experience. Directs the Administrator to revise FAA hiring practices for air traffic controller applicants with the Department of Transportation (DOT) to eliminate the use of biographical assessments or other personality tests that unduly disqualify applicants.

Changes from discretionary to mandatory the Administrator's authority to maintain the Collegiate Training Initiative program.

Directs the Administrator to establish an Air Traffic Control Education and Training Advisory Committee.

Requires the Administrator to take into consideration any locally developed training initiatives for air traffic controllers for use in establishing best practices nationwide.</summary>
</bill>
