<bill session="113" type="h" number="4167" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-04-29T13:21:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-04-29T13:21:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-03-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Restoring Proven Financing for American Employers Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Restoring Proven Financing for American Employers Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend section 13 of the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956, known as the Volcker Rule, to exclude certain debt securities of collateralized loan obligations from the prohibition against acquiring or retaining an ownership interest in a hedge fund or private equity fund.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412541"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400641" joined="2014-03-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-02-26">
      <text>Hearings Held by the Subcommittee on Capital Markets and Government Sponsored Enterprises Prior to Introduction and Referral.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-14">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-03-14" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 53 - 3.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-04-29T12:47:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Garrett moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-29T12:47:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3257-3261" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-29T12:47:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4167.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2014-04-29T13:21:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3257" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-04-30">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, Markup"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="HSBA16" subcommittee="Capital Markets and Government Sponsored Enterprises" name="House Financial Services"/>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3819"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="5405"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="5461"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1907"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Credit and credit markets"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/29/2014--Passed House amended.
Restoring Proven Financing for American Employers Act - Amends the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956 with respect to certain prohibitions on proprietary trading by banking entities and certain relationships with hedge funds and private equity funds (Volcker Rule).

Prescribes rules of construction governing a collateralized loan obligation to prohibit the Volcker Rule from being construed to require divestiture, before July 21, 2017, of any debt securities of collateralized loan obligations issued before January 31, 2014.

Declares that a banking entity shall not be considered to have an ownership interest in a collateralized loan obligation because it either acquires, has acquired, or retains a debt security in such obligation if the debt security has no indicia of ownership other than the right of the banking entity to participate in the removal for cause, or in the selection of a replacement after removal for cause or resignation, of an investment manager or investment adviser of the collateralized loan obligation.

Defines "collateralized loan obligation" as any issuing entity of an asset-backed security comprised primarily of commercial loans.

Deems an investment manager or adviser to be removed "for cause" if the removal is a result of:

 a breach of a material term of the applicable management or advisory agreement or the agreement governing the collateralized loan obligation; the investment manager's or investment adviser's inability to continue to perform its obligations under any such agreement; any other action or inaction by the investment manager or investment adviser that has or could reasonably be expected to have a materially adverse effect on the collateralized loan obligation, if the investment manager or investment adviser fails to cure or take reasonable steps to cure such effect within a reasonable time; or an event or circumstance which threatens, or could reasonably be expected to threaten, the interests of holders of the debt securities.</summary>
</bill>
