<bill session="113" type="s" number="2826" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strengthening Forgiveness for Public Servants Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to provide for a percentage of student loan forgiveness for public service employment, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412490"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412542" joined="2014-09-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/16/2014--Introduced.
Strengthening Forgiveness for Public Servants Act - Amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to direct the Secretary of Education to cancel 15%, 15%, 20%, 20%, and 30% of the amount a borrower owes after 2, 4, 6, 8, and 10 years of public service employment, respectively, on a William D. Ford Federal Direct Loan made after this Act's enactment. (Currently, the balance of a borrower's Direct Loan is cancelled if the borrower is not in default and has made 120 monthly payments on such loan while employed as a public service employee.)

Requires borrowers availing themselves of such loan cancellation to submit an employment certification form that includes self-certification of employment and employer certification of employment dates. Places the borrower's loan in deferment during the period in which the borrower is employed in an eligible public service job if the borrower submits such form to the Secretary.

Cancels the entire amount of interest on such a loan that accrues for any year in which a portion of the loan is cancelled under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
