<bill session="113" type="h" number="3780" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-12-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-12-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-12-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ocean Energy Safety and Technology Improvement Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to establish an Ocean Energy Safety Institute, to promote the use of best available and safest offshore drilling technologies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400184"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2013-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412521" joined="2013-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412254" joined="2014-01-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-12-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1877-1878"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-16">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-16">
      <text>Referred to House Science, Space, and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY20" subcommittee="Energy" name="House Science, Space, and Technology"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/16/2013--Introduced.
Ocean Energy Safety and Technology Improvement Act of 2013 - Amends the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act, with respect to the consideration of permits for geological explorations and development and production, to allow the Secretary of the Interior to give priority to reviewing and processing plans and applications that use, develop, or demonstrate new safety-enhancing technologies.

Directs the Secretary to establish: (1) a small business innovation research program or technology transfer program, or both, to broaden participation in the development of safer technologies for offshore oil and gas exploration and development; and (2) an Ocean Energy Safety Institute, as a collaborative federally funded research and development center or university-affiliated research center, to enhance safe and responsible operations across the offshore oil and gas industry. Funds operations of the Institute through an annual fee applicable to areas of the outer Continental Shelf subject to an oil or gas lease under which production is not occurring.</summary>
</bill>
