<bill session="113" type="h" number="4097" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-02-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-02-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-02-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Salmon Solutions and Planning Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure that proper information gathering and planning are undertaken to secure the preservation and recovery of the salmon and steelhead of the Columbia River Basin in a manner that protects and enhances local communities, ensures effective expenditure of Federal resources, and maintains reasonably priced, reliable power, to direct the Secretary of Commerce to seek scientific analysis of Federal efforts to restore salmon and steelhead listed under the Endangered Species Act of 1973, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400262"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-02-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E247-248, E254"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Natural Resources, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-26">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-26">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-26">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/26/2014--Introduced.
Salmon Solutions and Planning Act - Directs the Secretary of Commerce to enter into an arrangement with the National Academy of Sciences for scientific analysis of federal salmon recovery actions, including the impact that removal of the&#160;four lower Snake River dams would have on recovery of salmon and steelhead populations and any additional actions that may be necessary to achieve recovery of salmon and steelhead populations.

Directs: (1) the Secretary of Transportation (DOT) to conduct a peer-reviewed study of the&#160;rail, highway, and Columbia River barge infrastructure improvements that&#160;would be necessary to ensure a cost-effective and efficient transportation system for shippers who currently use barge transportation between Lewiston, Idaho, and the confluence of the Snake and Columbia Rivers and who would be unable to do so if the four lower Snake River dams were removed; (2) the Secretary of Energy (DOE) to conduct a peer-reviewed study&#160; of the options to replace the power currently generated by such dams if they were removed; (3) the Army Corps of Engineers to analyze riverfront revitalization and restoration opportunities and costs in the event of such removal; and (4) the Bureau of Reclamation to conduct a peer-reviewed analysis of the options and costs regarding any needed modifications to affected irrigation systems, cooling systems, and private wells if the dams were removed.

Sets forth the congressional determination that the Secretary of the Army may remove the four lower Snake River dams.

Directs the Secretary to reevaluate and update the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers' Final Lower Snake River Juvenile Salmon Migration Feasibility Report/Environmental Impact Statement (February 2002) pursuant to new information.</summary>
</bill>
