<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HFBEF29926D41499E8A773A3FB159FFF3" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HR 5029 IH: International Science and Technology Cooperation Act of 2014</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2014-07-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 5029</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20140708">July 8, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000563">Mr. Lipinski</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001059">Mr. Hultgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001092">Mr. Collins of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000126">Ms. Eddie Bernice Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000293">Ms. Esty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000379">Mr. Kennedy</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To provide for the establishment of a body to identify and coordinate international science and
			 technology cooperation that can strengthen the domestic science and
			 technology enterprise and support United States foreign policy goals.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H7C66F3242E2B445ABCC0BACEE087DE5A" style="OLC">
		<section id="HE1EAF9AA9AB640C190F4DEAC8DBFE7F1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>International Science and Technology Cooperation Act of 2014</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="HE07FB6C57D8F4AD08264D728B2A1F81C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Coordination of international science and technology partnerships</header>
			<subsection id="H0663C51B205F40A4A1BD5BB06C9C468A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy shall establish a body under the
			 National Science and Technology Council with the responsibility to
			 identify and coordinate international science and technology cooperation
			 that can strengthen the United States science and technology enterprise,
			 improve economic and national security, and support United States foreign
			 policy goals.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H4AB9B68F65E64334A5997B9A622DF206"><enum>(b)</enum><header>NSTC body leadership</header><text>The body established under subsection (a) shall be co-chaired by senior level officials from the
			 Office of Science and Technology Policy and the Department of State.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HE4045A935E794EA8A5E27C1F166BB1D0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>The body established under subsection (a) shall—</text>
				<paragraph id="HA9F08FBD1198413E995DC87BD5005B8E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>coordinate interagency international science and technology cooperative research and training
			 activities and partnerships supported or managed by Federal agencies and
			 work with other National Science and Technology Council committees to help
			 plan and coordinate the international component of national science and
			 technology priorities;</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H4F8FB95B0396480D8B43985A7BF0FF4D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establish Federal priorities and policies for aligning, as appropriate, international science and
			 technology cooperative research and training activities and partnerships
			 supported or managed by Federal agencies with the foreign policy goals of
			 the United States;</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H3799DB1F5C3A4BDC8214A12D58B39053"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identify opportunities for new international science and technology cooperative research and
			 training partnerships that advance both the science and technology and the
			 foreign policy priorities of the United States;</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HC91A4BFE2B8A44B4B6705710566EAF9F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in carrying out paragraph (3), solicit input and recommendations from non-Federal science and
			 technology stakeholders, including universities, scientific and
			 professional societies, industry, and relevant organizations and
			 institutions; and</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HF9B0E573E05B4B109C6FCA73BA9C010C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>identify broad issues that influence the ability of United States scientists and engineers to
			 collaborate with foreign counterparts, including barriers to collaboration
			 and access to scientific information.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2E732E333FDF4139B5590EC3CA46AD20"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report to congress</header><text>The Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy shall transmit a report, to be updated
			 annually, to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology and the
			 Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, and to the
			 Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and the Committee on
			 Foreign Relations of the Senate. The report shall also be made available
			 to the public on the reporting agency’s website. The report shall contain
			 a description of—</text>
				<paragraph id="H70504DBEA0FD467D91A6185CA8ECD12F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the priorities and policies established under subsection (c)(2);</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HB7223C222B2B4D4481D42F12E366F548"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the ongoing and new partnerships established since the last update to the report;</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H34038C8D5A134EB3A18B506E3CC91120"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the means by which stakeholder input was received, as well as summary views of stakeholder input;
			 and</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H5E318DD11DE24A13B0F05F7349659F75"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the issues influencing the ability of United States scientists and engineers to collaborate with
			 foreign counterparts.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


