<bill session="113" type="s" number="2652" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the design-build process in Federal contracting.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412556"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2750"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/24/2014--Introduced.
Modifies design-build selection procedures for civilian and defense contracts for the design and construction of a public building, facility, or work to require the contracting officer to provide written documentation of how more than five finalists in a solicitation for a contract is consistent with the purposes and objectives of the two-phase selection process (a procurement process in which the first phase consists of prequalification or shortlisting and the second phase consists of preparation and submission of complete design-build proposals from the prequalified offerors).

Requires the use of two-phase selection procedures for civilian or defense contracts when a contracting officer determines that the contract has a value of $750,000 or greater, adjusted for inflation. Requires: (1) agencies to report on contracts for which more than five finalists were selected for phase-two requests or for which the contract was awarded without using two-phase selection procedures, and (2) the Comptroller General (GAO) to report on the compliance of executive agencies with design-build contract procedures.</summary>
</bill>
