<bill session="113" type="h" number="4872" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ending Special Mail Privileges for Congress Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To eliminate the use of the frank for mail transmitted by Members of Congress and Congressional officials, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412416"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2014-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412400" joined="2014-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412533" joined="2014-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412566" joined="2014-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412489" joined="2014-11-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-17">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-17">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/17/2014--Introduced.
Ending Special Mail Privileges for Congress Act of 2014 - Amends federal postal law to repeal franking privileges for mail transmitted by Members of Congress and congressional officials. Requires the mail to be transmitted as congressional mail.

Replaces requirements and procedures for the use of franked mail with those for congressional mail.

Repeals franked mailing privileges for survivors of Members of Congress.

Requires a former President and his or her surviving spouse to send nonpolitical mail within the United States and its territories and possessions as congressional mail instead of franked mail.</summary>
</bill>
