<bill bill-stage="Enrolled-Bill" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H028F5A71E5EF44A68CD199DFC2B3CF63" public-private="public" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"> HR 3095 ENR: To ensure that any new or revised requirement providing for the screening, testing, or treatment of individuals operating commercial motor vehicles for sleep disorders is adopted pursuant to a rulemaking proceeding, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"/>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">One Hundred Thirteenth Congress of the United States of America</congress> <session display="yes">At the First Session</session>
    <enrolled-dateline>Begun and held at the City of Washington on Thursday, the third day of January, two thousand and thirteen</enrolled-dateline> 
<legis-num>H. R. 3095</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no"/> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To ensure that any new or revised requirement providing for the screening, testing, or treatment of individuals operating commercial motor vehicles for sleep disorders is adopted pursuant to a rulemaking proceeding, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H588676C0D8624FC8839D47510F932281" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9B4DCF5835734D70BB98F254542E3921" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Commercial motor vehicle operator requirements relating to sleep disorders</header> 
<subsection id="H670C0572EEE7418AA9FEBFA7864FC239">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="6900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Transportation</cato:entity-ref> may implement or enforce a requirement providing for the screening, testing, or treatment (including consideration of all possible treatment alternatives) of individuals operating commercial motor vehicles for sleep disorders only if the requirement is adopted pursuant to a rulemaking proceeding.</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="H298C464A54FF4CCDAA820B41DB62EA20">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Applicability</header>
        <text>Subsection (a) shall not apply to a requirement that was in force before September 1, 2013.</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="H0EB4E9C02F4B47AE96A8A262272B4FDB">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Sleep disorders defined</header>
        <text>In this section, the term <term>sleep disorders</term> includes obstructive sleep apnea.</text> </subsection>
    </section>
</legis-body> <attestation>
    <attestation-group>
      <role>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</role>
    </attestation-group>
    <attestation-group>
      <role>Vice President of the United States and President of the Senate.</role>
    </attestation-group>
  </attestation>
</bill>