<bill session="113" type="s" number="2233" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-04-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-04-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Disaster Tax Relief Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide tax relief for major disaster areas declared in 2012 and 2013 and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300087"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412330" joined="2014-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412598" joined="2014-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2014-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2014-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2014-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2014-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="2014-04-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4497"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="5082"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2634"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Charitable contributions"/>
    <term name="Credit and credit markets"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Homelessness and emergency shelter"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Life, casualty, property insurance"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Tax treatment of families"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/9/2014--Introduced.
National Disaster Tax Relief Act of 2014 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide tax relief for disasters declared in 2012 and 2013 by:

 extending through 2013&#160;the election to expense qualified disaster expenses (i.e., for removal of debris, demolition, and repair of business-related property); increasing the tax deduction for charitable contributions for disaster relief for individual and corporate taxpayers; allowing through 2013 the deduction of losses attributable to disasters; allowing waivers of requirements relating to mortgage revenue bonds; extending through 2013 the additional allowance for depreciation of business property (bonus depreciation); allowing an increase in 2012 and 2013 of the new markets tax credit limitation amount within a federally-declared disaster area; permitting the use of tax-exempt retirement plan funds in federally-declared disasters without penalty; allowing an additional tax exemption for individuals who are displaced as a result of a federally-declared disaster; allowing an exclusion from gross income of imputed income from the cancellation of indebtedness resulting from federally-declared disasters; providing a special rule to allow individuals affected by a disaster in 2012 or 2103 to claim a full earned income tax credit; increasing the rehabilitation tax credit for buildings affected by a federally-declared disaster; permitting one additional advance refunding of a tax-exempt bond that is outstanding on the date on which a federally-declared disaster occurs; allowing the issuance of qualified disaster area recovery bonds; allowing an additional allocation of the low-income housing tax credit in 2014&#160;to states affected by a federally-declared disaster occurring in 2012 or 2013;&#160;&#160; allowing payments of disaster assistance to tax-exempt mutual ditch or irrigation companies without affecting their tax-exempt status; allowing an exclusion from gross income for disaster mitigation payments received from state and local governments; and allowing a tax deduction for payments to a tax-exempt natural disaster fund.</summary>
</bill>
