<bill session="113" type="h" number="5153" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Act of September 16, 1922, to clarify the responsibility of Federal agencies to remove snow and ice for areas around Federal buildings in the District of Columbia.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400295"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1192"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Pedestrians and bicycling"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/17/2014--Introduced.
Assigns responsibility to a federal agency for the removal of snow, sleet, or ice from any paved sidewalk or crosswalk within the fire limits of the District of Columbia that is: (1) in front of or adjacent to any building that is owned by the United States and under the jurisdiction of the federal agency; or (2) a public thoroughfare in front of, around, or through any public square, reservation, or open space that is owned by the United States and under the jurisdiction of the federal agency.

Requires: (1)&#160;the removal of such snow, sleet, or ice within a reasonable period after the snow or sleet ceases to fall or the ice has accumulated; and (2)&#160;the federal agency to make the sidewalk or crosswalk reasonably safe for travel by applying sand, ashes, salt, or other acceptable materials if the snow, sleet, or ice has hardened and cannot be removed.</summary>
</bill>
