<bill session="113" type="h" number="3835" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-01-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-01-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-01-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Before Registering for Obamacare, Window Shop Exchanges Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">BROWSE Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require new procedures for health care Exchange Web sites with regard to personal information, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412488"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-01-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H112-113"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/9/2014--Introduced.
Before Registering for Obamacare, Window Shop Exchanges Act of 2014 or the BROWSE Act of 2014 - Prohibits an American Health Benefit Exchange established pursuant to the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act from: (1) requesting personal information of an individual through a website maintained by such Exchange unless such information is necessary to calculate an estimated premium for such individual and such individual has access to compare health care plans offered through such Exchange; or (2) providing to an individual, through such a website, an estimated premium if such premium is calculated prior to the submission by the individual of personal information through the website. Requires such an Exchange to require that any employee who has access to personal information: (1) passes a criminal background check, (2) has not been convicted of a crime, and (3) enters into an agreement not to disclose any such personal information to anyone not authorized to access it.</summary>
</bill>
