<bill session="113" type="h" number="5566" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SMART Grant Reauthorization Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to restore National SMART Grants for a certain number of award years.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412407"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412396" joined="2014-09-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Training" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Foreign language and bilingual programs"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/18/2014--Introduced.
SMART Grant Reauthorization Act of 2014 - Amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to eliminate the program awarding Academic Competitiveness Grants to first- and second-year undergraduates who completed a rigorous high school curriculum and are eligible for Federal Pell Grants.

Reauthorizes and appropriates funds through FY2020 for National Science and Mathematics Access to Retain Talent Grants (SMART Grants) currently awarded to third, fourth, and fifth-year undergraduates who are eligible for Pell Grants and are pursuing:

 a major in the physical, life, or computer sciences, mathematics, technology, or engineering or a critical foreign language; or equivalent coursework in a qualifying liberal arts program that does not allow students to declare a major in a particular subject matter. Limits SMART Grant eligibility to students who are pursuing a major in the physical sciences or are pursuing equivalent coursework in a qualifying liberal arts program that does not allow students to declare a major in a particular subject matter.

Terminates the Secretary of Education's authority to award SMART Grants at the end of award year 2020-2021.</summary>
</bill>
