<bill session="113" type="s" number="2792" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Apprenticeship and Jobs Training Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a tax credit for on-site apprenticeship programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300018"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2014-09-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/11/2014--Introduced.
Apprenticeship and Jobs Training Act of 2014 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow employers a business-related tax credit for up to $5,000 for the training of a qualified individual in a qualified apprenticeship program. Defines a "qualified individual" as an individual who: (1) is an apprentice participating in a&#160;qualified apprenticeship program, (2)&#160;has been employed in such a program for a period of at least seven months that ends within the taxable year, and (3) is not a highly compensated employee or a seasonal worker. Defines a "qualified apprenticeship program" as a program that: (1) provides qualified individuals with on-the-job training and instruction for a qualified occupation (i.e., a skilled trade occupation in a high-demand mechanical, technical, health care, or technology field); (2) is registered with the Office of Apprenticeship of the Department of Labor; and (3) maintains records relating to the qualified individual.

Allows a premature distribution, without penalty, from&#160;a tax-qualified retirement plan to an employee who is serving as a mentor. Defines a "mentor" as a working individual who: (1) has attained age 55; (2) works reduced hours and engages in mentoring activities for at least 20% of such hours; and (3) is responsible for the training and education of employees or students in an area of expertise for which such individual has a professional credential, certificate, or degree.</summary>
</bill>
