<bill session="113" type="h" number="4300" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-03-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-03-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-03-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sacramento Valley Water Storage and Restoration Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to take actions to support non-Federal investments in water infrastructure improvements in the Sacramento Valley, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412510"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="2014-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400618" joined="2014-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412382" joined="2014-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400297" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400403" joined="2014-09-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-03-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/26/2014--Introduced.
Sacramento Valley Water Storage and Restoration Act of 2014 - Directs the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Bureau of Reclamation, to: (1) finalize and publish in the Federal Register the feasibility study authorized in the Water Supply, Reliability, and Environmental Improvement Act, for enlargement of the Los Vaqueros Reservoir in Contra Costa County, California; (2) work with the Secretary of Commerce, the Army Corps of Engineers, and the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) Administrator, by June 30, 2015, to coordinate the efforts of the relevant agencies and work with the state of California, the Sites Project Authority, and other stakeholders to complete and issue the final joint environmental impact statement and report on the Sites Project (the Sites Reservoir in Glenn and Colusa Counties, California, and related facilities, including associated water conveyance and hydropower generation and transmission facilities); and (3) enter into agreements with the Authority to carry out such work as the Bureau and the Authority mutually agree is appropriate to ensure that all studies and environmental reviews are completed on an expeditious basis and that the shortest applicable process under the National Environmental Policy Act is utilized, including in the completion of the final feasibility study and final joint environmental impact statement and report on the Sites Project.

Amends the Calfed Bay-Delta Authorization Act to: (1) authorize construction of the Sites Reservoir in Colusa County if the Secretary determines that the project is feasible; and (2) direct the Bureau, at the Authority's request, to enter into a project partnership agreement for the Authority to provide full project management control for construction of the Sites Project, or a separable element of the Project, in accordance with plans approved by the Secretary.

Authorizes and directs: (1) the Bureau to advance the Sites Project as a non-federal project if the Commissioner of the Bureau determines and the Secretary concurs that the Project can be expedited by the Authority as a non-federal project and that there is a demonstrable federal interest for the Project to be constructed and operated as a non-federal project, and (2) the Secretary to execute and implement a long-term agreement with the Authority for the coordination of operations of the Central Valley Project and the Sites Project.

Directs the Bureau to: (1) be the lead federal agency for the purposes of all federal reviews, analyses, opinions, statements, permits, licenses, or other approvals or decisions required under federal law to allow either the Bureau or the Authority to construct the Sites Project; and (2) take such steps as necessary to ensure that all such reviews, approvals, or decisions required to allow either the Bureau or the Authority to construct the Sites Project are completed on an expeditious basis and utilize the shortest applicable process.

Directs the Secretary of Energy (DOE): (1) acting through the Western Area Power Administration, to determine by no later than June 30, 2015, if there is a federal interest in providing power to, and purchasing and marketing power produced by, the Sites Project; (2) if so, to take actions to support such determination; and (3) if not, to provide such support as is necessary to enable the Authority to market the energy produced by the Project.</summary>
</bill>
