<bill session="113" type="h" number="3761" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-12-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-12-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-12-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To properly define and distinguish between decorative hearth products and vented hearth heaters.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412431"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400068" joined="2014-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412535" joined="2013-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412278" joined="2014-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400218" joined="2014-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400224" joined="2013-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412256" joined="2014-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412487" joined="2014-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400659" joined="2013-12-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-12-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Lighting and heating"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/12/2013--Introduced.
Amends the Energy Policy and Conservation Act to exempt decorative hearth products from consideration as direct heating equipment subject to the Act's energy efficiency standards.

Defines a "decorative hearth product" as a vented gas fireplace, stove, gas fireplace insert, or gas log set that: (1) is not certified to the ANSI Z21.88 standard and, in the case of vented gas fireplaces, fireplace inserts, or stoves, is certified to the ANSI Z21.50 standard; (2) is sold without a thermostat and with a warranty provision expressly voiding manufacturer warranties in the event the product is used with a thermostat; and (3) contains no energy efficiency representations other than P.4 efficiencies required for products sold in Canada.

Adds the product category "vented hearth heater," defined as a vented gas fireplace, fireplace insert, or stove: (1) for which any AFUE (annual fuel utilization efficiency) representation, or representation with respect to P.4 efficiencies required for products sold in Canada, is made in any manufacturer advertising or literature; (2) certified to the ANSI Z21.88 standard or identified in any manufacturer literature or advertising as a "heater-rated" product; or (3) equipped by the manufacturer with a thermostatic control.

Deems a vented gas fireplace, fireplace insert, stove, or gas log set that is not a decorative hearth product to be direct heating equipment for purposes of the Act.</summary>
</bill>
