<bill session="113" type="h" number="3034" updated="2015-09-01T10:19:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Flood Research and Education Center Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a National Flood Research and Education Center to provide research, data, and recommendations on physical science, social science, economic analysis, policy analysis, risk analysis, monitoring, predicting, and planning as they relate to flooding and flood related issues.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412209"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400008" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412208" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412571" joined="2014-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400081" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400195" joined="2013-08-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-08-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-02">
      <text>Referred to House Science, Space, and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-02">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY18" subcommittee="Environment" name="House Science, Space, and Technology"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hydrology and hydrography"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Policy sciences"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Social sciences and history"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/2/2013--Introduced.
National Flood Research and Education Center Act - Establishes within the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) a National Flood Research and Education Center (NFREC), which shall consist of: (1) an office within NOAA; (2) one public university or college selected by the NOAA Administrator, which shall serve as the lead partner institution with NOAA; and (3) a consortium of other public universities or colleges selected by the Administrator and such lead partner institution based on their ability to fulfill specific purposes of NFREC.

Lists the purposes of NFREC, including to plan, conduct, and arrange for competent public research, data, education, and recommendations within the following categories as they relate to flooding issues nationwide, regionally, and locally: (1) physical sciences, social science, and economic, policy, and risk analysis; (2) risk management; and (3) improvement of existing, and testing of new, risk assessment tools and methods, monitoring and predicting strategies and techniques, and flood management and prevention strategies and techniques.

Sets forth criteria for selection of a lead partner institution and consortium members.

Directs NFREC to: (1) partner with the U.S. Geological Survey (USGS) and the Army Corps of Engineers; (2) collaborate on federal flood-related issues with specified federal agencies; and (3) collaborate and share best practices on regional, state, and locally specific flooding and flood-related issues with state and local governments and with watershed, agriculture, environmental, and business and development organizations.

Sets forth review and reporting requirements. Requires NFREC to establish and make information available on a website.

Authorizes NFREC to provide technical assistance and demonstration project grant assistance to state and local governments on a competitive basis to assist with implementing recommendations of NFREC or testing new or improved strategies or technologies.</summary>
</bill>
