<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HACB2759736694E979929B3AA690296A7" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>105 HR 3615 IH: Careers for Heroes Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2013-11-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress>113th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>H. R. 3615</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20131121">November 21, 2013</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000578">Mr. Reichert</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans’ Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the hiring of veterans by the Federal Government.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6D4D91D8469F46A9BE31474764F49BE7" style="OLC"><section id="H38025A7D9C334346B9D9DC560BDE929C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Careers for Heroes Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HE6FA50DE4A8E4449A18D1AEA03AD0AAB" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Employment of veterans with the Federal Government</header><subsection id="H47490E95148D4E27AACBDAF6E7B8E8D8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/4214">Section 4214</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H12C4037839154993827620A5342E2DD9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H61630CBF28F34CD683473415B85E417B" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H7B694241C0FD438F93A7A8CCEB396D37" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H958FDDADFCF94493B87C78B0B498B41C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The requirement under this paragraph is in addition to the appointment of qualified covered veterans under the authority under paragraph (1) by the Department of Veterans Affairs and the Department of Defense.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE7FAADF50C1F4B3C8E5B7B91B7546D77" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The head of each agency (excluding the Secretary of Veterans Affairs and the Secretary of Defense), in consultation with the Director of the Office of Personnel Management, shall develop and implement a plan for exercising the authority specified in subparagraph (C) during the five-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this paragraph.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA5D849CB46E44DFDBC802C3D77ACA088" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The authority specified in this subparagraph is the authority as follows:</text><clause id="HD50BAA7A0F2249A7A2F2D8C4674B122B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The authority under paragraph (1).</text></clause><clause id="H1ABA82B2AC3D4C518C967764887E7C48"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The authority available to the agency concerned under the Veterans Employment Opportunities Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/105/339">Public Law 105–339</external-xref>) and the amendments made by that Act.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H34D35C2D1F42423883D5ED5A6C4AFC82" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall ensure that under the plans developed under subparagraph (B), agencies shall appoint to existing vacancies not fewer than 15,000 qualified covered veterans during the five-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this paragraph. For purposes of complying with this subparagraph, an appointment pursuant to the authority referred to in subparagraph (C)(ii) shall not count toward the number required by this subparagraph unless the appointment is to a vacancy in a full-time, permanent position.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HAF2FB49D24264373986EDFC60CA35F5C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (d), in the third sentence, by inserting <quote>(including, during the five-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of paragraph (4) of subsection (b), the development and implementation by each agency of the plan required under such paragraph, which shall include information regarding the grade or pay level of appointments by the agency under the plan and whether the appointments are, or are converted to, career or career-conditional appointments)</quote> after <quote>subsection (b) of this section</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDB25F382011240AAA4307EEE889A83F2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (e)—</text><subparagraph id="H789C2411414F4F4F85259F76F77F8911"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text><clause id="HBD5F7FC0F69A4F4ABB78460A7297CB2B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the matter before subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>to the Congress</quote> and inserting <quote>to the appropriate committees of Congress</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="HA49E1BA8718B41D4BDAB3478B4E1EEC3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>(including, during the five-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of paragraph (4) of subsection (b), the development and implementation by the agency of the plan required under such paragraph, which shall include information regarding the grade or pay level of appointments by the agency under the plan and whether the appointments are, or are converted to, permanent appointments)</quote> before the period; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC934D6CEC6AE432DB392A2184E119D0A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0A6D069CD3EF41C1BB581E844CD9F240" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H9968E13AB6734FBCB9DCA0B7C25322AA" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In this subsection, the term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H6C706C532B0E43BFBDE75158A5876B2C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD47FC4BC404A43ADB708ACF4C94ACCD1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs and the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA735FFB05FF147FCAC9E1410384BE070"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress (as defined under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/4214">section 4214(e)(3)</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, as amended by subsection (a)) a report containing a plan to carry out the amendments made by subsection (a).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


