<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="H9AEDA332B4784D359629DDA9510C4102" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HR 5059 EH: Clay Hunt SAV Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress> <session>2d Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 5059</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to provide for the conduct of annual evaluations of mental health care and suicide prevention programs of the Department of Veterans Affairs, to require a pilot program on loan repayment for psychiatrists who agree to serve in the Veterans Health Administration of the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HF3030EBF38194FAD9C1B681BFB6709C9" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H3ECFA284B11942F688296ED8E30F30D4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Clay Hunt Suicide Prevention for American Veterans Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote>Clay Hunt SAV Act</quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H93F7572AD70C4692B7D90B19C6E45095"><enum>2.</enum><header>Evaluations of mental health care and suicide prevention programs of Department of Veterans Affairs</header> 
<subsection id="HC9E7461686354895AFE70CFEC6903D38"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Evaluations</header> 
<paragraph id="H188B3463E189481C8D317076A38B2E00"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not less frequently than once each year, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall provide for the conduct of an evaluation of the mental health care and suicide prevention programs carried out under the laws administered by the Secretary.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2482C48482C74FE5B8B1F2EE705BE0B4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>Each evaluation conducted under paragraph (1) shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HCDFFF9D945CA4923A23B11F216460CAA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>use metrics that are common among and useful for practitioners in the field of mental health care and suicide prevention;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H60DDAA9702B34F19BE42867C93417053"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identify the most effective mental health care and suicide prevention programs conducted by the Secretary, including such programs conducted at a Center of Excellence;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H72C12573B523451AA5C4B25EAAC50B0B"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify the cost-effectiveness of each program identified under subparagraph (B);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H21FE861CC0A8414CA09F5E6B2AD7D886"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">measure the satisfaction of patients with respect to the care provided under each such program; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB514592D7876478185C984F48981F046"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">propose best practices for caring for individuals who suffer from mental health disorders or are at risk of suicide, including such practices conducted or suggested by other departments or agencies of the Federal Government, including the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration of the Department of Health and Human Services.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC75FBE0CB7634130BE92B605264FB6B0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Third party</header><text>Each evaluation conducted under paragraph (1) shall be conducted by an independent third party unaffiliated with the Department of Veterans Affairs. Such third party shall submit to the Secretary each such evaluation.</text></paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H7CF95E0E0CAD4AFFA68C289C41F38593"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Annual submission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than December 1 of each year, beginning in 2015, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report that contains the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H5817C4265487449BB7C8B3EF453F2900"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The most recent evaluations submitted to the Secretary under subsection (a)(3) that the Secretary has not previously submitted to such Committees.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H48348AE35BD94BA5976B08E59E807E95"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any recommendations the Secretary considers appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection> </section> 
<section id="H5905384EBEE9444FBEB5C0CD1291ADB6"><enum>3.</enum><header>Publication of Internet website to provide information regarding mental health care services</header> 
<subsection id="HD96AED106EC04BF1870807F63B405B21" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Using funds made available to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to publish the Internet websites of the Department of Veterans Affairs, the Secretary shall survey the existing Internet websites and information resources of the Department to publish an Internet website that serves as a centralized source to provide veterans with information regarding all of the mental health care services provided by the Secretary.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H428CCAC9EC484C438150C27ABAB68452"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Internet website published under subsection (a) shall provide to veterans information regarding all of the mental health care services available in the Veteran Integrated Service Network that the veteran is seeking such services, including, with respect to each medical center, Vet Center (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/1712A">section 1712A</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code), and community-based outpatient center in the Veterans Integrated Service Network—</text> 
<paragraph id="H6A38DE8A93A84DD3A3431997F3E7258C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the name and contact information of each social work office;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H81326EF885CA46339426754620822ED4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the name and contact information of each mental health clinic;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H741CE1608390430091FB6EF1E8849B74"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a list of appropriate staff; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3A740845000E43B7924FBE46BB8A4011"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any other information the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7D881C8E571442FF838D725712BDDECA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Updated information</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that the information described in subsection (b) that is published on the Internet website under subsection (a) is updated not less than once every 90 days.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H38E3A201EFDF4114B13611E1B9E06C19"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Outreach</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall ensure that the outreach conducted under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/1720F">section 1720F(i)</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, includes information regarding the Internet website published under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H3C0C0D8EC2084AE99FA31D0330089ABF"><enum>4.</enum><header>Pilot program for repayment of educational loans for certain psychiatrists of Veterans Health Administration</header> 
<subsection id="HECA138B424454A399AA0CF08B39C60F5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall carry out a pilot program to repay loans of individuals described in subsection (b) that—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA8F177466A534B728A31B34F7363655F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">were used by such individuals to finance education relating to psychiatric medicine, including education leading to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD29CDD1932844D52A77D168F53A8172C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a degree of doctor of medicine; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7A8EAF5C11B94D5BAEA73745C91EB4F4"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a degree of doctor of osteopathy; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8CFFAF184F4E422F91FBE82A7AE3EF9C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>were obtained from any of the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7B40660035BF4E0CA9024BE2EDA68A4F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A governmental entity.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6805897E3EFC40F2952EF7E549AC2358"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A private financial institution.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4BA9CFDB070642839A66E9BE10782779"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A school.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H366D815E72B14920AB85D09217480A54"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Any other authorized entity as determined by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4CA7EC777D0146DDA5DE9D5314CB1AF2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible individuals</header> 
<paragraph id="H5CB3D4D6095E40F6AA0AC8CC661B8F1A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), an individual eligible for participation in the pilot program is an individual who—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7957256BB72B4FE1825F5FCA7B286FD5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>either—</text> 
<clause id="H1E3DC616442E46AFBA7C0227B93B9702"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is licensed or eligible for licensure to practice psychiatric medicine in the Veterans Health Administration of the Department of Veterans Affairs; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H027534381FA6442FA23A7A9143F3E2D7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is enrolled in the final year of a residency program leading to a specialty qualification in psychiatric medicine that is approved by the Accreditation Council for Graduate Medical Education; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7184DB43F3F443B48B2EC3CE97AEB128"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">demonstrates a commitment to a long-term career as a psychiatrist in the Veterans Health Administration, as determined by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6D24FD97538445F2B30192C60F0D4508"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prohibition on simultaneous eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual who is participating in any other program of the Federal Government that repays the educational loans of the individual is not eligible to participate in the pilot program.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0E0E3F359BF84F5D85016EB648CFCCBB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Selection</header><text>The Secretary shall select not less than 10 individuals described in subsection (b) to participate in the pilot program for each year in which the Secretary carries out the pilot program.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H16E7D386C9874A2BA499D8C21B669D1C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Period of obligated service</header><text>The Secretary shall enter into an agreement with each individual selected under subsection (c) in which such individual agrees to serve a period of 2 or more years of obligated service for the Veterans Health Administration in the field of psychiatric medicine, as determined by the Secretary.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1A93364D05394C43BDD30B29D40A1CE5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Loan Repayments</header> 
<paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDA4F21C91D4441DEA84C3216AF242247"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Amounts</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), a loan repayment under this section may consist of payment of the principal, interest, and related expenses of a loan obtained by an individual who is participating in the pilot program for all educational expenses (including tuition, fees, books, and laboratory expenses) of such individual relating to education described in subsection (a)(1).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H19E49D0D1CA04869BB7DEC3890952EA5" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limit</header><text>For each year of obligated service that an individual who is participating in the pilot program agrees to serve under subsection (d), the Secretary may pay not more than $30,000 in loan repayment on behalf of such individual.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H05C3A4F5B298451DA4406EECB827E118"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Breach</header> 
<paragraph id="H66BFB5B537FF4FC8A7216BD6F58C6BED"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Liability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual who participates in the pilot program and fails to satisfy the period of obligated service under subsection (d) shall be liable to the United States, in lieu of such obligated service, for the amount that has been paid or is payable to or on behalf of the individual under the pilot program, reduced by the proportion that the number of days served for completion of the period of obligated service bears to the total number of days in the period of obligated service of such individual.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD79EFFE9E09C4EA0B5D429CBDBE235FE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Repayment period</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any amount of damages that the United States is entitled to recover under this subsection shall be paid to the United States not later than 1 year after the date of the breach of the agreement.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAB953D67BAE1421CA4DF34098FC30163"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Report</header> 
<paragraph id="HF9CBC89DF7574521B5F2DF26CCD8A5DC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date on which the pilot program under subsection (a) commences, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the pilot program.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H27395ADA4BB8482DA365B706241FC5FB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required by paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HAFFADCAF88394AB1A040F26CA08EE3BB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The number of individuals who participated in the pilot program, including the number of new hires.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H1FCE41DA918542B5894D9067E7F1D253"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The locations in which such individuals were employed by the Department, including how many such locations were rural or urban locations.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H7B07AFB9CB424213AFC564F5A24BF90B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An assessment of the quality of the work performed by such individuals in the course of such employment, including the performance reviews of such individuals.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H1E5E48AD32D8416F873DB35DF012DE85"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The number of psychiatrists the Secretary determines is needed by the Department in the future.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6FB90306124D4456A902BF92DBC31135"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Final report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days before the date on which the pilot program terminates under subsection (i), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives an update to the report submitted under paragraph (1) and any recommendations that the Secretary considers appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBDBE418CA2254F168ECB0023A9493ECD"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary shall prescribe regulations to carry out this section, including standards for qualified loans and authorized payees and other terms and conditions for the making of loan repayments.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H61C931CDAFBB46A7AACB7F619A2A184B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The authority to carry out the pilot program shall expire on the date that is 3 years after the date on which the Secretary commences the pilot program.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HD3F648014F3D46BE807175488E251483"><enum>5.</enum><header>Pilot program on community outreach</header> 
<subsection id="HDB5DAF5EFFBC44259E43D0EA769D368D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall establish a pilot program to assist veterans transitioning from serving on active duty and to improve the access of veterans to mental health services.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H28F6C1BAE522458AA77C211665FC9934"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Locations</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out the pilot program under subsection (a) at not less than five Veterans Integrated Service Networks that have a large population of veterans who—</text> 
<paragraph id="HF2182737BE234A0BB2CAA8202C368027"><enum>(1)</enum><text>served in the reserve components of the Armed Forces; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1543C9FF0F3440248554EFA0913BD30F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>are transitioning into communities with an established population of veterans after having recently separated from the Armed Forces.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H55FE9FC28F49475C940236198D382578"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Functions</header><text>The pilot program at each Veterans Integrated Service Network described in subsection (b) shall include the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H7C98743DF60F4AEAB15533EDB97E0625"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A community oriented veteran peer support network, carried out in partnership with an appropriate entity with experience in peer support programs, that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD0E208C0A5BF4D1DABB8B1EC781664D8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establishes peer support training guidelines;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3245E03F4CF244959D825237A1EA1ED5"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develops a network of veteran peer support counselors to meet the demands of the communities in the Veterans Integrated Service Network;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEDC0A3AEA6614A86860814F96873FD97"><enum>(C)</enum><text>conducts training of veteran peer support counselors;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H77C961BDD6A149098DE2AA5EEFA58E04"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to one medical center selected by the Secretary in each such Veterans Integrated Service Network, has—</text> 
<clause id="H9A82AF81103B401F833397053DD445F8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a designated peer support specialist who acts as a liaison to the community oriented veteran peer network; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HAB4046171D5D4EFBA5EC261D84A448D4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a certified mental health professional designated as the community oriented veteran peer network mentor; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H978C865B08CA427892DB5055C2450297"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is readily available to veterans, including pursuant to the Veterans Integrated Service Network cooperating and working with State and local governments and appropriate entities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H64252BB010164380A5B5811FD0CA689B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A community outreach team for each medical center selected by the Secretary pursuant to paragraph (1)(D) that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H284D742A9C00471B9E055A5BCFB62220"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assists veterans transitioning into communities;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA04B38363E954CB2BF303452374B0DCA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establishes a veteran transition advisory group to facilitate outreach activities;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H00B77688082D431D868963CB41E1ACEC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>includes the participation of appropriate community organizations, State and local governments, colleges and universities, chambers of commerce and other local business organizations, and organizations that provide legal aid or advice; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H63A344F46FD147C4BD1E5AE9ECC50710"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coordinates with the Veterans Integrated Service Network regarding the Veterans Integrated Service Network carrying out an annual mental health summit to assess the status of veteran mental health care in the community and to develop new or innovative means to provide mental health services to veterans.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA0F49A3C955B4A92A2A79DAB3DC96635"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reports</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H4C63ADFFC8D4430898C7472D7F5D300B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date on which the pilot program under subsection (a) commences, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the pilot program. With respect to each Veterans Integrated Service Network described in subsection (b), the report shall include—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H2A5C4B5F993344F2A3A002B6B3D39C53"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a full description of the peer support model implemented under the pilot program, participation data, and data pertaining to past and current mental health related hospitalizations and fatalities;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HF7EB21EB7D974D7C854A8F3F6517978B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>recommendations on implementing peer support networks throughout the Department;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H4BDE4F6797E54803A5D03F415B6D6550"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether the mental health resources made available under the pilot program for members of the reserve components of the Armed Forces is effective; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H0F7B84884B2A4D69A3B95240CD75D521"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a full description of the activities and effectiveness of community outreach coordinating teams under the pilot program, including partnerships that have been established with appropriate entities.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE3463C5F9FE54FAE823CD1ECBB74B67B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Final report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days before the date on which the pilot program terminates under subsection (e), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives an update to the report submitted under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB6302F2A0EDE44188D358C0381966960" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Construction</header><text>This section may not be construed to authorize the Secretary to hire additional employees of the Department to carry out the pilot program under subsection (a).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC1C57001B2CC473DA28166CF9DAE07C3"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The authority of the Secretary to carry out the pilot program under subsection (a) shall terminate on the date that is 3 years after the date on which the pilot program commences.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HF0E90AF2FB2B4F1B90613D94C0D19022" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>6.</enum><header>Collaboration on suicide prevention efforts between Department of Veterans Affairs and non-profit mental health organizations</header> 
<subsection id="HBC058B2DCCA54B9B840CFADCAE2C864B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Collaboration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs may collaborate with non-profit mental health organizations to prevent suicide among veterans as follows:</text> 
<paragraph id="H978C05B11C464F2C8419F3E22B102584"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To improve the efficiency and effectiveness of suicide prevention efforts carried out by the Secretary and non-profit mental health organizations.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H74F94F2C8B924427A3E990E298CB7035"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To assist non-profit mental health organizations with the suicide prevention efforts of such organizations through the use of the expertise of employees of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBE6E5FBF4F3D4DA8AA45382F6BA3BDAA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>To jointly carry out suicide prevention efforts.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0D39E464807E4DEAA706075EE431FA65"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exchange of resources</header><text>In carrying out any collaboration under subsection (a), the Secretary and any non-profit mental health organization with which the Secretary is collaborating under such subsection shall exchange training sessions and best practices to help with the suicide prevention efforts of the Department and such organization.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2C50E4BC35C34439827CDF9DD04F3B2D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Director of Suicide Prevention Coordination</header><text>The Secretary shall select within the Department a Director of Suicide Prevention Coordination to undertake any collaboration with non-profit mental health organizations under this section or any other provision of law.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H2D67F8A7FF244FAA8E083598A0782C53" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>7.</enum><header>Additional period of eligibility for health care for certain veterans of combat service during certain periods of hostilities and war</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Paragraph (3) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/1710">section 1710(e)</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB1D237CB83974756B7FDF0903B89900B" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="H68EA48E066004C809374FA5B8FAC3ED3" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of care for a veteran described in paragraph (1)(D), hospital care, medical services, and nursing home care may be provided under or by virtue of subsection (a)(2)(F) only during the following periods:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA7BD06A9F0174D34902714372F7F6731"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided by subparagraph (B), with respect to a veteran described in paragraph (1)(D) who is discharged or released from the active military, naval, or air service after January 27, 2003, the five-year period beginning on the date of such discharge or release.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7A0C58501D6D4D83915C6C37C7CAA91F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to a veteran described in paragraph (1)(D) who is discharged or released from the active military, naval, or air service after January 1, 2009, and before January 1, 2011, but did not enroll to receive such hospital care, medical services, or nursing home care pursuant to such paragraph during the five-year period described in subparagraph (A), the one-year period beginning on January 1, 2015.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD9A45094315C4080BD50896DC8CD7F39"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to a veteran described in paragraph (1)(D) who is discharged or released from the active military, naval, or air service on or before January 27, 2003, and did not enroll in the patient enrollment system under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/1705">section 1705</external-xref> of this title on or before such date, the three-year period beginning on January 27, 2008.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section> 
<section id="H379FB888A0154C9C872540776CCF5CC4"><enum>8.</enum><header>Prohibition on new appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No additional funds are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act and the amendments made by this Act, and this Act and such amendments shall be carried out using amounts otherwise made available for such purposes.</text></section> 
</legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20141209" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives December 9, 2014.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation> 
<endorsement display="yes"></endorsement> 
</bill> 


