<bill session="113" type="h" number="4800" updated="2015-09-01T17:49:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-04T14:04:00-04:00">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-06-04T14:04:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Making appropriations for Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies programs for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2015, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400004"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-04T14:03:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 113-468, by Mr. Aderholt.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-06-04T14:04:00-04:00" state="REPORTED" calendar="Union" number="347">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 347.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-06-10T19:33:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 616 Reported to House. Rule provides for one hour of general debate on the bills. H.R. 4800 shall be considred for amendment under a modified open rule. H.R. 4457 and H.R. 4453 shall be considred for amendment under a closed rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11T13:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 616.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5265-5295" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5287, H5289, H5290, H5291, H5293-5294, H5294, H5296, H5297, H5298-5299" label="text of Title I as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5299" label="text of Title II as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5301-5303" label="text of Title III as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5303-5304" label="text of Title IV as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5304-5305" label="text of Title V as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5305, H5307" label="text of Title VI as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11T13:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for one hour of general debate on the bill. H.R. 4800 shall be considered for amendment under a modified open rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11T13:51:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 616 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11T13:51:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Doc Hastings to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11T13:52:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 4800.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11T15:01:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 616, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Lee (CA) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11T15:06:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 616, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Thompson (CA) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11T15:11:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 616, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gallego amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11T15:15:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 616, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hinojosa amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11T15:20:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 616, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gosar amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11T15:24:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 616, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the first Broun (GA) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11T15:27:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Broun (GA) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Broun (GA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11T15:28:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 616, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gosar amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11T15:33:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 616, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Cohen amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11T15:39:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 616, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the second Broun (GA) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11T15:46:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Broun (GA) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Broun (GA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11T15:48:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 616, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Schiff amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11T15:53:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 616, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Royce amendment No. 7.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11T16:02:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Royce amendment No. 7, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Aderholt demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11T16:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Aderholt moved that the committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11T16:03:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11T16:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 4800 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11T16:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5296-5312" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11T16:52:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11T16:53:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 616, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gardner amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11T16:57:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 616, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Grayson amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11T17:04:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Grayson amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Grayson demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11T17:06:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 616, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the McNerney amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11T17:10:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 616, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Garamendi amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11T17:15:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Garamendi amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Garamendi demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11T17:18:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 616, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the third Broun (GA) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11T17:28:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Broun (GA) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Broun (GA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11T17:29:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 616, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Duncan (TN) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11T17:36:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Duncan(TN) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Duncan(TN) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11T17:40:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 616, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Speier amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11T17:48:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 616, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the DeLauro amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11T18:02:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the DeLauro amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. DeLauro demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11T18:02:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that, pursuant to clause 6 of Rule XVIII, the unfinished business was the question of adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11T19:01:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Aderholt moved to rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11T19:02:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11T19:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 4800 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hr" number="616"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="113" type="hr" number="616"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="83"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2389"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation and pollution"/>
    <term name="Agricultural education"/>
    <term name="Agricultural marketing and promotion"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices, subsidies, credit"/>
    <term name="Agricultural research"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Animal and plant health"/>
    <term name="Animal protection and human-animal relationships"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Business ethics"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="Commodity Credit Corporation"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Farm Credit Administration"/>
    <term name="Food and Drug Administration (FDA)"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Food industry and services"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Fruit and vegetables"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government corporations and government-sponsored enterprises"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Mammals"/>
    <term name="Meat"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h846"/>
    <amendment number="h847"/>
    <amendment number="h848"/>
    <amendment number="h849"/>
    <amendment number="h850"/>
    <amendment number="h851"/>
    <amendment number="h852"/>
    <amendment number="h853"/>
    <amendment number="h854"/>
    <amendment number="h855"/>
    <amendment number="h856"/>
    <amendment number="h857"/>
    <amendment number="h858"/>
    <amendment number="h859"/>
    <amendment number="h860"/>
    <amendment number="h861"/>
    <amendment number="h862"/>
    <amendment number="h863"/>
    <amendment number="h864"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>6/4/2014--Reported to House without amendment.
Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2015 - Title I: Agricultural Programs - Appropriates FY2015 funds for the following Department of Agriculture (USDA) programs and services: (1) Office of the Secretary of Agriculture (Secretary); (2) Office of the Chief Economist; (3) National Appeals Division; (4) Office of Budget and Program Analysis; (5) Office of the Chief Information Officer; (6) Office of the Chief Financial Officer; (7) Office of the Assistant Secretary for Civil Rights; (8) Office of Civil Rights; (9) agriculture buildings and facilities; (10) hazardous materials management; (11) Office of Inspector General; (12) Office of the General Counsel; (13) Office of Ethics; (14) Office of the Under Secretary for Research, Education, and Economics; (15) Economic Research Service; (16) National Agricultural Statistics Service; (17) Agricultural Research Service; (18) National Institute of Food and Agriculture; (19) Native American Institutions Endowment Fund; (20) extension and integrated activities; (21) Office of the Under Secretary for Marketing and Regulatory Programs; (22) Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service; (23) Agricultural Marketing Service; (24) Grain Inspection, Packers and Stockyards Administration; (25) Office of the Under Secretary for Food Safety; (26) Food Safety and Inspection Service; (27) Office of the Under Secretary for Farm and Foreign Agricultural Services; (28) Farm Service Agency; (29) Risk Management Agency; (30) Federal Crop Insurance Corporation Fund; and (31) Commodity Credit Corporation Fund.

Title II: Conservation Programs - Appropriates funds for the following: (1) Office of the Under Secretary for Natural Resources and Environment, and (2) Natural Resources Conservation Service.

Title III: Rural Development Programs - Appropriates funds for the following: (1) Office of the Under Secretary for Rural Development, (2) Rural Housing Service, (3) Rural Business-Cooperative Service, and (4) Rural Utilities Service.

Title IV: Domestic Food Programs - Appropriates funds for the following: (1) Office of the Under Secretary for Food, Nutrition and Consumer Services; and (2) Food and Nutrition Service.

Title V: Foreign Assistance and Related Programs - Appropriates funds for the following: (1) the Foreign Agricultural Service, (2) Food for Peace Act (P.L. 480) program title I and title II grants, (3) Commodity Credit Corporation (CCC) export loan credit guarantee program, and (4) the McGovern-Dole international food for education and child nutrition program.

Title VI: Related Agencies and Food and Drug Administration - Appropriates funds for the following: (1) Food and Drug Administration (FDA), and (2) Farm Credit Administration (FCA).

Title VII: General Provisions - Specifies certain uses and limits on or prohibitions against the use of funds appropriated by this Act.

(Sec. 702) Authorizes the Secretary to transfer unobligated balances to the Working Capital Fund for plant and capital equipment acquisition, which shall remain available until expended.

(Sec. 703) Prohibits appropriations under this Act from remaining available for obligation beyond the current fiscal year unless expressly provided for.

(Sec. 704) Limits negotiated indirect costs on cooperative agreements between USDA and nonprofit organizations to 10%.

(Sec. 705) Makes USDA appropriations for direct and guaranteed loans available for: (1) the Rural Development Loan Fund program account, (2) the Rural Electrification and Telecommunication Loans program account, and (3) the Rural Housing Insurance Fund program account.

(Sec. 706) Prohibits funds made available to USDA under this Act from being used to acquire new information technology systems or significant upgrades without the approval of the Chief Information Officer and the concurrence of the Executive Information Technology Investment Review Board.

(Sec. 707) Makes funds available in the current fiscal year for agricultural management assistance under the Federal Crop Insurance Act and for specified conservation programs under the Food Security Act of 1985 until expended for current fiscal year obligations.

(Sec. 708) Makes eligible for economic development and job creation assistance under the Rural Electrification Act in the same manner as a borrower under such Act any former Rural Utilities Service borrower that has repaid or prepaid an insured, direct, or guaranteed loan under such Act, or any not-for-profit utility that is eligible to receive an insured or direct loan under such Act.

(Sec. 709) Rescinds specified funds from unobligated balances for the tree assistance program.

(Sec. 710) Makes unobligated balances for salaries and expenses for the Farm Service Agency and the Rural Development mission area under this Act available for information technology expenses through September 30, 2016.

(Sec. 711) Authorizes the Secretary to permit a state agency to use funds provided in this Act to exceed a specified maximum amount of liquid infant formula when issuing liquid infant formula to participants.

(Sec. 712) Prohibits first-class travel by employees of agencies funded under this Act.

(Sec. 713) States that with regard to certain programs established or amended by the Agricultural Act of 2014 to be carried out using CCC funds: (1) such funds shall be available for salaries and administrative expenses without regard to certain allotment and fund transfer limits, and (2) the use of such funds shall not be considered to be a fund transfer or allotment for purposes of applying such limits.

(Sec. 714) Limits funds made available in FY2015 or preceding fiscal years under P.L. 480 to reimburse the CCC for the release of certain commodities under the Bill Emerson Humanitarian Trust Act.

(Sec. 715) Limits funds available for USDA advisory committees, panels, commissions, and task forces.

(Sec. 716) Prohibits funds under this Act from being used to pay indirect costs charged against any agricultural research, education, or extension grant awards issued by the National Institute of Food and Agriculture that exceed 30% of total federal funds provided under each award.

(Sec. 717) Limits the use of funds for the:

 watershed rehabilitation program; environmental quality incentives program; agricultural conservation easement program; conservation stewardship program; biomass crop assistance program; rural energy for America program; and biorefinery, renewable chemical and biobased product manufacturing assistance program. (Sec. 718) Limits FY2015 funds for the following domestic food assistance categories: (1) child nutrition program entitlement commodities, (2) state option contracts, and (3) defective commodity removal.

Limits funds for the fresh fruit and vegetable program until October 1, 2015.

Rescinds specified unobligated balances available in FY2015 for domestic food assistance.

(Sec. 719) Prohibits the use of funds for user fee proposals that fail to provide certain budget impact information.

(Sec. 720) Prohibits, without congressional notification, funds available under this Act or under previous appropriations Acts from being used through a reprogramming of funds to: (1) eliminate or create a new program, (2) relocate or reorganize an office or employees, (3) privatize federal employee functions, or (4) increase funds or personnel for any project for which funds have been denied or restricted.

Prohibits, without congressional notification, funds available under this Act or under previous appropriations Acts from being used through a reprogramming of funds in excess of $500,000 or 10%, whichever is less: (1) to augment an existing program, (2) to reduce by 10% funding or personnel for any existing program, or (3) that results from a reduction in personnel which would result in a change in existing programs.

(Sec. 721) Authorizes the Secretary to assess a one-time fee for any guaranteed business and industry loan that does not exceed 3% of the guaranteed principal portion of the loan.

(Sec. 722) Prohibits USDA or FDA funds from being used to transmit to any non-USDA or non-Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) employee questions or responses to questions that are a result of information requested for the appropriations hearing process.

(Sec. 723) Prohibits the use of funds under this Act by any executive branch entity to produce a prepackaged news story for U.S. broadcast or distribution unless it contains audio or text notice that it was produced or funded by such executive entity.

(Sec. 724) Requires USDA agencies to reimburse each other for employees detailed for longer than 30 days.

(Sec. 725) Prohibits funds under this Act from being used to provide nonrecourse marketing assistance loans for mohair.

(Sec. 726) Directs the Secretary, the FDA Commissioner, and the FCA Chairman to submit to Congress a spending plan by program, project, and activity for the funds made available under this Act.

(Sec. 727) Makes specified funds available for assistance to recipient nations only if adequate controls are in place to ensure that emergency food aid is received by the intended beneficiaries and not otherwise diverted.

(Sec. 728) Directs the Secretary to: (1) continue the pilot program in effect for FY2013 for packaging direct loans for single family rural housing, and (2) enter into additional agreements that increase the number of participating intermediary organizations to at least 10.

(Sec. 729) Authorizes the Secretary to increase by up to 25% the program level for certain loans and loan guarantees that do not require budget authority.

(Sec. 730) Prohibits the use of funds to write, prepare, or publish a final or interim rule in furtherance of the proposed USDA rule "Implementation of Regulations Required Under Title XI, of the Food, Conservation and Energy Act of 2008; Conduct in Violation of the Act" unless the combined annual cost to the economy of such rule does not exceed $100 million.

(Sec. 731) Declares that certain credit card refunds or rebates transferred to the Working Capital Fund: (1) shall not be made available for obligation without congressional notification and approval; but (2) shall be available for obligation only for the acquisition of plant and capital equipment necessary for the delivery of financial, administrative, and information technology services of primary benefit to USDA agencies.

(Sec. 732) Prohibits funds under this Act from from being used for a project or program named for an individual serving as a Member, Delegate, or Resident Commissioner of the U.S. House of Representatives.

(Sec. 733) Provides that beginning with FY2014, losses under the supplemental agricultural disaster assistance program shall not be considered the "same loss" for purposes of the noninsured crop assistance program and the crop insurance program. (Thus making a loss eligible for benefits under the supplemental agricultural assistance program and the other programs.)

(Sec. 734) Provides that: (1) certain funds for the FDA shall not be available for obligation until the FDA finalizes a specified draft guidance; and (2) if the FDA fails to finalize such guidance by June 30, 2015, the funds shall be made available to assist federal, state, and local agencies combat the diversion and illegal sales of controlled substances.

(Sec. 735) Prohibits the use of funds under this Act to enter into specified transactions with, or provide a grant, loan or loan guarantee to, a corporation that was convicted of a felony criminal violation under any federal law within the preceding 24 months, where the awarding agency is aware of the conviction, unless the agency has considered suspension or debarment of the corporation and determined that such action is not necessary to protect the government's interests.

(Sec. 736) Prohibits the use of funds made available by this Act to enter into specified transactions with, or provide a grant, loan, or loan guarantee to, any corporation with any unpaid federal tax liability, for which all judicial and administrative remedies have been exhausted or have lapsed, and that is not being paid in a timely manner, where the awarding agency is aware of this unpaid tax liability.

Waives this prohibition if the agency has considered suspension or debarment of the corporation and determined that such an action is not necessary to protect the government's interests.

(Sec. 737) Limits funds available for repair or replacement of bulk fuel storage tanks in Alaska that are not in compliance with applicable federal or state law.

(Sec. 738) Prohibits funds under this Act from being used to exclude or restrict the eligibility of any variety of fresh, whole, or cut vegetables, except for vegetables with added sugars, fats, or oils, from being provided as supplemental foods under the special supplemental nutrition program for women, infants, and children (WIC).

(Sec. 739) Directs the Secretary to establish a process by which a state shall grant a compliance waiver for certain USDA regulations regarding nutrition standards in the national school lunch and school breakfast programs for the 2014-2015 school year to any school food authority located in a state that verifies a food service program net loss for a period of at least six months beginning on or after July 1, 2013.

(Sec. 740) Expresses the sense of Congress that Congress:

 celebrates May 8, 2014, as the 100th anniversary of the Smith-Lever Act and recognizes the significance of the establishment of a nationwide Cooperative Extension System; honors the university faculty and local educators who help people, families, youth, businesses, and communities solve problems, develop skills, and build a better future; thanks the volunteers who promote excellence for 4-H clubs, the master gardeners program, the family and consumer sciences program, and other Cooperative Extension System programs; and encourages collaboration among federal, state, and local governments to assure Cooperative Extension System sustainability. (Sec. 741) Prohibits funds under this Act from being used to inspect horses for slaughter purposes.

(Sec. 742) Prohibits funds under this Act from being used to procure processed poultry products from China for the school lunch program, the child and adult food care program, the summer food service program for children, or the school breakfast program.

(Sec. 743) States that the amount by which the applicable allocation of new budget authority made by the House Committee on Appropriations (under the Congressional Budget Act of 1974) exceeds the amount of proposed new budget authority is $0.</summary>
</bill>
