<bill session="113" type="s" number="2813" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Prostate Cancer Council Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the National Prostate Cancer Council for improved screening, early detection, assessment, and monitoring of prostate cancer, and to direct the development and implementation of a national strategic plan to expedite advancement of diagnostic tools and the transfer of such tools to patients.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300011"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300088" joined="2014-09-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5630"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/16/2014--Introduced.
National Prostate Cancer Council Act - Establishes in the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) the National Prostate Cancer Council on Screening, Early Detection, Assessment, and Monitoring of Prostate Cancer to: (1) develop and implement a strategic plan for the accelerated development of diagnostic tools for prostate cancer, (2) review the effectiveness of diagnostic tools for prostate cancer, (3) coordinate prostate cancer research and services across federal agencies, (4) evaluate all active federal prostate cancer programs, and (5) ensure the inclusion of men at high-risk for prostate cancer in clinical, research, and service efforts.

Directs the Council to submit annual reports. Requires the first report to include recommendations based on an evaluation of prostate cancer research and gaps in the development and validation of diagnostic tools for prostate cancer. Requires subsequent reports to include: (1) an outline for a national research plan for creation and validation of diagnostic tools, (2) roles for specified agencies, (3) an analysis of the disparities in rates of prostate cancer in men at high risk, and (4) a review of the progress towards the realization of the strategic plan.

Terminates the Council on December 31, 2019.</summary>
</bill>
