<bill session="113" type="s" number="2191" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-04-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-04-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to repeal the excise tax on high cost employer-sponsored health coverage, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300083"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2014-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="2014-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2014-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2014-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400284" joined="2014-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2014-04-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-01">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1934-1935"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/1/2014--Introduced.
Amends the Internal Revenue Code to repeal the excise tax on employer-sponsored health care coverage for which there is an excess benefit (high-cost plans).

Amends the Public Health Service Act to replace the annual review of unreasonable increases in health insurance premiums with a five-year program of grants to states for establishing centers to collect and make available medical reimbursement information from health insurance issuers.

Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to repeal the authority of the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to deny plan bids under the Medicare Advantage Program and the Prescription Drug Benefit Program.

Abolishes the Independent Payment Advisory Board established by the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to develop proposals to reduce the rate of growth in Medicare spending.</summary>
</bill>
