<bill session="113" type="h" number="4847" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">End Neglected Tropical Diseases Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To facilitate effective research on and treatment of neglected tropical diseases through coordinated domestic and international efforts.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400380"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400657" joined="2014-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412199" joined="2014-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400271" joined="2014-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2014-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400606" joined="2014-06-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Foreign Affairs, and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Argentina"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Brazil"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug therapy"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="HIV/AIDS"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="India"/>
    <term name="Indonesia"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development programs"/>
    <term name="National Institutes of Health (NIH)"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Saudi Arabia"/>
    <term name="South Africa"/>
    <term name="South Korea"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/11/2014--Introduced.
End Neglected Tropical Diseases Act - Defines "neglected tropical diseases" (NTDs), for purposes of this Act, as infections caused by pathogens, including viruses, bacteria, protozoa, and helminths that disproportionately impact individuals living in extreme poverty, especially in developing countries.

Expresses the sense of Congress that the Neglected Tropical Diseases Program of the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) should be modified with respect to rapid impact package treatments, school-based NTD programs, and new approaches to reach the goals of eliminating NTDs set forth by the World Health Organization. Sets forth measures to expand the USAID program, including by establishment of a research and development program.

Adds to the duties of the of the Coordinator of United States Government Activities to Combat HIV/AIDS Globally the coordination with HIV/AIDS activities of those relating to combatting NTDs, particularly in countries and regions that are highly endemic for female genital schistosomiasis.

Urges the Secretary of State to: (1) engage the Global Fund to Fight AIDS, Tuberculosis and Malaria in discussions of whether to expand the authority of the Fund for the control and elimination of NTDs; and (2) engage G-20 countries to significantly increase their role in the that effort, particularly Argentina, Brazil, China, India, Indonesia, Mexico, the Republic of Korea, Saudi Arabia, and South Africa.

Requires the President to direct the U.S. representatives to the United Nations and the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development to urge actions on NTDs, including deworming programs.

Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to:

 continue to promote the need for NTD programs and activities through interagency groups and international forums, report to Congress on NTDs in the United States, enter into cooperative agreements to support one or more centers of excellence for NTD research. Requires the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to establish a panel to evaluate issues relating to worm infections, including potential solutions such as deworming medicines.</summary>
</bill>
