<bill session="113" type="s" number="2146" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-03-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-03-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-03-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Patent Fee Integrity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a United States Patent and Trademark Office Innovation Promotion Fund, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300043"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2014-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2014-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400134" joined="2014-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2014-03-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-03-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1658-1661"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3349"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/13/2014--Introduced.
Patent Fee Integrity Act - Establishes in the Treasury the United States Patent and Trademark Office Innovation Promotion Fund (Innovation Promotion Fund) to be used as a revolving fund by the Director of the U.S. Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) without fiscal year limitation.

Requires to be credited to or deposited in the Innovation Promotion Fund: (1) appropriations for defraying the costs of USPTO activities; (2) fees collected under federal patent and trademark laws; and (3) any available unobligated balances remaining in the Patent and Trademark Office Appropriation Account and in the Patent and Trademark Fee Reserve Fund. (Replaces the Patent and Trademark Office Appropriation Account, eliminates the Patent and Trademark Fee Reserve Fund, and provides a source of permanent funding for the USPTO.)

Requires fees collected by the Director to remain available to the Director until expended.

Makes the Public Enterprise Fund available to cover: (1) ordinary and reasonable administrative, operating, and other expenses incurred by the Director for the continued operation of USPTO services, programs, activities, and duties relating to patents and trademarks; and (2) expenses incurred pursuant to obligations, representations, or other commitments of the USPTO.

Requires the Director, on an annual basis, to: (1) report to Congress with operation and spending plans for the current and next fiscal year, including financial details and staff levels broken down by each major activity; (2) provide for an independent audit of USPTO financial statements; and (3) submit a budget to the President.</summary>
</bill>
