<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Enrolled-Bill" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HF81A123766154E3F88F781BB5FED6235" public-private="public" stage-count="1">  
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title> HR 4028 ENR: International Religious Freedom Act of 1998</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>One Hundred Thirteenth Congress of the United States of America</congress> <session>At the Second Session</session><enrolled-dateline>Begun and held at the City of Washington on Friday, the third day of January, two thousand and fourteen</enrolled-dateline> 
<legis-num>H. R. 4028</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no"></current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To amend the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998 to include the desecration of cemeteries among the many forms of violations of the right to religious freedom.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HCE8317A898A84108A44C5E23B9FC72A0" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HB34A73C9D86A46CD86E57CDE60785254" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HA86F7D92B7B849E0ABC86CF550D47C34"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Cemeteries are sacred sites that are of great spiritual, cultural, and historical significance to many religious and ethnic groups.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD4F6827586CE4B208A8D2FA38F2BA552"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Congress is committed to protecting and preserving the heritage and sacred sites of national, religious, and ethnic groups, which includes cemeteries in the United States and abroad.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9805556E228144768353FB7842EA80C1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Cemeteries around the world have and continue to be defaced or destroyed as a direct result of their affiliation with a particular religious or spiritual group.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H07E499D0D41F412295409A7C91ACBF5D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Such attacks constitute an assault on the fundamental right to freedom of religion, and are especially egregious when sponsored or tolerated by the local or national governments in the countries in which such offenses occur.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HBAE482287801423F8DB6FD1AA5FF44BD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Amendment to International Religious Freedom Act of 1998</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2(a)(4) of the <short-title>International Religious Freedom Act of 1998</short-title> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/6401">22 U.S.C. 6401(a)(4)</external-xref>) is amended in the fourth sentence by inserting <quote>desecration of cemeteries,</quote> after <quote>confiscations of property,</quote>.</text> </section> 
</legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><role>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</role></attestation-group><attestation-group><role>Vice President of the United States and President of the Senate.</role></attestation-group></attestation>
</bill> 


