<bill session="113" type="h" number="4601" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-05-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Deficit Reduction for Infrastructure, Value, and Efficiency Now Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DRIVE Now Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide additional funding for the Highway Trust Fund, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412557"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-07">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-07">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-07">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3951-3952"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Livestock, Rural Development, and Credit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG29" subcommittee="Livestock, Rural Development, and Credit" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1232"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1313"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1856"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1960"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1999"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="5196"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="632"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Agricultural trade"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Aquaculture"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Seafood"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/7/2014--Introduced.
Deficit Reduction for Infrastructure, Value, and Efficiency Now Act of 2014 or the DRIVE Now Act of 2014 - Appropriates additional funding for the Highway Account in the Highway Trust Fund.

Requires the Federal Chief Information Officer&#160;(defined as the Administrator of the Office of Electronic Government in the Office of Management and Budget [OMB]) to: (1) develop and implement the Federal Data Center Optimization Initiative to optimize the usage and efficiency of federal data centers, and (2) submit a plan to Congress for the implementation of the Initiative

Sets forth permissible methods for agencies to consolidate data centers and achieve maximum server utilization and energy efficiency.

Requires agencies to track their costs and savings resulting from implementation of the Initiative and to report annually to the Federal Chief Information Officer on such implementation. Directs the&#160;Comptroller General (GAO)&#160;to examine methods for calculating savings from the Initiative and to report findings and make recommendations to the Federal Chief Information Officer and to Congress. Requires the Federal Chief Information Officer to&#160;report annually to relevant congressional committees assessing agency progress in carrying out the Initiative.

Directs the OMB Director to issue recommendations for reducing or consolidating the number of federal data centers by at least 40% not later than September 30, 2018, and by at least 80% not later than September 30, 2023.

Repeals a provision of the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008 establishing an inspection and grading program for catfish and other species of farm-raised fish or shellfish effective on the date of enactment of such Act.

Directs the Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency to submit a report to Congress that lists each bank account held by the federal government that has had a zero balance for 180 days, with recommendations as to which accounts should be immediately closed. Requires the closure of any accounts recommended for closure&#160;within 7 days after the submission of such report.</summary>
</bill>
