<bill session="113" type="h" number="5334" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Open Our Democracy Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require all candidates for election for the office of Member of the House of Representatives to run in a single open primary regardless of political party preference, to limit the ensuing general election for such office to the two candidates receiving the greatest number of votes in such single open primary, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412544"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412583" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412308" joined="2014-09-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Government Reform, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU10" subcommittee="Constitution and Civil Justice" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="Congressional districts and representation"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Employee leave"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Political parties and affiliation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2014--Introduced.
Open Our Democracy Act of 2014 - Requires all candidates for election to the House of Representatives to run in a single open primary, regardless of political party preference.

Limits the ensuing general election to the two candidates receiving the greatest number of votes in the single open primary.

Gives candidates the option, at the time of filing to run for office, to declare a political party preference, which does not constitute or imply endorsement of the candidate by the party designated.

Treats the general election day in the same manner as a legal public holiday for purposes of federal employment.

Expresses the sense of Congress that private employers should give their employees a day off on the general election day in November 2016 and each even-numbered year thereafter to enable them to cast votes in elections held on that day.

Requires the Comptroller General (GAO) to study the feasibility and desirability of enacting national standards and criteria for congressional redistricting.</summary>
</bill>
