<bill session="113" type="h" number="5074" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">LAND Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Land Adjacency Notification and Disclosure Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 to improve the transparency and oversight of land conveyances involving the sale, exchange, or other disposal of National Forest System lands or public lands under the jurisdiction of the Bureau of Land Management or the acquisition of non-Federal lands for inclusion in the National Forest System or administration as public lands, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412405"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412271" joined="2014-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412397" joined="2014-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412295" joined="2014-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412581" joined="2014-07-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-11">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-11">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-08-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Energy, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-09">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII10" subcommittee="Public Lands and Environmental Regulation" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG15" subcommittee="Conservation, Energy, and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="General public lands matters"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Property rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/11/2014--Introduced.
Land Adjacency Notification and Disclosure Act or LAND Act - Amends the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 to instruct the Department of the Interior or the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to provide advance written notification to each owner of land that is adjacent to a parcel to be acquired to become public lands or National Forest System (NFS) lands.

Instructs Interior or USDA to provide advance written notification to each owner of land that is adjacent to a parcel of public lands or NFS lands to be conveyed by sale, exchange, or other disposal method.</summary>
</bill>
