<bill session="113" type="h" number="5778" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-12-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-12-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-12-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Boko Haram Disarmament and Northeast Nigeria Recovery Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To support stabilization and lasting peace in northeast Nigeria and areas affected by Boko Haram through development of a regional strategy to support multilateral efforts to successfully protect civilians and eliminate the threat posed by Boko Haram, to support efforts to rescue female students abducted in Nigeria on April 14, 2014, as well as other kidnapping victims of Boko Haram, and to provide funds for humanitarian relief, development programs, transitional justice, and victim support, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412412"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2014-12-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-12-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Cameroon"/>
    <term name="Chad"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Niger"/>
    <term name="Nigeria"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Reconstruction and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/1/2014--Introduced.
Boko Haram Disarmament and Northeast Nigeria Recovery Act of 2014 - Directs the President to develop and submit to Congress a regional strategy to guide U.S. support for multilateral efforts to: (1) eliminate the threat to civilians and regional stability from Boko Haram, and (2) enforce the rule of law and ensure full humanitarian access in Boko Haram-affected areas.

States that such strategy should include a plan to work with Nigeria and other international partners to liberate Boko Haram's kidnapping victims.

Authorizes the President to provide humanitarian and development assistance to the populations in Boko Haram-affected areas. Makes funds available for such assistance pursuant to final judgment of a specified legal case.

Expresses the sense of Congress that the President should support efforts by the people of Boko Haram-affected areas and the governments of Nigeria, Chad, Cameroon, and Niger to:

 assist internally displaced people and returnees; enhance the administrative competency of state and local governance institutions and public agencies in northeast Nigeria; provide all children with a quality basic education while ensuring student and faculty safety; strengthen the operational capacity of the civilian police in Nigeria, and strengthen measures to prevent corruption; and promote programs to address physical harm and psychosocial trauma. Expresses the sense of Congress that:

 the Secretary of State and Administrator of the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) should work with Congress to increase future assistance to support reconstruction activities if Nigeria demonstrates a commitment to transparent reconstruction in Boko Haram-affected areas of Nigeria, and the Secretary should withhold assistance if Nigeria is not committed to transparent reconstruction and reconciliation in the Boko Haram-affected areas of Nigeria.</summary>
</bill>
