<bill session="113" type="h" number="5477" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Enhancing Educational Opportunities for all Students Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to encourage the use of 529 plans and Coverdell education savings accounts, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412540"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412426" joined="2014-09-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7540"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-16">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-16">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3977"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2998"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/16/2014--Introduced.
Enhancing Educational Opportunities for all Students Act - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to allow a state educational agency to allocate grant funds among local educational agencies based on the number of eligible children (children age 5 to 17 from a family with an income below the poverty level)&#160;enrolled in the public schools and the state-accredited private schools within each local agency's geographic jurisdiction.

Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) allow payment of home school expenses from Coverdell education savings accounts; (2) remove the dollar limitation on contributions to Coverdell education savings accounts and require such accounts to provide adequate safeguards to prevent contributions from exceeding the amount necessary to provide for the qualified education expenses of the account beneficiary; and (3) allow tax-exempt qualified tuition programs (529 tuition programs) to pay qualified pre-kindergarten, elementary, and secondary education expenses.</summary>
</bill>
