<bill session="113" type="h" number="4892" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Military and Veteran Caregiver Services Improvement Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To expand eligibility for the program of comprehensive assistance for family caregivers of the Department of Veterans Affairs, to expand benefits available to participants under such program, to enhance special compensation for members of the uniformed services who require assistance in everyday life, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400230"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412524" joined="2014-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400274" joined="2014-06-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Armed Services, Ways and Means, Oversight and Government Reform, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-18">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-18">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-18">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-18">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-18">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR09" subcommittee="Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="s" number="2243"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Employee leave"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/18/2014--Introduced.
Military and Veteran Caregiver Services Improvement Act of 2014 - Expands eligibility for the family caregiver program of the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to include members of the Armed Forces or veterans who are seriously injured or who became ill on active duty prior to September 11, 2001 (currently, limited to service after September 11, 2001). Expands services to caregivers of veterans under such program to include&#160;child care services, financial planning services, and legal services.

Authorizes the transfer of entitlement to post 9/11 education assistance to family members by veterans who are retired for a physical disability or&#160;who are seriously injured veterans in need of family caregiver services, without regard to length-of-service requirements.

Authorizes the VA Secretary to pay monthly special compensation to seriously injured or ill veterans in need of personal care services and to their caregivers. Excludes from gross income, for income tax purposes, such compensation paid to injured or ill veterans.

Authorizes&#160;flexible work schedules or telework&#160;for federal employees who are caregivers of veterans.

Amends the Public Health Service Act to&#160;designate a veteran participating in the program of comprehensive assistance for family caregivers as an adult with a special need for purposes of the&#160;lifespan respite care program.

Establishes in the executive branch an interagency working group to review and report on policies relating to the caregivers of veterans and members of the Armed Forces.

Directs the Secretary to provide for studies on members of the Armed Forces who commenced service after September 11, 2001, and veterans who have incurred a serious injury or illness, including a mental health injury, and their caregivers.</summary>
</bill>
