<bill session="113" type="s" number="2341" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-05-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 10, United States Code, to enhance the authority for members of the Armed Forces to obtain professional credentials.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412582"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3076-3077"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Military readiness"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/15/2014--Introduced.
Revises the conditions for payment of expenses to military personnel to obtain professional credentials to include those for federal occupational licenses.

Adds as conditions for such payment that the credentials be necessary to meet: (1) readiness requirements or professional occupational development goals of the particular armed force or the member's self-development needs; and (2) certain International Organization for Standardization/International Electrotechnical Commission accreditation standards, with exceptions for a credentialing agency that agrees to seek to obtain compliance certification within three years.

Authorizes the payment of the expenses from amounts available for tuition assistance for members under the jurisdiction of the appropriate Secretary.

Defines "expenses" as those for classroom instruction, hands-on training (and associated materials), manuals, study guides and materials, textbooks, and processing, test, and related fees.</summary>
</bill>
