<bill session="113" type="h" number="3189" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-03-13T17:43:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-03-13T17:43:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-09-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Water Rights Protection Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Water Rights Protection Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Water Rights Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit the conditioning of any permit, lease, or other use agreement on the transfer, relinquishment, or other impairment of any water right to the United States by the Secretaries of the Interior and Agriculture.</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by house">To prohibit the conditioning of any permit, lease, or other use agreement on the transfer of any water right to the United States by the Secretaries of the Interior and Agriculture.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412405"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412500" joined="2013-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400029" joined="2013-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412270" joined="2013-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412271" joined="2013-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412555" joined="2013-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412406" joined="2014-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412397" joined="2013-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412294" joined="2013-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400255" joined="2013-10-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412295" joined="2013-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400313" joined="2013-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400652" joined="2013-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412308" joined="2013-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400376" joined="2013-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412581" joined="2013-10-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-09-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-26">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-26">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Energy, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-10">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-14">
      <text>Subcommittee on Water and Power Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-14">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-11-14" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 19 - 14.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-03-04T19:16:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 113-372, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-04T19:17:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee on Agriculture discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-03-04T19:17:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="278">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 278.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-03-12T19:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 515 Reported to House. The resolution provides for one hour of debate on H.R. 3189. The rule makes in order as original text for the purpose of amendment an amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Natural Resources now printed in the bill and provides that it shall be considered as read. The rule provides for a closed rule for H.R. 4015 with one hour of debate on the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-13T14:25:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 515.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2385-2401" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-13T14:25:00-04:00">
      <text>The resolution provides for one hour of debate on H.R. 3189. The rule makes in order as original text for the purpose of amendment an amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Natural Resources now printed in the bill and provides that it shall be considered as read. The rule provides for a closed rule for H.R. 4015 with one hour of debate on the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-13T14:25:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 515 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-13T14:25:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Virginia Foxx to act as Chairwoman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-13T14:26:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 3189.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-13T15:32:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 515, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Tipton Part A amendment no. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-13T15:43:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 515, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Mullin Part A amendment no. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-13T15:50:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 515, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Polis Part A amendment no. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-13T16:13:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINS - At the conclusion of debate on the Polis Part A substitute amendment No. 3, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Polis demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-13T16:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hastings (WA) moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-13T16:13:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-13T16:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 3189 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-13T17:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2405-2408" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-13T17:16:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-13T17:16:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question on adoption of an amendment which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-13T17:22:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 3189.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-13T17:23:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2395-2396" label="text of amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-13T17:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Mrs. Kirkpatrick moved to recommit with instructions to Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2406-2407" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2406" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-13T17:24:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Kirkpatrick motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to report the same back to the House forthwith with an amendment to clarify that nothing in the underlying legislation may prohibit the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture from (1) protecting Tribal treaty rights; (2) preserving recreational fishing; (3) mitigating drought conditions in an area covered by an emergency drought declaration; or (4) facilitating fire suppression.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-13T17:29:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2407" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-13T17:36:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 183 - 227 (Roll no. 131).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2407" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="132" datetime="2014-03-13T17:43:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 238 - 174 (Roll no. 132).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-03-13T17:43:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-13T17:43:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-24">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG15" subcommittee="Conservation, Energy, and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hr" number="515"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="113" type="hr" number="515"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="s" number="1630"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h595"/>
    <amendment number="h596"/>
    <amendment number="h597"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>3/13/2014--Passed House amended.
Water Rights Protection Act - Prohibits the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) from: (1) conditioning the issuance, renewal, amendment, or extension of any permit, approval, license, lease, allotment, easement, right-of-way, or other land use or occupancy agreement on the transfer of any water right (including joint or sole ownership) directly to the United States, or any impairment in title, in whole or in part, granted or recognized under state law, by federal or state adjudication, decree, or other judgment, or pursuant to any interstate water compact; and (2) requiring any water user (including any federally recognized Indian tribe) to apply for a water right in the name of the United States under state law as a condition of such a land use or occupancy agreement.

States that nothing in this Act shall: (1) limit or expand any existing authority of the Secretaries to condition any permit, approval, license, lease, allotment, easement, right-of-way, or other land use or occupancy agreement on federal lands subject to their respective jurisdictions; (2) interfere with existing or future Bureau of Reclamation contracts; (3) affect the implementation of the Endangered Species Act of 1973; (4) limit or expand any existing federal reserved water rights on lands administered by the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture; (5) limit or expand certain authorities under the Federal Power Act; and (6) limit or expand any existing reserved water right or treaty right of any federally recognized Indian tribe.</summary>
</bill>
