<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 SRES 595 IS: Recognizing Nobel Laureates Kailash Satyarthi and Malala Yousafzai for their efforts to end the financial exploitation of children and to ensure the right of all children to an education. </dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2014-12-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. RES. 595</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20141208">December 8, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S172">Mr. Harkin</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Recognizing Nobel Laureates Kailash Satyarthi and Malala Yousafzai for their efforts to end the
			 financial exploitation of children and to ensure the right of all children
			 to an education.	</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas><text>Whereas, on October 10, 2014, the Norwegian Nobel Committee awarded the 2014 Nobel Peace Prize to
			 Kailash Satyarthi and Malala Yousafzai;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the International Labour Organization estimates that, worldwide, 168,000,000 children are
			 exploited financially, with 85,000,000 children working in very hazardous
			 environments and deprived of an education;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization estimates that
			 121,000,000 children are not in school;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Kailash Satyarthi has personally rescued more than 82,000 children from the worst forms of
			 child labor;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Malala Yousafzai has promoted education for girls in Pakistan since she was 11 years old
			 and is an advocate for worldwide access to education;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Kailash Satyarthi has endured threats on his life as a result of such rescue efforts; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Taliban attempted to kill Malala Yousafzai on October 9, 2012, as a result of her
			 efforts to encourage more girls to attend school: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body>
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="idfb07c7ca41a54b8595fcb59bf4c85a5e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes Nobel Laureates Kailash Satyarthi and Malala Yousafzai as symbols of peace and advocates
			 for ending the financial exploitation of children and for the right of all
			 children to an education;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idee750b962b4f4d04abe3d61a2d62d280"><enum>(2)</enum><text>commends all individuals working around the world to end the scourge of child slavery and to
			 advance education for all children;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1b1abc447a8d4b4595f962d2b057a7af"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recognizes the challenges that remain in ending the financial exploitation of children and
			 providing access to an education for all children;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idC525CEF5AA1149E084C8B6123B4910A7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>urges all governments, civil society organizations, businesses, and individuals to unite in the
			 common purpose of protecting children from losing their childhoods as well
			 as their futures; and</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="id274FB7FE7FFB46B0AE7FA082AD09065C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>recognizes the dedication and commitment to freedom, the rights of children, and the endurance of
			 the human spirit, demonstrated by all individuals who make sacrifices to
			 build a more peaceful world.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


