<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H211D3C8414444B73A699264FD7562618" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HR 5786 IH: Small Financial Institutions Regulatory Relief Act of 2014</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2014-12-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 5786</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20141203">December 3, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000575">Mr. Lankford</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="W000800">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend certain banking statutes to exempt community banks from certain regulatory requirements,
			 to include a community bank representative in the membership of the Board
			 of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, to create a process for a
			 county to be designated as a rural area, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H263ECF5077044AFBAC635999FE555CFB" style="OLC">
		<section commented="no" id="H0612FD780A75400D92C2923EEE142A4A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Small Financial Institutions Regulatory Relief Act of 2014</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCBD1E686F0B5426ABA59CAC9F5B083F1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Certain loans included as qualified mortgages</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 129C(b)(2) of the Truth in Lending Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1639c">15 U.S.C. 1639c(b)(2)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the
			 end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H45C24B2088944147AF04BF5E293BCF45" style="OLC">
				<subparagraph id="H70E2BBFFA0064CE484D04CD8AD757C2A"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Loans held on portfolio</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>qualified mortgage</term> includes a residential mortgage loan made by a creditor having less than $10,000,000,000 in total
			 assets, so long as such loan is originated and retained in portfolio of
			 the creditor for the duration of the loan term.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="HAB73262257044984B38F6C077EA039AE"><enum>3.</enum><header>Exemption from escrow requirements for loans held by small creditors</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 129D(c) of the Truth in Lending Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1639d">15 U.S.C. 1639d(c)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
			<paragraph id="H2D3FEA75BDAA4ED5A31F2374E457DA61"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (1), (2), (3), and (4) as subparagraphs (A), (B), (C), and (D) and
			 moving such subparagraphs 2 ems to the right;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H4F58183114FA48A1870722D3CD569D2F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>striking <quote>The Board</quote> and inserting the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0E75DD44281F4163A48DFF66F0E4AB18" style="OLC">
					<paragraph id="H99BFEC3951B8441CAB96398FC56AD8C2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Bureau</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HB056701A36654C34ADA7127611C7D65C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HCD1FE48D1EDE4FECAD213CF95ED86071" style="OLC">
					<paragraph id="H90B96BE71E9346F0876A419F66920ACD" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Treatment of loans held by smaller creditors</header><text>The Bureau shall, by regulation, exempt from the requirements of subsection (a) any loan secured by
			 a first lien on a consumer’s principle dwelling, if such loan is held by a
			 creditor with assets of less than $10,000,000,000.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H08AB6498CFD34FA4A92F5EBB4DEC1EFF" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>4.</enum><header>Increase in small servicer exemption</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 6 of the Real Estate Settlement Procedures Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/2605">12 U.S.C. 2605</external-xref>) is amended by
			 adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7930E43E909842ABB3F8DD97F9E8213D" style="OLC">
				<subsection id="HCBEEB12EC43748708969A1FF68974587"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Small servicer exemption</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Bureau shall, by regulation, provide exemptions to, or adjustments for, the provisions of this
			 section for servicers that service 10,000 or fewer mortgage loans, in
			 order to reduce regulatory burdens while appropriately balancing consumer
			 protections.</text>
				</subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4D0F0D7A04174AFCA1C553A857E9DCCD" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>5.</enum><header>Exception to annual privacy notice requirement under the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 503 of the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/6803">15 U.S.C. 6803</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the
			 following:</text>
			<quoted-block id="H24F91CCDFB0C4A328BABA4A20EAE2EC2" style="OLC">
				<subsection id="H81806D291B844993A8A5F949F165D61D"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Exception to annual notice requirement</header><text>A financial institution that—</text>
					<paragraph commented="no" id="H52BDFC6F2FD644DD8C7F481AD89DD8C1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provides nonpublic personal information only in accordance with the provisions of subsection (b)(2)
			 or (e) of section 502 or regulations prescribed under section 504(b), and</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="H67688C601C134600A91069693DBA2426"><enum>(2)</enum><text>has not changed its policies and practices with regard to disclosing nonpublic personal information
			 from the policies and practices that were disclosed in the most recent
			 disclosure sent to consumers in accordance with this subsection,</text>
					</paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">shall not be required to provide an annual disclosure under this subsection until such time as the
			 financial institution fails to comply with any criteria described in
			 paragraph (1) or (2).</continuation-text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="H883CCF7213F045888664814DF8CEB3D5"><enum>6.</enum><header>Changes required to small bank holding company policy statement on assessment of financial and
			 managerial factors</header>
			<subsection id="H76085EA3ADC04B5182687B5FDC279678"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Small bank holding company policy statement on assessment of financial and managerial factors</header>
				<paragraph id="H21D86A20C50A40E686A1FD75E3D5B4F6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Before the end of the 6-month period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, the Board
			 of Governors of the Federal Reserve System shall publish in the Federal
			 Register proposed revisions to the Small Bank Holding Company Policy
			 Statement on Assessment of Financial and Managerial Factors (12 C.F.R.
			 part 225—appendix C) that provide that the policy shall apply to a bank
			 holding company which has pro forma consolidated assets of less than
			 $5,000,000,000 and that—</text>
					<subparagraph id="H4C654CA107BB4A47A5A5355C2EFFDC74"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is not engaged in any nonbanking activities involving significant leverage; and</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC036385C75454C9FBB9810AF6E31F9D9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not have a significant amount of outstanding debt that is held by the general public.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H909F7DEB9108430F8AA78A71F5428440"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Adjustment of amount</header><text>The Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System shall annually adjust the dollar amount
			 referred to in paragraph (1) in the Small Bank Holding Company Policy
			 Statement on Assessment of Financial and Managerial Factors by an amount
			 equal to the percentage increase, for the most recent year, in total
			 assets held by all insured depository institutions, as determined by the
			 Board.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE466EBB2FF8C4805952B96549239F35B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Increase in debt-to-Equity ratio of small bank holding company</header><text>Before the end of the 6-month period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, the Board
			 of Governors of the Federal Reserve System shall publish in the Federal
			 Register proposed revisions to the Small Bank Holding Company Policy
			 Statement on Assessment of Financial and Managerial Factors (12 C.F.R.
			 part 225—appendix C) such that the debt-to-equity ratio allowable for a
			 small bank holding company in order to remain eligible to pay a corporate
			 dividend and to remain eligible for expedited processing procedures under
			 Regulation Y of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System would
			 increase from 1:1 to 3:1.</text>
			</subsection></section><section commented="no" id="H691420F3ABDD4FD191B0902C25A7AA11"><enum>7.</enum><header>Membership of Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System</header>
			<subsection commented="no" id="H890D002F41164C6DBD8CB0D16400516E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Inclusion of a person with community bank experience</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The first undesignated paragraph of section 10 of the Federal Reserve Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/241">12 U.S.C. 241</external-xref>) is
			 amended by inserting after the second sentence the following: <quote>The Board shall at all times have as a member at least 1 person with demonstrated experience
			 working in or supervising community banks having less than $10,000,000,000
			 in total assets</quote>.</text>
			</subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HA1FE758FD128430C8F464E0B52FF66DF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment made by subsection (a) shall take effect on the date of enactment of this Act and
			 apply to appointments made on and after that effective date, excluding any
			 nomination pending in the Senate on that date.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H43054394EF734488AC997BEA559BB0CD"><enum>8.</enum><header>Designation of rural area</header>
			<subsection id="H1527FBEDD40D46CAA59B8D2E78B958E2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Bureau of Consumer
			 Financial Protection shall establish an application process under which a
			 person who lives or does business in a State may, with respect to an area
			 identified by the person in such State that has not been designated by the
			 Bureau as a rural area for purposes of a Federal consumer financial law
			 (as defined under section 1002 of the Consumer Financial Protection Act of
			 2010), apply for such area to be so designated.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HDD8236168BAB459FB098CD30EAC13582"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Evaluation Criteria</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">When evaluating an application submitted under subsection (a), the Bureau shall take into
			 consideration the following factors:</text>
				<paragraph id="H956A166D5C8148199F1ADED7BC2AB8D6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Criteria used by the Director of the Bureau of the Census for classifying geographical areas as
			 rural or urban.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H42DB6A9BAC904FA385A3AF5BA000DB68"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Criteria used by the Director of the Office of Management and Budget to designate counties as
			 metropolitan or micropolitan or neither.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H86CD91548C6C4503A1730B1523DC3606"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Criteria used by the Secretary of Agriculture to determine property eligibility for rural
			 development programs.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HB8410CA53A814F278033EEEA5B81FE48"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Department of Agriculture rural-urban commuting area codes.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HDA8AF62CFB2C43C68CB95C85A82FEE4D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A written opinion provided by the State’s bank supervisor, as defined under section 3(r) of the
			 Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1813">12 U.S.C. 1813(r)</external-xref>).</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H9B9F8D1FD5BE4FAEB491FB631F98FFE0"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Population density.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0222C01A1C854DC6803E3EF0C31FFABC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Public Comment Period</header>
				<paragraph id="HCC42672477E54E9ABD2FEF9126C08530"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after receiving an application submitted under subsection (a), the Bureau
			 shall—</text>
					<subparagraph id="HDC7DA279D3E14A018987DE56278076E7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>publish such application in the Federal Register; and</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7A4BC3BB2E2641FFBEFFD02DC29DBCC8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>make such application available for public comment for not fewer than 90 days.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8E8C93373B56491C9A070E854EC0B3FE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation on additional applications</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to require the Bureau, during the public comment period
			 with respect to an application submitted under subsection (a), to accept
			 an additional application with respect to the area that is the subject of
			 the initial application.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H092EFA946DDC473EB925983BA19458C8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Decision on Designation</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the end of the public comment period under subsection (c)(1) for an
			 application, the Bureau shall—</text>
				<paragraph id="H0BD0ECE030334166A5B1A427F9F614A9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>grant or deny such application, in whole or in part; and</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HD1C61ECD3BC64832BE0A832FEB4FA226"><enum>(2)</enum><text>publish such grant or denial in the Federal Register, along with an explanation of what factors the
			 Bureau relied on in making such determination.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3D331B0048BE469BA9A60FA87A8358D6"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Subsequent Applications</header><text>A decision by the Bureau under subsection (d) to deny an application for an area to be designated
			 as a rural area shall not preclude the Bureau from accepting a subsequent
			 application submitted under subsection (a) for such area to be so
			 designated, so long as such subsequent application is made after the end
			 of the 90-day period beginning on the date that the Bureau denies the
			 application under subsection (d).</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


