<bill session="113" type="h" number="6" updated="2015-09-01T10:18:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-25T16:48:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-06-25T16:48:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-03-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Domestic Prosperity and Global Freedom Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Domestic Prosperity and Global Freedom Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Domestic Prosperity and Global Freedom Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for expedited approval of exportation of natural gas to World Trade Organization countries, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412406"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412469" joined="2014-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400018" joined="2014-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412478" joined="2014-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400032" joined="2014-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400636" joined="2014-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412567" joined="2014-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412539" joined="2014-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400052" joined="2014-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400061" joined="2014-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412269" joined="2014-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412271" joined="2014-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412563" joined="2014-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400655" joined="2014-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400618" joined="2014-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412555" joined="2014-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400089" joined="2014-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400648" joined="2014-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412457" joined="2014-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412482" joined="2014-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412480" joined="2014-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400141" joined="2014-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400151" joined="2014-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412397" joined="2014-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="2014-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412485" joined="2014-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412278" joined="2014-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400165" joined="2014-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400175" joined="2014-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400179" joined="2014-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412283" joined="2014-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412460" joined="2014-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412465" joined="2014-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400224" joined="2014-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412191" joined="2014-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412290" joined="2014-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412256" joined="2014-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412294" joined="2014-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400656" joined="2014-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400654" joined="2014-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400659" joined="2014-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412552" joined="2014-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400441" joined="2014-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412302" joined="2014-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412443" joined="2014-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400320" joined="2014-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412462" joined="2014-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400342" joined="2014-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400348" joined="2014-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400352" joined="2014-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412261" joined="2014-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412399" joined="2014-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400367" joined="2014-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400373" joined="2014-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412461" joined="2014-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400400" joined="2014-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412317" joined="2014-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400404" joined="2014-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400411" joined="2014-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400414" joined="2014-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412574" joined="2014-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400431" joined="2014-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412402" joined="2014-03-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-03-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-25">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-08">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-09">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-09">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 15 - 11 .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-29">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-30">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-04-30" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 33 - 18.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-06-19T13:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 113-477.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-06-19T13:14:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="353">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 353.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-06-23T19:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 636 Reported to House. For H.R. 6, one hour of general debate and amendments are confined to those printed in part A of the report accompanying this resolution. For H.R. 3301, one hour of general debate and amendments are confined to those printed in part B of the report accompanying this resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-24T16:10:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 636.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5676-5683" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-24T16:10:00-04:00">
      <text>The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 6 and H.R. 3301. For H.R. 6, one hour of general debate and amendments are confined to those printed in part A of the report accompanying the resolution. For H.R. 3301, one hour of general debate and amendments are confined to those printed in part B of the report accompanying the resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-24T16:11:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 636 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-24T16:11:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Andy Harris to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-24T16:11:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 6.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-24T17:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Gardner moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-24T17:15:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-24T17:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 6 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-25T13:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5741-5742" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-25T13:17:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-25T13:18:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 636, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gardner part A amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-25T13:32:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 636, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Holt part A amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-25T13:45:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 636, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the DeFazio part A amendment No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-25T13:53:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the DeFazio part A amendment No. 3, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. DeFazio demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-25T13:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Gardner moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-25T13:54:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-25T13:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 6 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-25T16:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5749-5752" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-25T16:17:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-25T16:17:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that, pursuant to clause 6 of Rule XVIII, the unfinished business was the question of adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-25T16:23:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 6.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-25T16:23:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5749" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-25T16:24:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5741" label="text of amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-25T16:25:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Garamendi moved to recommit with instructions to the Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5750-5751" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5750" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-25T16:25:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Garamendi motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to direct the Secretary of Energy to deny applications to export natural gas if: (1) it would increase the price of natural gas, electricity, or home heating for Seniors on fixed incomes or (2) the natural gas would be exported to any nation that is a state sponsor of terrorism or to any nation or corporation that steals U.S. military technology or intellectual property through cyber-attacks. The motion also requires the Department of Energy to direct the applicant to ensure that U.S.-flagged ships and shipping containers are used to export liquefied natural gas.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-25T16:32:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5770" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-25T16:40:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 192 - 225 (Roll no. 358).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="359" datetime="2014-06-25T16:48:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 266 - 150 (Roll no. 359).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-06-25T16:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-26">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hr" number="636"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="113" type="hr" number="636"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4139"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2083"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2274"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Free trade and trade barriers"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements and negotiations"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h959"/>
    <amendment number="h960"/>
    <amendment number="h961"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>6/25/2014--Passed House amended.
Domestic Prosperity and Global Freedom Act - (Sec. 2) Directs the Department of Energy (DOE) to issue a decision on an application for authorization to export natural gas within 30 days after the later of: (1) the conclusion of the review to site, construct, expand, or operate the liquefied natural gas (LNG) facilities required by the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (NEPA); or (2) the date of enactment of this Act.

Deems any NEPA review to be concluded: (1) 30 days after publication of a required Environmental Impact Statement if the project needs one; (2) 30 days after publication by DOE of a Finding of No Significant Impact if the project needs an Environmental Assessment; and (3) upon a determination by the lead agency that an application is eligible for a categorical exclusion pursuant to regulations under NEPA.

(A "categorical exclusion" under NEPA is a category of actions which do not individually or cumulatively have a significant effect on the human environment and which have been found to have no such effect in procedures adopted by a federal agency in implementing environmental regulations and for which, therefore, neither an Environmental Assessment nor an Environmental Impact Statement is required.) Confers original and exclusive jurisdiction upon the U.S. Court of Appeals for the circuit in which the export facility under an application will be located over any civil action for the review of: (1) a DOE order regarding the application, or (2) DOE failure to issue a final decision on the application.

Requires the Court, if it finds in a civil action that DOE has failed to issue a final decision on an application, to order DOE to issue one within 30 days.

Requires the Court to set any civil action brought under this Act on the docket, for expedited consideration, as soon as practical after the filing date of the initial pleading.

(Sec. 3) Amends the Natural Gas Act to set, as a condition for approval of any authorization to export LNG, that the DOE Secretary require the applicant to disclose publicly the specific destination or destinations of any such authorized LNG exports.</summary>
</bill>
