<bill session="113" type="h" number="4047" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-02-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-02-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-02-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Restoring the 10th Amendment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To protect 10th Amendment rights by providing special standing for State government officials to challenge proposed regulations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400089"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400029" joined="2014-05-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412510" joined="2014-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412191" joined="2014-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412295" joined="2014-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412213" joined="2014-06-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-02-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU05" subcommittee="Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU10" subcommittee="Constitution and Civil Justice" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="s" number="1632"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Constitution and constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Federal district courts"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction and venue"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/11/2014--Introduced.
Restoring the 10th Amendment Act - Authorizes a designated state official to submit to the head of a federal agency proposing a rule, during the period when the proposed rule is open for public comment, a legal brief challenging the constitutionality of the rule under the Tenth Amendment to the Constitution.

Directs the agency head: (1) to notify the designated official of each state within 15 days after such a brief was submitted; (2) to post prominently on the front page of the agency's website a link to the brief; and (3) within 15 days after posting such link, to certify in writing that such rulemaking does not violate the Tenth Amendment and post the certification prominently on the agency's website next to the briefs pertaining to the rule, unless the agency determines not to finalize such proposed rule.

Authorizes a designated state official, at any time after an agency head posts such a certification, to commence a civil action against the agency on the grounds that the rule violates the Tenth Amendment. Permits such state official, in addition to any other venue or jurisdiction provided by law, to bring such action in the U.S. district court for the district in which the official's place of business is located.

Directs the appropriate U.S. court of appeals, upon the filing of a notice by a designated state official, to grant expedited review of a decision by the district court in such an action.</summary>
</bill>
