<bill session="113" type="h" number="4474" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-04-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-04-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To remove the Kurdistan Democratic Party and the Patriotic Union of Kurdistan from treatment as terrorist organizations and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400157"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412385" joined="2014-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400654" joined="2014-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412308" joined="2014-06-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Border Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2255"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Political movements and philosophies"/>
    <term name="Political parties and affiliation"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/10/2014--Introduced.
Declares that the Kurdistan Democratic Party and the Patriotic Union of Kurdistan shall not be considered terrorist organizations under the Immigration and Nationality Act. Authorizes the Secretary of State, however, to suspend this declaration for either or both groups.

 Makes terrorist activity-related inadmissibility criteria inapplicable to an alien's activities undertaken in association with the Kurdistan Democratic Party or the Patriotic Union of Kurdistan if the alien is applying for a nonimmigrant visa, presents himself or herself for inspection at a port of entry as a nonimmigrant, or is applying in the United States for nonimmigrant status unless a consular officer or the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS): (1) knows or has reasonable grounds to believe that the alien poses a threat to U.S. security; or (2) believes that the alien does not warrant a visa, U.S. admission, or a grant of nonimmigrant status. Authorizes the Secretary of State, however, to suspend the application of such relief.

Prohibits judicial review of any determination made pursuant to this Act.</summary>
</bill>
