<bill session="113" type="h" number="1123" updated="2015-09-01T10:19:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-02-25T19:10:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-02-25T19:10:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Unlocking Consumer Choice and Wireless Competition Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Unlocking Consumer Choice and Wireless Competition Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Unlocking Consumer Choice and Wireless Competition Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To promote consumer choice and wireless competition by permitting consumers to unlock mobile wireless devices, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400154"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412270" joined="2013-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400076" joined="2013-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2013-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412505" joined="2013-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412561" joined="2013-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412199" joined="2013-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="2013-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400259" joined="2013-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400652" joined="2013-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400424" joined="2013-03-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, Intellectual Property, And The Internet.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-06">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-22">
      <text>Subcommittee on Courts, Intellectual Property, and the Internet Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-31">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-07-31" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-02-25T12:14:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 113-356.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-02-25T12:14:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="264">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 264.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-02-25T15:55:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Goodlatte moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1904" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-25T15:55:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1904-1912" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-25T15:55:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1123.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-25T16:36:00-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-25T19:02:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1922-1923" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="64" datetime="2014-02-25T19:10:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 295 - 114 (Roll no. 64).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1904-1905" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-02-26">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts, Intellectual Property, and the Internet" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="s" number="517"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="517"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Library of Congress"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/25/2014--Passed House amended.
Unlocking Consumer Choice and Wireless Competition Act - Repeals a Library of Congress (LOC) rulemaking determination, made upon the recommendation of the Register of Copyrights, regarding the circumvention of technological measures controlling access to copyrighted software on wireless telephone handsets (mobile telephones) for the purpose of connecting to different wireless telecommunications networks (a practice commonly referred to as "unlocking" such devices). Reestablishes, as an exemption to provisions of the Digital Millennium Copyright Act (DMCA) prohibiting such circumvention, a previous LOC rule permitting the use of computer programs, in the form of firmware or software, that enable used wireless telephone handsets to connect to a wireless telecommunications network, when circumvention is initiated by the owner of the copy of such computer program solely to connect to such a network and access to the network is authorized by the network operator, thus permitting unlocked phones.

Directs the Librarian of Congress, upon the recommendation of the Register, to determine whether to extend such exemption to include any other category of wireless devices in addition to wireless telephone handsets (e.g., tablets and other mobile broadband-enabled devices).

Allows such circumvention (unlocking) to be initiated by the owner of such a device, by another person at the direction of the owner, or by a provider of a commercial mobile radio service or a commercial mobile data service at the direction of such owner or other person, solely in order to enable such owner or a family member of such owner to connect to a wireless telecommunications network, when such connection is authorized by the operator of such network. Prohibits such owner-directed unlocking from being construed to: (1) permit the unlocking of devices for the purpose of bulk resale, or (2) authorize the Librarian to authorize circumvention for such purpose.</summary>
</bill>
