<bill session="113" type="h" number="5734" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-11-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-11-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-11-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Right of Return Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To achieve a lasting peace in the Middle East and improve the economic situation for its people.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410396"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-11-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Arab-Israeli relations"/>
    <term name="Citizenship and naturalization"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans and debt"/>
    <term name="Gaza Strip"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Palestinians"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="West Bank"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/18/2014--Introduced.
Right of Return Act - Requires the following courses of action:

 the Secretary of State shall call for Israel to increase the standard of living of those living in Judea, Samaria, and Gaza by extending its sovereignty over those territories, and for the Palestinian Arab residents currently residing in those areas to be granted citizenship in the countries that controlled them from 1949 to 1967 and have a right of return to those countries; no funds appropriated by Congress may be obligated or expended to provide any U.S. assistance, loan guarantee, or debt relief to the Palestinian Authority (PA) as long as part of the PA unity government refuses to allow such right of return; the Secretary shall ensure that refugees are allowed to return to their host countries in accordance with United Nations High Commission for Refugees (UNHCR) regulations; and all U.S. assistance, loan guarantee, and debt relief that currently go to the United Nations Relief and Works Agency for Palestinian Refugees in the Near East (UNRWA) shall instead be used to assist those who exercise their right of return.</summary>
</bill>
