<bill session="113" type="h" number="3202" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-28T19:04:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-07-28T19:04:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Essential Transportation Worker Identification Credential Assessment Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Essential Transportation Worker Identification Credential Assessment Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Essential Transportation Worker Identification Credential Assessment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Homeland Security to prepare a comprehensive security assessment of the transportation security card program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400199"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400276" joined="2013-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="2013-09-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-09-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border and Maritime Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-20">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-20">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-06-11" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-07-17T12:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Homeland Security. H. Rept. 113-528.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-07-17T12:52:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="394">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 394.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-07-28T15:58:00-04:00">
      <text>Mrs. Miller (MI) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-28T15:58:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6895-6899" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-28T15:58:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3202.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-28T16:13:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-28T18:58:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6938-6939" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="456" datetime="2014-07-28T19:04:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 400 - 0 (Roll no. 456).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6895" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-07-28T19:04:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-29">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSHM11" subcommittee="Border and Maritime Security" name="House Homeland Security"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM07" subcommittee="Transportation Security" name="House Homeland Security"/>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/28/2014--Passed House amended.
Essential Transportation Worker Identification Credential Assessment Act - Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to submit to Congress and the Comptroller General (GAO) a comprehensive assessment of the effectiveness of the transportation security card program at enhancing security and reducing security risks for maritime facilities and vessels. Requires the assessment to be conducted, to the extent practicable, by a national laboratory within the DHS laboratory network or a maritime security university-based center within the DHS centers of excellence network.

Directs the Secretary to submit to Congress a corrective action plan responding to the assessment which: (1) includes an implementation plan with benchmarks, and (2) shall be considered in any DHS rulemaking with respect to the transportation security card program.

Directs the Comptroller General, within 120 days after the corrective action plan is issued, to: (1) review the extent to which it implements the recommendations of the national laboratory or the maritime security university-based center and of the Comptroller General, and (2) inform Congress as to the plan's responsiveness to such recommendations.

Prohibits the Secretary from issuing a final rule requiring the use of transportation security card readers until: (1) the Comptroller General informs Congress that the submission is responsive to the GAO recommendations, and (2) the Secretary issues an updated list of transportation security card readers that are compatible with active transportation security cards.

Requires the Comptroller General to report to Congress on implementation of the plan at least 18 months after it is issued, and every 6 months thereafter for the ensuing 3-year period.

Declares that no additional funds are authorized to carry out this Act. Requires this Act to be carried out using amounts otherwise available for the purpose.</summary>
</bill>
