<bill session="113" type="s" number="2716" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Aleut Confinement and Relocation Sites Study Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a special resource study to determine the suitability and feasibility of adding the sites associated with the forced relocation and confinement of the Aleut people during World War II in the State of Alaska as a unit of the National Park System, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412326"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Military history"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2014--Introduced.
Aleut Confinement and Relocation Sites Study Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a special resource study to determine whether the following sites are suitable for inclusion in the National Park System: (1) the World War II Aleut relocation sites at Funter Bay, Burnett Inlet, Killisnoo, Ward Lake, and the Wrangell Institute in Alaska; and (2) the villages of Makushin, Kashega, and Biorka around Unalaska Island and Attu on Attu Island in Alaska, from which the Aleut people were forcibly removed.

Requires the Secretary to:

 evaluate the national significance of the sites; determine the suitability and feasibility of designating those sites as units of the National Park System; consider alternatives for preservation, protection, and interpretation of the land comprising those sites; and identify cost estimates for any federal acquisition, development, interpretation, operation, and maintenance associated with carrying out such alternatives.</summary>
</bill>
