<bill session="113" type="s" number="1616" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-10-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-10-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Family Fairness and Opportunity Tax Reform Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for simplification, to reduce the number of tax brackets, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412495"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Capital gains tax"/>
    <term name="Charitable contributions"/>
    <term name="Employment taxes"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Income tax rates"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Tax reform and tax simplification"/>
    <term name="Tax treatment of families"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/30/2013--Introduced.
Family Fairness and Opportunity Tax Reform Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to the taxation of individual and married taxpayers, to:

 reduce to two the number of individual income tax brackets, imposing a 15% tax rate on income up to $87,850 ($175,700 for married couples filing a joint return and surviving spouses) and a 35% rate on income above such level; eliminate or reduce the capital gains tax rate based on taxable income levels; repeal after 2013 the alternative minimum tax (AMT) for individual and corporate taxpayers; increase from $1,000 to $2,500 the child tax credit and make a portion of such credit refundable; allow a new personal income tax credit of $2,000 for individual taxpayers ($4,000 for married couples filing a joint return and surviving spouses) in lieu of the standard tax deduction, the personal tax exemption, and certain itemized deductions, other than the deductions for mortgage interest and charitable contributions; provide annual inflation adjustments after 2013 to income levels and credit amounts in this Act; make mortgage interest and charitable contributions deductible from gross income (above-the-line deductions); limit to $300,000 the deductible amount of acquisition indebtedness for principal residences (currently, $1 million); repeal the additional hospital insurance tax on individual taxpayers earning over $200,000 ($250,000 for married couples filing joint tax returns); and repeal the 3.8% Medicare tax on certain unearned income (e.g., income from rents, royalties, stocks, bonds, and other investments).</summary>
</bill>
