<bill session="113" type="hr" number="574" updated="2015-09-01T10:18:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-07T19:03:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-05-07T19:03:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Recommending that the House of Representatives find Lois G. Lerner, former Director, Exempt Organizations, Internal Revenue Service, in contempt of Congress for refusal to comply with a subpoena duly issued by the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400196"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-07T16:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 568.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3482-3909" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-07T16:17:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 568, the House proceeded with 50 minutes of debate on H. Res. 574, the resolution accompanying House Report 113-415.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-07T17:27:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - Pursuant to clause 1(c) of Rule 19, the Speaker postponed further proceedings on H.Res. 574.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-07T18:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3919-3922" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-07T18:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Cummings moved to refer to Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-07T18:18:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 568, the House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Cummings motion to refer.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-07T18:30:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to refer was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3921" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-07T18:56:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to refer Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 191 - 224 (Roll no. 202).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3922" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="203" datetime="2014-05-07T19:03:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 231 - 187 (Roll no. 203).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3902" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-05-07T19:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional-executive branch relations"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Internal Revenue Service (IRS)"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/7/2014--Passed House without amendment.
Resolves that Lois G. Lerner, former Director, Exempt Organizations, Internal Revenue Service (IRS), be found in contempt of Congress for failure to testify before the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform as required by a congressional subpoena.

Directs the Speaker of the House of Representatives to certify the Committee's report&#160;detailing the refusal of Ms. Lerner to testify before the Committee as directed by the subpoena&#160;to the U.S. Attorney for the District of Columbia to the end that Ms. Lerner be proceeded against in the manner and form provided by law, and to otherwise take all appropriate action to enforce the subpoena.</summary>
</bill>
