<bill session="113" type="s" number="1411" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rural Veterans Health Care Improvement Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to specify requirements for the next update of the current strategic plan for the Office of Rural Health of the Department of Veterans Affairs for improving access to, and the quality of, health care services for veterans in rural areas.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412378"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400040" joined="2013-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-30">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 113-280.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4561"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1950"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1982"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2413"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2013--Introduced.
Rural Veterans Health Care Improvement Act of 2013 - Sets forth requirements for the first update of the Strategic Plan Refresh for Fiscal Years 2012 through 2014 after the enactment of this Act.

Requires the Director of the Office of Rural Health of the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to prepare the update in consultation with the Director of the Health Care Retention and Recruitment Office, the Director of the Office of Quality and Performance, and the Director of the Office of Care Coordination Services of the Department.

Requires the update to include: (1) goals and objectives for the provision of health care in rural areas, including for recruiting and retaining health care personnel, ensuring timeliness and improving quality in the delivery of health care services through contract and fee-basis providers, implementing and enhancing the use of telemedicine services, ensuring the full and effective use of mobile outpatient clinics, and coordinating and sharing of resources among federal agencies; (2) procedures for soliciting from each Veterans Health Administration facility that serves a rural area a statement of the facility's clinical capacity, the facility's procedures in the event of an emergency outside the scope of such capacity, and the facility's procedures and mechanisms for the provision and coordination of health care for women veterans; and (3) modification of funding allocation mechanisms to ensure that the Office of Rural Health distributes funds to VA components to best achieve goals and objectives in a timely manner.</summary>
</bill>
