<bill session="113" type="h" number="4009" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-02-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-02-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-02-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protect Academic Freedom Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to prohibit an institution that participates in a boycott of Israeli academic institutions or scholars from being eligible for certain funds under that Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412202"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400630" joined="2014-02-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-02-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Arab-Israeli relations"/>
    <term name="Area studies and international education"/>
    <term name="Cultural exchanges and relations"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="International exchange and broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/6/2014--Introduced.
Protect Academic Freedom Act - Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 (HEA) to prohibit institutions of higher education (IHEs) from being eligible to receive any form of financial assistance under such Act if the Secretary of Education determines that they are participating in a boycott of Israeli academic institutions or scholars.

Directs the Secretary, no later than May 1 of each year, to: (1) identify and make publicly available a list of all IHEs participating in such boycott, and (2) notify each IHE that is so identified of its designation as a participant in such boycott.

Gives IHEs 30 days after their identification as a boycott participant to request the Secretary to waive their ineligibility for financial assistance under the HEA.

Makes the funding prohibition inapplicable to funds available for student financial aid.</summary>
</bill>
