<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H7ED99CA27B1A4FB7B0280DF84C8AC4B0" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HR 5708 IH: Veterans Care Financial Protection Act of 2014</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2014-11-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 5708</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20141114">November 14, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001090">Mr. Cartwright</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001094">Mr. Cook</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000460">Mr. Farenthold</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans’ Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To protect individuals who are eligible for increased pension under laws administered by the
			 Secretary of Veterans Affairs on the basis of need of regular aid and
			 attendance from dishonest, predatory, or otherwise unlawful practices, and
			 for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HC7AC8ADB087443DEA6153A037E9909E4" style="OLC">
		<section id="H69175AA9AF4C4422958BEA2237D8345D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veterans Care Financial Protection Act of 2014</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="HC7B7380C8D2547FD88B4199CB2F190F2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Protection of individuals eligible for increased pension under laws administered by the Secretary
			 of
			 Veterans Affairs on basis of need for regular aid and attendance</header>
			<subsection id="HF0DE4561CE224BE8A0BD17ADFBFC4556"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Development and implementation of standards</header>
				<paragraph id="H3B52ACFBCC0B4DEE855BAAB785341313"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall work with the heads of Federal agencies, States, and such
			 experts as the Secretary considers appropriate to develop and implement
			 Federal and State standards that protect individuals from dishonest,
			 predatory, or otherwise unlawful practices relating to increased pension
			 available to such individuals under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/15">chapter 15</external-xref> of title 38, United States
			 Code, on the basis of need for regular aid and attendance.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H6B81B0768B0946B0955A0ABD5F87909E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Submittal to Congress</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to
			 the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on
			 Veterans' Affairs of the House of Representatives the standards developed
			 under paragraph (1).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0593DC7BD30943C89F92749740606244"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conditional recommendation by Comptroller General</header><text>If the Secretary does not, on or before the date that is 180 days after the date of the enactment
			 of this Act, submit to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the Senate
			 and the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the House of Representatives
			 standards that are developed under subsection (a)(1), the Comptroller
			 General of the United States shall, not later than the date that is one
			 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, submit to such
			 committees a report containing standards that the Comptroller General
			 determines are standards that would be effective in protecting individuals
			 as described in such subsection.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H7179F6A2917E445CB4425668BE4C83B3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Study by Comptroller General</header><text>Not later than 540 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the
			 United States shall complete a study on standards implemented under this
			 section to protect individuals as described in subsection (a)(1) and
			 submit to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the Senate and the
			 Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the House of Representatives a report
			 containing the findings of the Comptroller General with respect to such
			 study.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


