<bill session="113" type="s" number="2342" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-05-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Subsidizing Childhood Obesity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to protect children's health by denying any deduction for advertising and marketing directed at children to promote the consumption of food of poor nutritional quality.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412490"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2014-05-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2831"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Business expenses"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Food industry and services"/>
    <term name="Fruit and vegetables"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/15/2014--Introduced.
Stop Subsidizing Childhood Obesity Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to deny a tax deduction for any business expenses: (1) for advertising or marketing&#160;primarily directed at children (defined as individuals under the age of 14) to promote the consumption by such children&#160;of food of poor nutritional quality or of a brand primarily associated&#160;with food of poor nutritional quality that is primarily directed at children; and (2) for related expenses, including for travel, goods or services constituting entertainment, amusement, or recreation, gifts, or other promotion expenses.

Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to enter into a contract with the Institute of Medicine to develop procedures to evaluate and identify food of poor nutritional quality and brands that are primarily associated with such food.

Authorizes additional funding to carry out the Fresh Fruit and Vegetable Program under the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act.</summary>
</bill>
