<bill session="113" type="h" number="4425" updated="2015-09-01T17:49:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-04-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-04-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Perkins Modernization Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 to improve the Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412543"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412536" joined="2014-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412422" joined="2014-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412421" joined="2014-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400249" joined="2014-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412308" joined="2014-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412579" joined="2014-04-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/8/2014--Introduced.
Perkins Modernization Act of 2014 - Amends the Carl D. Perkins and Technical Education Act of 2006 to revise its purposes, which are to develop more fully the academic and career and technical skills of secondary education students and postsecondary students who elect to enroll in career and technical education programs (as under current law), by: (1) preparing those students for employment in current or emerging in-demand industry sectors or occupations; (2) aligning the skills, certifications, and credentials of the students with those needed by employers in the labor markets served by educational institutions; and (3) ensuring that the selection of skills, certifications, and credentials acquired by such students is guided by timely labor market information.

Defines "in-demand industry sector or occupation" to mean an industry sector or occupation that: (1) has or is projected to have a substantial role or a positive economic impact in the economy of the area served by an eligible institution; (2) provides workers with jobs that lead to economic self-sufficiency and opportunities for advancement; and (3) is documented in labor market information collected by state and federal agencies, workforce investment boards, or other third-party organizations.</summary>
</bill>
