<bill session="113" type="s" number="2486" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Restoring Overtime Pay for Working Americans Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to establish salary thresholds for and limitations on executive, administrative, and professional employees and address highly compensated employees, for purposes of the requirements for exemption from the Federal minimum wage and maximum hour provisions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300051"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2014-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2014-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2014-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2014-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2014-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2014-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2014-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412542" joined="2014-06-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3812-3813" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4435"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Labor standards"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/18/2014--Introduced.
Restoring Overtime Pay for Working Americans Act - Amends the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (FLSA) to establish salary thresholds for the exemption of executive, administrative, and professional employees from federal minimum wage and maximum hour requirements (allowing these individuals to receive overtime pay.)

Establishes salary thresholds also for exemption of highly compensated employees from these FLSA requirements, if the Secretary of Labor determines such employees may be exempted.

Prescribes a fine for any employer who repeatedly or willfully violates the FLSA requirement to make, keep, and preserve records of employees and their wages, hours, and other conditions and practices of employment.</summary>
</bill>
