<bill session="113" type="h" number="5456" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Great Lakes and Fresh Water Algal Bloom Information Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration to create an electronic database of research and information on the causes of, and corrective actions being taken with regard to, algal blooms in the Great Lakes, their tributaries, and other surface fresh waters, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412256"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412327" joined="2014-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412463" joined="2014-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412566" joined="2014-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400276" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412527" joined="2014-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412305" joined="2014-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412331" joined="2014-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412489" joined="2014-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400352" joined="2014-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412461" joined="2014-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412213" joined="2014-09-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-11">
      <text>Referred to House Science, Space, and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-11">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY18" subcommittee="Environment" name="House Science, Space, and Technology"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII22" subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2798"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/11/2014--Introduced.
Great Lakes and Fresh Water Algal Bloom Information Act - Requires the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) to create an online database of research and information on the causes and corrective actions being taken with regard to algal blooms in the Great Lakes, their tributaries, and other surface fresh waters. Requires NOAA to include relevant chemical, physical, and biological data that have been collected by an accredited university, association or organization, research group, federal agency, state, or local government in the United States or Canada.

Declares that this Act does not grant NOAA any new authority, including the authority to require submission of data.</summary>
</bill>
