<bill session="113" type="h" number="4142" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-03-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-03-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-03-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">No Welfare for Weed Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 to prohibit the use of benefits to purchase marijuana products, to amend part A of title IV of the Social Security Act to prohibit assistance provided under the program of block grants to States for temporary assistance for needy families from being accessed through the use of an electronic benefit transfer card at any store that offers marijuana for sale, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412397"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412513" joined="2014-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400116" joined="2014-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412275" joined="2014-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400141" joined="2014-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2014-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412286" joined="2014-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412510" joined="2014-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412442" joined="2014-03-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-03-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-04">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-04">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, and Nutrition.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG22" subcommittee="Department Operations, Oversight, and Nutrition" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4137"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/4/2014--Introduced.
No Welfare for Weed Act of 2014 - Amends the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 to exclude marijuana products from the definition of food which may be purchased under the supplemental nutrition assistance program (SNAP, formerly the food stamp program).

Preserving Welfare for Needs Not Weed Act - Amends part A (Temporary Assistance for Needy Families) (TANF) of title IV of the Social Security Act (SSA) to require a state receiving a TANF grant to maintain policies and practices necessary to prevent assistance under the TANF program from being used in any electronic benefit transfer (via a card) at any establishment that offers marijuana for sale.</summary>
</bill>
