<bill session="113" type="s" number="2800" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Patient Centered Quality Care for Life Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to create a patient-centered quality of care initiative for seriously ill patients through the establishment of a stakeholder strategic summit, quality of life education and awareness initiative, health care workforce training, an advisory committee, and palliative care focused research, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412326"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412545" joined="2014-09-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="1666"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Allied health services"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/11/2014--Introduced.
Patient Centered Quality Care for Life Act - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to convene a Patient-Centered Health Care and Quality of Life Stakeholder Strategic Summit to analyze health system barriers to patient-centered care and make recommendations to improve patient-centered care and address quality of life concerns for individuals with serious, complex, and chronic illness and their families.

Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) to award grants to increase demand for and delivery of integrated, patient-centered care to improve the quality of life of seriously ill patients.

Directs the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration (HRSA) to award health care professional workforce training grants to promote quality of life focused clinical core competencies across clinical specialties that serve patients who are seriously ill or have complex chronic disease.

Requires the Secretary to update and expand the September 2002 HRSA report "The Supply, Demand and Use of Palliative Care Physicians in the United States" and to establish a Quality of Life Cross-Agency Advisory Committee to disseminate findings on best practices and to assist the CDC and HRSA in conducting the grant programs established by this Act.

Requires the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to develop and implement a strategy to expand national research programs in symptom management, palliative, psychosocial, and survivorship care in accordance with the Advisory Committee's recommendations.</summary>
</bill>
