<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="H86E17A25D78B4FBC996B9F2BFE3C85C1" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-joint" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HJ 128 IH: To authorize the use of United States Armed Forces against the Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2014-09-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IA</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. J. RES. 128</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20140919">September 19, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</sponsor> introduced the following joint resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Rules</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>JOINT RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To authorize the use of United States Armed Forces against the Islamic State of Iraq and the
			 Levant.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas the Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant (ISIL) has committed gruesome atrocities in Iraq
			 and Syria;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas ISIL has been instigating sectarian violence that threatens the stability of the Middle
			 East region and the national security interest of the United States;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas ISIL has directly threatened the United States and has kidnapped and killed United States
			 citizens in Syria;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas such acts continue to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and
			 foreign policy of the United States;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas such acts render it both necessary and appropriate that the United States exercise its
			 rights to self-defense and to protect United States citizens both at home
			 and abroad;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas consistent with the War Powers Resolution (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/93/148">Public Law 93–148</external-xref>), the President authorized a
			 series of limited airstrikes in Iraq to protect United States personnel
			 and support certain humanitarian operations; and</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas continued use of the United States Armed Forces after the time limitations specified in
			 section 5(b) of the War Powers Act requires authorization by the United
			 States Congress: Now, therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body id="HE4CC4DA55BBC48F1A1B71F1FB90D0F16" style="OLC">
		<section id="H0064052D8B9C43CEA9904E4D8B4A4293" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This joint resolution may be cited as the <quote>Authorization for Use of Military Force Against ISIL Resolution</quote>.</text>
		</section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6BAAEF3B58AB4C3DB7EA1AB63A6920B3" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text>
			<paragraph id="HB226F76362924C958E40385E85E68FBA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the President has rightly committed limited forces in Iraq to protect United States diplomatic and
			 military personnel against the threat of the Islamic State of Iraq and the
			 Levant (<quote>ISIL</quote>);</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HD746FD3193F84FBDBFD38AF2FF7FCAE3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the President should be commended for authorizing military operations to protect ethnic and
			 religious minorities from slaughter at the hands of ISIL and for providing
			 assistance to prevent a humanitarian disaster;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H5633F03058C848DD9BD8DBC17319825B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the President should be commended for working with North Atlantic Treaty Organization allies to
			 form a coordinated world response to the threat of ISIL;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HB139CBE3E9AD41639EE3D7DC2BFB58DE"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the President determines that it is necessary to use the United States Armed Forces against
			 ISIL, the President—</text>
				<subparagraph id="HC33456D94C104B4E851A33DE50651E44"><enum>(A)</enum><text>should seek consensus in the United Nations Security Council prior to pursuing a multilateral
			 military campaign against ISIL;</text>
				</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3960D338C62D4F95A31AB9AA827C90A9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>should endeavor to form a coalition of allies as broadly based as practicable to support and
			 participate with the United States Armed Forces; and</text>
				</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAA22933C12E34ABB8372CC8D5ADC1846"><enum>(C)</enum><text>should seek equal participation and assistance from members of the Arab League; and</text>
				</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3EDD9D4E374A45F2820D4A22A4B75959"><enum>(5)</enum><text>although military intervention might be necessary to significantly disrupt and degrade ISIL’s
			 activities and operational capabilities in Iraq and Syria, a negotiated
			 political solution among ethnic groups is the only sure solution to end
			 sectarian violence and reach permanent peace.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section commented="no" id="H8320267C7CA949CFA88DB05A8D91B5AE"><enum>3.</enum><header>Authorization for use of United States Armed Forces in accordance with United Nations Security
			 Council resolution</header>
			<subsection commented="no" id="HE5E2A6CDA12D489FB806F7AD07E61F46"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President is authorized to use the United States Armed Forces as the President determines to be
			 necessary and appropriate in order to—</text>
				<paragraph commented="no" id="H6ADF7A31400646E08E8057EEE356C00C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">defend the national security of the United States against the Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant
			 (<quote>ISIL</quote>); and</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H4D550043811D4F318587D4C21AA8BBD2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enforce a United Nations Security Council resolution adopted on or after the date of the enactment
			 of this joint resolution that—</text>
					<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4A78D9F8F2714538AEF2E756A71F86A4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provides for multilateral action against ISIL, including sanctions, humanitarian assistance to
			 those affected by the violence, and the protection of civilians, refugees,
			 nongovernmental organization workers and journalists; and</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HF1E30F71FD9347959446A6C6EBC87737"><enum>(B)</enum><text>authorizes a military force, formed by a coalition of nations, including members of the Arab
			 League, under the auspices of the United Nations Security Council for the
			 individual and collective self-defense against ISIL and to degrade its
			 capacities to commit terrorist acts, destabilize peaceful governments, and
			 perpetuate further attacks.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HFCC87910759042B8B23BE2E6AD4502DD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in subsection (a) shall be construed to prevent or otherwise limit the authority of the
			 Armed Forces to use all appropriate force for self-defense and enforcement
			 purposes.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HF4D63E53715B41D6A6411EB2F7AEBCA4"><enum>4.</enum><header>Authorization for use of United States Armed Forces in absence of United Nations Security Council
			 resolution</header>
			<subsection id="H1DBA5447B61E42C3AA8C5409C8587FE6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President is authorized to use the United States Armed Forces as the President determines to be
			 necessary and appropriate to defend the national security of the United
			 States against the Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant (<quote>ISIL</quote>), other than the use of such Armed Forces in direct ground combat operations, if—</text>
				<paragraph id="HB8CDE4BED77D4F9BA35906E8993A5E32"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the President submits to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore
			 of the Senate—</text>
					<subparagraph id="HE24CB58E0E724E77BB5A135A20A7C6BC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a certification described in subsection (b); and</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H975C1B4AB59E4E4F83F42A84E1F7C26F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a strategy for the use of military force against ISIL; and</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA5209A99A2D14DA1962E37F065E65A5C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a joint resolution that meets the requirements of a qualifying resolution under section 5 is
			 enacted into law.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H37A77C0198E84C078C62849F8D9C2A39"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Certification described</header><text>A certification described in this subsection is a certification that—</text>
				<paragraph id="H4667497988394545A7E34976547F6AA3"><enum>(1)</enum>
					<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HB98111DC0E9248A590F962DBD3C8AE16"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the United States has sought adoption by the United Nations Security Council of a resolution
			 described in section 2(4), and the Security Council has failed to adopt
			 such a resolution, and no other action taken by the United Nations
			 Security Council has been sufficient to compel action against ISIL; or</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H222A5888663C4E80B7607D8B3BF64C7A" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the United Nations Security Council has passed a resolution that does not sanction the use of
			 force, and—</text>
						<clause id="H197129EF99E84A2DADF43669BF5692A5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the United Nations Security Council is unlikely to take further action that will result in
			 authorizing military action; and</text>
						</clause><clause id="H8663FAD9C1934CDF833C0F41EC91554A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the use of military force against ISIL is necessary to combat its threat; and</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9362E6CF265941DE9BAEB4ECABA4C063"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the United States is in the process of establishing, or has established, a coalition of other
			 countries as broadly based as practicable to support and participate with
			 the United States in any action that is taken against ISIL.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H9EDB99024AC04610B95B3E7966143C49"><enum>5.</enum><header>Expedited congressional consideration of joint resolution authorizing use of force under section 4</header>
			<subsection commented="no" id="H7AEC1E6DA9B04B24874BC450888DEE01"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Qualifying resolution</header>
				<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HAD8F1AB2541A4237BD262D834C8D8282"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section applies with respect to a joint resolution of the Senate or House of Representatives—</text>
					<subparagraph commented="no" id="H65E8AA2F5341454EB46A2B6C6F61B106" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that is a qualifying resolution; and</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H2AFA1B78F9B34D6594DB4EFF49DABA33" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that is introduced (by request) by a qualifying Member as described in paragraph (2) not later than
			 the next legislative day after the date of submission of a certification
			 described in section 4(b) by the Speaker of the House of Representatives
			 and the President pro tempore of the Senate; and</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H36F631B42D9B4BA98AA7EF41A4CE57B4" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the text of which is as follows: <quote>The President is authorized to use the United States Armed Forces as the President determines to be
			 necessary and appropriate to defend the national security of the United
			 States against the Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant (<quote>ISIL</quote>), other than the use of such Armed Forces in direct ground combat operations.</quote>.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HB5FB65A71C86423F88D286693F5C59FA" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>For purposes of this subsection, a qualifying Member is—</text>
					<subparagraph commented="no" id="H9CD69779F0CF4038912D1CC7D03C65AB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of the House of Representatives, the majority leader or minority leader of the House of
			 Representatives; and</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HFAD073AE56E6480BB7D442803E054D1C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of the Senate, the majority leader or minority leader of the Senate.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8E5057F23B404C4DA096852B32E233DE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Placement on calendar</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon introduction in either House of a resolution described in subsection (a), the resolution shall
			 be placed on the appropriate calendar of the House involved.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HA2AD9D107D5F438B8DC091D81CC97321"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consideration in the house of representatives</header>
				<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H7AE9407C45554B3A8C4B55C5BF7DB52A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A resolution described in subsection (a) shall be considered in the House of Representatives in
			 accordance with the provisions of this subsection.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H04EDDAFD7A484A0786E810D253AF5376" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>On or after the first legislative day after the day on which such a resolution is introduced, it is
			 in order (even though a previous motion to the same effect has been
			 disagreed to) for any Member of the House of Representatives to move to
			 proceed to the consideration of the resolution. All points of order
			 against the resolution (and against consideration of the resolution) are
			 waived. Such a motion is privileged and is not debatable. An amendment to
			 the motion is not in order. It shall not be in order to move to postpone
			 the motion or to proceed to the consideration of other business. A motion
			 to reconsider the vote by which the motion is agreed to or disagreed to
			 shall not be in order. If a motion to proceed to the consideration of the
			 resolution is agreed to, the House of Representatives shall immediately
			 proceed to consideration of the resolution without intervening motion, and
			 the resolution shall remain the unfinished business of the House of
			 Representatives until disposed of.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HB26EBE59E7B44219A2126EF2718A9A04" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Debate on the resolution shall be limited to not more than a total of 20 hours, which shall be
			 divided equally between the majority leader and the minority leader or
			 their designees. A motion to further limit debate is not debatable. An
			 amendment to, or motion to recommit, the resolution is not in order.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H717E99954B57406FBB9ED3FA809F6B4C" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Immediately following the conclusion of the debate on the resolution, the vote on final passage of
			 the resolution shall occur.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H8635AC9523E24C9F8B0DFDF4DC163EF9" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A motion to reconsider the vote by which the resolution is agreed to or disagreed to is not in
			 order.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBA56564A504B47738C2B8F8F257719BD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Consideration in senate</header>
				<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H959D6AD804D44B7EACC92F8088661625"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A resolution described in subsection (a) shall be considered in the Senate in accordance with the
			 provisions of this subsection.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HE6FDCC3A3C794C1681AF6157C46A46D1" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>On or after the first legislative day after the day on which such a resolution is introduced, it is
			 in order (even though a previous motion to the same
			 effect has been disagreed to) for any Member of the Senate to move to
			 proceed to the consideration of the resolution. All points of order
			 against the resolution (and against consideration of the resolution) are
			 waived. The motion is privileged and is not debatable. The motion is not
			 subject to amendment, or to a motion to postpone, or to a motion to
			 proceed to the consideration of other business. A motion to reconsider the
			 vote by which the motion is agreed to or disagreed to shall not be in
			 order. If a motion to proceed to the consideration of the resolution is
			 agreed to, the Senate shall immediately proceed to consideration of the
			 resolution without intervening motion, order, or other business, and the
			 resolution shall remain the unfinished business of the Senate until
			 disposed of.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H707C4BADF1F5496CA6155CBD647F95F9" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Debate on the resolution, and on all debatable motions and appeals in connection therewith, shall
			 be limited to not more than a total of 20 hours, which shall be divided
			 equally between the majority leader and the minority leader or their
			 designees. A motion to further limit debate is not debatable. An amendment
			 to, or motion to recommit, the resolution is not in order.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H3E729C4E920E417FBFAAB74A35F18573" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Immediately following the conclusion of the debate on a resolution and a single quorum call at the
			 conclusion of the debate if requested in accordance with the rules of the
			 Senate, the vote on final passage of the resolution shall occur.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HFB18923B5ECA4211BE6C1F6EB147D1EA" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A motion to reconsider the vote by which the resolution is agreed to or disagreed to is not in
			 order.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H7492DFE480AB488E96F80FAE3156E3F0" indent="up1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Appeals from the decisions of the Chair relating to the application of the rules of the Senate to
			 the procedure relating to a resolution described in subsection (a) shall
			 be decided without debate.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H968E3CB829AE40008BC27449012BCDF5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Action on measure from other house</header>
				<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HB96313BD998F487684FF3F8EE1CBC4E0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>If, before the passage by one House of a resolution of that House described in subsection (a), that
			 House receives from the other House a resolution described in subsection
			 (a), then the following procedures shall apply:</text>
					<subparagraph id="H12B99C419183481DB490DF1473356A07" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The resolution of the other House shall not be referred to a committee and may not be considered in
			 the House receiving it except as provided in subparagraph (B)(ii).</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2779CDD2D38947D5BA433B785BCA7FA6" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>With respect to a resolution described in subsection (a) of the House receiving the resolution—</text>
						<clause id="H4354FFA73F3E4830AAF83BB7496846A9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the procedure in that House shall be the same as if no resolution had been received from the other
			 House; but</text>
						</clause><clause id="H086FD9D15997489FB4AEDB6CDB5365FD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the vote on final passage shall be on the resolution of the other House.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9E351E4A1DA04FFC99843DAFF1CFA931" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Upon disposition pursuant to paragraph (1)(B)(ii) of a resolution described in subsection (a) that
			 is received by one House from the other House, it shall no longer be in
			 order to consider such a resolution that was introduced in the receiving
			 House.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9286866DFB164649A876EC578E159108"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Legislative day defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purposes of this section, with respect to either House of Congress, a <quote>legislative day</quote> is a calendar day on which that House is in session.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HB4378B5552B54A86BFD78B6A6CA914E1"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Section enacted as exercise of rulemaking power of the two houses</header><text>The provisions of this section (other than subsection (h)) are enacted by the Congress—</text>
				<paragraph id="HE21437BC71C64C9AA4463918ECAC5D89"><enum>(1)</enum><text>as an exercise of the rulemaking power of the House of Representatives and the Senate,
			 respectively, and, as such, shall be considered as part of the rules of
			 either House and shall supersede other rules only to the extent they are
			 inconsistent therewith; and</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HB2FA45360E324A73A11C88B480087C8A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>with full recognition of the constitutional right of either House to change the rules (so far as
			 they relate to the procedures of that House) at any time, in the same
			 manner, and to the same extent as in the case of any other rule of that
			 House.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H9980A01DF3094F4886D83AA1095AC17E"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Presidential recall of congress</header><text>In the event that Congress is not in session upon submission of a Presidential certification under
			 section 4, the President is authorized to convene a special session of the
			 Congress to allow consideration of a joint resolution under this section.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H0B6BB3AB3F8F432DBE60C88878EAAAA9"><enum>6.</enum><header> Reports to Congress</header>
			<subsection id="HEE4926173E11435396980D5467FCE992"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At least once every 60 days after the date of the enactment of this joint resolution, the President
			 shall transmit to Congress a report on matters relevant to this joint
			 resolution. The President shall include in such report when, where, and
			 under what circumstances lethal force has been used pursuant to the
			 authorization for use of the United States Armed Forces under section 3 or
			 4 (as the case may be), and how many civilian casualties have resulted
			 from those actions as well as an estimate of expenditures by the United
			 States and allied nations to combat the Islamic State of Iraq and the
			 Levant (<quote>ISIL</quote>). The President shall include in such report the status of planning for efforts that are expected
			 to be required for the redeployment of United States Armed Forces after
			 actions taken pursuant to this joint resolution are completed.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H7CC933E46C95403F9EB5D0B221271F00"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>The President shall consult on a regular basis with the congressional committees of jurisdiction to
			 provide updated information on actions being taken pursuant to this joint
			 resolution in either public or closed sessions.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HB62A2F4FB24148918CDA056D482B5F52"><enum>7.</enum><header>War powers resolution requirements</header>
			<subsection id="HA6434BCF13A8439995A12394E9D93F56"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Specific statutory authorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Consistent with section 8(a)(1) of the War Powers Resolution, the Congress declares that section 3
			 or 4 (as the case may be) is intended to constitute specific authorization
			 within the meaning of section 5(b) of the War Powers Resolution.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HD8BCF448A7CD4D75A7156A6B359530E6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability of other requirements</header><text>Nothing in this resolution supersedes any requirement of the War Powers Resolution.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HB5D4B8D9FC5749F29C7AB08785FD536C"><enum>8.</enum><header>Inherent right to self-defense</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this joint resolution is intended to derogate or otherwise limit the authority of the
			 President to use military force in self-defense pursuant to the
			 Constitution of the United States and the War Powers Resolution.</text>
		</section><section id="H3E14D0D8E10D4AE48C3AB9F1DE2C4786"><enum>9.</enum><header>Repeals</header>
			<subsection id="HA296A5B683514E8EA360CCCA534F70B0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subsection (b), the following provisions of law are hereby repealed:</text>
				<paragraph id="HD6A34EF20AF54C239A5FE45EEB9576EE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Authorization for Use of Military Force Against Iraq Resolution of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/107/243">Public Law 107–243</external-xref>).</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H0B71FF404F5B43D7AD466C986EA29028"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Authorization for Use of Military Force (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/107/40">Public Law 107–40</external-xref>).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HADE6AF0D763347ABA5663EF631DAC1FC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The repeal made by subsection (a)(2) shall be effective as of the date that is two years after the
			 date of the enactment of this joint resolution.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H6F4A1619D9E741049C8FEAECCCF7FAFC"><enum>10.</enum><header>Sunset</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This joint resolution and the authorities under this joint resolution (other than section 9) shall
			 expire on the date that is two years after the date of the enactment of
			 this joint resolution.</text>
		</section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


