<bill session="113" type="h" number="4152" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-04-03">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-04-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Support for the Sovereignty, Integrity, Democracy, and Economic Stability of Ukraine Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Support for the Sovereignty, Integrity, Democracy, and Economic Stability of Ukraine Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the costs of loan guarantees for Ukraine.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400340"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400157" joined="2014-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412561" joined="2014-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="2014-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400246" joined="2014-03-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-03-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Appropriations, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-05">
      <text>Referred to House Appropriations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-05">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-06T11:18:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Rogers (KY) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-06T11:18:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2215-2219" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-06T11:18:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4152.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-06T11:53:00-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-06T14:55:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2243-2244" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="114" datetime="2014-03-06T15:02:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 385 - 23 (Roll no. 114).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2215" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-03-10">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-11">
      <text>Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-03-12" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="328">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 328.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-03-25">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1720" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-27">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1785-1792" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote2" datetime="2014-03-27" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_BACK:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-03-27">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-01T16:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Royce moved that the House suspend the rules and concur to the Senate amendment.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2752-2756" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-01T16:07:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on the motion to suspend the rules and concur in the Senate amendment to H.R. 4152.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-01T16:20:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-01T18:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2784-2785" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="pingpong" roll="149" datetime="2014-04-01T18:56:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On motion that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays (2/3 required): 378 - 34 (Roll No. 149).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2752-2755" label="text as House agreed to Senate amendment"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-04-01T18:56:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2014-04-03">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2014-04-03" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="113-95" type="public" datetime="2014-04-03">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 113-95.</text>
    </enacted>
    <action datetime="2014-04-09">
      <text>Committee on Commission on Security and Cooperation in Europe. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="JCSE" name="Commission on Security and Cooperation in Europe (Helsinki Commission)" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2124"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans and debt"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Ukraine"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s2867"/>
    <amendment number="s2869"/>
    <amendment number="s2870"/>
    <amendment number="s2872"/>
    <amendment number="s2873"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>4/3/2014--Public Law.
Support for the Sovereignty, Integrity, Democracy, and Economic Stability of Ukraine Act of 2014 - (Sec. 4) Makes available to Ukraine for loan guarantees specified funds under the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2014 and funds under prior Acts for the Department of State, foreign operations, and related programs.

States that such amounts shall not be considered "assistance" for the purposes of law limiting assistance to Ukraine.

(Sec. 5) Directs the Secretary of State to assist: (1) the government of Ukraine to recover assets linked to acts of corruption by Viktor Yanukovych, members of his family, or other former or current Ukrainian government officials in any jurisdiction through appropriate programs, including the Kleptocracy Asset Recovery Initiative of the Department of Justice (DOJ); and (2) the government of Ukraine, the European Union (EU), and other appropriate countries with related investigative assistance and training.

Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to ensure that the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network provides related assistance.

(Sec. 6) Directs the Secretary of State to: (1) improve democratic governance and anti-corruption efforts in Ukraine, (2) support Ukrainian government efforts to foster national unity, (3) assist in diversifying Ukraine's economy and energy supplies, (4) strengthen democratic institutions and political and civil society organizations in Ukraine, (5) expand free access to independent media in Ukraine and assist with the protection of journalists and civil society activists, (6) support political and economic reform initiatives by Eastern Partnership countries, and (7) support efforts to enhance the economic and political empowerment of women in Ukraine and to address violence against women and girls in Ukraine.

Authorizes FY2015 appropriations for such activities.

(Sec. 7) Directs the President to: (1) enhance security cooperation efforts and relationships amongst countries in Central and Eastern Europe and among the United States, the EU, and countries in Central and Eastern Europe; (2) provide additional security assistance, including defense articles, services, and military training, to countries in Central and Eastern Europe, including Ukraine; and (3) support reform and capacity-building efforts within the military, intelligence, and security services in Central and Eastern Europe, including Ukraine.

Authorizes FY2015-FY2017 appropriations for such activities.

(Sec. 8) Directs the President to impose asset blocking and U.S. exclusion sanctions against: (1) any person, including a current or former official of the government of Ukraine or a person acting on behalf of that government, who has perpetrated or is responsible for directing significant acts of violence or gross human rights abuses against persons associated with the anti-government protests in Ukraine that began on November 21, 2013; (2) any person who has perpetrated or is responsible for directing significant acts intended to undermine Ukraine's peace, sovereignty, or territorial integrity, including acts of economic extortion; (3) any official of the government of the Russian Federation, or a close associate or family member of such an official, who is responsible for or complicit in directing acts of significant corruption in Ukraine; and (4) any individual who has materially assisted, sponsored, or provided financial, material, or technological support for such acts.

Sets forth related penalty requirements.

States that U.S. exclusion sanctions shall not apply if necessary to permit the United States to comply with the Agreement regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations or other applicable international obligations. Authorizes the President to waive sanctions if in the U.S. national security interests, and with prior congressional notification. (Sec. 9) Authorizes and encourages the President to impose asset blocking and U.S. exclusion sanctions against: (1) any government official of the Russian Federation, or a close associate or family member of such an official, who is responsible for or complicit in directing acts of significant corruption in the Russian Federation, including the expropriation of private or public assets for personal gain, corruption related to government contracts or the extraction of natural resources, bribery, or the facilitation or transfer of the proceeds of corruption to foreign jurisdictions; and (2) any individual who has materially assisted, sponsored, or provided financial, material, or technological support for such acts. Sets forth related penalty requirements.

States that U.S. exclusion sanctions shall not apply if necessary to permit the United States to comply with the Agreement regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations or other applicable international obligations.

Authorizes the President to waive sanctions if in the U.S. national security interests, and with prior congressional notification.

(Sec. 10) Directs the Secretary of Defense (DOD) to report to Congress each year through 2020 on the current and probable future course of military-technological development of the Russian military, the probable development of the security strategy and military strategy of the government of Russia, and military organizations and operational concepts.</summary>
</bill>
