<bill session="113" type="s" number="1597" updated="2015-09-01T17:50:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-10-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-10-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Savings Promotion Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the use of savings promotion raffle products by financial institutions to encourage savings, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400284"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2013-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412542" joined="2014-02-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="3374"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Consumer Financial Protection Bureau"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Organized crime"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/29/2013--Introduced.
American Savings Promotion Act - Amends the Revised Statutes of the United States, the Federal Reserve Act, the Federal Deposit Insurance Act, and the Home Owners' Loan Act to authorize covered financial institutions to conduct a contest, known as a "savings promotion raffle," in which the sole consideration required for a chance of winning designated prizes is obtained by the deposit of a specified amount of money in a savings account or program, where each ticket or entry has an equal chance of being drawn. Subjects such a drawing contest to regulations promulgated by the appropriate prudential regulator.

Excludes such a "savings promotion raffle" from the prohibition against a covered financial institution's dealing in "lottery" tickets.

Amends the federal criminal code to exempt savings promotion raffles conducted by an insured depository institution or an insured credit union from specified prohibitions against interstate and foreign travel or transportation in aid of racketeering enterprises.</summary>
</bill>
