<bill session="113" type="h" number="2719" updated="2015-09-01T10:19:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-12-18">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-12-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Transportation Security Acquisition Reform Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Transportation Security Acquisition Reform Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Transportation Security Acquisition Reform Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Transportation Security Acquisition Reform Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Transportation Security Acquisition Reform Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Transportation Security Administration to implement best practices and improve transparency with regard to technology acquisition programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412550"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400654" joined="2013-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412432" joined="2013-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="2013-07-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-29">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-10-29" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-11-21T15:02:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Homeland Security. H. Rept. 113-275.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-11-21T15:02:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="196">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 196.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-12-03T12:47:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. McCaul moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-03T12:47:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7409-7414" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-03T12:47:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2719.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-03T12:58:00-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-03T14:35:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7427" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="616" datetime="2013-12-03T14:44:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 416 - 0 (Roll no. 616).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7409-7411" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-12-09">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-09">
      <text>Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-09">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6401" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote2" datetime="2014-12-09" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_BACK:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-12-09">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-10T14:51:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Hudson moved that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8968-8973" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-10T14:51:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 40 minutes of debate on the motion to suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment to H.R. 2719.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-10T14:58:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House resumed debate on the motion to suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment to H.R. 2719.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-10T15:06:00-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-10T17:06:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8992-8993" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="pingpong" roll="559" datetime="2014-12-10T17:13:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On motion that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 425 - 0 (Roll no. 559).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8969-8970" label="text as House agreed to Senate amendment"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-12-10T17:13:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2014-12-12">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2014-12-18" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="113-245" type="public" datetime="2014-12-18">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 113-245.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSHM07" subcommittee="Transportation Security" name="House Homeland Security"/>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1893"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1893"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s3978"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>12/18/2014--Public Law.
Transportation Security Acquisition Reform Act - (Sec. 3) Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) to:

 develop and update biennially a strategic five-year technology investment plan, which may include a classified addendum to report sensitive transportation security risks, technology vulnerabilities, or other sensitive security information; and publish the plan in an unclassified form in the public domain. Directs the Administrator, before acquiring any security-related technology, to analyze whether acquisition is justified. Requires the Administrator, 30 days before any TSA award of a contract for acquisitions exceeding $30 million, to report to Congress the results of the analysis and certify that the transportation security benefits justify the contract cost.

Requires the appropriate TSA acquisition official to establish certain performance baseline requirements before any TSA security-related technology acquisition. Requires that official to review and assess each acquisition for meeting the baseline requirements and to report the results to Congress.

Requires the Administrator, before procuring additional quantities of equipment to fulfill a TSA mission need, to utilize, to the extent practicable, any existing units in the TSA's inventory to meet that need.

Directs the Administrator to report annually to Congress on TSA's performance record in meeting its goals for contracting with small businesses.

Directs the Administrator to execute all responsibilities set forth in this Act in a manner consistent with the Federal Acquisition Regulation and TSA policies and directives.

(Sec. 4) Directs the Comptroller General (GAO) to: (1) assess TSA's implementation of GAO recommendations regarding the acquisition of security-related technology made before enactment of this Act, and (2) evaluate TSA's progress in implementing this Act.

(Sec. 5) Directs the Administrator to report to Congress on the feasibility of tracking TSA security-related technology, including software solutions, through automated information and data capture technologies.

(Sec. 6) Directs the GAO to evaluate TSA's testing and evaluation process relating to security-related technology.

(Sec. 7) Declares that no additional appropriations are authorized to carry out this Act.</summary>
</bill>
