<bill session="113" type="h" number="5269" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HALT Campus Sexual Violence Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Hold Accountable and Lend Transparency on Campus Sexual Violence Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to increase transparency and reporting on campus sexual violence, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412259"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412571" joined="2014-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412195" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412379" joined="2014-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412544" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412529" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2014-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2014-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412189" joined="2014-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412466" joined="2014-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2014-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412514" joined="2014-11-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-30">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-30">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Training" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/2014--Introduced.
Hold Accountable and Lend Transparency on Campus Sexual Violence Act or the HALT Campus Sexual Violence Act - Amends the Department of Education Organization Act to require the Department to make publicly available on its website:

 a list of the institutions of higher education (IHEs) under investigation, and a copy of program reviews and resolution agreements entered into with the Secretary of Education or the Attorney General, under title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972 (Title IX) or title IV of the Civil Rights Act of 1964; the letter terminating the Department's monitoring of such agreements; and a list of the IHEs under investigation, and a copy of the program reviews, fines levied, and resolution agreements entered into with the Secretary or Attorney General, under the provisions of the Higher Education Act of 1965 known as the Jeanne Clery Disclosure of Campus Security Policy and Campus Crime Statistics Act (Clery Act). Authorizes the Assistant Secretary for Civil Rights to impose a civil penalty on an IHE that has violated a law under the jurisdiction of the Department's Office for Civil Rights.

Amends the Clery Act to direct the Secretary to develop an annual sexual violence climate survey and include statistics from such survey in the annual campus security report provided to current and prospective students and employees.

Creates a private right of action in a judicial proceeding for individuals allegedly aggrieved by a violation of the Clery Act.

Increases the maximum monetary penalty that may be imposed on an IHE for substantially misrepresenting the number, location, or nature of the crimes required to be reported under the Clery Act.

Requires an IHE's annual statement of its policy regarding domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking to:

 use simple and understandable language and clear formatting; be made available and posted on its public website and in conspicuous places in and around student housing and academic buildings; be provided to each student group, team, or organization that has a specified connection to the IHE or is known by the IHE to act on an unaffiliated basis; and ensure that each of those student groups, teams, or organizations distributes a copy of such policy to each of its members or applicants for membership. Directs the Secretary and the Attorney General to create a joint interagency Campus Sexual Violence Task Force, the duties of which include:

 providing IHEs with recommendations for preventing and responding to campus sexual violence; reviewing the Department's authority to levy intermediate fines for noncompliance with Title IX and the advisability of additional remedies for such noncompliance; and creating a plan for recruiting, retaining, and training a highly qualified Department of Education workforce to investigate alleged violations of and enforce Title IX and the Clery Act with respect to campus sexual violence. Authorizes funding to train, hire, and retain such a workforce.</summary>
</bill>
