<bill session="113" type="h" number="3822" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-01-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-01-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-01-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fort Wingate Land Division Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the implementation of the property division regarding former Fort Wingate Depot Activity in McKinley County, New Mexico, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412293"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400313" joined="2014-01-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-01-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-09">
      <text>Re-referred to the Subcommittee Indian and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-09">
      <text>Re-referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-27">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII24" subcommittee="Indian and Alaska Native Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="Public Lands and Environmental Regulation" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="5428"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/8/2014--Introduced.
Fort Wingate Land Division Act of 2014 - Declares that all interest of the United States in and to certain lands of the former Fort Wingate Depot Activity in McKinley County, New Mexico, and transferred to the Secretary of the Interior are to be held in trust for the Zuni Tribe as part of the Zuni Reservation, unless the Tribe elects to have specified parcels of those lands conveyed to it in restricted fee status.

 Declares that all interest of the United States in and to specified lands of the former Fort Wingate Depot Activity and transferred to the Secretary are to be held in trust for the Navajo Nation as part of the Navajo Reservation, unless the Navajo Nation elects to have specified parcels of those lands conveyed to it in restricted fee status.

Subjects the lands of the former Fort Wingate Depot Activity held in trust or conveyed in restricted fee status to reservation by the United States of such easements as the Secretary of the Army determines are reasonably required to permit access to lands of the Activity for administrative, environmental cleanup, and environmental remediation purposes.

Requires the lands of the former Fort Wingate Depot Activity identified as parcel 1 to be held in trust subject to a shared easement for cultural and religious purposes only.

Declares that the entire access road for the former Fort Wingate Depot Activity shall be held in common by both the Zuni Tribe and the Navajo Nation to provide for equal access to the Activity.

Subjects lands held in trust or conveyed in restricted fee status to such easements as may be reasonably required to permit the Department of Defense (DOD) access to the Missile Defense Agency facility at the former Fort Wingate Depot Activity.

Requires the Zuni Tribe or the Navajo Nation, after a parcel of land has been transferred or conveyed, to notify the Secretary of the Army of the existence or discovery of any contamination or hazardous material on it.</summary>
</bill>
