<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE amendment-doc PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/amend.dtd//EN" "amend.dtd">
<amendment-doc amend-degree="first" amend-type="engrossed-amendment"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HR 1204 EAS: Aviation Security Stakeholder Participation Act of 2014</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2014-12-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<engrossed-amendment-form>
<congress display="no">113th CONGRESS</congress><session display="no">1st Session</session><legis-num display="no">H.R. 1204</legis-num><current-chamber display="yes">In the Senate of the United States,</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20141209">December 9, 2014.</action-date></action><legis-type display="yes">Amendment:</legis-type></engrossed-amendment-form><engrossed-amendment-body><section id="ideafbee099d7342be924363247a5ef57f" section-type="resolved"><text>That the bill from the House of Representatives (H.R. 1204) entitled <quote>An Act to amend title 49, United States Code, to direct the Assistant Secretary of Homeland
			 Security (Transportation Security Administration) to establish an Aviation
			 Security Advisory Committee, and for other purposes.</quote>, do pass with the following</text></section><amendment><amendment-instruction blank-lines-after="0"><text>Strike all after the enacting clause and insert the following:</text></amendment-instruction><amendment-block blank-lines-after="1" changed="added" id="id86DFC5E41483415987B7E13E5267F5D0" reported-display-style="italic"><section id="id643984a9-8b85-4541-bdba-923a6009e610" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Aviation Security Stakeholder Participation Act of 2014</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id49cf6d75-2e5d-4112-a7cc-85583ea0d037"><enum>2.</enum><header>Aviation Security Advisory Committee</header><subsection id="idc0fcf83c-49b6-4e2e-a9e4-f6e90870132e"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/449">chapter 449</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the
			 following:</text><quoted-block id="ida8c5f26e-fdf5-4c5d-99c2-90a86f573fe4" style="USC"><section id="ide09f72b9-7ace-47f3-962c-4da98e444a62"><enum>44946.</enum><header>Aviation Security Advisory Committee</header><subsection id="idb23bb6a4-c710-4f97-83da-93334f5d5e72"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Assistant Secretary shall establish within the Transportation Security Administration an
			 aviation security advisory committee.</text></subsection><subsection id="idc27f9488-7345-42fd-a5f6-586d44e4fc65"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><paragraph id="id1d2998f3-d01d-4efa-9172-34befda91ff8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Assistant Secretary shall consult the Advisory Committee, as appropriate, on aviation security
			 matters, including on the development, refinement, and implementation of
			 policies, programs, rulemaking, and security directives pertaining to
			 aviation security, while adhering to sensitive security guidelines.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8519cf57-7c51-4172-9eff-9e3363c635ae"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Recommendations</header><subparagraph id="id582a172b-dbb9-4523-9d83-38d0f3c38c7c"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Advisory Committee shall develop, at the request of the Assistant Secretary, recommendations
			 for improvements to aviation security.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9ab8e1fb-0da5-4769-b86a-40ae52577ed2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Recommendations of subcommittees</header><text>Recommendations agreed upon by the subcommittees established under this section shall be approved
			 by the Advisory Committee before transmission to the Assistant Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5c868b80-a22e-4cdb-ab03-a8f261678bf7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Periodic reports</header><text>The Advisory Committee shall periodically submit to the Assistant Secretary—</text><subparagraph id="idbc85510c-3cbe-44c6-b70c-4a2c8052a6e2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reports on matters identified by the Assistant Secretary; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc9930126-16b0-4149-9bad-d7a0c0850ae0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reports on other matters identified by a majority of the members of the Advisory Committee.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idada7bcc1-0a4d-4c61-b845-0c0fa7cd3c4d"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Advisory Committee shall submit to the Assistant Secretary an annual report providing
			 information on the activities, findings, and recommendations of the
			 Advisory Committee, including its subcommittees, for the preceding year. 
			 Not later than 6 months after the date that the Secretary receives the
			 annual report, the Secretary shall publish a public version describing the
			 Advisory Committee's activities and such related matters as would
			 be informative to the public consistent with the policy of section 552(b)
			 of title 5.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id795b354a-54ec-4204-b647-4d7512e91f60"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Feedback</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after receiving recommendations transmitted by the Advisory Committee under
			 paragraph (4), the Assistant Secretary shall respond in writing to the
			 Advisory Committee with feedback on each of the recommendations, an action
			 plan to implement any of the recommendations with which the Assistant
			 Secretary concurs, and a justification for why any of the recommendations
			 have been rejected.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf36aea9c-bf9d-498d-98d5-7199ebbfa8de"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Congressional notification</header><text>Not later than 30 days after providing written feedback to the Advisory Committee under paragraph
			 (5), the Assistant Secretary shall notify the Committee on Commerce,
			 Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Homeland
			 Security of the House of Representatives on such feedback, and provide a
			 briefing upon request.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf823ec18-59cd-41f1-9d93-cdae0bc2aa63"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prior to briefing the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the
			 Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives under
			 paragraph (6), the Assistant Secretary shall submit to such committees a
			 report containing information relating to the recommendations transmitted
			 by the Advisory Committee in accordance with paragraph (4).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id822aedb7-59e2-420d-8ac8-72021106c3ec"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Membership</header><paragraph id="id7c1fd2af-e914-4dc2-8b99-de8afadcd6c4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appointment</header><subparagraph id="id14e3559b-e887-4ced-b2a5-e04755a4e1f4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Aviation Security Stakeholder Participation Act of 2014</short-title>, the Assistant Secretary shall appoint the members of the Advisory Committee.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd435dcb0-caf1-49bb-ba88-15a0e70a13bd"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Composition</header><text>The membership of the Advisory Committee shall consist of individuals representing not more than 34
			 member organizations. Each organization shall be represented by 1
			 individual (or the individual’s designee).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5f1cf78b-4b2d-40a3-bfe2-38bfd05be720"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Representation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The membership of the Advisory Committee shall include representatives of air carriers, all-cargo
			 air transportation, indirect air carriers, labor organizations
			 representing air carrier employees, labor organizations representing
			 transportation security officers, aircraft manufacturers, airport
			 operators, airport construction and maintenance contractors, labor
			 organizations representing employees of airport construction and
			 maintenance contractors, general aviation, privacy organizations, the
			 travel industry, airport-based businesses (including minority-owned small
			 businesses), businesses that conduct security screening operations at
			 airports,
			 aeronautical repair stations, passenger advocacy groups, the aviation
			 security technology industry (including screening technology and
			 biometrics), victims of terrorist acts against aviation, and law
			 enforcement and security experts.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9B2047DEEC3B42C0BCC9F6F45FE6D994"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Term of office</header><subparagraph id="id60AC813F604C43328067C23FBC33B08B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Terms</header><text>The term of each member of the Advisory Committee shall be 2 years.  A member of the Advisory
			 Committee may be reappointed.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf1e7fcc1-6dd9-4bbf-8c0a-3f82b3b4ca75"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Removal</header><text>The Assistant Secretary may review the participation of a member of the Advisory Committee and
			 remove such member for cause at any time.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2ed63469-f657-493c-8838-c9ab8870a6b3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prohibition on compensation</header><text>The members of the Advisory Committee shall not receive pay, allowances, or benefits from the
			 Government by reason of their service on the Advisory Committee.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb4a57a02-79c5-487d-9c4f-6cd76492c402"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Meetings</header><subparagraph id="idC4CE925C33334F6CA2F92D06DCA77DB6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Assistant Secretary shall require the Advisory Committee to meet at least semiannually and may
			 convene additional meetings as necessary.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id73EF7262F329429187D48D3996C20B66"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Public meetings</header><text>At least 1 of the meetings described in subparagraph (A) shall be open to the public.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4B58EF17FFBC4333ACF25F7FD6D13725"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Attendance</header><text>The Advisory Committee shall maintain a record of the persons present at each meeting.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id84B30984E9AB4B389450FEE30449BFA9"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Member access to sensitive security information</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of a member’s appointment, the Assistant Secretary shall
			 determine if there is cause for the member to be restricted from
			 possessing sensitive security information. Without such cause, and upon
			 the member voluntarily signing a non-disclosure agreement, the member may
			 be granted access to sensitive security information that is relevant to
			 the member's advisory duties. The member shall protect the sensitive
			 security information in accordance with part 1520 of title 49, Code of
			 Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id80C6D4697B3E48A9A292F7987D6BFD17"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Chairperson</header><text>A stakeholder representative on the Advisory Committee who is elected by the appointed membership
			 of the Advisory Committee shall chair the Advisory Committee.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4FA390A067504DB48565AA413F461A11"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Subcommittees</header><paragraph id="id062A4656B71C49A993596B4AA57F18A7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The Advisory Committee chairperson, in coordination with the Assistant Secretary, may establish
			 within the Advisory Committee any subcommittee that the Assistant
			 Secretary and Advisory Committee determine to be necessary. The Assistant
			 Secretary and the Advisory Committee shall create subcommittees to address
			 aviation security issues, including the following:</text><subparagraph id="id8913DF36A74545759CDB19AE69E7E9FB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Air cargo security</header><text>The implementation of the air cargo security programs established by the Transportation Security
			 Administration to screen air cargo on passenger aircraft and all-cargo
			 aircraft in accordance with established cargo screening mandates.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5c25cd44-6cb5-4e74-8896-a5a42f1f60f2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>General aviation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">General aviation facilities, general aviation aircraft, and helicopter operations at general
			 aviation and commercial service airports.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9cb66159-f0b5-44de-9a9d-656ff8b3ac67"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Perimeter and access control</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Recommendations on airport perimeter security, exit lane security and technology at commercial
			 service airports, and access control issues.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idFEAC3017F9464112AC7F8D5F965292BB"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Security technology</header><text>Security technology standards and requirements, including their harmonization internationally,
			 technology to screen passengers, passenger baggage, carry-on baggage, and
			 cargo, and biometric technology.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id51B6C054004B4BABA71B10E1F6B59305"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Risk-based security</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">All subcommittees established by the Advisory Committee chairperson in coordination with the
			 Assistant Secretary shall consider risk-based security approaches in the
			 performance of their functions that weigh the optimum balance of costs and
			 benefits in transportation security, including for passenger screening,
			 baggage screening, air cargo security policies, and general aviation
			 security matters.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id33f84e8f-175f-4190-bc4e-35447f5317d0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Meetings and reporting</header><text>Each subcommittee shall meet at least quarterly and submit to the Advisory Committee for inclusion
			 in the annual report required under subsection (b)(4) information,
			 including recommendations, regarding issues within the subcommittee.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id54d14c09-566a-468d-a565-51934b72c9cc"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Subcommittee chairs</header><text>Each subcommittee shall be co-chaired by a Government official and an industry official.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc2af2892-8133-4eda-912d-bcc1f3ef2c83"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Subject matter experts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each subcommittee under this section shall include subject matter experts with relevant expertise
			 who are appointed by the respective subcommittee chairpersons.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="idb5b598bb-6059-4352-a5ca-9a74c84b34ca"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Nonapplicability of FACA</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.) shall not apply to the Advisory Committee and
			 its subcommittees.</text></subsection><subsection id="id5a7625d5-c261-422d-b81d-838b61216901"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="idb9acb964-4f1c-429f-a5d6-e0f11fe68e66"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Advisory Committee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Advisory Committee</term> means the aviation security advisory committee established under subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id2854e7a8-6d19-4ca9-be02-f6535c7ade9d"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Assistant Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Assistant Secretary</term> means the Assistant Secretary of Homeland Security (Transportation Security Administration).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id86a6cd0a-fcef-48bb-89e0-b0c439bb87b5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Perimeter security</header><subparagraph id="id8C6882887AF141EFA7584F948C9C1F79"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>perimeter security</term> means procedures or systems to monitor, secure, and prevent unauthorized access to an airport,
			 including its airfield and terminal.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcc5673c2-a766-434f-be29-1c050f1b895d"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>perimeter security</term> includes the fence area surrounding an airport, access gates, and access controls.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="iddc292df0-1c86-459c-899c-39c6483b462c"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The analysis for subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/449">chapter 449</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding
			 at the end the following new item:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb8ae5a67-5073-4c0d-8c8f-e237a9b661fa" style="USC"><toc container-level="quoted-block-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">44946. Aviation Security Advisory Committee.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></amendment-block></amendment></engrossed-amendment-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestor></attestor><role>Secretary</role></attestation-group></attestation><endorsement></endorsement></amendment-doc>


