<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE amendment-doc PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/amend.dtd//EN" "amend.dtd">
<amendment-doc amend-degree="first" amend-type="engrossed-amendment"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HR 669 EAS: Sudden Unexpected Death Data Enhancement and Awareness Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2014-11-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<engrossed-amendment-form>
<congress display="no">113th CONGRESS</congress><session display="no">2d Session</session><legis-num display="no">H.R. 669</legis-num><current-chamber display="yes">In the Senate of the United States,</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20141120">November 20, 2014.</action-date></action><legis-type display="yes">Amendments:</legis-type></engrossed-amendment-form><engrossed-amendment-body><section id="idbaaf63a85cdc4ce78d27601b1a265957" section-type="resolved"><text>That the bill from the House of Representatives (H.R. 669) entitled <quote>An Act to amend the Public Health Service Act to improve the health of children and help better
			 understand and enhance awareness about unexpected sudden death in early
			 life.</quote>, do pass with the following</text></section><amendment><amendment-instruction blank-lines-after="0"><text>Strike all after the enacting clause and insert the following:</text></amendment-instruction><amendment-block blank-lines-after="1" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic"><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the
		  <quote><short-title>Sudden Unexpected Death Data Enhancement and Awareness Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id39AFE0636DB94724942710EF247C0591"><enum>2.</enum><header>Continuing activities related to stillbirth, sudden unexpected infant death and sudden unexplained
			 death in childhood</header><subsection id="idDFE236AA6B924EAB889297504E06E63F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall continue activities related to still birth,
			 sudden unexpected infant death, and sudden unexplained death in childhood,
			 including, as appropriate—</text><paragraph id="id4bc046b6a6924a7ea83f5a9a9a9bf6f6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>collecting information, such as socio-demographic, death scene investigation, clinical history,
			 and autopsy information, on
			 stillbirth, sudden unexpected infant death, and sudden unexplained
			 death in childhood through the utilization of existing
			 surveillance systems and collaborating with States to improve the quality,
			 consistency, and collection of such data;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5622d5fd97c44c5f90c6bc3adea6a68f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>disseminating information to educate the public, health care providers, and other stakeholders
			 on stillbirth,
			 sudden unexpected infant death and sudden unexplained
			 death in childhood; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2efb6c5f7e7f4f56ad4f18c1b2ffed0d"><enum>(3)</enum><text>collaborating with the Attorney General, State and local departments of health, and other experts,
			 as appropriate, to provide consistent information for medical
			 examiners and coroners, law
			 enforcement personnel, and health care providers related to death scene
			 investigations and autopsies for sudden unexpected infant death and sudden
			 unexplained
			 death in childhood, in order to improve
			 the quality and consistency of the data collected at such death scenes and
			 to promote consistent reporting on the cause of death after autopsy to
			 inform prevention,
			 intervention, and other activities.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idE545D12BCADF4785B3F61435DC0C5D22"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human
			 Services shall submit
			 to Congress a report that includes a description of any activities that
			 are being carried out by agencies within the Department of Health and
			 Human Services, including the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention
			 and the
			 National Institutes of Health, related to stillbirth, sudden unexpected
			 infant death, and sudden unexplained
			 death in childhood, including those activities identified under subsection
			 (a).</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5375CE1EDFD54720A6E7E794ECED2A22" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>No additional appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall not be construed to increase the amount of appropriations that are authorized to
			 be appropriated for any fiscal year.</text></section></amendment-block></amendment></engrossed-amendment-body><title-amends><official-title-amendment>Amend the title so as to read: <quote>An Act to improve the health of children and help better understand and enhance awareness about
			 unexpected sudden death in early life.</quote>.</official-title-amendment></title-amends><attestation><attestation-group><attestor></attestor><role>Secretary</role></attestation-group></attestation><endorsement></endorsement></amendment-doc>


