<bill session="113" type="h" number="4716" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-05-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sage Grouse Protection and Conservation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture to provide certain Western States assistance in the development of statewide conservation and management plans for the protection and recovery of sage grouse species, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412406"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412500" joined="2014-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400029" joined="2014-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400032" joined="2014-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412270" joined="2014-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412271" joined="2014-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412555" joined="2014-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412549" joined="2014-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412397" joined="2014-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412419" joined="2014-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412191" joined="2014-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412294" joined="2014-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412295" joined="2014-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400659" joined="2014-05-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412475" joined="2014-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412310" joined="2014-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412581" joined="2014-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412405" joined="2014-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400419" joined="2014-07-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="Public Lands and Environmental Regulation" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII22" subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2394"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Birds"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="North Dakota"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="South Dakota"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
    <term name="Wyoming"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/22/2014--Introduced.
Sage Grouse Protection and Conservation Act - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) or the Secretary of the Interior to give effect to a statewide conservation and management plan for the protection and recovery of the greater sage-grouse (Centrocercus urophasianus) and the Gunnison sage-grouse (Centrocercus minimus) from either California, Colorado, Idaho, Montana, Nevada, North Dakota, Oregon, South Dakota, Utah, Washington, or Wyoming. Requires the appropriate Secretary to:

 hold for at least 10 years actions to list the species as endangered or threatened, the enforcement of the listing, and the designation of critical habitat for the species in that state; withdraw any land use planning activities related to federal management of the species on National Forest System lands and Bureau of Land Management (BLM) land within the state; and amend federal land use plans with respect to that state to comply with a state plan. Applies these requirements to states that submit a plan or have a plan previously endorsed by the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service.

Requires the appropriate Secretary to: (1) review statewide plans to determine if they are likely to conserve the species to the point at which the measures provided pursuant to the Endangered Species Act of 1973 are no longer necessary; (2) approve or endorse, or make comments on, statewide plans; and (3) provide states with information and make personnel available to help with plans.

Prohibits any proposed action pursuant to the National Environmental Policy Act (NEPA) that occurs within one of those states from being denied or restricted solely on the basis of such sage-grouse if the action is consistent with a state plan that has been submitted to the appropriate Secretary.</summary>
</bill>
