<bill session="113" type="h" number="5463" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">End Financing to ISIL Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To suspend military assistance to countries that harbor persons that provide material or financial support to the Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412531"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412489" joined="2014-09-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/15/2014--Introduced.
End Financing to ISIL Act - Directs the Secretary of the Treasury and the Secretary of State to jointly submit to Congress an annual report that:

 identifies each person that provides material or financial support to the Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant, as well as any successor organization (ISIL), including purchasing oil or other materials that fund ISIL or other terrorist organizations in the region; identifies the country in which such person is located and describes actions taken by the Secretaries to notify the government of such country of these activities; and describes actions taken by the government of such country to restrict these activities. Directs the President to suspend foreign military sales and financing under the Arms Export Control Act to a listed country that has not taken actions to restrict persons in that country from providing material or financial support to ISIL.

Amends the Arms Export Control Act to apply the same transaction prohibitions provided for by that Act against countries supporting acts of international terrorism to a country whose government has knowledge of persons within its territory that provide material support for terrorist organizations, including selling materials that produce income for such organizations.</summary>
</bill>
