<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="HF4F81A97E63F41C49AFE949DF0F54802" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HRES 444 IH: Honoring the accomplishments of Nicarsia Nikki Mayes, a Capitol Hill trailblazer and the first African-American woman to serve as a Doorkeeper of the House of Representatives.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2013-12-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>H. RES. 444</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20131212">December 12, 2013</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C000537">Mr. Clyburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000455">Ms. Fudge</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000126">Ms. Eddie Bernice Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000380">Mrs. Christensen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001157">Mr. David Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000410">Mr. Gene Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000096">Mr. Pascrell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001227">Mr. Brady of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Al Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000287">Mr. Lewis</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Honoring the accomplishments of Nicarsia <term>Nikki</term> Mayes, a Capitol Hill trailblazer and the first African-American woman to serve as a Doorkeeper of the House of Representatives.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas Nicarsia <term>Nikki</term> Mayes began her career of service to the House of Representatives and the people of the United States on September 7, 1977, when she was hired on the recommendation of Congressman Augustus Hawkins of California as an elevator operator and entrusted to operate the last <term>Members Only</term> manual elevator;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas in 1980, Nicarsia <term>Nikki</term> Mayes was hired as a staff member of the then Office of the Doorkeeper, the first African-American woman ever hired by that office;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas in 1994, Nicarsia <term>Nikki</term> Mayes joined the staff of the Office of the Sergeant at Arms, serving as a member of the Chamber Security Division until her retirement in 2013;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Nicarsia <term>Nikki</term> Mayes’ excellent performance, distinguished service, professionalism, and good cheer paved the way for more African-Americans to join the appointments as Office of the Sergeant at Arms and other important House institutions, earned her the respect and friendship of her colleagues, and endeared her to Members of Congress;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas in December 2013, Nicarsia <term>Nikki</term> Mayes retired from active duty after 36 years of faithful, honorable, and distinguished service to the United States House of Representatives; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Nicarsia <term>Nikki</term> Mayes is the mother of three children, sons John Mayes III and David, and a daughter, Tira, all of whom she instilled the importance of public service and each of whom followed her example: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body id="H2051D0C06E2942D1BCAAD15A9DBC676B" style="traditional"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H00B0D185DB6D4FB68EA97B33DE3ADC01" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives commends Nicarsia <term>Nikki</term> Mayes for her distinguished career of service to the House of Representatives and the people of the United States.</text></section></resolution-body></resolution>


