<bill session="113" type="h" number="5449" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-17">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-09-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Passenger Rail Reform and Investment Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Passenger Rail Reform and Investment Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reauthorize Federal support for passenger rail programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="409888"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="2014-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400076" joined="2014-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412403" joined="2014-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412463" joined="2014-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412454" joined="2014-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400276" joined="2014-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400331" joined="2014-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412578" joined="2014-09-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-17">
      <text>Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-17">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-09-17" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-12-01T14:14:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure. H. Rept. 113-629.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-12-01T14:14:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="469">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 469.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSPW14" subcommittee="Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1710"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1710"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Alternative dispute resolution, mediation, arbitration"/>
    <term name="Animal protection and human-animal relationships"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Commuting"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Connecticut"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Food industry and services"/>
    <term name="Government corporations and government-sponsored enterprises"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="Massachusetts"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="National Railroad Passenger Corporation (Amtrak)"/>
    <term name="New York City"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/11/2014--Introduced.
Passenger Rail Reform and Investment Act of 2014 - Authorizes appropriations for FY2015-FY2018 to the Secretary of Transportation (DOT) for the National Railroad Passenger Corporation (Amtrak) for:

 the Northeast Corridor Improvement Fund account, the National Network account, the Office of the Inspector General, and national infrastructure investment capital grants. Directs Amtrak to establish internal controls to ensure its costs and revenues are allocated to either the Northeast Corridor or the National Network.

Directs the Secretary to establish substantive and procedural requirements for Northeast Corridor and National Network investment capital grant requests.

Directs Amtrak to establish:

 a Northeast Corridor Improvement Fund account for Northeast Corridor capital improvement projects, and a National Network account for capital expenses and operating costs of the National Network. Requires the Northeast Corridor Infrastructure and Operations Advisory Commission to:

 develop an annual capital investment plan for the Northeast Corridor main line between Boston, Massachusetts, and the District of Columbia, and the Northeast Corridor branch lines connecting to Harrisburg, Pennsylvania, Springfield, Massachusetts, and Spuyten Duyvil, New York; and update, once every 10 years, a Northeast Corridor service development plan. Requires Amtrak, and states and public entities that own infrastructure supporting or providing intercity rail passenger transportation on the Northeast Corridor, to develop and update asset management plans for the Northeast Corridor main line and the Northeast Corridor branch lines.

Requires the Amtrak Board of Directors to prepare a five-year capital and operating plan for the Northeast Corridor and National Network.

Directs the Secretary to establish a State-Supported Route Advisory Committee.

Amends the Passenger Rail Investment and Improvement Act of 2008 to revise requirements with respect to methodologies for Amtrak route and service planning decisions. Requires Amtrak, as a condition of receiving a grant, to obtain the services of an independent entity to develop and recommend objective methodologies for Amtrak to use in the planning of intercity rail passenger transportation routes and services.

Revises alternate passenger rail service pilot program requirements.

Requires the Surface Transportation Board, within 120 days after submission of a dispute between Amtrak and a rail carrier (or carriers) awarded the right to provide rail service over a route in which Amtrak is to grant access to its reservation system, stations, and facilities, to issue an order requiring Amtrak to provide such facilities and services to those carriers if certain criteria are met.

Directs Amtrak to develop a plan to eliminate the operating loss for food and beverage service on board its trains.

Directs Amtrak to request proposals from private sector persons or entities to utilize Amtrak-owned rights-of-way for telecommunications systems, energy distribution systems, and other appropriate activities. Authorizes Amtrak to enter into an agreement to implement any such proposal or proposals. Requires Amtrak to report to Congress on options to enhance development around Amtrak stations. Amends the Passenger Rail Investment and Improvement Act of 2008 to extend indefinitely specified authority to restructure long-term Amtrak debt and capital leases. Directs Amtrak to develop a pilot program to allow passengers to transport domesticated cats or dogs on certain Amtrak trains.

Directs the Amtrak Inspector General to evaluate Amtrak's boarding procedures at the 10 stations through which the most people pass.

Directs the Secretary to develop a program to issue competitive grants for capital improvement projects included in the Northeast Corridor Priority Project List.

Amends the Railroad Revitalization and Regulatory Reform Act of 1976 to revise Railroad Rehabilitation and Improvement Financing program requirements. Modifies application procedures for direct loans and loan guarantees for railroad improvement projects.

Requires the Secretary, in granting applications for such loans and guarantees, to give priority to projects for the installation of a positive train control.

Directs the Secretary to make direct loans and loan guarantees or capital improvement projects in the Northeast Corridor (NEC Fast Forward Program).

Prescribes requirements for the award of grants in excess of $1 billion.

Directs the Secretary to study the availability and use of small businesses owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals in Federal Railroad Administration (FRA)-funded intercity rail passenger transportation projects.

Directs the FRA to convene a working group to evaluate the restoration of intercity rail passenger service in the Gulf Coast region between New Orleans, Louisiana, and Orlando, Florida.

Directs the Secretary to begin a rulemaking to govern the federal review, permitting, and approval or disapproval of freight railroad and intercity and commuter rail passenger transportation infrastructure projects.

Directs the Secretary to: (1) pursue program alternatives to promote a consistent approach in the treatment of railroad and rail-related properties for historic preservation review, and (2) develop mechanisms for streamlining compliance with specified requirements.</summary>
</bill>
