<bill session="113" type="h" number="4759" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-05-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out a pilot program under which eligible veterans may elect to receive hospital care and medical services at non-Department of Veterans Affairs facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400244"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412555" joined="2014-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400116" joined="2014-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2014-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412510" joined="2014-06-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR03" subcommittee="Health" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="New Jersey"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/29/2014--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out a two-year pilot program under which: (1) eligible veterans may elect to receive hospital care and services at non-Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) facilities, and (2) the Secretary shall reimburse such facilities for the cost of such care and services.

Defines an "eligible veteran" as a veteran who: (1) is enrolled in the VA's patient enrollment system, and (2) resides in a geographic area selected by the Secretary. Directs the Secretary to select: (1) one geographic area within each Veterans Integrated Service Network, and (2) NJ-2 as the geographic area for participation in the pilot program for Veterans Integrated Service Network 4.

Requires the Secretary to: (1) issue a unique identification card to each eligible veteran who elects to receive hospital care and medical services at non-VA facilities under the pilot program, and (2) take steps to ensure that such veterans receive such care and services at such non-VA facilities.</summary>
</bill>
