<bill session="113" type="s" number="2811" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Children and Firefighters Protection Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit the distribution in commerce of children's products and upholstered furniture containing certain flame retardants, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300087"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2014-09-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Consumer Product Safety Commission"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/15/2014--Introduced.
Children and Firefighters Protection Act of 2014 - Prohibits manufacturers, distributors, or retailers from selling, manufacturing for sale, distributing in commerce, or importing into the United States any children's product or upholstered furniture that contains a flame retardant exceeding a specified amount of the total chemical content by weight for any part of the product or furniture. Specifies flame retardants that are subject to such prohibitions.

Requires the Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC) to appoint a chronic hazard advisory panel to study the effects on human health of all chemical flame retardants as used in such products or upholstered furniture.

Directs the CPSC, after receiving a report from the advisory panel evaluating the full range of such retardants, to promulgate a final rule specifying retardants that are not already listed in this Act that may cause substantial personal injury or illness. Makes such CPSC-specified retardants subject to the prohibitions of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
