<bill session="113" type="h" number="3593" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-16T19:33:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-09-16T19:33:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-11-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">VA Construction Assistance Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">VA Construction Assistance Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">VA Construction Assistance Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the construction of major medical facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412271"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400137" joined="2014-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412406" joined="2014-01-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412286" joined="2013-11-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412191" joined="2014-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412310" joined="2014-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412461" joined="2014-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412405" joined="2014-02-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-11-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-07">
      <text>Subcommittee on Health Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Oversight and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-25">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-10">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-09-10" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-09-15T14:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Veterans' Affairs. H. Rept. 113-586.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-09-15T14:31:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="433">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 433.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-09-16T19:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Lamborn moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-16T19:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7581-7585" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-16T19:13:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3593.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2014-09-16T19:33:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7581-7582" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-09-16T19:33:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-17">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSVR03" subcommittee="Health" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSVR08" subcommittee="Oversight and Investigations" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Army Corps of Engineers"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/16/2014--Passed House amended.
VA Construction Assistance Act of 2014 - (Sec. 2) Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the management of the major medical center construction projects of the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) has been an abysmal failure; and (2) the Secretary of Veterans Affairs should fully implement all recommendations made by the Comptroller General in an April 2013 report to improve VA construction procedures.

(Sec. 3) Requires the Secretary, for any construction or alteration project that is a major medical facility project, to: (1) use the services of a medical equipment planner as part of the architectural and engineering firm for the project, (2) develop and use a project management plan to ensure clear and consistent communication among all parties, (3) subject the project to construction peer excellence review, (4) develop a metrics program to enable the monitoring of change-order processing time and goals for the change-order process consistent with the best practices of other federal agencies, and (5) use design-build processes to minimize multiple change orders.

(Sec. 4) Directs the Secretary to procure the services of the Army Corps of Engineers with respect to appointing not less than one special project manager who has experience in managing construction projects that exceed $60 million to oversee such covered projects until completion. Requires a special project manager to submit to specified congressional committees detailed plans of a covered project and progress reports, which shall include an analysis of all changes ordered by the VA and recommendations for improving the operation of any construction-related activity to reduce costs or complete the project in a more timely manner.

Defines "covered projects" to mean each construction project that is a major medical facility project that: (1) was the subject of a report by the Comptroller General (GAO) titled "Additional Actions Needed to Decrease Delays and Lower Costs of Major Medical-Facility Projects," published in April 2013; and (2) has not been activated to accept patients as of this Act's enactment.

(Sec. 5) Prohibits additional funds from being authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act.</summary>
</bill>
