<bill bill-stage="Enrolled-Bill" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H0D17FC83A0ED475582E8E662A60FA8A5" public-private="public" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"> HR 2650 ENR: To allow the Fond du Lac Band of Lake Superior Chippewa in the State of Minnesota to lease or transfer certain land.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"/>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>One Hundred Thirteenth Congress of the United States of America</congress> <session>At the Second Session</session>
    <enrolled-dateline>Begun and held at the City of Washington on Friday, the third day of January, two thousand and fourteen</enrolled-dateline> 
<legis-num>H. R. 2650</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no"/> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To allow the Fond du Lac Band of Lake Superior Chippewa in the State of Minnesota to lease or transfer certain land.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H9A35755430CD4C3C93B6818B72414DDC" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD55DD26D6FA84C26AA23AD8BC5DC1D91" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Congressional approval of certain land transactions</header> 
<subsection id="H2B2D2C81489C4FA9B766EE55C9BAA896">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law (including regulations), and without further approval, ratification, or authorization by the United States, the Fond du Lac Band of Lake Superior Chippewa in the State of Minnesota (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Band</quote>) may lease, sell, convey, warrant, or otherwise transfer all or any portion of the interest of the Band in any real property that is not held in trust by the United States for the benefit of the Band.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H0B6486011E2940C59F898610F5B7B7EE">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>No effect on trust land</header>
        <text>Nothing in this Act—</text> 
<paragraph id="H9C62C50DC9F4429FA7F2413455F74BC5">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>authorizes the Band to lease, sell, convey, warrant, or otherwise transfer all or any portion of any interest in any real property that is held in trust by the United States for the benefit of the Band; or</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9F485CDFD8B94FC984E4FBDEACE88274">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>affects any Federal law (including regulations) relating to leasing, selling, conveying, warranting, or otherwise transferring any interest in the real property described in paragraph (1).</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
</legis-body> <attestation>
    <attestation-group>
      <role>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</role>
    </attestation-group>
    <attestation-group>
      <role>Vice President of the United States and President of the Senate.</role>
    </attestation-group>
  </attestation>
</bill>