<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="H08d2e0de-ef16-4d2e-81db-a746e5e2f27d" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Reported-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HRES 766 RH: Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 5771) to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to extend certain expiring provisions and make technical corrections, and for other purposes, and providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 647) to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for the tax treatment of ABLE accounts established under State programs for the care of family members with disabilities, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2014-12-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<calendar display="yes">House Calendar No. 147</calendar>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 766</legis-num>
		<associated-doc display="yes" role="report">[Report No. 113–643]</associated-doc>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20141202">December 2, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc><cosponsor name-id="S000250">Mr. Sessions</cosponsor>, from the <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</committee-name>, reported the following resolution; which was referred to the House Calendar and ordered to be
			 printed</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 5771) to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to
			 extend certain expiring provisions and make technical corrections, and for
			 other purposes, and providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 647) to
			 amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for the tax treatment
			 of ABLE accounts established under State programs for the care of family
			 members with disabilities, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<resolution-body id="Hb10b1799-39d2-43b9-b054-fbbb3c86ed47" style="traditional">
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="Hb015b506-984f-40aa-9e8b-038e9568e120" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That upon adoption of this resolution it shall be in order to consider in the House the bill (H.R.
			 5771) to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to extend certain
			 expiring provisions and make technical corrections, and for other
			 purposes. All points of order against consideration of the bill are
			 waived. The amendment printed in part A of the report of the Committee on
			 Rules accompanying this resolution shall be considered as adopted. The
			 bill, as amended, shall be considered as read. All points of order against
			 provisions in the bill, as amended, are waived. The previous question
			 shall be considered as ordered on the bill, as amended, and on any further
			 amendment thereto, to final passage without intervening motion except: (1)
			 one hour of debate equally divided and controlled by the chair and ranking
			 minority member of the Committee on Ways and Means; and (2) one motion to
			 recommit with or without instructions.</text>
		</section><section id="H6ED9363E79DC422E9C8616242A2DFC5C"><enum>2.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon adoption of this resolution it shall be in order to consider in the House the bill (H.R. 647)
			 to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for the tax
			 treatment of ABLE accounts established under State programs for the care
			 of family members with disabilities, and for other purposes. All points of
			 order against consideration of the bill are waived. In lieu of the
			 amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on
			 Ways and Means now printed in the bill, the amendment in the nature of a
			 substitute printed in part B of the report of the Committee on Rules
			 accompanying this resolution shall be considered as adopted. The bill, as
			 amended, shall be considered as read. All points of order against
			 provisions in the bill, as amended, are waived. The previous question
			 shall be considered as ordered on the bill, as amended, and on any further
			 amendment thereto, to final passage without intervening motion except: (1)
			 one hour of debate equally divided and controlled by the chair and ranking
			 minority member of the Committee on Ways and Means; and (2) one motion to
			 recommit with or without instructions.</text>
		</section><section id="HB909B0059DCA4D3A9AD3E53F0362BBC5"><enum>3.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the engrossment of H.R. 5771 the Clerk shall—</text>
			<subsection id="H17165B3A286746E1881C120B3E79D440"><enum>(a)</enum><text>add the text of H.R. 647, as passed by the House, as new matter at the end of H.R. 5771;</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HAB98D2EA1F5246F0984FA9D0CBF078FC"><enum>(b)</enum><text>conform the title of H.R. 5771 to reflect the addition of H.R. 647, as passed by the House, to the
			 engrossment;</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HBE576E5CF5BB4EE194E12C7578A014DE"><enum>(c)</enum><text>assign appropriate designations to provisions within the engrossment; and</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H68BE383E96044081B540D2C7EF957CE6"><enum>(d)</enum><text>conform cross-references and provisions for short titles within the engrossment.</text>
			</subsection></section></resolution-body>
	<endorsement><action-date>December 2, 2014</action-date><action-desc>Referred to the House Calendar and ordered to be
			 printed</action-desc></endorsement></resolution>


