<bill session="113" type="s" number="2316" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-05-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Inspector General of the Department of Veterans Affairs to submit a report on wait times for veterans seeking medical appointments and treatment from the Department of Veterans Affairs, to prohibit closure of medical facilities of the Department, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400546"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2014-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2014-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412495" joined="2014-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412322" joined="2014-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="2014-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412471" joined="2014-05-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/12/2014--Introduced.
Requires the Inspector General of the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to submit to Congress within 180 days after enactment of this Act a report on wait times for veterans seeking medical appointments and treatment from the VA, which shall include: (1) information on wait times throughout the United States, and (2) a determination by the Inspector General as to whether such wait times have been prolonged by VA employees without a valid medical or administrative reason.

Prohibits the VA Secretary from closing any VA medical facility, or from using any VA funds to prepare any environment impact statement related to such closure, before such report is submitted, or after the report is submitted if the Inspector General determines that wait times have been prolonged by VA employees without a valid reason, unless the Secretary certifies that such closure will not:

 increase the wait times for veterans in the catchment area of such medical facility; decrease the quality of care provided to such veterans; impede the access of such veterans to specialized health care services or to VA residential rehabilitation treatment programs and other inpatient care; increase the distance required to be traveled by such veterans to receive care; or impede the access to medical care for such veterans that are members of Indian tribes. Terminates such prohibition when the Inspector General certifies that such wait times are not being prolonged by VA employees without a valid reason.</summary>
</bill>
