<bill session="113" type="s" number="517" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-08-01">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-08-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Unlocking Consumer Choice and Wireless Competition Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Unlocking Consumer Choice and Wireless Competition Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Unlocking Consumer Choice and Wireless Competition Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Unlocking Consumer Choice and Wireless Competition Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Unlocking Consumer Choice and Wireless Competition Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to promote consumer choice and wireless competition by permitting consumers to unlock mobile wireless devices, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300065"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412330" joined="2014-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2014-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412390" joined="2014-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2013-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="2013-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="2013-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2013-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412495" joined="2013-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2013-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2013-03-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1594-1595"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1595" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-07-10" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-07-10">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Reported by Senator Leahy with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-07-10" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="461">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 461.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2014-07-15" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4510-4511" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S4510-4511" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-07-16">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-16T10:25:00-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-16T16:58:00-04:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-17">
      <text>By Senator Leahy from Committee on the Judiciary filed written report. Report No. 113-212.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-25T13:01:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Chaffetz asked unanimous consent to take from the Speaker's table and consider.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-25T13:01:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6835-6836" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote2" datetime="2014-07-25T13:01:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On passage Passed by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6835-6836" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-07-25T13:01:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2014-07-28">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2014-08-01" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="113-144" type="public" datetime="2014-08-01">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 113-144.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="1123"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1123"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Library of Congress"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/1/2014--Public Law.
(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the Senate on July 10, 2014. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Unlocking Consumer Choice and Wireless Competition Act - Repeals a Library of Congress (LOC) rulemaking determination, made upon the recommendation of the Register of Copyrights, regarding the circumvention of technological measures controlling access to copyrighted software on wireless telephone handsets (mobile telephones) for the purpose of connecting to different wireless telecommunications networks (a practice commonly referred to as "unlocking" such devices). Reestablishes, as an exemption to provisions of the Digital Millennium Copyright Act (DMCA) prohibiting such circumvention, a previous LOC rule permitting the use of computer programs, in the form of firmware or software, that enable used wireless telephone handsets to connect to a wireless telecommunications network, when circumvention is initiated by the owner of the copy of such computer program solely to connect to such a network and access to the network is authorized by the network operator, thus permitting unlocked phones.

Directs the Librarian of Congress, upon the recommendation of the Register, to determine whether to extend such exemption to include any other category of wireless devices in addition to wireless telephone handsets (e.g., tablets and other mobile broadband-enabled devices).

Allows such circumvention (unlocking) to be initiated by the owner of such a device, by another person at the direction of the owner, or by a provider of a commercial mobile radio service or a commercial mobile data service at the direction of such owner or other person, solely in order to enable such owner or a family member of such owner to connect to a wireless telecommunications network, when such connection is authorized by the operator of such network.

Prohibits this Act from being construed to alter any party's rights under existing law.</summary>
</bill>
