<bill session="113" type="h" number="3520" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-11-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-11-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-11-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Exempt Organization Simplification and Taxpayer Protection Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to reform rules relating to 501(c)(4) organizations and provide certain taxpayer protections, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400636"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-11-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="5418"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="5420"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Internal Revenue Service (IRS)"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/18/2013--Introduced.
Exempt Organization Simplification and Taxpayer Protection Act of 2013 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) require an organization that intends to operate as a tax-exempt social welfare organization to notify the Secretary of the Treasury of such intent with information as to its identity and purpose, (2) allow such an organization to seek a declaratory judgment concerning its status and classification as a tax-exempt organization, and (3) authorize the Secretary to disclose information for investigations of violations of internal revenue laws relating to unauthorized disclosure or inspection of tax information and unlawful acts of revenue officers or agents.

Directs the Comptroller General (GAO) to study and report on the process used for determining how Internal Revenue Service (IRS) enforcement cases are selected and processed.

Prohibits any IRS officer or employee from using a personal email account to conduct official business.</summary>
</bill>
