<bill session="113" type="h" number="5398" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-08-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-08-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Marriage and Family Therapists for Veterans Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to provide for additional qualification requirements for individuals appointed to marriage and family therapist positions in the Veterans Health Administration of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412523"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412516" joined="2014-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412453" joined="2014-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412520" joined="2014-08-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-08-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR03" subcommittee="Health" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Marriage and family status"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/1/2014--Introduced.
Marriage and Family Therapists for Veterans Act - Revises the eligibility criteria for appointment to a marriage and family therapist position with the Veterans Health Administration of the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to require a person: (1) to hold a master's degree in marriage and family therapy, or a comparable degree in mental health, from an institution that is regionally accredited or approved by the VA Secretary (currently, approved by the Secretary); and (2) to have passed the Association of Marital and Family Therapy regulatory board examination in marital and family therapy or an examination for a marriage and family therapy license given by a state board of behavioral sciences (or its equivalent).</summary>
</bill>
