<bill session="113" type="hr" number="510" updated="2015-09-01T10:18:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-03-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-03-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the National Institutes of Health should develop a pilot program to improve medical trial participation, retention, efficiency, effectiveness, and diversity.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400221"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-03-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/11/2014--Introduced.
Encourages the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to use its existing budget and authority to establish a pilot partnership with nonprofit organizations that hold prior experience and expertise in diverse community outreach and trial accrual to increase the efficiency and effectiveness of NIH clinical trials, increase patient enrollment and retention in such trials, and address the lack of diversity in such trials.

Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that the goals of the pilot partnership should include providing clinical trial navigation services to help patients find, enroll, and manage logistical issues related to enrollment and retention in federally supported clinical trials and to improve participation by populations such as underrepresented and uninsured individuals in such trials.</summary>
</bill>
