<bill session="113" type="s" number="2028" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-04-09">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-04-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-02-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sport Fish Restoration and Recreational Boating Safety Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Sport Fish Restoration and Recreational Boating Safety Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the law relating to sport fish restoration and recreational boating safety, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300084"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2014-02-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-02-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-04-09" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-07-07">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Rockefeller without amendment. With written report No. 113-205.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-07-07" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="452">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 452.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Hunting and fishing"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/7/2014--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Sport Fish Restoration and Recreational Boating Safety Act of 2014 - Amends the Federal Aid in Fish Restoration Act to reauthorize through FY2021 the Sport Fish Restoration and Boating Trust Fund. Extends the distributions of appropriations to: (1) the Department of the Interior for coastal wetlands distributions, the Clean Vessel Act of 1992, boating infrastructure, and national outreach and communications; and (2) the Department of Homeland Security (the department in which the Coast Guard is operating) for state recreational boating safety programs. Sets forth a formula that determines the maximum amount Interior may spend on administrative expenses incurred to implement the Act.

Sets forth separate set-aside amounts through FY2021 for Coast Guard national recreational boating safety personnel and activities, the National Boating Safety Advisory Council (NBSAC), and boating safety activities of national nonprofit public service organizations.

Amends the Internal Revenue Code to extend Fund transfer restriction exceptions through September 30, 2021.

 Revokes a limitation on the amount the Coast Guard is authorized to allocate for national boating safety activities of national nonprofit public service organizations.

Extends the NBSAC through September 30, 2021.</summary>
</bill>
