<bill session="113" type="h" number="5746" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-11-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-11-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-11-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Keeping America Safe from Ebola Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit an alien who is a national of a country with a widespread Ebola virus outbreak from obtaining a visa and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412465"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-11-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8149-8150"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-20">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-20">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Border Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2953"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Immigrant health and welfare"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/20/2014--Introduced.
Keeping America Safe from Ebola Act of 2014 - Defines "covered alien" as an alien: (1) who is a national or a resident of a country designated by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) as one with widespread transmission of the Ebola virus; and (2) whose last habitual residence, or last habitual residence before residence in the United States if the alien is seeking to reenter the United States, was a designated country.

States that a covered alien is ineligible to: (1) receive a U.S. visa or otherwise be admitted to the United States; or (2) enter the United States if the alien was lawfully present in the United States, departed the United States and visited a designated country, and is seeking to reenter the United States. Requires the Secretary of State to revoke the visa of each covered alien.

Exempts from such coverage and requirements: (1) certain aid workers, and (2) persons authorized by the Secretary of Defense (DOD) to travel to the United States for training.

Directs the President to report to Congress every 30 days regarding the spread of Ebola.</summary>
</bill>
