<bill session="113" type="h" number="4303" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-03-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-03-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-03-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Border Enforcement Accountability, Oversight, and Community Engagement Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To increase transparency, accountability, and community engagement within U.S. Customs and Border Protection, provide independent oversight of border security activities, improve training for U.S. Customs and Border Protection agents and officers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412575"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412505" joined="2014-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2014-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400163" joined="2014-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400313" joined="2014-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="2014-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412522" joined="2014-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412579" joined="2014-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412580" joined="2014-03-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-03-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-26">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-26">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-26">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border and Maritime Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM11" subcommittee="Border and Maritime Security" name="House Homeland Security"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Border Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Customs enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Due process and equal protection"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="Immigrant health and welfare"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Property rights"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/26/2014--Introduced.
Border Enforcement Accountability, Oversight, and Community Engagement Act of 2014 - Establishes: (1) the Department of Homeland Security Border Oversight Commission, and (2) a northern border subcommittee and a southern border subcommittee within the Commission.

Requires the Commission and the subcommittees to: (1) recommend border enforcement policy improvements; (2) evaluate policies of federal agencies operating along the borders to protect due process and human rights of border residents and visitors, protect land owner private property rights, and reduce the number of migrant deaths; (3) recommend safety improvements for U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) personnel; and (4) evaluate training and the extent to which CBP supervisory and management personnel practices encourage workforce development and promote field safety.

Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to rename the position of Citizenship and Immigration Services Ombudsman in the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) as the Ombudsman for Border and Immigration Related Concerns. Revises related function and administrative provisions, including requiring the Ombudsman to establish a Border Community Liaison Office in each Border Patrol sector on the northern and southern borders.

Sets forth specified training and continuing education requirements for CBP and U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) personnel.

Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to submit to Congress an assessment of current guidelines for managing ports of entry under DHS control.

 Directs: (1) CBP to report to Congress regarding deaths occurring along the U.S.-Mexico border, and (2) the Government Accountability Office (GAO) to review such report.

Directs: (1) GAO to examine the extent to which CBP has clarified use of force policies, and (2) the Secretary to require CBP to implement any recommendations contained in such examination.</summary>
</bill>
