<bill session="113" type="s" number="2327" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-05-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Keeping Public Lands Open Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to make continuing appropriations for certain programs that benefit sportsmen in the event of a lapse in appropriations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412602"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Birds"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/13/2014--Introduced.
Keeping Public Lands Open Act - Provides that if an appropriations measure for a covered account for a fiscal year is not enacted before the beginning of that fiscal year and a joint resolution making continuing appropriations for such account is not in effect, such sums as necessary shall be made available without further appropriation to continue any activity for which funds were provided from such account in the preceding fiscal year.

Defines "covered account" to mean specified appropriation accounts of: (1) the Department of the Interior for the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, including amounts for activities of the National Wildlife Refuge System, habitat conservation, the Migratory Bird Conservation Account, the North American Wetlands Conservation Fund, the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation, and land acquisition; (2) the Department of the Interior for the Bureau of Land Management (BLM), including amounts for the National Landscape Conservation System, land acquisition, and the activities of recreation management, resource protection, and maintenance; (3) the Department of the Interior for the National Park Service, including amounts for land acquisition and state assistance; and (3) the Department of Agriculture (USDA) for the Forest Service, including amounts for land acquisition, law enforcement operations, and the activities of recreation, heritage, and wilderness.</summary>
</bill>
