<bill session="113" type="h" number="5200" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Care Coordination for Older Americans Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Older Americans Act of 1965 to define care coordination, include care coordination as a fully restorative service, and detail the care coordination functions of the Assistant Secretary, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400647"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412385" joined="2014-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412276" joined="2014-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400663" joined="2014-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400347" joined="2014-07-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Training" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/24/2014--Introduced.
Care Coordination for Older Americans Act of 2014 - Amends the Older Americans Act of 1965 to make it a duty and function of the Administration on Aging (AOA) in the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to provide technical assistance to, and share best practices with, states, area agencies on aging, Aging and Disability Resource Centers, and service providers to carry out outreach and coordinate activities with health care entities in order to assure better care coordination for individuals with multiple chronic illnesses. Requires AOA also to coordinate activities with other federal agencies working to improve care coordination and developing new models and best practices.

Requires the designated state agency to promote the development and implementation of a state system to: (1) address the care coordination needs of older individuals with multiple chronic illnesses; and (2) work with acute care providers, area agencies on aging, service providers, and federal agencies to ensure that the system uses best practices.

Requires area and state plans to provide assurances that the area agencies on aging will facilitate the area-wide development and implementation of an area-wide system to address the care coordination needs of older individuals with multiple chronic illnesses.</summary>
</bill>
