<bill session="113" type="h" number="3420" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-10-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-10-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Truth in Obamacare Advertising Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require any communication using Federal funds to advertise or educate the public on certain provisions of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act and the Healthcare and Education Reconciliation Act of 2010 to state that such communication was produced at taxpayer expense, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400221"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412284" joined="2014-01-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-30">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-30">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-30">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/30/2013--Introduced.
Truth in Obamacare Advertising Act of 2013 - Requires each communication that is federally funded, directly or indirectly, to advertise or educate the public on provisions of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act or the Health Care and Education Reconciliation Act of 2010 or any programs, activities, requirements, or regulations established, funded, or authorized by such provisions to include statements that: (1) the Congressional Budget Office (CBO) estimates that Obamacare will cost taxpayers $1.76 trillion over a decade, and (2) such communication is printed and published, or produced and disseminated, at taxpayer expense.

Sets forth requirements for the format and readability of such communications that are conveyed in print, by audio and video means, or by e-mail.</summary>
</bill>
