<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H06719AC7EB964F85BA4BB1EE4365A58E" public-private="public">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HR 5862 IH: Improvements in Global MOMS Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-12-11</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 5862</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20141211">December 11, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="C001036">Mrs. Capps</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To provide assistance to improve maternal and newborn health in developing countries, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HFCA850FFB07F4356A2DB37BC1F2AEE61" style="OLC">
		<section id="H6D75FDFDF5E94603A068EF42F2808A75" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
          <quote>
          <short-title>
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Improvements in Global Maternal and Newborn Health Outcomes while Maximizing Successes Act" proposed="true">Improvements in Global Maternal and Newborn Health Outcomes while Maximizing Successes Act</cato:entity-ref>
            </short-title>
        </quote> or <quote>
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Improvements in Global MOMS Act" proposed="true">Improvements in Global MOMS Act</cato:entity-ref>
          </quote>.</cato:entity>
      </text>
		</section>
    <section id="H6D4FD01F3C9A4F5EA6D0B65BDFA09314">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Findings and purposes</header>
			<subsection id="HCD55C06B4F264397A364A01A031B8190">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Findings</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
				<paragraph id="HE055CA1DC59C42A6A17D60FBB710096F">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In 2000, the United States joined 188 other countries in supporting the 8 United Nations Millennium
			 Development Goals (MDGs), including MDG 4, which aims to reduce child
			 mortality by two-thirds and MDG 5, which aims to reduce the maternal
			 mortality ratio by three-quarters by 2015. In 2005, universal access to
			 reproductive health was added as a target for MDG 5.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HA5EDE60EF6DE4D7AAB636257C24DD8FE">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>Substantial progress in maternal health has been made. The total number of maternal deaths
			 decreased by over 50 percent from 529,000 maternal deaths in 2000 to
			 287,000 maternal deaths in 2010. Egypt, Honduras, Malaysia, Sri Lanka, and
			 parts of Bangladesh have all halved their maternal mortality ratios over
			 the past few decades.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HBE8A0B562EA94A648DD6235FADE078B0">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>While significant progress has been made in reducing maternal mortality, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="19UN" entity-type="federal-body">United Nations</cato:entity-ref> reports
			 that current maternal mortality levels are <quote>far removed from the 2015 target</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H74B2B75E107C4800AA690BA7CF31C029">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>Women in developing countries are nearly 100 times more likely to die of complications during
			 pregnancy or childbirth than in developed countries, with higher rates for
			 women living in rural areas and among poorer communities.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H7CECB67A9D9C4F9AAF5B0B166845DED2">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7200" entity-type="federal-body">United States Agency for International Development (USAID)</cato:entity-ref> estimates the global economic impact
			 of maternal and newborn mortality at $15 billion in lost productivity
			 every year.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HF4E739E04C894BECB815E21EF6AB4204">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <text>Annually, 287,000 women die from complications during pregnancy or childbirth, with 99 percent of
			 these deaths occurring in developing countries. Six countries—Afghanistan,
			 the Democratic Republic of Congo, Ethiopia, India, Nigeria, and
			 Pakistan—account for almost one-half of all maternal deaths worldwide.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HB2FE4896F4B0448A8343ABF099267EEF">
          <enum>(7)</enum>
          <text>It is estimated that up to 90 percent of these maternal deaths are preventable. With access to
			 medicines and skilled health care providers, most women across the world
			 can expect a successful delivery and a healthy newborn.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H1932ECDF575E4A09BBEE62BA7717DAB8">
          <enum>(8)</enum>
          <text>The leading cause of maternal deaths is hemorrhage. Other primary causes of maternal death include
			 sepsis, hypertensive disorder (pre-eclampsia/eclampsia), unsafe abortion,
			 and prolonged or obstructed labor.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H4C92103C3C6D496CB038AFFF00741DA3">
          <enum>(9)</enum>
          <text>An essential part of ensuring a woman survives pregnancy and childbirth includes access to maternal
			 health medicines and other supplies. Uterotonics prevent and treat
			 postpartum hemorrhage by causing contractions of the uterus during and
			 after childbirth, effectively controlling excessive bleeding. If
			 uterotonic medicines, such as oxytocin and misoprostol, were available to
			 all women giving birth over a 10-year period, approximately 41 million
			 postpartum hemorrhage cases could be prevented and 1.4 million women’s
			 lives saved.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HA7B67E4AC1E34D1EBEB600367FAA41A0">
          <enum>(10)</enum>
          <text>Pregnancy is the leading killer of adolescent girls ages 15 to 19 in the developing world. Nearly
			 70,000 adolescent girls die every year because their bodies are not ready
			 for childbirth. Compared to women in their twenties, adolescent girls aged
			 15 to 19 are twice as likely to die in childbirth, and girls under 15 are
			 five times as likely to die, and mortality and morbidity rates are also
			 higher among infants born to young mothers.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H97E8F788644F454D8D779C91DED37715">
          <enum>(11)</enum>
          <text>For every maternal death, approximately 20 women and girls experience serious or long-term negative
			 health consequences. Severe pregnancy-related injuries include fistula,
			 uterine prolapse, infections, diseases, and disabilities. Maternal
			 morbidities accrue an estimated global cost of $6.8 billion.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HF9B7FD9D959A40E9A1B60103766F3472">
          <enum>(12)</enum>
          <text>Healthy timing and spacing of pregnancy has a powerful impact on the chances of survival for women,
			 newborns, infants, and children. Access to voluntary family planning plays
			 an essential role in improving maternal health.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H3B33EDF131B44856B6415D51F5FBCEE1">
          <enum>(13)</enum>
          <text>Delaying a first pregnancy until at least 18 years old, waiting at least 24 months to become
			 pregnant after a live birth, and waiting at least 6 months after a
			 miscarriage or induced abortion, can reduce all maternal mortality by 30
			 percent and prevent 70,000 deaths per year of women who die from unsafe
			 abortion.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HD1CF38552EE149ABA833FD099922641A">
          <enum>(14)</enum>
          <text>Healthy timing and spacing of birth can also reduce newborn and child death by more than 50
			 percent. Children born less than two years after the previous birth are
			 approximately 2.5 times more likely to die before the age of five than
			 children born three to five years after the previous birth.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H290564584F8A4213B1FA36CE9898BE03">
          <enum>(15)</enum>
          <text>If all women who wanted to delay or avoid pregnancy had access to modern contraception, 26 million
			 abortions would be averted.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H4E394D6736F04E1EAF2B56F3666BA4A6">
          <enum>(16)</enum>
          <text>More than 220 million women in developing countries who would prefer to delay or avoid childbearing
			 lack access to safe and effective family planning methods. Less than
			 one-half of married women of reproductive age in South Asia and less than
			 25 percent of women in sub-Saharan Africa use modern contraceptives. In
			 2012, an estimated 80 million women in developing countries had an
			 unintended pregnancy.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H5E83FA4347B54E41AAF36C4BC3D25A32">
          <enum>(17)</enum>
          <text>It is estimated that if 120 million more women had access to family planning information, services
			 and supplies, without coercion or discrimination by 2020, 200,000 fewer
			 girls and women would die during pregnancy and childbirth, there would be
			 100 million fewer unintended pregnancies, there would be 50 million fewer
			 abortions, and 3 million fewer infants would die in their first year of
			 life.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HEA108E6AAAD641FDAB89885C0DFC5DD7">
          <enum>(18)</enum>
          <text>Violent acts against pregnant women can also lead to poor health outcomes for women and their
			 babies, including miscarriage, pre-term birth, low birthweight,
			 stillbirths, and maternal deaths. The risk for maternal mortality is 3
			 times as high for abused mothers. In emergency settings, gender-based
			 violence rates continue to increase.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H47B1A47484E74D349A5DD902A70EFF93">
          <enum>(19)</enum>
          <text>According to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="19UH" entity-type="federal-body">World Health Organization</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="19UH" entity-type="federal-body">WHO</cato:entity-ref>), women that have undergone female genital
			 mutilation/cutting are significantly more likely to experience serious
			 postpartum health problems than those who have not undergone female
			 genital mutilation, and children born to mothers who have undergone female
			 genital mutilation face higher death rates immediately after birth.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HA3837A2DE2024ADB9D8BE226C32ACBB0">
          <enum>(20)</enum>
          <text>Maternal health is inextricably tied to newborn health and survival. In some countries in the
			 developing world the risk of newborn death doubles following maternal
			 death. The conditions in utero, during labor, delivery, and shortly after
			 birth have a direct relationship on newborn outcomes.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HB619DCF5848C4A058ED02FC00CB42CBE">
          <enum>(21)</enum>
          <text>In 2012, 2.9 million newborns or 44 percent of total under-five mortality did not survive the first
			 month of life. One million of these deaths occurred during the first day
			 of life.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HF532798BB8554613A46AE2212400713D">
          <enum>(22)</enum>
          <text>The leading causes of newborn mortality include prematurity, intrapartum complications (including
			 birth asphyxia), and neonatal infections. Over two-thirds of these deaths
			 could be prevented through low-cost medicines, products, and interventions
			 that would not require intensive care.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H20E6F99FF5224560A4378D01BF5ADDE7">
          <enum>(23)</enum>
          <text>In addition to newborn mortality there are an additional 2.65 million stillbirths each year that
			 are not included in newborn or under-five mortality statistics.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H0F10292C3E15465CAD2D9175F2BB268B">
          <enum>(24)</enum>
          <text>Women in Africa are 24 times more likely to have a stillbirth than women in high-income countries.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HC66A3C896EBE4009BA340E0B87CB3CB1">
          <enum>(25)</enum>
          <text>In developing countries, nearly one-third of stillbirth babies were alive when labor began. If 99
			 percent of women in developing countries had comprehensive emergency
			 obstetric care, nearly 700,000 stillbirths could be prevented each year.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HD6E3DF085EBE4AF9A3C4894B623602C0">
          <enum>(26)</enum>
          <text>In many developing countries, lack of access to quality health care facilities, health services,
			 and trained providers results in deaths for mothers, newborns, and
			 children—the majority of births in Africa take place without a skilled
			 attendant present or the necessary medicines and medical supplies,
			 increasing the risk of death or disability for both mother and newborn.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HB7F00A5AE0A542208E591AF2C195B81C">
          <enum>(27)</enum>
          <text>If family planning and maternal and newborn services were provided simultaneously, the costs of
			 these services would decline by $1.5 billion and would result in a 70
			 percent decline in maternal deaths and a 44 percent decline in newborn
			 deaths.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H9A1B651A43154533A0A973E571F15F01">
          <enum>(28)</enum>
          <text>More than one-half of all children and pregnant women in developing countries suffer from anemia,
			 which is exacerbated by malaria, neglected tropical diseases, and
			 nutritional deficits, causing adverse pregnancy outcomes and even death.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H76577E891804450286DFC0C67CB39D0F">
          <enum>(29)</enum>
          <text>Maternal deaths worldwide could be reduced by 60,000 per year if women received appropriate HIV
			 diagnosis and treatment.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H55873672BBCE409B8DB35A285888D58F">
          <enum>(30)</enum>
          <text>With proper interventions, the transmission of HIV between women and their infants during pregnancy
			 and breastfeeding can be reduced to 5 percent in the developing world. The
			 <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="19UH" entity-type="federal-body">WHO</cato:entity-ref> recommends early diagnosis and immediate treatment for children
			 identified as HIV positive because, without treatment, half of these
			 children will die before the age of two.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H3965C0E6DA184A24880CF9B716A14134">
          <enum>(31)</enum>
          <text>Nine out of ten women in sub-Saharan Africa will lose a child during their lifetimes, and only 30
			 percent of women in sub-Saharan Africa have contact with a health worker
			 after giving birth.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HD31E9BADAE934A208984C83F5A18876C">
          <enum>(32)</enum>
          <text>According to the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Office of the Director of National Intelligence">Director of National Intelligence</cato:entity-ref>’s 2009 Annual Threat Assessment, widespread poor
			 maternal and child health and malnutrition has the potential to weaken
			 central governments and empower non-state actors, including terrorist and
			 paramilitary groups.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H35C508DF9E9541019A6B6319A9113804">
          <enum>(33)</enum>
          <text>The experiences of United States Government-supported and nongovernmental organization maternal and
			 child health programs in countries such as Nepal, Ethiopia, and Senegal
			 have demonstrated that community-based approaches, linked to primary and
			 referral care when possible, can deliver high-impact interventions to
			 prevent or treat many of the life-threatening conditions affecting mothers
			 and newborns.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HC3AA0CB26A1D4FECA7BEF2656B2E7DA1">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Purposes</header>
        <text>The purposes of this Act are—</text>
				<paragraph id="H2737AFD584E14A6F9A97A6AFA3252E76">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to authorize assistance to improve maternal and newborn health in developing countries; and</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HAFFDB9D5112A43009DDE5A964185A686">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>to develop a strategy to reduce mortality and morbidity and improve maternal and newborn health in
			 developing countries.</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="H9EE143B0317F4574AB70C70D381ED469">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Assistance to Reduce Mortality and Improve Maternal and Newborn Health in developing countries</header>
			<subsection id="HDE38951B39214DBB8F39FB3E13D5B0BB">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/pt:I/ch:1">Chapter 1 of part I of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2151">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/2151/etseq">22 U.S.C. 2151 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity> is amended—</text>
				<paragraph commented="no" id="HE4703314E0C949C9AAA2D5720974FEE3">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:102/ss:b/p:4/sp:B">section 102(b)(4)(B)</cato:entity-ref>, by striking <quote>reduction of infant mortality</quote> and inserting <quote>reduction of maternal and newborn mortality, morbidity, and stillbirths</quote>; and</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H1C1EEDD0A21B49F49FCDDC345B61F71C">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>by inserting after <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:104C">section 104C</cato:entity-ref> the following new section:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9AE5D1681A1144CEA17CBAFDA99A453A" style="OLC">
						<section id="H8B64D7D79D834F7F854809C5A9997C1A">
              <enum>104D.</enum>
              <header>Assistance to Reduce Mortality and Improve Maternal and Newborn Health</header>
							<subsection id="H7B590C204E9C4E08AFF2E79CD7F6A76E">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>Authorization</header>
                <text>Consistent with <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:104/ss:c">section 104(c)</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> is authorized to furnish assistance, on such terms
			 and conditions as the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> may determine, to reduce maternal and
			 newborn mortality and morbidity and improve maternal health and the health
			 of newborns in developing countries.</text>
							</subsection>
              <subsection id="H006BD654B2E0456A9B848AE9BADDEC9C">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Activities supported</header>
                <text>Assistance provided under subsection (a) shall, to the maximum extent practicable, include—</text>
								<paragraph id="H6958CD1D49284EF2B6DD3A6D7AA6AE0D">
                  <enum>(1)</enum>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">activities to expand access to and improve quality of maternal health services, including—</text>
									<subparagraph id="HFBB47790B5FD49FBA164A0F0FE1D83F1">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
                    <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">birth preparedness through the provision of quality pre-pregnancy and antenatal care with a skilled
			 provider (midwife, nurse, or doctor), which should consist of, at minimum—</text>
										<clause id="HD63FE6CB3ABE47E08D4108505F6B3723">
                      <enum>(i)</enum>
                      <text>iron and folic acid supplementation;</text>
										</clause>
                    <clause id="H8436F8BB401649DD854C0253D1D84BDF">
                      <enum>(ii)</enum>
                      <text>tetanus vaccine;</text>
										</clause>
                    <clause id="H0932025525354800B32341F7EE0C8001">
                      <enum>(iii)</enum>
                      <text>smoking cessation;</text>
										</clause>
                    <clause id="H1D636DC994234EDD910B7999226969E2">
                      <enum>(iv)</enum>
                      <text>prevention and management of sexually transmitted infections and HIV, including access to
			 Preventing Mother-to-Child Transmission;</text>
										</clause>
                    <clause id="H421B4FF9487F4D67AF9316D6D11E219D">
                      <enum>(v)</enum>
                      <text>screening, diagnosis, and treatment of existing conditions, such as syphilis, HIV/AIDS, malaria,
			 and tuberculosis, and ensuring that women are provided with, or referred
			 to, appropriate care and treatment and prophylaxis for those conditions,
			 including access to antiretrovirals (ARVs);</text>
										</clause>
                    <clause id="H1D44251F784749A0A1DAEA3692ECA9F3">
                      <enum>(vi)</enum>
                      <text>magnesium sulfate and low-dose aspirin to prevent pre-eclampsia and calcium supplementation to
			 prevent hypertension;</text>
										</clause>
                    <clause id="H6E901EAC42BE48849CB4F4D2ABB2DF01">
                      <enum>(vii)</enum>
                      <text>screening for complications, including blood pressure screenings;</text>
										</clause>
                    <clause id="HDA34FC56D8E8480F93859DACBAA7B62B">
                      <enum>(viii)</enum>
                      <text>magnesium sulfate for eclampsia; antihypertensive medication;</text>
										</clause>
                    <clause id="H243AB32AB75A4A7DA0081C05DEE21639">
                      <enum>(ix)</enum>
                      <text>corticosteroids to prevent respiratory distress syndrome;</text>
										</clause>
                    <clause id="H0526FB57398F46D9B74AE92A28632AB1">
                      <enum>(x)</enum>
                      <text>induction of labor at term to manage pre-labor rupture of membranes;</text>
										</clause>
                    <clause id="HBB57AF67D70A48928F1CD815364938A4">
                      <enum>(xi)</enum>
                      <text>nutrition treatment of malnourished pregnant women; and</text>
										</clause>
                    <clause id="H70782FC4F5E14EAA8F3C399FB9D1EBCA">
                      <enum>(xii)</enum>
                      <text>antibiotics for pre-term labor;</text>
										</clause>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="HDA706CB0BD0C43459722CE5077FDE43C">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
                    <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expanding access to skilled childbirth and postnatal care, particularly in areas with low
			 utilization of skilled delivery, including—</text>
										<clause id="HC2D0EA401A50427F8FC4380C47294262">
                      <enum>(i)</enum>
                      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the presence of a skilled health professional (nurse, midwife, or doctor) who has been educated and
			 trained to proficiency in the skills needed to manage normal or
			 uncomplicated pregnancies or referral of complications in women and
			 newborns,</text>
										</clause>
                    <clause id="H5475077AA146499AACDB24B16F9C0A17">
                      <enum>(ii)</enum>
                      <text>clean delivery;</text>
										</clause>
                    <clause id="HD20740E3F3BA4C57A40B162AADDC44E5">
                      <enum>(iii)</enum>
                      <text>uterotonics and active management of third stage of labor to prevent postpartum hemorrhage;</text>
										</clause>
                    <clause id="H810A2EFC36E64544BC6EC80407B4F630">
                      <enum>(iv)</enum>
                      <text>social support during childbirth;</text>
										</clause>
                    <clause id="HB897F5CF53CD4DFF9B638C4AD573BF0B">
                      <enum>(v)</enum>
                      <text>screening for HIV, linkages to HIV care and treatment services, and follow up tracking;</text>
										</clause>
                    <clause id="H4D4C40E1E67644CF9E3440C03438E2B5">
                      <enum>(vi)</enum>
                      <text>induction of labor for prolonged pregnancy;</text>
										</clause>
                    <clause id="H74B42F28BFC04C48AF20D60FE1BBA2A5">
                      <enum>(vii)</enum>
                      <text>nutrition counseling;</text>
										</clause>
                    <clause id="HA74FA39F62DB407D8CE4C446BDB77647">
                      <enum>(viii)</enum>
                      <text>management of postpartum hemorrhage;</text>
										</clause>
                    <clause id="HCDD6531C51F5465489315EDB6B03A84D">
                      <enum>(ix)</enum>
                      <text>caesarean section for maternal/fetal indication with prophylactic antibiotics;</text>
										</clause>
                    <clause id="H580E92F034194048B086EB16B90F9A4E">
                      <enum>(x)</enum>
                      <text>treating maternal anemia; and</text>
										</clause>
                    <clause id="H7961B657DF704F54B0C7198BF7BE80DC">
                      <enum>(xi)</enum>
                      <text>postpartum family planning methods;</text>
										</clause>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H697BC1A6F1E342EF834B813ECAB0228D">
                    <enum>(C)</enum>
                    <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">comprehensive voluntary family planning services, integrated into antenatal and postnatal care, to
			 support women and men in making informed decisions and having timely,
			 intended, well-spaced pregnancies, and to help women with pre-existing
			 conditions avoid high-risk, unintended pregnancies, including—</text>
										<clause id="H3DF80D214CFB4D619F66F33A3BF5E72D">
                      <enum>(i)</enum>
                      <text>provision of family planning/birth spacing counseling and services; and</text>
										</clause>
                    <clause id="H5397DDCAED6543928764DFDF176F99D3">
                      <enum>(ii)</enum>
                      <text>emergency treatment of complications of unsafe abortions and linkages to other reproductive health
			 services;</text>
										</clause>
                  </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H3B73E5809E374BF7A12329AB883F21C5">
                  <enum>(2)</enum>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">activities to expand access to and improve quality of services that reduce newborn and infant
			 mortality, including—</text>
									<subparagraph id="H870BBB20F13E4E1993B2C90B242B137C">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
                    <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">immediate thermal care;</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H83C756D32D194AB6A281881436B90244">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
                    <text>initiation of early, exclusive, and continued breastfeeding;</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H95408206C14A4F7B8E9D6520CBCEC088">
                    <enum>(C)</enum>
                    <text>hygienic cord and skin care;</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph commented="no" id="HBB073A7CADCC41049546C5C087CAECB5">
                    <enum>(D)</enum>
                    <text>kangaroo mother care;</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="HAA8DEAC303614E328A5871238BABC850">
                    <enum>(E)</enum>
                    <text>extra support for feeding small and preterm infants;</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="HA236DBE893F44414A4B5A411373D44EB">
                    <enum>(F)</enum>
                    <text>antibiotic therapy for newborns at risk of bacterial infection;</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="HC3ADB25B9E6344B6A8FEF0C3598F858B">
                    <enum>(G)</enum>
                    <text>use of surfactant in pre-term infants;</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H6617B6558E3C4B409D727E6C4E493F6B">
                    <enum>(H)</enum>
                    <text>initiate prophylactic antiretroviral therapy for infants exposed to HIV;</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H6029009742144706860237DA268B713C">
                    <enum>(I)</enum>
                    <text>neonatal resuscitation with a bag and mask for infants suffering from birth asphyxia;</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H9114644A96894D0785D8BBCE7F299B7C">
                    <enum>(J)</enum>
                    <text>continuous positive airway pressure to manage respiratory distress syndrome;</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="HA5022F79E1784CABA866EDFEABDA7CCF">
                    <enum>(K)</enum>
                    <text>case management of neonatal sepsis, neonatal meningitis, and pneumonia;</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H6E1AFD7F46F8475ABF0C528F6523CAEF">
                    <enum>(L)</enum>
                    <text>case management of meningitis, malaria, diarrhea, pneumonia, and severe acute malnutrition; and</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H46E1F007D6B542AFB72A014B751C2771">
                    <enum>(M)</enum>
                    <text>comprehensive care of HIV, including ARVs, cotrimoxazole, nutrition support, and psychosocial
			 support;</text>
									</subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H606EA8E12BEE48D8BB5F7AB596A6D6C2">
                  <enum>(3)</enum>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">activities to support communities and health care providers in identifying and removing barriers to
			 maternal health care services, including—</text>
									<subparagraph id="H2AD2A061A11949A0818383D20E199375">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
                    <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">financial and sociocultural barriers;</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H2C8930317F6B417DA9AA587B5ADE2255">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
                    <text>child marriage;</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H400D53543AB94298875892C680D8F760">
                    <enum>(C)</enum>
                    <text>transportation;</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H21D34D025DFF4CAF9D67A022296D26FD">
                    <enum>(D)</enum>
                    <text>gender discrimination and gender-based violence;</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H6993904F1BAF4AE1BA1B7EACC157B6A7">
                    <enum>(E)</enum>
                    <text>stigma based on pre-existing health concerns; and</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="HEFCCD4C7BD184AB8BB33096A537ADD5C">
                    <enum>(F)</enum>
                    <text>female genital mutilation/cutting;</text>
									</subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H25402669FBA34EE6855A988F975B7933">
                  <enum>(4)</enum>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">activities that focus on empowering women and girls and engaging men and boys at the individual,
			 household, and community levels to improve the health outcomes of women,
			 newborns, and children, including education and awareness programs about
			 gender-based violence, the health risks of female genital mutilation, and
			 shared responsibility for, and benefits of, family planning;</text>
								</paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HA5C2BFBA86844187BF72859D4A1D693F">
                  <enum>(5)</enum>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">activities to improve the supply of critical maternal and newborn health commodities, including
			 lifesaving medicines and supplies, such as activities designed to
			 strengthen regulatory systems to ensure the quality of commodities in
			 circulation and those related to strengthening supply chain systems so
			 that these commodities reach the women and children who need them;</text>
								</paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HECA1F8FC812B4B76B4E24D468FE73846">
                  <enum>(6)</enum>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">activities supporting country-led efforts to improve capacity for health governance, health
			 finance, and the health workforce, including in the private sector, and
			 support for training clinicians, nurses, technicians, sanitation and
			 public health workers, community-based health workers, midwives, birth
			 attendants, peer educators, volunteers, and private sector enterprises to
			 provide integrated health and nutrition services and referrals that meet
			 the needs of patients across a continuum of care;</text>
								</paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HD8FACDBD6C7E409F85EFD9FABEB2192F">
                  <enum>(7)</enum>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">activities that support country-led plans to reduce maternal and newborn mortality and morbidity
			 and stillbirths, including—</text>
									<subparagraph id="H37D68CFC46B34046A57EB8D1B880AFD8">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
                    <text>management of host country institutions’ information systems and the development and use of tools
			 and models to collect, analyze, and disseminate information related to
			 maternal and newborn health; and</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H3DEDDB8E897F46B79D2155EED16B29EF">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
                    <text>activities to develop and conduct needs assessments, baseline studies, targeted evaluations, or
			 other information-gathering efforts for the design, monitoring, and
			 evaluation of maternal and newborn health efforts, including—</text>
										<clause id="HACD41146F66D49249B962F59D21069AA">
                      <enum>(i)</enum>
                      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the study of the availability and effects of critical medicines and devices, particularly those of
			 importance in developing countries, on pregnant women and newborns;</text>
										</clause>
                    <clause id="H6CCA76F532754FCDB617A110B2F58F59">
                      <enum>(ii)</enum>
                      <text>the collection, evaluation, and use of data on the medical and socioeconomic factors that led to a
			 maternal or newborn death or stillbirths at the community and health
			 facility levels; and</text>
										</clause>
                    <clause id="HFF7C88937BE9480AAAA421966CFBB584">
                      <enum>(iii)</enum>
                      <text>the improvement of vital registries to capture live births, neonatal deaths, and the number of
			 stillbirths; and</text>
										</clause>
                  </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H971CE69BC3904B01AB90B8F200742905">
                  <enum>(8)</enum>
                  <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">activities to integrate and coordinate assistance provided under this section with existing health
			 programs for the prevention of the transmission of HIV from mother to
			 child and other HIV/AIDS prevention, care, treatment, and counseling
			 activities, including better integration with programs addressing—</text>
									<subparagraph id="H2A08FC4E8FE84BCAA32818E7384DDA9A">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
                    <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">malaria;</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H03FC84D5BA834A75977CA07E395F876D">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
                    <text>tuberculosis;</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="HFAD1EF44E585418E8C0C128D0F732AC0">
                    <enum>(C)</enum>
                    <text>family planning and reproductive health;</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H6DAE27B0FD3A408DB809F1A843955D15">
                    <enum>(D)</enum>
                    <text>counseling for survivors of sexual- and gender-based violence;</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="HAA926D9E82574C358C6606405C0BDEC1">
                    <enum>(E)</enum>
                    <text>neglected tropical diseases;</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="HED65FC2465194F34B8032E82366712FE">
                    <enum>(F)</enum>
                    <text>nutrition; and</text>
									</subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H2CBC0E5F412749708442EBC144A04DAC">
                    <enum>(G)</enum>
                    <text>child survival.</text>
									</subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
              </subsection>
              <subsection id="H1A47D798594C4D4F9C82626A8C743C81">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Guidelines</header>
                <text>To the maximum extent practicable, programs, projects, and activities carried out using assistance
			 provided under this section shall be—</text>
								<paragraph id="H710C10AFFD1247FBB540E6D19D1FFE24">
                  <enum>(1)</enum>
                  <text>carried out through private and voluntary organizations, including community and faith-based
			 organizations, local organizations, and relevant international and
			 multilateral organizations that demonstrate effectiveness, including the
			 United Nations Population Fund, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="19UN" entity-type="federal-body">United Nations</cato:entity-ref> Children’s Fund, and
			 the Global Alliance for Vaccines and Immunizations, and that demonstrate
			 commitment to improving the health and rights of mothers and newborns and
			 reducing the number of stillbirths;</text>
								</paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H122C0A3A9C3D44919C21B51DCBA29D54">
                  <enum>(2)</enum>
                  <text>carried out in the context of country-driven plans in whose development the United States
			 Government participates along with other donors and multilateral
			 organizations, nongovernmental organizations, and civil society;</text>
								</paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HD1021911446348C2A03E1E41C978B555">
                  <enum>(3)</enum>
                  <text>carried out with input by beneficiaries and other directly affected populations, especially women
			 and marginalized communities; and</text>
								</paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H1F64612CF0F2486E9FCA4E5E2B9D66A6">
                  <enum>(4)</enum>
                  <text>designed to build the capacity of host country governments and civil society organizations.</text>
								</paragraph>
              </subsection>
              <subsection id="H6DAF35D4F1684948B7464A5A9BAA0A66">
                <enum>(d)</enum>
                <header>Annual report</header>
                <text>Not later than January 31, 2016, and annually thereafter for 4 years, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall transmit
			 to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> a report on the implementation of this section for the prior
			 fiscal year.</text>
							</subsection>
              <subsection id="H463AEDFE95C446378E4AE75111CA3CA5">
                <enum>(e)</enum>
                <header>Definitions</header>
                <text>In this section:</text>
								<paragraph id="HF5F29AE41C6C4B7FA30C002502C691C0">
                  <enum>(1)</enum>
                  <header>AIDS</header>
                  <text>The term <term>AIDS</term> has the meaning given the term in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:104A/ss:g/p:1">section 104A(g)(1)</cato:entity-ref> of this Act.</text>
								</paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HD528B0101EEE467596154723B561C7EF">
                  <enum>(2)</enum>
                  <header>HIV</header>
                  <text>The term <term>HIV</term> has the meaning given the term in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:104A/ss:g/p:2">section 104A(g)(2)</cato:entity-ref> of this Act.</text>
								</paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H909EB62A5F464B62A18C0C2A3FAA10C0">
                  <enum>(3)</enum>
                  <header>HIV/AIDS</header>
                  <text>The term <term>HIV/AIDS</term> has the meaning given the term in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:104A/ss:g/p:3">section 104A(g)(3) of this Act</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
								</paragraph>
              </subsection>
            </section>
            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="H848B58923677403885B3C5D9A51F82F8">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Development of strategy to reduce mortality and morbidity and improve maternal and newborn health
			 in developing countries</header>
			<subsection id="H52767C94C5224B4F9B2EF274D1C33443">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Development of strategy</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall develop and implement a comprehensive strategy to reduce mortality and
			 morbidity and improve the health of mothers and newborns in developing
			 countries that integrates all current United States Government efforts on
			 improving maternal and newborn health, including strategies with respect
			 to HIV/AIDS, gender, child survival.</text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="H09C024E42B0F4B6EA109568382FABBDB">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Components</header>
        <text>The comprehensive United States Government strategy developed pursuant to subsection (a) shall
			 include the following:</text>
				<paragraph id="HCDA85A52471A42658E1E1F8EAE140268">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An identification of not less than 24 countries, including fragile states and countries affected by
			 conflict, with priority needs for the 5-year period beginning on the date
			 of the enactment of this Act based on—</text>
					<subparagraph id="H05B85734635F4353A33DBE5B1C3ED372">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>the number and rate of neonatal deaths;</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HAB507123597B4A4097DAA513599E7D8D">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number and rate of near-miss morbidity for women and newborns;</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HDB61F85FF58B49D39091E0A4ADC3E34E">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>the number and rate of maternal deaths;</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HD92313FC51164D2EA0165B49F761B0C0">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number and rate of caesarean sections;</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H45E32D1F1DE1403AA42D3F05833DD5C2">
            <enum>(E)</enum>
            <text>the number and rate of malnourished women of reproductive age; and</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H6441AC81F3B44F119027275F513014F7">
            <enum>(F)</enum>
            <text>the number of individuals with an unmet need for family planning.</text>
					</subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H37C660F249674A0FAA7CE76E30944A3F">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>For each country identified in paragraph (1)—</text>
					<subparagraph id="H09A62B40BF8A4EA89C5129DE00BE937B">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>an assessment of the most common causes of maternal and newborn mortality and morbidity;</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H01DBE61E9F614A36BB4FE1924B6EE8EF">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>a description of the programmatic areas and interventions providing maximum health benefits to
			 populations at risk and maximum reduction in mortality and morbidity;</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HD3AC2461557145C8B7E4112FE2CFC67C">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>an assessment of the investments needed in identified programs and interventions to achieve the
			 greatest results;</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H0FA97C85468E4E87B0CABE5125D47AB3">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <text>a description of how United States assistance complements and leverages efforts by other donors and
			 builds capacity and self-sufficiency among recipient countries; and</text>
					</subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H3E61CCEAF05D4EF1A61BB525B2283CD6">
            <enum>(E)</enum>
            <text>a description of goals and objectives for improving maternal and newborn health, including, to the
			 extent feasible, objective and quantifiable indicators.</text>
					</subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HF7FBFAE73FD342849FCDDCD8B8D783CB">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>Enhanced coordination among relevant departments and agencies of the United States Government
			 engaged in activities to improve the health and well-being of mothers and
			 newborns in developing countries.</text>
				</paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H1D259D933D1C45F883730FB514EC29D7">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>A description of the measured or estimated impact on maternal and newborn morbidity and mortality
			 of each project or program receiving assistance under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:104D" proposed="true">section 104D of the
			 Foreign Assistance Act of 1961</cato:entity-ref> (as added by <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Improvements in Global Maternal and Newborn Health Outcomes while Maximizing Successes Act/s:3" proposed="true">section 3 of this Act</cato:entity-ref>).</text>
				</paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HC25894D6A7CF432FA61F83604A71908C">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Report</header>
        <text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall transmit
			 to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> a report that contains the strategy described in this section.</text>
			</subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="H6B245F06DEB3486D947E4307A8659291">
      <enum>5.</enum>
      <header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
			<subsection id="H5E1AAB4A5FFA4C4DB7A92D19DEE07480">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">There are authorized to be appropriated <cato:property name="purpose">to carry out <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Improvements in Global Maternal and Newborn Health Outcomes while Maximizing Successes Act" proposed="true">this Act</cato:entity-ref>
            </cato:property>, and the amendments made by this Act,
			 <cato:funds-and-year amount="indefinite" year="2016, 2017, 2018, 2019, 2020">such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2016 through 2020</cato:funds-and-year>.</cato:entity>
        </text>
			</subsection>
      <subsection id="HBBC89780CA1642058B05BBB219ADA6B5">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Availability of funds</header>
        <text>Amounts appropriated pursuant to the authorization of appropriations under subsection (a) are
			 authorized to remain available until expended.</text>
			</subsection>
    </section>
  </legis-body>
</bill>