<bill session="113" type="h" number="3475" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-11-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-11-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-11-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cruise Vessel Consumer Confidence Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 46, United States Code, to provide protections for cruise vessel passengers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412382"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400663" joined="2013-11-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-11-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW07" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Competition and antitrust"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Digestive and metabolic diseases"/>
    <term name="Federal Maritime Commission"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/13/2013--Introduced.
Cruise Vessel Consumer Confidence Act of 2013 - Amends federal shipping law to authorize the Federal Maritime Commission (FMC) to investigate, on its own initiative or upon receiving a complaint, whether the sale of a ticket to a cruise vessel passenger by a cruise vessel owner is: (1) an unfair or deceptive practice, or (2) an unfair method of competition.

Requires the FMC, in cases of an affirmative determination, to order the owner to cease such sales. Authorizes the FMC to impose a civil penalty of up to $25,000 for owners who violate such orders.

Makes it an unfair or deceptive practice for an owner that fails to make certain written disclosures before offering to sell a ticket to a passenger.

Makes it an unfair or deceptive practice for an owner offering to sell a ticket to a passenger via the Internet (electronic ticket) to require that the ticket purchaser provide a printed version of that ticket if the purchaser is able to provide appropriate identification at the time of travel.

Directs the FMC to establish a process to ensure that a passenger with a ticket for a vessel whose initial departure or final disembarkment is delayed for more than 24 hours is reimbursed by the owner in an amount that is equal to: (1) the lesser of half the ticket price or $500, if the delay is between 24 and 48 hours; or (2) the full price of the ticket, if the delay is 48 hours or more.

Requires a cruise vessel owner to: (1) submit a customer service plan to the FMC, (2) incorporate it into the ticket contract of that owner, and (3) make both of them easily available on the owner's website.

Directs the FMC to establish a process for passengers to report complaints to the FMC.

Authorizes the FMC to establish, adjust, and collect fees in ticket prices to fund implementation of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
