<bill session="113" type="h" number="5148" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-30">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Access to Affordable Mortgages Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Truth in Lending Act to exempt certain higher-risk mortgages from property appraisal requirements and to exempt individuals from penalties for failure to report certain appraisers, and to amend the Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery, and Enforcement Act of 1989 to exempt certain higher-risk mortgages from property appraisal requirements, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412292"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-30">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-07-30" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 31 - 23.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, Markup"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC)"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Real estate business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/17/2014--Introduced.
Access to Affordable Mortgages Act of 2014 - Amends the Truth in Lending Act to exempt from property appraisal requirements certain higher-risk mortgage loans of $250,000 or less if such a loan appears on the balance sheet of the creditor of the loan for at least three years.

Exempts certain individuals required to make such reports from penalties for failure to report any appraisers reasonably suspected of failing to comply with the Uniform Standards of Professional Appraisal Practice, of violating applicable laws, or of otherwise engaging in unethical or unprofessional conduct.

Amends the Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery, and Enforcement Act of 1989 to exempt such higher-risk mortgage loans from property appraisal or evaluation standard requirements.</summary>
</bill>
