<bill session="113" type="h" number="3730" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-12-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-12-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-12-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Public Infrastructure Modernization Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of the Army to establish a process to expedite the consideration of applications submitted by States and municipalities for permits in connection with public safety projects, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412250"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-12-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1863-1864"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-12">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-12">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Army Corps of Engineers"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Military civil functions"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/12/2013--Introduced.
Public Infrastructure Modernization Act of 2013 - Requires the Secretary of the Army to approve or disapprove a covered permit application for a public safety project within two years after the application is submitted. Requires an application upon which the Secretary fails to act within such time to be considered under an expedited process, unless the governor of the state in which the project is to be located issues a declaration of emergency with respect to the project. Defines "covered permit application" as an application for a permit to discharge dredge or fill material submitted by a state or municipality under the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act).

Directs the Secretary to establish such an expedited process, under which the Secretary shall: (1) prepare an environmental assessment or an environmental impact statement, (2) weigh the public safety aspects of the project as greater than the environmental costs, and (3) complete consultation with other agencies within six months. Provides that the Secretary, in issuing a permit under the expedited process: (1) may not require mitigation costs in an amount that exceeds 20% of the project's total cost, and (2) may relocate from the project any of the members of a threatened or endangered species of plant or animal that the relevant federal agencies determine would be taken in the course of the project.

 Authorizes the state or municipality that submitted a covered permit application for a project, if a governor issues a declaration of emergency with respect to the project, to request that: (1) the application be considered under the expedited process; or (2) the Council on Environmental Quality approve the project or create an alternative, which must be done within 90 days or the application shall be deemed approved and the environmental requirements shall be deemed satisfied.</summary>
</bill>
