<bill session="113" type="h" number="5499" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Consumer Review Freedom Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit contracts that prohibit consumers from making certain public comments on businesses.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412514"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412517" joined="2014-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2014-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="2014-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400371" joined="2014-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412520" joined="2014-11-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF17" subcommittee="Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Competition and antitrust"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Contracts and agency"/>
    <term name="First Amendment rights"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/16/2014--Introduced.
Consumer Review Freedom Act of 2014 - Declares a provision of a form contract to be void from the inception if it: (1) prohibits or restricts a person who is a party to the contract from engaging in written, verbal, or pictorial reviews, or other similar performance assessments or analyses of, the products, services, or conduct of a business that is a party to the contract; (2) imposes penalties or fees against such a person for engaging in such communications; or (3) assigns or provides an exclusive license, or requires such a person to assign or provide an exclusive license, to any of the person's intellectual property rights in such communications. (Thus, bars certain contract provisions that prohibit consumers from commenting publicly about businesses.)

Sets forth exceptions under which a provision shall not be considered void under this Act if the provision prohibits disclosure of certain: (1) trade secrets or commercial or financial information, (2) personnel and medical files, or (3) law enforcement records.

Provides for this Act to be inapplicable to contracts establishing an employer-employee or independent contractor relationship.

Prohibits businesses from offering or entering into form contracts containing a provision that is considered void under this Act. Treats violations by businesses as unfair or deceptive acts or practices under the Federal Trade Commission Act. Sets forth authority for the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) and state attorneys general to enforce such violations.</summary>
</bill>
