<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HC4B6054574C1450798A38B695D3B55C5" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HR 3170 IH: Health Care Regulator Accountability Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2013-09-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress>113th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>H. R. 3170</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20130923">September 23, 2013</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000599">Mr. Posey</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000583">Mr. Rooney</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001144">Mr. Miller of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">House Administration</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HAP00">Appropriations</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide that the only health plans that the Federal Government may make available to Federal employees responsible for the administration of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act are those created under such Act or offered through a health insurance exchange, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB91E1C546FDB40D2A4E2C5F3C42394BB" style="OLC"><section id="H9C5B3F03D2BB48FF8514EF2062207ADE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Health Care Regulator Accountability Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H2799B77E53C04E62BF64D7FF5FF58B6D" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Health plans created under PPACA or offered through Exchanges to be only health plans Federal Government may make available to Federal employees responsible for administration of PPACA</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1312(d)(3)(D) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18032">42 U.S.C. 18032(d)(3)(D)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HE6738FBF5D424AA6A33D7C334E1A2F79"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the subparagraph heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subparagraph" style="OLC">Members of Congress</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subparagraph" style="OLC">Members of Congress and certain Federal employees</header-in-text></quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8A5122419C9348A78403F034DF68929F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in clause (i), in the matter preceding subclause (I)—</text><subparagraph id="H5C7663B770634684B9F697CDAD6A73F1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>after the effective date of this subtitle,</quote> and inserting <quote>after December 31, 2013,</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF2245A7B185D46C8B743388726D5953D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Members of Congress and congressional staff</quote> and inserting <quote>Members of Congress, congressional staff, and Federal employees responsible for the administration of this Act</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF3A8DB33F5274441A7D3547A5E9EF870"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>a Member of Congress or congressional staff</quote> and inserting <quote>a Member of Congress, congressional staff, or Federal employee responsible for the administration of this Act</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H55B55D42B75E4F10B6DE8E2A9EE6B6F4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4A38CDADEF99409899E9F7F248FB8C28" style="OLC"><subclause id="HAEEC7DE568074ADE85A3A4248FE8830E"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Federal employee responsible for the administration of this Act</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Federal employee responsible for the administration of this Act</term>, as used with respect to a year, means a Federal employee—</text><item id="HF4628D1AE62946CC99843EEFEA7B6C6E"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>who holds a position in the Department of Health and Human Services, the Internal Revenue Service, or any other Executive agency (as defined by <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/105">section 105</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code) during such year; and</text></item><item id="H72F9A37319BA465A9123FC3F9DA74B29"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the duties and responsibilities of whose position (as described in item (aa)) during such year—</text><subitem id="HCCB432816F91442F9F611B4AB73C970B"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>involves the promulgation of rules or regulations to carry out this Act (or amendments made by this Act);</text></subitem><subitem id="H9A66A88FAABF4C768D907C391FB87D26"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>involves the enforcement of this Act (or amendments made by this Act); or</text></subitem><subitem id="H2CF9976A748E456DB2288D748888ECFA"><enum>(CC)</enum><text>otherwise involves the administration of this Act (or amendments made by this Act),</text></subitem><continuation-text continuation-text-level="item">as determined under regulations promulgated by the head of the employing agency.</continuation-text></item></subclause><subclause id="H1992E55C9F784EF9866430B46491F7C5"><enum>(IV)</enum><header>Federal employee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Federal employee</term> means an <term>employee</term>, as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/2105">section 2105</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, and includes an individual to whom subsection (c) or (f) of such section 2105 pertains (whether or not such individual otherwise satisfies such section).</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="HE71A74BFC596427192888C5B536F0B31"><enum>3.</enum><header>Enforcement</header><subsection id="H4D2D0D5283B747EE8B69326667BB8CD0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Director of the Internal Revenue Service, and the head of any other agency involved in promulgating rules or regulations to carry out or to enforce the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act or any amendments made by such Act (as described in the amendment made by section 2(3)) may not, in any fiscal year, obligate or expend more than 90 percent of the funds made available for the salaries and expenses of the office of the Secretary, Director, or head (as the case may be) for such fiscal year unless such regulations are promulgated and take effect before the close of such fiscal year.</text></subsection><subsection id="H86650C905C5147628F4385A6F4974E97"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rescission</header><text>Any amounts which (by virtue of subsection (a)) remain precluded from obligation or expenditure on the last day of any fiscal year shall be rescinded on the close of such last day.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDEE9ADF846C54C07B5283997B9374577"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be considered to affect any funds or other amounts to the extent that such amounts would (disregarding this section) otherwise be available for purposes apart from salaries or other administrative expenses of the office involved.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


