<bill session="113" type="s" number="1889" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-12-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-12-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-12-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PLANT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Lands Against Narcotics Trafficking Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the United States Sentencing Commission with respect to penalties for the unlawful production of a controlled substance on Federal property or intentional trespass on the property of another that causes environmental damage.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300043"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="2013-12-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-12-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9107"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9107-9108" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="15"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2270"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="744"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Crimes against property"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="U.S. Sentencing Commission"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/20/2013--Introduced.
Protecting Lands Against Narcotics Trafficking Act of 2013 or the PLANT Act - Amends the Controlled Substances Act to: (1) impose an additional term of up to ten years' imprisonment for cultivating or manufacturing controlled substances on federal property; (2) prohibit a person, while cultivating or manufacturing a controlled substance on federal property, from clear cutting timber or diverting, obstructing, or draining an aquifer, spring, stream, river or body of water; and (3) apply the prohibition against assembling, maintaining, or placing a booby trap on federal property where a controlled substance is being manufactured to federal property where a controlled substance is being cultivated. Directs the U.S. Sentencing Commission to amend and review the Federal Sentencing Guidelines to provide for a penalty enhancement of not less than one offense level for manufacturing, distributing, or dispensing, or possessing with intent to manufacture, distribute, or dispense a controlled substance or a counterfeit substance while on federal property or intentionally trespassing on the property of another if such offense: (1) includes the use of a poison, chemical, or other hazardous substance to cultivate or manufacture controlled substances; (2) creates a hazard to humans, wildlife, or domestic animals; (3) degrades or harms the environment or natural resources; (4) pollutes an aquifer, spring, stream, river, or body of water; (5) involves the diversion, redirection, obstruction, or draining of an aquifer, spring, stream, river, or body of water or the clear cut of timber while cultivating or manufacturing a controlled substance; or (6) involves the possession of a firearm while cultivating or manufacturing controlled substances.</summary>
</bill>
