<bill session="113" type="s" number="1437" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-08-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-08-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Hermiston Agricultural Research and Extension Center Land Conveyance Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the release of the reversionary interest held by the United States in certain land conveyed in 1954 by the United States, acting through the Director of the Bureau of Land Management, to the State of Oregon for the establishment of the Hermiston Agricultural Research and Extension Center of Oregon State University in Hermiston, Oregon.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300100"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2013-08-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6219-6220"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6220" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-30">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on Public Lands, Forests, and Mining. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 113-433.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG03" subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3366"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Agricultural research"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/1/2013--Introduced.
Hermiston Agricultural Research and Extension Center Land Conveyance Act - Releases by the United States, without consideration: (1) the reversionary interest retained by the United States to identified land in Hermiston, Oregon, under a specified patent granted by the Director of the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) to the state of Oregon for the establishment of the Hermiston Agricultural Research and Extension Center of Oregon State University; and (2) the reservation of mineral rights by the United States to such land under such patent.

Subjects the release of such reversionary interest to the condition that the state agrees to use any consideration it receives from the sale, lease, or other conveyance of the research center land after enactment of this Act for the agricultural experimental and research work of Oregon State University.</summary>
</bill>
