<bill session="113" type="s" number="2442" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-30">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Northern Cheyenne Lands Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Northern Cheyenne Lands Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of the Interior to take certain land and mineral rights on the reservation of the Northern Cheyenne Tribe of Montana and other culturally important land into trust for the benefit of the Northern Cheyenne Tribe, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412602"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2014-06-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-09">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 113-419.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-07-30" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-08-26">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Reported by Senator Tester under authority of the order of the Senate of 08/05/2014 with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-08-26" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="542">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 542.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-12-12">
      <text>By Senator Tester from Committee on Indian Affairs filed written report. Report No. 113-317.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4350"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2256"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Energy revenues and royalties"/>
    <term name="Farmland"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/26/2014--Reported to Senate amended.
Northern Cheyenne Lands Act - (Sec. 4) Directs the Secretary of the Interior to take approximately 932 acres of land in Montana into trust for the Northern Cheyenne Tribe.

(Sec. 5) Requires Great Northern Properties to convey to the Tribe its coal and iron ore mineral interests underlying the land on the Northern Cheyenne Reservation in exchange for U.S. coal mineral interests underlying the land referred to as Bull Mountains and East Fork. Sets forth conditions on the conveyance to Great Northern Properties.

Directs the Secretary to ensure that the deed for those federal coal mineral interests includes a covenant that precludes surface mining of the coal unless certain conditions are met.

Prohibits Montana from taxing the mineral interests this Act conveys to the Tribe.

Sets forth conditions regarding waiver of claims by the Tribe and Great Northern Properties.

(Sec. 6) Requires the Northern Cheyenne Trust Fund to be transferred to the Tribe in exchange for the Tribe waiving all of its claims arising from U.S. management of the Fund.

(Sec. 7) Directs the Secretary to prepare an inventory of fractionated land interests held by the United States in trust for the benefit of the Tribe or individual Indians on the Tribe's Reservation.</summary>
</bill>
