<bill session="113" type="s" number="994" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-09">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-05-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Digital Accountability and Transparency Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">DATA Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Digital Accountability and Transparency Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">DATA Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Digital Accountability and Transparency Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">DATA Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Digital Accountability and Transparency Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">DATA Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Digital Accountability and Transparency Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to expand the Federal Funding Accountability and Transparency Act of 2006 to increase accountability and transparency in Federal spending, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412321"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412493" joined="2013-11-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300019" joined="2013-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2013-11-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412390" joined="2013-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2013-11-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412496" joined="2013-11-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="2013-11-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2014-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400325" joined="2013-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2013-11-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-11-06" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-03-27">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Carper with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 113-139.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-03-27" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="337">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 337.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-04-10">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2359-2362" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-10">
      <text>The committee substitute was withdrawn by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2014-04-10" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2359-2361" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-04-10">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-28T14:10:00-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-28T14:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-28T16:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Issa moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-28T16:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3203-3207" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-28T16:11:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 994.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote2" datetime="2014-04-28T16:31:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3203-3205" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="2014-04-30">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2014-05-09" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="113-101" type="public" datetime="2014-05-09">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 113-101.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2061"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2061"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Office of Management and Budget (OMB)"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s2970"/>
    <amendment number="s2971"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>5/9/2014--Public Law.
Digital Accountability and Transparency Act of 2014 or the DATA Act - (Sec. 2) States as the purposes of this Act to:

 expand the Federal Funding Accountability and Transparency Act of 2006 by disclosing direct federal agency expenditures and linking federal contract, loan, and grant spending information to federal programs to enable taxpayers and policy makers to track federal spending more effectively; establish government-wide data standards for financial data and provide consistent, reliable, and searchable government-wide spending data that is displayed accurately for taxpayers and policy makers on USASpending.gov; simplify reporting for entities receiving federal funds by streamlining reporting requirements and reducing compliance costs while improving transparency; improve the quality of data submitted to USASpending.gov by holding federal agencies accountable for the completeness and accuracy of the data submitted; and apply approaches developed by the Recovery Accountability and Transparency Board to spending across the federal government. (Sec. 3) Amends the Federal Funding Accountability and Transparency Act of 2006 to define "federal agency," for purposes of such Act, to mean an executive department, a government corporation, or an independent establishment.

Directs the Secretary of the Treasury, not later than three years after the enactment of this Act and monthly, when practicable, but not less than quarterly thereafter, to ensure that information on funds made available to or expended by a federal agency is posted online, in a searchable, downloadable format.

Directs the Secretary and the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to establish government-wide financial data standards for federal funds and entities receiving such funds. Requires such data standards, to the extent reasonable and practicable, to: (1) incorporate widely-accepted common data elements and a widely-accepted, nonproprietary, searchable, platform-independent, computer-readable format; (2) include government-wide universal identifiers for federal awards and entities; (3) be consistent with and implement applicable accounting principles; (4) be capable of being continually updated; (5) produce consistent and comparable data; and (6) establish a standard method of conveying the reporting period, reporting entity, unit of measure, and other associated attributes.

Requires the Secretary and the Director to issue guidance to federal agencies on such data standards and consult with public and private stakeholders in establishing such standards.

Requires the Director to review the information required to be reported by recipients of federal awards to identify: (1) common reporting elements across the federal government, (2) unnecessary duplication in financial reporting, and (3) unnecessarily burdensome reporting requirements for recipients of federal awards.

Requires the Director to establish a two-year pilot program to develop recommendations for: (1) standardized reporting elements across the federal government, (2) the elimination of unnecessary duplication in financial reporting, and (3) the reduction of compliance costs for recipients of federal awards. Requires such pilot program to include: (1) a combination of federal contracts, grants, and subawards, with an aggregate value of not less than $1 billion and not more than $2 billion; (2) a diverse group of recipients of federal awards; (3) recipients who receive awards from multiple programs across multiple agencies; and (4) data collected during a 12-month reporting cycle.

Requires the Director, not later than 90 days after the termination of the pilot program, to submit a report to the House Committees on the Budget and Oversight and Government Reform and the Senate Committees on the Budget and Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs that includes: (1) a description of the data collected under the pilot program, its usefulness, and the cost to collect the data from other recipients; and (2) recommendations.

Directs the Inspector General of each federal agency to: (1) review a statistically valid sampling of the spending data submitted under this Act by the federal agency; and (2) submit to Congress and make publicly available a report assessing the completeness, timeliness, quality, and accuracy of the data sampled and the implementation and use of data standards by the federal agency.

Directs the Comptroller General (GAO) to submit a publicly available report to Congress assessing and comparing the data completeness, timeliness, quality, and accuracy of the data submitted under this Act by federal agencies and the implementation and use of data standards by federal agencies.

Authorizes the Secretary to establish a data analysis center, or expand an existing service, to provide data, analytic tools, and data management techniques to support: (1) the prevention and reduction of improper payments, and (2) the improvement of efficiency and transparency in federal spending. Transfers assets of the Recovery Accountability and Transparency Board to the Department of the Treasury upon the establishment of the data analysis center.

Declares that nothing in this Act: (1) shall require disclosure to the public of information protected from disclosure under the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) or information protected under the Privacy Act of 1974 or the Internal Revenue Code; and (2) shall be construed to create a private right of action.

(Sec. 4) Requires the OMB Director to make available on the OMB website a financial management status report and government-wide five-year financial management plan.

(Sec. 5) Requires a federal agency to notify the Secretary of the Treasury of any legally enforceable non-tax debt owed to such agency that is over 120 (currently, 180) days delinquent so that the Secretary can offset such debt administratively. Requires the Secretary to notify Congress of any instance in which an agency fails to notify the Secretary of such a debt.</summary>
</bill>
