<bill session="113" type="s" number="2403" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-05-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Leverage Prior Skills Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to ensure that programs of training services under the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 make better use of participants' prior learning so as to better assist the participants in obtaining degrees and other recognized postsecondary credentials, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412321"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2014-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300080" joined="2014-05-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/22/2014--Introduced.
Leverage Prior Skills Act - Amends the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 to require a governor, in establishing a procedure for local workforce investment boards in the state in determining the initial eligibility of a provider to receive funds for a program of training services, to require the applicant proposing a program that leads to a recognized postsecondary credential to include in the application information on the quality of the services that lead to that credential.

Requires a state to use federal funds reserved to carry out statewide employment and training activities (other than certain statewide rapid response activities) to identify and implement a process by which local boards will contract with providers of training services, or identify eligible providers of training services, only if the providers involved agree to:

 use direct assessments to assess the prior learning of the participants in noncredit employment and training programs; and take that prior learning into account when determining whether a participant has earned credit hours or made progress toward earning a degree from an institution of higher education, or has earned or made progress towards earning a recognized postsecondary credential.</summary>
</bill>
