<bill session="113" type="h" number="5379" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">China Human Rights Protection Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To impose sanctions on individuals that are responsible for the commission of serious and ongoing violations of human rights or gross violations of human rights against nationals of the People's Republic of China or their family members, to protect universal freedoms in the People's Republic of China, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400380"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412460" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400343" joined="2014-09-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Financial Services, the Judiciary, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Africa, Global Health, Global Human Rights and International Organizations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Asia and the Pacific.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA16" subcommittee="Africa, Global Health, Global Human Rights and International Organizations" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA05" subcommittee="Asia and the Pacific" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Border Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international banking"/>
    <term name="Foreign property"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements and negotiations"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2014--Introduced.
China Human Rights Protection Act of 2014 - Directs the President to submit to Congress a list (with updates) of individuals responsible for, or complicit in, the commission of:

 serious and ongoing violations of human rights against nationals of China or their family members, regardless of whether such abuses occurred in China; and gross violations of human rights against nationals of China or their family members, regardless of whether such abuses occurred in China, or who have benefitted materially or financially from such actions. Requires the President to impose: (1) U.S. entry and financial sanctions on listed individuals, and (2) additional sanctions on individuals listed for two and three years.

States that entry, financial, and U.S. program benefits sanctions shall not apply if necessary to permit the United States to comply with the Agreement regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations or other applicable international obligations. Requires congressional notification.

Authorizes the President to terminate sanctions against an individual under specified circumstances.

Sets forth related penalty requirements.

Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to authorize the refusal of a nonimmigrant I-visa (foreign media representative) to aliens who are executives at a state-controlled media organization from China if any U.S. media personnel were expelled, had visas denied, or faced intimidation or violence working in China during the prior fiscal year.

Directs the President to order the revocation, delay, or refusal of a sufficient number of visas already issued to executives of state-controlled media organizations from China in proportion to the expulsions, visa delays or denials, and intimidation experienced by personnel from U.S. journalist or media organizations in the previous 12 months.

Expresses the sense of Congress that:

 restrictions on the activities of U.S. journalists and media personnel in China and the censorship and blockage of news media websites damages the competitiveness of U.S. media corporations and should be considered a trade restriction and an unfair competitive advantage benefitting Chinese government-controlled media organizations; and the U.S. government should link to any bilateral investment treaty currently being negotiated language that guarantees fair treatment of journalists, a reciprocal number of journalist visas, and free and unfettered operation of news websites in China.</summary>
</bill>
