<bill session="113" type="hr" number="604" updated="2015-09-01T10:18:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-30T09:49:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-05-30T09:49:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 4745) making appropriations for the Departments of Transportation, and Housing and Urban Development, and related agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2015, and for other purposes; providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 4681) to authorize appropriations for fiscal years 2014 and 2015 for intelligence and intelligence-related activities of the United States Government, the Community Management Account, and the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement and Disability System, and for other purposes; and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400029"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-29T18:55:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 113-465, by Mr. Bishop (UT).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-29T18:55:00-04:00">
      <text>All points of order against consideration of the bills are waived. General debate shall not exceed one hour, after debate the bills shall be considered for amendment under the five-minute rule. In lieu of the amendment in the nature of a substitute for H.R. 4681, an amendment in the nature of a substitute printed in Rules Committee Print 113-45 shall be considered as an original bill. No amendment to the amendment in the nature of a substitute shall be made in order except those printed in the report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-05-29T20:10:00-04:00" state="REPORTED" calendar="House" number="110">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 110.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-05-30T09:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5029-5034" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-30T09:22:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 604.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-30T09:49:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5034" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2014-05-30T09:49:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5029" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-05-30T09:49:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hr" number="567"/>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="113" type="h" number="4681"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4745"/>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="113" type="h" number="4745"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/29/2014--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of the bill (H.R. 4745) making appropriations for the Departments of Transportation, and Housing and Urban Development, and related agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2015, and for other purposes; providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 4681) to authorize appropriations for fiscal years 2014 and 2015 for intelligence and intelligence-related activities of the United States Government, the Community Management Account, and the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement and Disability System, and for other purposes.</summary>
</bill>
