<bill session="113" type="h" number="3695" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-12-12T15:52:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-12-12T15:52:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-12-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide a temporary extension of the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008 and amendments made by that Act, as previously extended and amended and with certain additional modifications and exceptions, to suspend permanent price support authorities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400247"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-12-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-12T15:45:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Lucas moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-12T15:45:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8046-8047" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-12T15:45:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3695.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2013-12-12T15:52:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8046" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-12-12">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hr" number="438"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices, subsidies, credit"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/12/2013--Passed House amended.
Extends until January 31, 2014: (1) specified agricultural programs under the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008, (2) suspension of permanent price support authorities, and (3) supplemental agricultural disaster assistance.

Exempts from such extensions: (1) mandatory funding for nutrition education; (2) the conservation stewardship program, the farmland protection program, the environmental quality incentives program, and the wildlife habitat incentives program; (3) Commodity Credit Corporation funding for local and regional food aid procurement projects, the McGovern-Dole International Food for Education and Child Nutrition Program, and a survey of foods purchased by school food authorities; (4) rural development programs for micro entrepreneur assistance, pending rural development loans and grants, value-added agricultural market development grants, and the National Sheep Industry Improvement Center; (5) market loss assistance for asparagus producers; (6) supplemental agricultural disaster assistance; (7) Pigford claims determinations; and (8) specified requirements of the Heartland, Habitat, Harvest, and Horticulture Act of 2008 relating to supplemental agricultural disaster assistance, revenue and tax, and trade.

Backdates the effective date of this Act to September 30, 2013.</summary>
</bill>
