<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="H52A2BCAFADCC4A6ABD2CEA6A36F5A279" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HRES 644 IH: Condemning and disapproving of the Obama administration’s failure to comply with the lawful statutory requirement to notify Congress before releasing individuals detained at United States Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba, and expressing national security concerns over the release of five Taliban leaders and the repercussions of negotiating with terrorists.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2014-06-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 644</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20140625">June 25, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000589">Mr. Rigell</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000587">Mr. Ribble</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001252">Mr. Barrow of Georgia</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000011">Mr. Rahall</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Condemning and disapproving of the Obama administration’s failure to comply with the lawful
			 statutory requirement to notify Congress before releasing individuals
			 detained at United States Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba, and
			 expressing national security concerns over the release of five Taliban
			 leaders and the repercussions of negotiating with terrorists.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas><text>Whereas section 1035 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2014 (Public Law
			 113–66; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/801">10 U.S.C. 801</external-xref> note) clearly requires the Secretary of Defense to
			 notify the appropriate committees of Congress at least 30 days before the
			 transfer or release of an individual detained at United States Naval
			 Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on May 31, 2014, the Department of Defense executed the release of five senior Taliban
			 detainees held at United States Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the five released Taliban detainees are all senior Taliban leaders: Abdul Haq Wasiq was the
			 Taliban Deputy Minister of Intelligence, Mullah Norullah Noori was the
			 Taliban military commander at Mazar-e-Sharif, Mullah Mohammad Fazl was the
			 Taliban Deputy Minister of Defense, Khairullah Said Wai Khairkwa was the
			 Taliban Minister of Interior, and Mohammad Nabi Omari was the Taliban
			 commander of secret police;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas these five senior Taliban leaders have associations with al-Qaeda or have engaged in
			 hostilities against the United States or its coalition partners;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas these five senior Taliban detainees held leadership positions within the Taliban when it
			 provided safehaven for al-Qaeda to conduct planning, training, and
			 operations for the September 11, 2001, attacks;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the President has stated that there is <quote>absolutely</quote> a possibility of the released detainees returning to activities that are detrimental to the United
			 States, and, according to media reports, United states intelligence
			 officials told members of the Senate that four of the five detainees are
			 expected to return to the battlefield;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Secretary Hagel stated before the Committee on Armed Services of the House of
			 Representatives on June 11, 2014, that the threat, <quote>should these five detainees return and reintegrate with the Taliban, their focus would almost
			 certainly be on Taliban efforts inside Afghanistan,</quote> where the United States and coalition partners will retain military and civilian personnel;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas in 2010, after an extensive evaluation meant to identify detainees who could be transferred
			 out of the detention facility at United States Naval Station, Guantanamo
			 Bay, Cuba, the Obama administration determined that these five should
			 remain in United States detention because they were <quote>too dangerous to transfer</quote> because each <quote>poses a high level of threat that cannot be mitigated sufficiently except through continued
			 detention</quote>;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Obama administration negotiated, through intermediaries in the Government of Qatar,
			 with the Taliban, with whom the United States remains engaged in active
			 combat, and with the Haqqani Network, which the State Department has
			 designated as foreign terrorist organization, and who had held Sergeant
			 Bowe Bergdahl captive;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas congressional notification was not received until June 2, 2014, three days after such
			 individuals were released, and 33 days after the date on which such
			 notification was required by law;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Obama administration admits that it made no effort to comply with the 30-day
			 notification requirement;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Obama administration officials acknowledge that approximately 80 or 90 employees within the
			 administration were knowledgeable of the transfer of the five Taliban
			 detainees prior to their release;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Obama administration has offered differing, unconvincing, and conflicting explanations
			 of why it failed to comply with the 30-day notification requirement and
			 has described the failure to notify Congress as an <quote>oversight</quote>;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas article II, section 3 of the Constitution states that the President <quote>shall take care that the laws be faithfully executed</quote>;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on January 15, 2009, the Office of Legal Counsel in the Department of Justice acknowledged
			 that Congress possesses under article I of the Constitution <quote>significant war powers</quote>, including legislative authority concerning the detention and release of enemy combatants;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Obama administration has complied with section 1035 of the National Defense
			 Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/66">Public Law 113–66</external-xref>; 10 U.S.C. 801
			 note) and section 8111 of the Department of Defense Appropriations Act,
			 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/76">Public Law 113–76</external-xref>) in all previous detainee transfers from United
			 States Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba, since the date of the
			 enactment of each such Act; and</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the leadership and the leaders of the national security committees of the Senate and House
			 of Representatives are on record, specifically in 2011, as opposing the
			 transfer of detainees in exchange for a prisoner of war: Now, therefore,
			 be it</text></whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body id="H3AA91E4BDBA04A6593286CF0438CB417" style="traditional">
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HEB1B8AB177144492BEA18DC55143320A" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text>
			<paragraph id="H00C50D9AF60243C5B528833B3ACF40C5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>condemns and disapproves of the failure of the Obama administration to comply with the lawful
			 30-day statutory reporting requirement in executing the release of five
			 senior members of the Taliban from detention at United States Naval
			 Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HD6EF46C4D85643D0A1F56387E5D084D9"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expresses grave concern over national security implications that may arise due to the release of
			 Taliban officials, including the national security threat to the people
			 and Armed Forces of the United States and complications of the current
			 efforts of the United States to combat terrorism worldwide;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HED7A13588CBE4ED68A6560E9CC8FEBCD"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expresses grave concern over the repercussions of negotiating with terrorists, and the risk that
			 such negotiations with terrorists may further encourage hostilities and
			 the abduction of Americans as a means of further prisoner exchanges;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HB58A60605BDF4AFBB6943BF87B498DDF"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">stipulates that further violations of the law set forth in section 1035 of the National Defense
			 Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/66">Public Law 113–66</external-xref>; 10 U.S.C. 801
			 note) and section 8111 of the Department of Defense Appropriations Act,
			 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/76">Public Law 113–76</external-xref>) are unacceptable;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H9508D969A99C447EB960D690EF7033AE"><enum>(5)</enum><text>declares grave misgivings about the prospect of any other similar transfers from United States
			 Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba, even if undertaken pursuant to
			 statutory requirements; and</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HA7E98A7AFBBF4AD8BAE60A9F20FA80B8"><enum>(6)</enum><text>expresses that the Obama administration’s release of the five detainees has burdened unnecessarily
			 the trust and confidence in the administration’s commitment and ability to
			 constructively engage and work with the legislative branch, and therefore
			 works against what is in the best interest of the people of the United
			 States.</text>
			</paragraph></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


