<bill session="113" type="h" number="4378" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-04-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-04-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">EAT for Health Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Education and Training for Health Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to issue to Federal agencies guidelines for developing procedures and requirements relating to certain primary care Federal health professionals completing continuing medical education on nutrition and to require Federal agencies to submit annual reports relating to such guidelines, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400162"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400352" joined="2014-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412219" joined="2014-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412317" joined="2014-04-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Digestive and metabolic diseases"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/2/2014--Introduced.
Education and Training for Health Act of 2014 or the EAT for Health Act of 2014 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to issue guidelines to federal agencies for developing procedures and requirements to ensure that every primary care health professional employed full-time for such agencies have at least six credits of continuing medical education courses relating to nutrition. Requires these to include at least courses on the role of nutrition in the prevention, management, and, as possible, reversal of obesity, cardiovascular disease, diabetes, and cancer.

Requires each agency employing such primary care professionals to report to Congress annually on the extent to which it has adopted and enforced the guidelines issued under this Act with respect to those employed during any portion of the previous year.</summary>
</bill>
