<bill session="113" type="h" number="4452" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-04-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-04-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Corporate Crime Database Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a corporate crime database, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400080"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-10">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-10">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Business ethics"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/10/2014--Introduced.
Corporate Crime Database Act - Directs the Attorney General to: (1) acquire data, for each calendar year, regarding all administrative, civil, and criminal judical proceedings against any corporation or corporate official involving a felony or misdemeanor or civl charge where potential fines may be $1,000 or more; (2) establish and maintain a publicly available website on improper conduct by all corporations with annual revenues of more than $1 billion; and (3) prepare an annual report to Congress detailing the number of civil, administrative, and criminal enforcement actions brought against any corporation or corporate official and the&#160;final dispositions of such actions.</summary>
</bill>
