<bill session="113" type="h" number="5455" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SCAN Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Scan Containers Absolutely Now Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Security and Accountability For Every Port Act of 2006 ("SAFE Port Act") to administer a pilot program for 100 percent scanning of cargo containers at domestic ports, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412498"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7435, E1395"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border and Maritime Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM11" subcommittee="Border and Maritime Security" name="House Homeland Security"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/11/2014--Introduced.
Scan Containers Absolutely Now Act or the SCAN Act - Amends the Security and Accountability For Every Port Act of 2006 to direct the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to: (1) conduct a one-year pilot program at two domestic ports to evaluate the process of 100% scanning of cargo containers and its potential for use at all domestic ports, (2) achieve a full-scale implementation of the program within one year after enactment of this Act, and (3) evaluate and report on such program within one year after program completion.

Requires the Secretary to: (1) purchase the equipment necessary to conduct the pilot program, (2) make information about the equipment available to domestic ports as part of the application process, and (3) permit such equipment to remain with the selected ports upon completion of the program.</summary>
</bill>
