<bill session="113" type="h" number="3582" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-11-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-11-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-11-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Water Trust Fund Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a Water Infrastructure Investment Trust Fund, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400033"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400031" joined="2013-11-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400116" joined="2013-11-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412263" joined="2013-11-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412454" joined="2013-11-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2013-11-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400318" joined="2013-11-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400431" joined="2013-11-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-11-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1738"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-21">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-21">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-21">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and the Economy.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF18" subcommittee="Environment and the Economy" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/21/2013--Introduced.
Water Trust Fund Act of 2013 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to establish in the Treasury a Water Infrastructure Investment Trust Fund. Appropriates to such Fund amounts equivalent to the fees received in the Treasury before January 1, 2019, under this Act.

Requires 85% of amounts in the Fund to be available to the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) for making capitalization grants under the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act or CWA), and 15% to be available to the Secretary of the Treasury for carrying out the innovative financing program established under this Act.

Prohibits amounts in the Fund from being made available for a fiscal year unless the amount of funds appropriated to the Clean Water State Revolving Fund through annual capitalization grants is not less than the average of the annual amounts provided in capitalization grants under the CWA for the immediately preceding five-fiscal-year period.

Directs the Secretary to: (1) implement a program under which the Secretary provides a label suitable for placement on products (for a fee of three cents per unit) to inform consumers that the manufacturer, producer, or importer of the product and other stakeholders participate in the Fund and are contributing to America's clean water; and (2) deposit amounts received in the Treasury.

Directs the Secretary to: (1) establish an innovative financing program to make financial assistance available for projects eligible for assistance from a state water pollution control revolving fund established pursuant to the CWA, and (2) model the program after the Transportation Infrastructure Finance and Innovation Act of 1998 program.</summary>
</bill>
