<bill session="113" type="h" number="3625" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-12-11">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-12-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-12-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for termination liability costs for certain National Aeronautics and Space Administration projects, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412395"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400004" joined="2013-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="2013-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412512" joined="2013-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412516" joined="2013-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412271" joined="2013-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400086" joined="2013-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400165" joined="2013-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412583" joined="2013-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412527" joined="2013-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412302" joined="2013-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412443" joined="2013-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412309" joined="2013-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412399" joined="2013-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412396" joined="2013-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400381" joined="2013-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="410396" joined="2013-12-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-12-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-11">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-12-11" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral, Markup"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2687"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="National Aeronautics and Space Administration"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Spacecraft and satellites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/2/2013--Introduced.
Declares that termination liability costs for the International Space Station (ISS), the Space Launch System, and the Orion crew capsule (covered programs) shall be provided only pursuant to this Act.

Prohibits the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) from reserving funds from amounts appropriated for a covered program, and instructs the Administrator to direct prime contractors not to reserve funds for potential termination liability costs respecting such a program.

Declares that it is the intent of Congress that funds authorized to be appropriated for covered programs be applied in meeting established technical goals and schedule milestones.

Declares void and unenforceable any provision in a prime contract entered into before enactment of this Act that provides for the payment of termination liability costs through any other means than as provided in this Act.

Bars the Administrator from initiating termination of a prime contract on a covered program for the convenience of the government unless it is authorized or required by a law enacted after this Act's enactment. Requires notice to specified congressional committees before initiating termination of a prime contract for cause.

Requires the Administrator to notify Congress if an authorization of appropriations is necessary in advance of a proposed program termination because sufficient unobligated appropriations are not available in the appropriations account funding the contract.</summary>
</bill>
