<bill session="113" type="h" number="5104" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pay For Success Affordable Housing Energy Modernization Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to carry out a demonstration program to enter into budget-neutral, performance-based contracts for energy and water conservation improvements for multifamily residential units.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412411"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412571" joined="2014-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400639" joined="2014-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412544" joined="2014-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412488" joined="2014-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412282" joined="2014-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412548" joined="2014-07-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2074"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2262"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2438"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Housing for the elderly and disabled"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/14/2014--Introduced.
Pay For Success Affordable Housing Energy Modernization Act of 2014 - Directs the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to establish a demonstration program under which, between enactment of this Act and September 30, 2017, the Secretary may enter into budget-neutral, performance-based agreements (for up to 12 years each) that result in a reduction in energy or water costs with appropriate entities to carry out projects for energy or water conservation improvements at up to 20,000 residential units in multifamily buildings participating in:

 Section 8 project-based rental assistance programs under the United States Housing Act of 1937, other than Section 8 (voucher program) assistance; supportive housing for the elderly programs under the Housing Act of 1959; or supportive housing for persons with disabilities programs under the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act. Specifies requirements for payment under an agreement, which shall be contingent on documented utility savings, as well as for eligibility, geographical diversity, and funding for the program.

Requires the Secretary to submit to specified congressional committees a detailed plan for the implementation of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
