<bill session="113" type="hr" number="695" updated="2015-09-01T10:18:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Restore Democracy Resolution</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives regarding steps that Congress should take to restore democracy and change the way we do politics in the United States by reducing the influence of money and corporations and promoting the participation of the people in politics and government.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="408211"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committees on Rules, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-30">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-30">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-30">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU10" subcommittee="Constitution and Civil Justice" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional districts and representation"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Political advertising"/>
    <term name="Political parties and affiliation"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court"/>
    <term name="Voting rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/2014--Introduced.
Restore Democracy Resolution - Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives with respect to:

 the case of Citizens United v. Federal Election Commission; creation of a public finance system for congressional election; limitations on campaign spending and the campaign season; a prohibition against the solicitation or collecting of campaign contributions under certain circumstances; congressional power to prohibit voter suppression activities; state online voter registration systems; a federal reapportionment system, redistricting, and gerrymandering; and specified procedures in the House regarding committee hearings and reports, including conference committee meetings and reports.</summary>
</bill>
