<bill session="113" type="s" number="1589" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-10-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-10-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improving Quality of Care Within the Department of Veterans Affairs Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to ensure the Department of Veterans Affairs has an up-to-date policy on reporting of cases of infectious diseases, to require an independent assessment of the Veterans Integrated Service Networks and medical centers of the Department, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400054"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2013-11-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-30">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 113-280.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1950"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1982"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2413"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/28/2013--Introduced.
Improving Quality of Care Within the Department of Veterans Affairs Act of 2013 - Requires the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to: (1) ensure that the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) has in effect an up-to-date policy on reporting a notifiable infectious disease diagnosed at a VA facility in accordance with applicable state and local law, and (2) develop performance measures to assess whether and to what degree the directors of Veterans Integrated Service Networks (VISN) and VA medical centers are complying with such policy.

Requires the Secretary to enter into a contract with an independent third-party to: (1) assess the organizational structures of VA medical centers, and (2) improve succession planning among key leadership roles at VISN and VA medical centers.</summary>
</bill>
