<bill session="113" type="s" number="2510" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Guantanamo Bay Detainee Transfer Suspension Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a temporary limitation on the use of funds to transfer or release individuals detained at United States Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412573"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412493" joined="2014-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="2014-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300088" joined="2014-06-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="4938"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers"/>
    <term name="Qatar"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/19/2014--Introduced.
Guantanamo Bay Detainee Transfer Suspension Act of 2014 - Prohibits the obligation or expenditure of funds to transfer or release any covered detainee at the U.S. Naval Station Guantanamo Bay, Cuba (Guantanamo) to the custody or control of such individual's country of origin, any other foreign country, or any other foreign entity until the earlier of 90 days after the submittal to Congress of a report required by this Act or 180 days after this Act's enactment, except pursuant to an order issued by a court or competent tribunal of the United States having lawful jurisdiction.

Makes a U.S. officer or employee liable in his or her individual capacity for a civil penalty of $10,000 for each covered detainee transferred or released in violation of such prohibition. Prohibits the U.S. government from providing representation to, or retaining or reimbursing private counsel for the representation of, such officer or employee.

Authorizes a person to bring a civil action for a violation of such prohibition in the name of the government, subject to specified requirements.

Requires the Secretary to submit a report regarding the risk that the five detainees transferred from Guantanamo to Qatar on May 31, 2014, would reengage in terrorist activity after transfer.

Prohibits the transfer or release of a covered detainee from Guantanamo to a foreign country without the President's express written authorization.

Defines a "covered detainee" as Khalid Sheikh Mohammed or any other detainee who: (1) is not a U.S. citizen or a member of the U.S. Armed Forces; (2) is or was held on January 20, 2009, at Guantanamo by the Department of Defense (DOD); and (3) is held as of the date of enactment of this Act at Guantanamo Bay, Cuba, by DOD.</summary>
</bill>
