<bill session="113" type="h" number="4968" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Maya Angelou Congressional Gold Medal Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To posthumously award a Congressional gold medal to Maya Angelou in recognition of her achievements and contributions to American culture and the civil rights movement.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412559"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412565" joined="2014-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412539" joined="2014-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412540" joined="2014-06-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-25">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-25">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Art, artists, authorship"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Smithsonian Institution"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/25/2014--Introduced.
Maya Angelou Congressional Gold Medal Act - Directs the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate to arrange for the posthumous presentation of a congressional gold medal in commemoration of Maya Angelou in recognition of her achievements and contributions to American culture and the civil rights movement.

Requires the gold medal to be given to the Smithsonian Institution. Expresses the sense of Congress that the Smithsonian Institution make it available for display, particularly at the National Museum of African American History and Culture, or for loan as appropriate, particularly to locations associated with Angelou's life.</summary>
</bill>
