<bill session="113" type="s" number="2096" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-03-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-03-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-03-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Freedom Through Energy Export Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Alaska Natural Gas Pipeline Act of 2004 to provide for the authorization of liquified natural gas terminals and related facilities necessary for the export of Alaska natural gas, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412326"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-03-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="580"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="192"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Arctic and polar regions"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Free trade and trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Japan"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements and negotiations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/6/2014--Introduced.
Freedom Through Energy Export Act - Amends the Alaska Natural Gas Pipeline Act of 2004 to redefine the Alaska natural gas transportation project to include any liquified natural gas terminal and facilities necessary or required for the export of Alaska natural gas (including related facilities subject to the jurisdiction of the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission [FERC]).

Authorizes FERC to consider and act on an application for authorization for a liquefied natural gas terminal and related facilities determined necessary for the export of Alaska natural gas other than the Alaska natural gas transportation system.

Directs FERC to issue an authorization for the siting, construction, and operation of an Alaska natural gas transportation project if the applicant has satisfied certain Natural Gas Act requirements for a liquefied natural gas terminal and related facilities necessary or required for the export of Alaska natural gas.

Directs FERC, within 60 days after the issuance of a final environmental impact statement under the the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969, to approve or deny, under the expedited approval process, an application for a certificate of public convenience and necessity for projects designated under the Natural Gas Act and this Act.

Confers responsibility upon the Federal Coordinator for Alaska Natural Gas Transportation Projects for: (1) coordinating the expeditious discharge of all activities by federal agencies regarding a pipeline project carrying natural gas from the Alaska North Slope to market south of 68 degrees north latitude, and (2) ensuring that federal agencies are fully informed in carrying out an Alaska natural gas transportation project, including about any commercial, technological, or regulatory issues that could affect such project.

Declares that neither this Act nor the Alaska Natural Gas Transportation Act of 1976 precludes construction of either a gas liquefaction terminal or other facilities determined necessary or required for the transportation and export of natural gas from the Alaska North Slope.

Directs the Secretary of Labor to make grants to the Alaska Workforce Investment Board: (1) to train adult and dislocated workers in Alaska to construct and operate a natural gas transportation project (currently, a gas pipeline system), and (2) for construction of a training facility to support such a project.

Expresses the sense of Congress that Alaska Native Regional Corporations, companies owned and operated by Alaskans and individual Alaskans should have the opportunity to own shares of the Alaska natural gas transportation project (currently, gas pipeline system).

Authorizes federal loan guarantees for a liquefied natural gas pipeline approved to the border between Alaska and Canada. Amends the Natural Gas Act to deem consistent with the public interest an expedited application and approval process without modification or delay for the exportation of natural gas to a foreign country that is: (1) a nation with which there is in effect a free trade agreement requiring national treatment for trade in natural gas (as under existing law); (2) a member country of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO); (3) Japan, as long as the Treaty of Mutual Cooperation and Security between the United States and Japan remains in effect; and (4) any other foreign country if the Secretary of State determines that such exportation promotes U.S. national security interests.</summary>
</bill>
