<bill session="113" type="h" number="4937" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protection Against Wasteful Spending Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the implementation of report recommendations by an inspector general regarding wasteful and excessive spending, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412487"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412535" joined="2014-06-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Appropriations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-23">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-23">
      <text>Referred to House Appropriations</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/23/2014--Introduced.
Protection Against Wasteful Spending Act of 2014 - Requires the head of a federal agency to: (1)&#160;implement in each of fiscal years 2014-2020 all of the recommendations of the agency's inspector general (IG) regarding wasteful and excessive spending, or duplicative programs causing wasteful and excessive spending, except for any recommendation that would violate an existing law; and (2) report to Congress on such implementation.

Prohibits an agency that fails to implement an IG&#160;recommendation in a timely manner from obligating funds for: (1) convention or seminar attendance and international or domestic travel by any politically-appointed official, or (2) any bonus or salary increase for such official.

Directs that such funds that are prohibited from being obligated and amounts saved by the implementation of IG recommendations be credited or transferred&#160;equally&#160;to: (1) the Highway Trust Fund, and (2) the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) for capitalization grants for state water pollution control revolving funds under the Clean Water Act.</summary>
</bill>
