<bill session="113" type="s" number="1582" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-10-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-10-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improved Compensation for Hearing Loss Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to submit reports on the provision of services by the Department of Veterans Affairs to veterans with hearing loss and other auditory system injuries and the measures that can be taken jointly by the Department of Veterans Affairs and the Department of Defense with respect to hearing loss and other auditory system injuries, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400357"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-30">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 113-280.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1950"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1982"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2413"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Hearing, speech, and vision care"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/28/2013--Introduced.
Improved Compensation for Hearing Loss Act of 2013 - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) to report to the congressional veterans committees on actions taken to implement the findings and recommendations included in the 2006 report by the Institute of Medicine of the National Academies entitled "Noise and Military Service: Implications for Hearing Loss and Tinnitus."

Requires the Secretary's report to include an evaluation of the extent to which veterans who had a military occupational specialty that is not included on the Duty Military Occupational Specialty Noise Exposure Listing are precluded from receiving VA benefits related to hearing loss.

Directs the Secretary to report to Congress on joint VA-Department of Defense (DOD) programs concerning the prevention, early detection, and treatment of hearing loss of members of the Armed Forces and veterans, as well as related matters.</summary>
</bill>
