<bill session="113" type="s" number="1094" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-12">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-06-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strengthening America's Schools Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Commission on Effective Regulation and Assessment Systems for Public Schools Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">McKinney-Vento Homeless Education Reauthorization Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Strengthening America's Schools Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate" partial="1">Commission on Effective Regulation and Assessment Systems for Public Schools Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate" partial="1">McKinney-Vento Homeless Education Reauthorization Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300051"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400013" joined="2013-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412330" joined="2013-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2013-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2013-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412324" joined="2013-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2013-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412194" joined="2013-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2013-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2013-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412542" joined="2013-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2013-06-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-04">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3957-3958"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-11">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Committee consideration and Mark Up Session held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-06-12" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-10-11">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Reported by Senator Harkin with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 113-113. Additional views filed.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-10-11" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="218">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 218.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="5"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1652"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1736"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2920"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3122"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="829"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="840"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1010"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1082"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1088"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Economic theory"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employee performance"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Financial literacy"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign language and bilingual programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Homelessness and emergency shelter"/>
    <term name="Immigrant health and welfare"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Language arts"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
    <term name="Libraries and archives"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Physical fitness and lifestyle"/>
    <term name="Pornography"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/11/2013--Reported to Senate amended.
Strengthening America's Schools Act of 2013 - Revises and reauthorizes programs under the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA).

 Title I: College and Career Readiness for All Students - Part A: Improving the Academic Achievement of the Disadvantaged - (Sec. 1111) Revises the school improvement program under part A of title I of the ESEA.

Maintains the requirement conditioning a state's receipt of funds under part A on its developing and implementing academic content and achievement standards and assessments that are applicable to all public elementary and secondary schools and school students in the state.

Requires states to adopt college and career ready academic: (1) content standards in reading or language arts and mathematics by the end of 2014, and (2) achievement standards in those disciplines by the beginning of the 2015-2016 school year.

Requires college and career ready standards to be aligned with: (1) credit-bearing academic coursework at public institutions of higher education (IHEs) in the state, (2) relevant state career and technical education standards and the state performance measures identified in the state plan for career and technical education, and (3) appropriate career skills or state-developed standards that are voluntarily adopted by a significant number of states.

Requires the achievement standards to establish the level of performance expected for each grade level that demonstrates that the student has mastered the material in the state academic content standards for that grade level.

Requires states to adopt academic content and achievement standards in science by the end of 2014 that are aligned with the knowledge and skills needed to be college and career ready.

Requires states to adopt, by the close of 2015, high-quality English language proficiency standards that: (1) identify at least four levels of English proficiency, and (2) are aligned with their academic content standards in reading or language arts so that students can be reliably measured in those disciplines. Requires English learners (currently referred to as limited English proficient students) to be tested against those proficiency standards on an annual basis.

Allows states to adopt alternate academic achievement standards and assessments for students with the most significant cognitive disabilities. Requires the decision about which students should be measured against these standards to be made separately for each student in each subject assessed. Prohibits the number of students in a state who are being assessed in each grade level for each subject using the alternate assessment from exceeding 1% of the number of all students in that grade level in the state being assessed in that subject matter.

Directs states that use school improvement funds to support early childhood education to establish, or certify the existence of, early learning guidelines for preschool-aged children and early grade standards for children in kindergarten through grade three by the close of 2015.

Requires states, by the beginning of the 2015-2016 school year, to adopt and implement statewide assessments that measure student achievement against: (1) the reading or language arts and mathematics standards annually in grades 3 through 8 and at least once during grades 10 through 12; and (2) the science standards at least once in grades 3 through 5, 6 through 9, and 10 through 12; (3) the English language proficiency standards; and (4) any alternate academic achievement standards for students with the most significant cognitive disabilities.

Requires the assessments in reading or language arts, mathematics, and science to: (1) measure whether each student is performing at the student's grade level, (2) determine the specific grade level at which each student is performing, and (3) measure each student's academic growth.

Allows states to develop and administer computer adaptive assessments for those subjects.

Allows the assessments in reading or language arts and mathematics to be administered through a single annual summative assessment or through multiple assessments during an academic year, provided the multiple assessments yield a summative score that reliably measures student academic growth.

Requires states to reduce duplicative assessments.

Requires each state receiving part A funds to prepare and disseminate an annual report card on the performance of each public elementary and secondary school in the state, each local educational agency (LEA) in the state, and the state as a whole. Requires the report cards to include: (1) specified student information in the aggregate and disaggregated and cross-tabulated by student subgroup, (2) class size information, (3) information on each school's categorization under the state accountability system, (4) school sports information, and (5) information on the number of students using early intervening services.

Requires LEAs to issue report cards that contain specified student information disaggregated by student subgroup.

Requires LEAs to provide parents with an equity report card for each school that includes: (1) student achievement data, disaggregated by student subgroup; (2) information on the school's funding by source; (3) for each high school, the graduation rate and the rate students enroll in college; (4) information on student participation in educational opportunities at the school; and (5) school climate information.

(Sec. 1113) Alters the formula LEAs are to use to: (1) rank the poverty of school attendance areas if school improvement funds are insufficient to serve all areas, and (2) calculate the number of low-income students in secondary schools.

Requires LEAs to reserve part A funds to serve homeless and foster care children. Allows reserved funds to be used to provide homeless children and youth with services not ordinarily provided to other children under part A.

(Sec. 1114) Amends provisions concerning schoolwide programs (programs that allow LEAs to consolidate school improvement funds to upgrade the entire educational program of schools) to allow the delivery of those programs by external providers that have expertise in using scientifically valid strategies and programs to improve teaching, learning, and schools.

Requires schoolwide programs to include reform strategies that provide: (1) a multi-tier system of supports and positive behavioral interventions and supports; and (2) programs, activities, courses, and professional development in the core academic subjects that are targeted toward assisting low-performing or at-risk children in meeting the academic content and achievement standards.

(Sec. 1115) Allows targeted assistance programs (programs that direct school improvement funds toward the children in a school who are failing or most at risk of failing) to include: (1) a multi-tier system of supports and positive behavioral interventions and supports; and (2) support for programs, activities, courses, and professional development in the core academic subjects that are targeted toward assisting those children in meeting the academic content and achievement standards.

(Sec. 1116) Eliminates the requirement that LEAs and their elementary and secondary schools make adequate yearly progress (AYP) toward state performance standards or be subject to specified improvements, corrective action, or restructuring. Requires, instead, that each state accountability system:

 establish annual performance targets for the state and its LEAs and elementary and secondary schools that include targets for student proficiency, academic growth, English language proficiency for English learners, and high school graduation rates; use the assessments and high school graduation rates to annually measure and report on the performance of the state's elementary and secondary schools and LEAs; and require the improvement, through supports and interventions that address student needs, of all of the state's public schools that are low-performing or have low-performing subgroups of poor, minority, disabled, and English learner students. Requires state accountability systems to include student performance in reading or language arts and mathematics. Allows states to include other subjects, such as science, for which they have adopted academic content and achievement standards.

Requires LEAs to ensure that each school that, after two consecutive years, has not met state performance targets for the same student subgroup develops and implements a locally designed intervention to improve student achievement in that subgroup.

Subjects schools to improvement strategies if they are identified as: (1) focus schools due to their having among the largest achievement or graduation gaps among student subgroups in the state; or (2) priority schools due to their status as the lowest achieving schools in the state, high schools with graduation rates below 60%, or focus schools for the six preceding consecutive years.

Identifies a school as a focus school, beginning with the 2015-2016 school year, if it is not identified as a priority school and is in the 10% of all: (1) public schools in the state with the greatest achievement gaps among the subgroups of poor, minority, disabled, and English learner students; or (2) public high schools in the state with the greatest graduation rate gaps among those student subgroups.

Requires each LEA that serves a focus school to develop and implement a measurable and data-driven correction plan to improve the performance of the school's low-achieving subgroups.

Continues a focus school's characterization as a focus school for the three years following its designation as such, unless it meets all of its performance targets or the state determines, after the second year, that it will meet those targets by the end of the following year.

Allows states to apply to the Secretary of Education (Secretary) for a waiver of the requirement to identify schools as focus schools if they determine that all of their schools that would be identified as such are performing at a satisfactory level.

Identifies a school as a priority school, beginning with the 2015-2016 school year, if it: (1) is in the lowest-achieving 5% of elementary schools in the state, (2) is in the lowest-achieving 5% of secondary schools in the state, (3) is a public high school with a graduation rate of less than 60%, or (4) has been a focus school for the six preceding consecutive years.

Allows states to apply to the Secretary for a waiver of the requirement to identify schools as priority schools due to their being within the lowest-achieving 5% of elementary or 5% of secondary schools if they determine that all of those schools are performing at a satisfactory level.

Authorizes a state, state law permitting, to take over a school and act as its LEA if the school has been identified as a priority school for the initial three-year identification period and is then re-identified as a priority school for a subsequent three-year period.

Requires LEAs receiving part A funds to conduct a data-driven needs analysis of each of their priority schools and use it to select and implement the most appropriate school improvement strategy to improve student performance at each school.

Requires LEAs that are implementing any of the school improvement strategies to provide: (1) school staff with ongoing training and performance evaluations; (2) students with instruction and instructional supports that meet their individual needs; and (3) the school with assistance in implementing positive behavioral interventions and supports, other early intervening services, and school based mental-health programs.

Identifies the school improvement strategies as: (1) the transformation strategy, (2) the turnaround strategy, (3) the whole school reform strategy, (4) the restart strategy, and (5) the school closure strategy.

Includes as part of the transformation strategy: (1) replacing the principal, if the principal has served in that role at the school for more than two years, with a principal that has had more training, experience, or success; (2) requiring instructional and leadership personnel to reapply for their positions; (3) requiring hiring at the school to be done through mutual consent; and (4) implementing schedules and strategies that provide increased learning time.

 Includes as part of the turnaround strategy: (1) replacing the principal, if the principal has served in that role at the school for more than two years, with a principal that has had more training, experience, or success; (2) screening all teachers in the school and retaining not more than 65% of them; and (3) implementing schedules and strategies the provide increased learning time.

Identifies the whole school reform strategy as one undertaken in partnership with an external provider offering a school reform program that is based on at least a moderate level of evidence that it will have a statistically significant effect on student outcomes.

 Includes as part of the restart strategy: (1) converting the school into a public charter, magnet, or innovative school; (2) allowing students of the former school to enroll in the new school; and (3) using a random lottery system to admit additional students if the new school has more applicants than it can accommodate.

Requires LEAs implementing the school closure strategy to enroll students who attended the closed school in higher-performing schools that are within reasonable proximity to the closed school. Allows school improvement funds to be used to support the costs the higher-performing schools incur in meeting the needs of these new students.

 Allows states, with the Secretary's approval, to establish an alternative state-determined, evidence-based, school improvement strategy to be used by their LEAs, but prohibits funds under title I of the ESEA from being used for school vouchers.

Continues a priority school's characterization as a priority school for the three years following its designation as such, unless, after the second year, it has met all of its performance targets or the state determines that it will meet those targets by the end of the following year.

Requires LEAs to: (1) implement the restart or school closure strategy for schools that are re-classified as priority schools after their initial classification as such; and (2) allow students at priority schools to transfer to another public school that has not been identified as persistently low-achieving, unless that option is prohibited by state law.

(Sec. 1117) Repeals the school support and recognition program (a program that requires states to establish a statewide system of intensive and sustained support and improvement for LEAs and schools to increase the opportunity for students to meet the state's academic content and student academic achievement standards).

Requires teachers teaching a core academic subject in a program supported with school improvement funds to be highly qualified and certified to teach that subject area, but makes this requirement applicable only to new teachers if the state has fully implemented a professional growth and improvement system.

Allows LEAs that are unable to provide a small, rural, or remote school with a highly-qualified, on-site, classroom teacher for a core academic subject to use distance education provided by a teacher highly qualified in the subject, but only if a teacher highly qualified in another subject is present in the classroom to assist students during the distance education.

Excepts teachers of American Indian, Alaska Native, or Native Hawaiian language, culture, or history from the requirement that teachers be highly qualified. Allows states to require a local tribe or tribal organization to verify those teachers' competency.

Prohibits a state from requiring a school or LEA to spend a specific amount of funds for professional development activities under part A.

(Sec. 1118) Requires LEAs to conduct an annual survey of parents, family members, and school personnel and, on the basis of that survey, develop and implement an annual parent and family engagement plan to support the meaningful engagement of parents and other family members in children's education.

Provides that each plan shall establish parent engagement goals for the LEA and its schools and annual quantifiable performance benchmarks for such goals.

Requires LEAs to conduct an end-of-the-year survey of parents and school personnel and, on the basis of that survey and their progress in meeting their annual performance benchmarks, revise their parent and family engagement plan as needed.

Directs LEAs to: (1) establish a parent advisory board to assist them in developing, revising, and reviewing their parent and family engagement plan; and (2) reserve at least 2% of their part A allocation to assist schools in carrying out activities pursuant to that plan.

(Sec. 1120) Conditions an LEA's receipt of part A funds, beginning with the 2015-2016 school year, on the LEA showing its state that combined state and local per-pupil expenditures in each of its schools served under part A are not less than the average combined state and local per-pupil expenditures for each of its schools not served under that program.

Requires an LEA that serves all of its schools under part A to show its state that the average combined state and local per-pupil expenditures for its high-poverty schools were not less than those expenditures for its low-poverty schools.

Allows LEAs to meet these requirements on an LEA-wide or grade-span by grade-span basis.

Requires LEAs to exclude from these calculations state and local funds expended in any school for capital expenditures or the excess costs of providing services to English learners or disabled children.

Allows LEAs to satisfy comparability of education expenditure requirements by meeting expenditure requirements enacted by the state or LEA before this Act's enactment, provided those requirements provide the same or a higher standard of comparability than this Act's provisions.

(Sec. 1121) Requires LEAs to engage in specified activities with Head Start agencies, special education providers, and, if feasible, other early childhood education providers to ease the transition of children into elementary education.

(Sec. 1125) Replaces the school support and recognition program with a blue ribbon schools program that allows each state to annually identify the highest 5% of its schools as blue ribbon schools based on: (1) the percentage of their students who are meeting or exceeding state academic achievement standards in English or language arts and mathematics; (2) in the case of high schools, their graduation rates; (3) the performance of their student subgroups; (4) the percentage of their students who are meeting or exceeding state academic achievement standards or are achieving sufficient academic growth; and (5) school gains.

Allows states to provide each blue ribbon school with: (1) increased autonomy over its budget, staffing, and time; (2) flexibility in using funds provided to the school under the ESEA for any purpose allowed under the ESEA; and (3) a monetary award, through its LEA, if it agrees to use the reward to improve student achievement and provide technical assistance to the lowest-achieving schools in the state that are closest geographically to it.

Directs the Secretary, acting jointly with the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), to designate exemplary early childhood education programs as centers of excellence in early childhood for a five-year term and award each of them a bonus grant to improve the quality of their program and others in their region. Requires eligible programs to have been nominated by their state Governor as centers of excellence and to serve children who are eligible to participate in the school lunch program. Requires the selection of at least one center of excellence in each state.

Requires the centers of excellence to use at least 15% of their bonus grant to disseminate best practices for achieving early academic success to other early childhood education programs in their state and to use the remainder for at least two of the following activities:

 providing Head Start services to additional eligible young children; extending services to provide full-day, full-week, or full-year care to children; further coordinating early childhood education programs and services and social services in their community; providing instructional and support staff with professional development; developing or maintaining partnerships with institutions of higher education and nonprofit organizations that recruit, train, place, and support postsecondary students to serve as mentors and reading partners to preschool children in centers; carrying out other activities to improve the overall quality of their early childhood education programs; and sharing best practices concerning children's transition to elementary school. Authorizes the Secretary to identify and recognize exemplary schools, programs, and individuals, including through: (1) a Green Ribbon Schools program that recognizes excellence in reducing environmental impact, increasing health and wellness, and providing sustainability education; and (2) an award program recognizing excellence exhibited by classified school employees in the public school system.

(Sec. 1126) Directs the Secretary to award grants to states to develop, improve, or administer their college and career ready academic standards and assessments.

Directs the Secretary to award competitive grants to states to enhance such assessments by: (1) collaborating with IHEs or other entities, (2) using multiple measures of student achievement from multiple sources, (3) charting student progress over time, or (4) developing comprehensive assessment instruments.

(Sec. 1127) Provides that a state is free from all federal requirements under part A if the state chooses to not receive funding under that part.

Reauthorizes appropriations under part A of title I of the ESEA for FY2014-FY2018.

Part B: Pathways to College - (Sec. 1201) Replaces part B (Student Reading Skills Improvement Grants) of title I with a new part B (Pathways to College). Establishes, under subpart 1 (Improving Secondary Schools) of part B, a program awarding competitive, matching, five-year grants to high-need LEAs that partner with IHEs, employers or industry-related organizations, and nonprofit organizations or qualified intermediaries to assist schools in implementing innovative and effective secondary school reform strategies. Requires grantees to use up to 25% of their grant funds to:

 implement an early warning indicator system to identify and assist struggling students in their high schools and feeder middle schools; provide support and credit recovery opportunities for struggling secondary school students; establish secondary school dropout recovery or reentry programs; establish grade and school transition programs and supports; and keep school staff, students, and families apprised of certain education requirements, processes, and opportunities. Requires grantees to use at least 75% of their grant funds on certain efforts to: (1) reform secondary schools that have a graduation rate below 75% and are identified as low-performing schools, but not priority schools; and (2) improve the academic performance of students who attend middle schools that feed a majority of their students to those secondary schools.

Requires those secondary school reforms to include:

 personalized learning environments attuned to the needs of each student; student engagement through applied learning opportunities; flexible budget and staffing authority for school leaders; training and collaborative opportunities for school staff; improved curriculum and instruction; activities that strengthen the transition from high school to postsecondary education; and Graduation Promise Academies, Career Academies, dual enrollment programs, or Early College High Schools which represent specified strategies that have proven effective in preparing students for graduation, college, and a career. Establishes a program, under subpart 2 (Accelerated Learning) of part B, allotting grants to states, based on their share of low-income elementary and secondary school students, to cover part or all of the Advanced Placement (AP) or International Baccalaureate (IB) examination fee low-income students incur.

Directs the Secretary to award competitive matching grants to states, high-need LEAs, or partnerships between a public or nonprofit organization and a state or high-need LEA for activities that increase: (1) the number of teachers at high-need schools who are qualified to teach AP or IB courses, and (2) the number of students at high-need schools who pass the examination for such courses.

Gives priority, in awarding the competitive grants, to applicants that: (1) have a statewide or district-wide strategy for increasing the availability of AP or IB courses, and pre-AP or pre-IB courses, in high-need schools; (2) focus on increasing AP or IB courses in core academic subjects; and (3) target high-need schools.

Authorizes appropriations under part B's Pathways to College program for FY2014-FY2018.

Part C: Education of Migratory Children - (Sec. 1301) Amends part C (Education of Migratory Children) of title I, which provides grants to states for the education of migratory children.

(Sec. 1303) Alters the formula for determining each state's grant by considering, in addition to other factors, the average number of migratory children residing in each state the preceding three years, rather than the number of migratory children who resided in each state the previous year.

Requires the Secretary to develop and implement a procedure for monitoring the accuracy of estimates of the number of migratory children residing in each state.

(Sec. 1304) Gives program priority to migratory children who have made a move within the year and are failing or at risk of failing or who have dropped out of school.

(Sec. 1306) Requires migratory children to be given the opportunity to meet the same college and career readiness standards as other children.

(Sec. 1308) Adds international coordination as an authorized use of the grants currently awarded to states, LEAs, IHEs, and other entities for improved intrastate and interstate coordination of migrant education.

Allows the Secretary to provide technical assistance to states to support their efforts to meet the needs of migratory children.

(Sec. 1309) Requires each state that receives a grant under part C to: (1) annually report to the Secretary and make public certain data regarding the academic achievement of migratory students, and (2) assist the Secretary in determining the number of migratory children in such state through such procedures as the Secretary may require.

Requires the Secretary: (1) to evaluate the implementation and impact of the activities supported under part C, and (2) conduct a pilot study on the feasibility of using the National Assessment of Educational Progress for assessing and reporting on the academic achievement of migratory children in grades four and eight in reading and mathematics.

Reauthorizes appropriations under part C of title I of the ESEA for FY2014-FY2018.

Part D: Prevention and Intervention Programs for Children and Youth Who Are Neglected, Delinquent, or At-Risk - (Sec. 1401) Amends part D (Prevention and Intervention Programs for Children and Youth Who are Neglected, Delinquent, or At-Risk) of title I.

(Sec. 1402) Requires the Secretary to reserve 0.5% of the amount appropriated for part D in any fiscal year to provide assistance to the Secretary of the Interior to provide educational services for at-risk Indian children, including Indian youth in correctional facilities operated by the Secretary of the Interior or by an Indian tribe.

 (Sec. 1403) Requires states that desire grants under part D to establish: (1) procedures to ensure that students who have been placed in the juvenile justice system are promptly re-enrolled in secondary school or placed in re-entry programs that best meet their educational and social needs, (2) procedures for facilitating the transfer of credits that such students earned during placement, and (3) opportunities for those students to participate in higher education or career pathways.

(Sec. 1404) Allows states to use grant funds for the cost of testing children and youth for a recognized equivalent of a secondary school diploma.

(Sec. 1407) Requires the Secretary to evaluate the implementation and impact of the activities supported under part D.

(Sec. 1411) Authorizes LEAs to use part D funds on programs for at-risk Indian children and youth in their area.

(Sec. 1412) Requires correctional facilities that enter into an agreement with an LEA to provide services to children and youth under part D to: (1) work with the LEA and family members to develop an initial educational services and transition plan for children or youth upon their entry into the correctional facility, and (2) work with the LEA to facilitate the continued achievement of those children and youth upon their discharge from the correctional facility.

(Sec. 1413) Requires correctional facilities or institutions for delinquent children and youth to annually report: (1) the number of children and youth they have released who returned or did not return to school, (2) the number who obtained a secondary school diploma or its recognized equivalent, and (3) the number who obtained employment.

(Sec. 1414) Requires each state, LEA, and Indian tribe's evaluation of its part D program to assess the program's success in making children and youth college and career ready and able to graduate from high school in a timely manner.

(Sec. 1414) Redefines "at-risk" children or youth as school-aged individuals who: (1) are at risk of academic failure; and (2) have a drug or alcohol problem, are pregnant or are parents, have come into contact with the juvenile justice system or have been determined to have been neglected in the past, are gang members, or have dropped out of school in the past.

Reauthorizes appropriations under part D of title I of the ESEA for FY2014-FY2018.

Part E: Educational Stability of Children in Foster Care - (Sec. 1501) Replaces part E (National Assessment of Subchapter I) of title I with a new part E (Educational Stability of Children in Foster Care).

Requires states to develop and implement a plan to ensure that children who move to a new school attendance area due to being placed in foster care, changing their foster care placement, or leaving foster care: (1) enroll or remain in their school of origin and receive transportation to and from that school, unless it is determined to be in their best interest to attend a different school; (2) are immediately enrolled in a school once it is determined to be in their best interest to attend the school, even if they are unable to produce the records normally required for enrollment; and (3) have their school records maintained and available for immediate transfer to their new school.

Gives a child who leaves foster care the right to remain in his or her school of origin only for the remainder of the school year.

Requires states to ensure that foster children are able to: (1) preserve the credits or partial credits they earned at schools they previously attended, and (2) receive a secondary school diploma from one of the schools at which they were enrolled or through a state-issued secondary school diploma system.

Requires LEAs and state educational agencies to each designate an individual to oversee implementation of their part E obligations and serve as a point of contact for the child welfare agencies responsible for foster children.

Part F: General Provisions - (Sec. 1601) Eliminates parts F (Comprehensive School Reform), G (Advanced Placement Programs), and H (School Dropout Prevention) of title I of the ESEA. Title II: Supporting Teacher and Principal Excellence - (Sec. 2101) Replaces title II (Preparing, Training, and Recruiting High Quality Teachers and Principals) of the ESEA with a new title II (Supporting Teacher and Principal Excellence). Redesignates the Ready-to-Learn Television program (under subpart 3 of part D of title II) as the Ready-to-Learn program under part I of title IV of the ESEA. Redesignates subpart 5 (Teacher Liability Protection) of part C of title II as subpart 3 of part E of title IX (General Provisions) of the ESEA. Strikes parts A (Teacher and Principal Training and Recruiting Fund), B (Mathematics and Science Partnerships), C (Innovation for Teacher Quality), and D (Enhancing Education Through Technology) of title II. Establishes a new part A (Continuous Improvement and Support for Teachers and Principals) of title II. Directs the Secretary, under such program, to make formula grants to states and, through them, subgrants to LEAs to increase achievement for all students. Requires LEAs applying for a subgrant to assure their state that they will create, or improve, and implement a professional growth and improvement system by a date identified by the LEA and approved by the state educational agency that shall not be later than the 2015-2016 school year. Requires the LEAs to use their subgrant funds to address the achievement of students in focus schools, priority schools, and schools not meeting their performance targets through the development and provision of professional development to school staff. Allows LEAs to use subgrant funds to implement strategies that lead to increased student achievement for all students, including: 
 
 developing, implementing, and improving induction or mentoring programs; 
 improving the equitable distribution of teachers within school districts; 
 developing and implementing professional growth and improvement systems; 
 carrying out in-service training for school personnel to recognize troubled children and direct them to appropriate services; 
 increasing the capacity of teachers to evaluate student work and use student achievement data; 
 creating career ladders that enable high-quality teachers or paraprofessionals to advance or take on additional roles and responsibilities; 
 recruiting, preparing, placing, supporting, developing, rewarding, and retaining high-quality teachers and principals in high-need schools and low-performing schools; and 
 reducing class sizes from prekindergarten through grade three. 
 Allocates part A grants to states and, through them, subgrants to LEAs pursuant to formulae that apportion: (1) 35% of the funding to states and 20% of the funding to LEAs based on their share of students aged 5 through 17 on the national and state level, respectively; and (2) 65% of the funding to states and 80% of the funding to LEAs based on their share of low-income students in that age group on the national and state level, respectively.

Requires states to use 95% of their part A grant for subgrants to LEAs. Requires states to use 2% to 5% of their grant to: (1) improve the performance and distribution of high quality principals and, at their discretion, other school leaders; and (2) provide technical assistance to LEAs to support the design and implementation of professional growth and improvement systems.

Directs the Secretary to: (1) continue research and development activities related to the education of gifted and talented students, (2) support a National Research Center on the Gifted and Talented that conducts research and serves as a national clearinghouse for best practices to improve the identification and education of such students, and (3) administer demonstration grants to programs that build and enhance the ability of elementary and secondary school personnel to support gifted and talented students.

Establishes a principal recruitment and training grant program to award renewable, matching grants to states, LEAs or educational service agencies, nonprofit organizations, IHEs, and partnerships of those entities to recruit, prepare, place, and support principals in eligible schools.

Defines "eligible schools" as high-need schools, priority schools, focus schools, schools with middle grades that feed students to high schools with low graduation rates, and rural schools served by high-need LEAs.

Requires grantees to work with experts and stakeholders to develop, during the first year of a grant, a leadership training program for principals, mentors, and other school leaders that prepares and supports them in leading effective school reform efforts in priority schools.

Makes grant renewal decisions dependent on the Secretary's evaluation of the extent to which the principals recruited, prepared, placed, or supported by the grantee have improved school-level student outcomes in eligible schools.

Establishes a new part B (Teacher Pathways to the Classroom) of title II. Directs the Secretary to award renewable, matching grants to eligible entities to:

 recruit, select, prepare, place, retain, and support teachers for high-need schools and high-need subjects or fields; prepare all teachers to teach students with disabilities and English learners; prepare teachers in classroom management, instructional planning and delivery, learning theory and cognitive development, literacy development, and student assessment; provide school-based, clinical experience at a high-need school that includes the observation of, and feedback on, teacher candidates' teaching; and provide ongoing mentoring and support, which may include coursework, for participants for at least one school year. Defines an "eligible entity" as: (1) a partnership of at least one IHE or nonprofit organization and a high-need LEA and at least one other LEA or state educational agency, or (2) an IHE or nonprofit organization experienced in preparing successful teachers and placing them in high-need schools.

Requires grantees to track the placement rate, retention rate, and performance in improving student achievement of teachers recruited and prepared by their programs. Permits the Secretary to renew a grant only if that data indicates that the teachers are successful in improving student achievement.

Requires the Director of the Institute of Education Sciences to: (1) evaluate the implementation and impact of the part B program; (2) identify best practices for recruiting, selecting, preparing, placing, retaining, and supporting teachers in high-need subjects or fields for high-need schools; and (3) disseminate research on best practices.

Establishes a new part C (Teacher Incentive Fund) of title II. Authorizes the Secretary to award competitive renewable grants to states, LEAs, and IHEs or nonprofit organizations that partner with states or LEAs to develop, implement, improve, or expand strategies to increase the number of highly-effective teachers and principals serving in high-need schools.Includes among the acceptable uses of grant funds: (1) paying bonuses and increased salaries to highly effective teachers or principals who work in high-need schools, (2) improving a professional growth and improvement system, (3) reforming the LEA's system of compensating teachers and principals, and (4) developing and implementing a human capital system.

Directs the Secretary to give grant priority to applicants that concentrate their proposed activities: (1) on high-need schools designated as priority schools, or (2) in a state or LEA that has developed a professional growth and improvement system. Establishes a new part D of title II, entitled the Achievement Through Technology and Innovation Act of 2013 or the ATTAIN Act. Allots matching funds to states under part D on the basis of each state's share of funds under part A of title I of the ESEA. Requires states to use: (1) 10% of part D funds for specified mandatory activities that include developing college and career ready academic content and achievement standards in technological literacy and assessing and tracking student performance in acquiring technological literacy, and (2) 80% of the remainder for formula subgrants to LEAs to improve teaching and learning through technology and 20% for competitive subgrants to LEAs for systemic education transformation through technology integration. Requires LEAs to: (1) include a new or updated local long-range strategic educational technology plan in their applications, (2) use a specified percentage of each subgrant for teacher training, and (3) use each subgrant to acquire and apply technology to identify individual student learning needs and support personalized learning. Allows LEAs that receive funds for both programs to use all the funds for systemic school redesign through technology integration program activities.

Prohibits the use of part D funds to pay for computers or Internet access for schools that do not receive discounted telecommunication rates under the universal service program, unless the school has in place and enforces an Internet safety policy that includes the operation of a technology protection measure that blocks visual depictions that are obscene, child pornography, or harmful to minors.

Authorizes appropriations under title II of the ESEA for FY2014-FY2018.

 Title III: Language and Academic Content Instruction for English Learners and Immigrant Students - (Sec. 3001) Revises title III (Language Instruction for Limited English Proficient and Immigrant Students) of the ESEA and renames it (Language and Academic Content Instruction for English Learners and Immigrant Students).

 Changes the current references to "limited English proficient students" to "English learners." Amends part A (English Language Acquisition, Language Enhancement, and Academic Achievement Act), which provides funding to states and, through them, subgrants to LEAs to improve the education of English learners.

Authorizes Indian tribes and educational entities that carry out programs in schools operated predominately for Native American children to use part A subgrants for Native American language immersion and restoration programs, which may be taught by traditional or tribal leaders.

Requires states to establish a performance target for the percentage of English learners they serve who are making progress in achieving English proficiency not more that five years after being identified as English learners. Requires states that fail to meet their performance target for two consecutive years to develop an improvement plan to meet the target.

Requires LEAs to: (1) enter into agreements with their state on local English proficiency performance targets, and (2) develop and implement an improvement plan to meet those targets if they fail to meet them for two consecutive years.

Directs states to: (1) require an LEA that fails to meet its performance target for three consecutive years to develop and implement a plan to modify its curriculum, program, and method of instruction; and (2) manage an LEA's subgrant funds for the lesser of four years or until its performance target is reached, if the LEA misses its performance target for a fourth consecutive year.

Requires states that fail to meet their performance targets for four consecutive years to: (1) modify their plan under part A and instructional methods, and (2) partner their low-performing LEAs with their high-performing LEAs that have met their local performance targets for the previous three years.

Revises the professional development grant program for English language instructors to allow IHEs or nonprofit organizations, in consortia with states or LEAs, to use the grants to support:

individuals that are completing baccalaureate and masters programs and to improve services and programs for English learners; 
 research on promising instructional strategies or programs; 
 strategies that promote school readiness for English learners; 
 strategies that promote high school graduation for English learners; 
 strategies that strengthen and increase family and community member engagement in education; 
 the development of curricula that are appropriate to the needs of the participating consortium; and 
 the dissemination of information, best practices, and technical assistance. 
 
 Directs the Secretary to establish an independent commission on the assessment and advancement of English learners, comprised of experts capable of providing the Secretary with advice regarding the educational advancement and development of English learners and their inclusion in state assessment and accountability systems.

Requires the Secretary to distribute English language acquisition technology innovation grants for the pursuit of breakthrough research and development in educational technology that benefits English learners.

Eliminates the Improving Language Instruction Educational Programs under part B of title III.

Authorizes appropriations under title III of the ESEA for FY2014-FY2018.

Title IV: Supporting Successful, Well-Rounded Students - (Sec. 4101) Replaces title IV (21st Century Schools) of the ESEA with a new title IV (Supporting Successful, Well-Rounded Students).

(Sec. 4102) Replaces part A (Safe and Drug-Free Schools and Communities) of title IV with a new part A (Improving Literacy Instruction and Student Achievement).

Authorizes the Secretary, under subpart 1 (Improving Literacy Instruction) of part A, to award planning grants to states to complete comprehensive planning to carry out activities that improve literacy for children from birth through grade 12.

Requires grantees to form or designate a state literacy leadership team, composed of individuals having certain literacy expertise, to guide the development and implementation of the comprehensive, statewide literacy plan.

Directs the Secretary to award grants to states to implement their comprehensive literacy plans and to award competitive subgrants to: (1) LEAs and early childhood education providers that serve high-need children to support certain early literacy initiatives for children from birth through kindergarten entry; (2) LEAs that serve a high number or proportion of low-income children, children reading or writing below grade level, or priority schools to implement certain literacy initiatives for children in kindergarten through grade 12.

Includes among the literacy initiatives: (1) the acquisition and implementation of literacy assessments, (2) efforts targeting students reading and writing below grade level, (3) professional development opportunities for educators, and (4) family literacy services.

Requires state grantees to: (1) provide technical assistance to subgrantees, (2) work with the state literacy leadership team and IHEs to include evidence-based literacy methods in preservice courses for students preparing to teach children from birth through grade 12, (3) review and update state licensure or certification standards in literacy instruction, and (4) make information on promising child literacy improvement practices available to the public.

Awards the implementation grants to states: (1) on a competitive basis if funds appropriated under subpart 1 of part A fall below $500 million; and (2) otherwise on the basis of each state's share of low-income children under age 18.

Requires states to use at least: (1) 10% of the grant funds for state and local activities pertaining to children from birth through kindergarten entry, (2) 30% of the grant funds for state and local activities pertaining to children from kindergarten through grade 5, and (3) 30% of the grant funds for state and local activities pertaining to children from grades 6 through 12.

Directs the Secretary to arrange for an independent five-year evaluation of the grant and subgrant programs assisted under subpart 1 and make its findings and the results of additional research on literacy instruction available to literacy providers.

Establishes a new program under subpart 2 (Improving Literacy and College and Career Readiness Through Effective School Library Programs) of part A authorizing the Secretary to award competitive three-year grants to certain LEAs to develop and enhance effective school library programs. Makes LEAs or consortia of LEAs eligible for such grants only if: (1) at least 20% of their students are impoverished, or (2) their percentage of impoverished children is in the highest quartile among all LEAs in the state.

Defines an "effective school library program" as one that: (1) is staffed by a state sanctioned school librarian; (2) has up-to-date materials and technology, including broadband; (3) includes regular collaboration between teachers and school librarians concerning school reform efforts; and (4) supports the development of digital literacy skills.

Redesignates subpart 3 (Gun Possession) of part A of title IV as subpart 1 of a new part G (Miscellaneous Provisions) of title IX (General Provisions) of the ESEA.

(Sec. 4103) Moves part B (21st Century Community Learning Centers) to a new part F of title IV of the ESEA.

Creates a new part B (Improving Science, Technology, Engineering, and Mathematics Instruction and Student Achievement). Directs the Secretary, under subpart 1 (Improving STEM Instruction and Student Achievement) of part B, to allot formula grants to states and, through them, award competitive subgrants to high-need LEAs, educational service agencies serving such LEAs, or certain outside partners of those entities to improve preschool and elementary and secondary school science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM) education. Defines those "outside partners" as nonprofit or community based organizations, businesses, IHEs, or educational service agencies that have expertise and a demonstrated record of success in improving STEM learning and engagement.

Allots such grants to states pursuant to a formula that takes into account each state's share of elementary and secondary school students and each state's share of such students who are low-income students.

Awards the grants to states on a competitive basis if this subpart's funding falls below $500 million. Authorizes the Secretary to award capacity-building grants to states to help them qualify for competitive grants.

Requires the grants to be used to: (1) increase the access to STEM courses of students who belong to groups that are underrepresented in STEM fields, (2) implement evidence-based programs of instruction based on high-quality standards and assessments in the STEM subjects, (3) provide professional development and other support systems to STEM educators, and (4) provide technical assistance to subgrantees and other high-need schools and LEAs to improve students' STEM achievement and narrow achievement gaps.

Requires the subgrants to be used for activities that include: (1) recruiting, supporting, evaluating, and training STEM teachers; (2) developing and improving high-quality STEM curricula and instructional supports to improve student achievement in those subjects; and (3) integrating STEM instruction with instruction in reading, English language arts, or other academic subjects.

Directs states to require subgrantees to obtain a commitment from one or more outside partners to match, from nonfederal funds, at least 15% of the subgrant funds.

Directs the Secretary to establish performance metrics and use those metrics to evaluate subpart 1 activities and identify best practices to improve STEM instruction.

Directs the Secretary, under subpart 2 (STEM Master Teacher Corps Program) of part B, to award competitive matching grants to consortia of LEAs or states, acting in partnership with IHEs or nonprofit organizations to establish a STEM Master Teacher Corps program.

Requires grantees to:

 select exemplary elementary and secondary school STEM teachers for membership in the STEM Master Teacher Corps; provide those teachers with compensation that supplements their base salaries, with higher compensation going to those teaching at high-need public schools; provide, and track the effectiveness of, research-based training for Corps members; provide discretionary resources for Corps members at high-need schools to use; help coordinate instructional leadership and mentoring roles for Corps members; facilitate efforts by Corps members to inform STEM education policy at the national, state, and local levels; and help defray the costs associated with affording Corps members the time to fulfill their duties. Gives grant priority to applicants that intend to include: (1) large numbers of teachers in the STEM Master Teacher Corps; and (2) rural schools, particularly high-need rural schools, in the area they serve.

Requires grantees to ensure that at least 75% of their STEM Master Teacher Corps are teachers at high-need schools.

Authorizes the Secretary to award planning grants to such consortia to make plans to establish the STEM Master Teacher Corps program.

Directs the Secretary to: (1) establish performance metrics to evaluate the program; (2) identify optimal strategies for designing and advancing the program; and (3) identify best practices for developing, supporting, and retaining STEM teachers based on lessons learned from the program.

(Sec. 4104) Redesignates part C (Environmental Tobacco Smoke) of title IV as subpart 2 of the new part G of title IX. Establishes a new part C (Increasing Access to a Well-Rounded Education and Financial Literacy) of title IV.

Directs the Secretary, under subpart 1 (Increasing Access to a Well-Rounded Education) of part C, to allot formula grants to states that enter into partnerships with nonprofit organizations, IHEs, LEAs, educational service agencies, or other states to increase the access of low-income students, English learners, and disabled students to high-quality instruction in the arts, civics and government, economics, environmental education, financial literacy, foreign languages, geography, health education, history, music, physical education, or social studies. Requires grantees to do this by: (1) improving the knowledge and skills of teachers through professional growth and improvement systems and other instructional supports; and/or (2) building local capacity to develop and implement high-quality curricula, instructional supports, and assessments in those subjects. Authorizes grantees to award competitive subgrants to high-need LEAs or educational service agencies to engage in such activities.

Allots the grants to states pursuant to a formula that takes into account each state's share of elementary and secondary school students and each state's share of such students who are low-income students. Awards the grants on a competitive basis if this subpart's funding falls below $500 million. Directs the Secretary to: (1) establish performance metrics and use those metrics to evaluate subpart 1 activities, and (2) identify best practices to improve such instruction.

Authorizes the Secretary, under subpart 2 (Financial Literacy Education) of part C (entitled the Financial Literacy for Students Act), to award matching grants to states to: (1) integrate financial literacy education into each of their public elementary and secondary schools that are eligible for school improvement funds under title I of the ESEA, and (2) train their secondary school financial literacy or entrepreneurship teachers to teach financial literacy in core academic subjects.

Prohibits states from using over 20% of their grant funds to train those teachers, develop curricula, and evaluate the impact of financial literacy or personal finance education on students' understanding of financial literacy concepts.

 (Sec. 4105) Establishes a new part D (Successful, Safe, and Healthy Students) of title IV, under which the Secretary allots formula grants to states to: (1) develop, improve, and implement state reporting and information systems that measure conditions for learning, based on surveys of school students and staff; and (2) award competitive subgrants to LEAs or nonprofit organizations that use such measurement systems to make comprehensive improvements to school-level conditions for learning. Allots such grants to states pursuant to a formula that takes into account each state's share of school improvement funds under part A of title I of the ESEA. Awards the grants on a competitive basis if this part's funding falls below $500 million. Identifies conditions conducive to learning as those that: (1) promote physical activity, education, fitness, and nutrition; (2) promote mental health; (3) prevent violence, harassment, and substance abuse among students; and (4) promote safe and supportive schools and communities.

Conditions a state's grant eligibility on its: (1) having a statewide physical education requirement that is consistent with widely recognized standards; and (2) requiring its LEAs to establish policies that prevent and prohibit harassment in schools, notify students, parents, and educational professionals of prohibited conduct each year, and provide students and parents with grievance procedures that target such conduct.

Requires each state to ensure that of the aggregate subgrant funds they award under this program: (1) at least 20% are used for drug and violence prevention; (2) at least 20% are used to promote mental health; and (3) at least 20% are used to promote physical activity, education, fitness, and nutrition.

Directs the Secretary to: (1) establish performance metrics and use those metrics to evaluate part D activities; and (2) provide technical assistance to program applicants, grantees, and subgrantees.

Authorizes the Secretary to award grants to LEAs to fund certain actions they deem necessary to improve the learning environment at a school that has experienced a violent or traumatic crisis on campus. Requires LEAs to use such grants to: (1) acquire real property; (2) construct new facilities; or (3) renovate, repair, or alter existing facilities for an elementary and secondary school that has experienced such a crisis. Prohibits the grant from covering more than 50% of an LEA's cost in taking such actions.

(Sec. 4106) Establishes a new part E of title IV, entitled the Student Non-Discrimination Act of 2013.

Prohibits public school students from being excluded from participating in, or subject to discrimination under, any federally-assisted educational program on the basis of their actual or perceived sexual orientation or gender identity or that of their associates. Considers harassment to be a form of discrimination.

Prohibits retaliation against anyone for opposing conduct made unlawful under this part.

Authorizes federal departments and agencies to enforce these prohibitions by cutting off the educational assistance of recipients found to be violating them. Allows aggrieved individuals to assert a violation of this part in a judicial proceeding and recover reasonable attorney's fees should they prevail. Authorizes the Attorney General to institute a civil action in any appropriate U.S. district court for a violation of this Act.

Deems an educational agency's or state's receipt of federal educational assistance for a program to constitute a waiver of sovereign immunity for conduct prohibited under this part regarding such program.

(Sec. 4107) Revises the 21st Century Community Learning Centers program, which this Act moves from part B of title IV to a new part F of title IV of the ESEA. (Currently, that program awards formula grants to states and, through them, competitive subgrants to LEAs, community-based organizations, and other public or private entities to carry out a broad array of before- and after-school activities that advance student academic achievement.)

Includes before- and after-school, summer learning, and expanded learning time activities in the program.

Requires the subgrants to be awarded to partnerships composed of high-need LEAs and public entities or nonprofit organizations experienced in designing and implementing before-school, after-school, summer learning, or expanded learning time activities.

Eliminates the requirement that the subgrants serve students who primarily attend schools that serve a high percentage of low-income students or schools eligible for participation in Schoolwide programs under part A of title I of the ESEA. (Schoolwide programs allow LEAs to consolidate school improvement funds to upgrade the entire educational program of schools that serve a high proportion of low-income families.) Requires, instead, that the subgrants serve students who primarily attend high-need schools and schools that are identified as focus or priority schools.

Allows the subgrant to be provided for a period of up to three years and, if the subgrantee meets certain performance standards established by the state, renewed for an additional two-year period.

Requires states to give priority to subgrant applications that: (1) are based on strong research evidence for improving student learning, (2) propose to serve the highest percentage of low-income students, (3) include specified partnership commitments, and (4) are submitted by entities that will provide matching funds.

(Sec. 4108) Establishes a new part G of title IV, entitled the Promise Neighborhoods Act of 2013.

Directs the Secretary, under new subpart 1 (Promise Neighborhood Partnership Grants), to award renewable, competitive, matching grants to nonprofit organizations to implement a comprehensive continuum of coordinated services and supports that engage community partners in improving the academic achievement, health and social development, and college and career readiness of children who live in distressed neighborhoods with schools identified as focus or priority schools.

Directs the Secretary, under new subpart 2 (Promise School Grants), to award renewable, competitive, matching grants to high-need LEAs that partner with nonprofit organizations or IHEs, and to Indian schools that partner with nonprofit organizations or IHEs, to implement school-centered strategies and integrated student supports that leverage community partnerships to improve student achievement and development in schools with high concentrations of low-income children. Gives priority to applicants that propose to: (1) include significant investments in high-quality early learning programs, and (2) give schools the operational flexibility to carry out grant activities.

Requires part G grantees to evaluate their programs continuously and improve them based on data and outcomes. Directs the Secretary to use certain performance metrics to determine the eligibility of part G grantees for continued funding and renewal of their grant. Directs the Secretary to evaluate this part's grant programs and disseminate research on best practices for improving the academic and developmental outcomes of children living in our most distressed communities.

(Sec. 4109) Establishes a new part H (Parent and Family Information and Resource Centers) of title IV.

Authorizes the Secretary to award competitive, matching, five-year grants to nonprofit organizations or consortia consisting of a nonprofit organization and a state or LEA to operate state parent and family information and resource centers.

Requires those centers to:

 assist the state in identifying, implementing, and replicating effective parent, family, and community engagement strategies; provide technical assistance, training, information, and support regarding parent and family engagement to high-need schools, schools that are served by high-need LEAs, and early care and education providers that primarily serve low-income parents and families; and strengthen partnerships among parents, family members, community-based organizations, early care and education providers, schools, LEAs, employers, and other appropriate community members to improve student achievement and support positive child development. Requires grantees to: (1) be governed by a board of directors, at least 50% of which is composed of members who are community stakeholders or parents or family members of school-age children in the state, (2) use at least 60% of their grant funds to support parent and family engagement in high-need local educational areas, and (3) reserve at least 30% of their grant funds to support parent and family engagement of low-income parents and family members whose children attend early childhood education programs.

Requires at least one grant to be awarded to an eligible entity in each state.

Requires each grantee to establish annual performance goals for its centers. Terminates a grantee's funding if its center fails to meet those performance goals for two consecutive years.

Prohibits: (1) any individual from being required to participate in any parent or family education program or any developmental screening program under part H, and (2) a program or center assisted under part H from infringing on a parent's right to direct his or her child's education.

Transfers the Ready-to-Learn Television program, currently under subpart 3 of part D of title II, to a new part I (Ready-to-Learn) of title IV of the ESEA.

(Sec. 4110) Transfers subpart 1 (Fund for the Improvement of Education) of part D of title V of the ESEA to a new part J (Programs of National Significance) of title IV of the ESEA. Requires part J funds to support nationally significant programs that help all children meet the college and career ready academic content and achievement standards required by this Act. Directs program grants to states or LEAs, IHEs, and other public and nonprofit entities.

Allows nonprofit entities to use part J funds for:

civic learning; 
 a national principal and teacher certification process; 
 a national corps of outstanding college graduates to teach in underserved communities; 
 a national network of providers of effective professional development in writing instruction; 
 certain efforts to encourage low-income children to read and caregivers to read to their children; 
 programs to engage and support students who are recent immigrants or whose formal education has been interrupted and their families; 
 researching and promoting the use of instructional technology and strategies to drastically accelerate language acquisition by English learners and assist them in accessing rigorous academic content; 
 programs that encourage the disabled, children, youth, and educators to become involved in the performing and visual arts; 
 efforts to enhance the ability of educators to meet the special educational needs of gifted and talented students in high-poverty schools; 
 programs to engage and support students who experience homelessness or are at risk of homelessness and their families; 
 the provision of social, emotional, and academic support to students from military families and their families; 
 financial literacy education for low-income students; 
 the promotion of gender equity in education; and 
 other high-quality, nationally significant programs that improve elementary and secondary education. 
 
 (Sec. 4111) Establishes a new part K (Competency-Based Assessment and Accountability Demonstration Authority) of title IV, which authorizes the Secretary to provide states with the authority to incorporate competency-based targets for student learning in their title I accountability systems.

Authorizes the Secretary to provide states with that authority for a three-year period and renew that authority for additional two-year periods if they demonstrate student progress on state academic assessments and graduation rates. Limits the availability of this authority to three states or consortia of states during the initial three-years of the program.

Defines "competency," for purposes of part K, as a target for student learning representing key content-specific concepts and higher order skills, such as critical thinking, problem solving, and self-directed learning, that is applied within or across content domains and is aligned with college and career ready standards.

Directs the Secretary to disseminate best practices on the implementation of competency-based accountability systems.

Authorizes appropriations under title IV of the ESEA for FY2014-FY2018.

Title V: Promoting Innovation - (Sec. 5001) Replaces title V (Promoting Informed Parental Choice and Innovative Programs) of the ESEA with a new title V (Promoting Innovation).

Part A: Race to the Top - (Sec. 5101) Creates a new part A (Race to the Top) of title V that awards grants to states and high-need LEAs to carry out one or more educational goals selected by the Secretary.

Lists those goals as:

 increasing the access of low-income children to highly-rated teachers and school leaders; enhancing the availability and use of high-quality, timely data to improve education; implementing academic standards that prepare students to be college and career ready and strategies that translate those standards into classroom practice; turning around focus or priority schools; creating successful conditions for the creation, expansion, and replication of high-performing public charter schools and the creation of new, innovative, and highly autonomous public schools that will enroll a large percentage of students from low-income families; providing more equitable state and local resources to high-poverty schools; and improving school readiness by increasing the enrollment of low-income children in high-quality early childhood education programs and strengthening the coordination of those programs and services on the federal, state, and local level. Gives grant priority to: (1) high-need LEAs that serve schools in remote towns or rural areas; and (2) high-need LEAs and states that provide a full-day kindergarten program to all kindergarten students or all low-income kindergarten students, if the grant goal is to improve childhood education.

Requires each grantee to: (1) have a comprehensive and coherent plan for achieving the goals selected by the Secretary; and (2) establish annual performance measures and targets, approved by the Secretary, to track its progress in implementing the plan and to determine its eligibility for continued grant funding.

Requires each state grantee, other than those using the grant to improve childhood education, to use at least 50% of its grant for subgrants to LEAs that participate in its plan.

Part B: Investing in Innovation - (Sec. 5201) Creates a new part B (Investing in Innovation) of title V. Allows the Secretary to reserve up to 30%, but no more than $100 million, of the funds appropriated each fiscal year for the Programs of National Significance, under part J of title IV of the ESEA, to carry out the activities of the Advanced Research Projects Agency-Education (ARPA-ED) (established by section 11021 of this Act) under the Department of Education Organization Act.

Directs the Secretary to award renewable, competitive grants to LEAs, or to partnerships between nonprofit organizations or educational service agencies and LEAs or consortia of public schools, to support the school innovation efforts of public schools and LEAs.

Requires at least 22% of the grant funds to be awarded for projects in rural areas.

Gives priority to applicants that propose to address the needs of high-need LEAs, improve school readiness, or address the unique needs of students who are disabled or English learners.

Requires each grant applicant to demonstrate that it has partnered with at least one public or private organization that will provide matching funds. Allows the Secretary to waive the matching funds requirement upon a showing of exceptional circumstances.

Requires each grant to be used to carry out at least one of the following activities:

improving the effectiveness of teachers and school leaders and increasing the equity in the distribution of effective teachers and leaders; 
 strengthening the use of data to improve education; 
 providing high-quality instruction that is based on college and career ready standards and measuring students' mastery of standards using high-quality assessments that are aligned to those standards; 
 turning around the lowest-performing schools; 
 improving the school readiness of students who are low-income students, English learners, or disabled; and 
 any other area of school improvement the Secretary determines to be consistent with this part's purposes. 
 
 Directs the Secretary to establish performance measures for part B programs and activities that, at a minimum, track each grantee's progress in improving outcomes for specified student subgroups served by the grantee.

Requires grantees to use grant funds to develop or expand strategies to improve high-need students' showing on those performance measures.

Part C: Magnet Schools Assistance - (Sec. 5301) Revises part C (Magnet Schools Assistance) of title V, which provides grants to LEAs to establish and operate magnet schools under a court-ordered desegregation plan or voluntary desegregation plan approved by the Secretary. (Sec. 5302) Requires such grants to be competitive grants.

(Sec. 5304) Gives grant priority to applicants that: (1) have the highest quality applications or demonstrate the greatest need for assistance; (2) propose to carry out new magnet school programs or substantially revise or expand existing programs; (3) select, or propose to select, students solely or primarily by lottery; and (4) propose to serve the entire population of a school.

(Sec. 5305) Adds as authorized uses of grant funds: (1) compensating highly-rated school teachers, leaders, and other instructional staff; (2) forming partnerships with public or nonprofit organizations to enhance a program or promote parent and family decision making and engagement; and (3) covering operational costs that cannot be met with state or local funds.

(Sec. 5306) Allows a grant to be renewed for an additional two years (after the initial period of up to three years) if the Secretary finds that the grantee is improving student academic achievement and reducing minority group isolation.

Part D: Public Charter Schools - (Sec. 5401) Replaces the existing Public Charter Schools program under part B of title V with a new Public Charter Schools program under part D of title V. Establishes under part D: (1) a subpart 1 (Successful Charter Schools Program), to which 85% of this part's funding is devoted; and (2) a subpart 2 (Charter School Facility Acquisition, Construction, and Renovation), to which 15% of this part's funding is devoted. Defines a "charter school" as a public school that: (1) is governed by a separate and independent board that exercises authority over at least one school; and (2) has significant autonomy in the areas of staffing, budget, schedule, and instructional programs.

Directs the Secretary, under subpart 1, to award competitive grants to states, LEAs, charter school authorizers, or charter management organizations to award subgrants to developers to create, expand, or replicate high-performing charter schools.

Defines "high-performing charter schools" as those that have for the student body and each specified student subgroup: (1) academic achievement and growth results that are significantly higher than the average results in demographically similar schools in the state; (2) student retention rates that are similar to or higher than the average rates in demographically similar schools in the state; and (3) for high schools, higher rates of graduation and student enrollment and persistence at IHEs than the average such rates in demographically similar schools in the state.

Requires charter schools that are not yet open to have a written performance contract with a charter school authorizer that includes such goals.

Directs the Secretary to award at least 25% of the grant funds to states and to give priority to states that: (1) do not prohibit or effectively inhibit increasing the number of high-performing charter schools in such state; (2) support at least two charter school authorizers, at least one of which is a statewide authorizer; and (3) ensure that charter schools are reauthorized or have their charter renewed at least once every five years.

Sets the initial term of a grant at no more than three years, but allows the Secretary to renew a grant for an additional two years if the grantee is achieving grant objectives and performance targets.

Permits the Secretary to waive certain statutory or regulatory requirements if the waiver is requested by a grant applicant and promotes the purpose of the grant program without affecting what is definitionally required of charter schools.

Requires grantees to provide equitable access to, and effectively serve the needs of, all students, including disabled children and English learners.

Gives grant priority to applicants, and subgrant priority to developers, that propose to create, expand, or replicate high-performing charter schools that enroll a large percentage of students from low-income families.

Requires each grantee to establish performance measures and annual targets, approved by the Secretary, for the charter schools created, expanded, or replicated with funds under subpart 1.

Authorizes the Secretary to reserve up to 5% of subpart 1 funding to carry out national research, development, data collection, technical assistance, outreach, and dissemination activities regarding charter schools.

Directs the Secretary to use 65% of subpart 2 (Charter School Facility Acquisition, Construction, and Renovation) funds for competitive grants to states, LEAs, nonprofit organizations, and state financing authorities to demonstrate innovative credit enhancement methods that give high-performing charter schools access to private sector capital to acquire, construct, and renovate their facilities. (The current program awards all subpart 2 funds to public and private nonprofit entities to demonstrate innovative means of enhancing credit to finance the acquisition, construction, or renovation of charter schools.)

Requires the Secretary to use the remainder of the subpart 2 funds to award competitive grants to: (1) those entities to improve access to facilities and facilities financing for high-performing charter schools through such methods as leveraging state and local facilities funds or implementing open-facilities-access programs; and (2) states to establish, enhance, and administer per-pupil facilities aid programs (which provide annual state funding to charter schools on a per-pupil basis) through federal payments that are scaled down after each year of assistance.

Allows state grantees to partner with another entity or entities that cover up to 50% of the state's share of the per-pupil facilities aid program.

Part E: Voluntary Public School Choice - (Sec. 5501) Revises subpart 3 (Voluntary Public School Choice Programs) of part B of title V and moves it to part E of title V. Directs the Secretary to award competitive grants to high-need LEAs that partner with other LEAs and states that partner with high-need LEAs to establish or expand inter- or intra-district public school choice programs that enable students attending focus or priority schools to attend high-quality public schools, including charter schools. Sets the initial term of a grant at no more than three years, but allows the Secretary to renew a grant for an additional two years if the grantee is achieving grant objectives.

Gives priority to grant applicants that propose to establish or expand: (1) an inter-district choice program that serves a large percentage of students from low-income families, and (2) a program that will increase diversity.

Requires grantees to: (1) disseminate timely and accurate information about their school choice program to the parents of students attending achievement gap or persistently low-achieving schools; (2) select students to participate in the program on the basis of a lottery, if more students apply to participate in the program than can be accommodated; and (3) establish performance measures and targets that are approved by the Secretary.

Directs the Secretary to evaluate the implementation and impact of the activities supported under part E.

Part F: College Information Demonstration Program - (Sec. 5601) Creates a new part F (College Information Demonstration Program) of title V that requires the Secretary to develop a packet of postsecondary education information that: (1) informs secondary school students about the net price of IHEs and available financial aid, and (2) gives them guidance on how to apply to IHEs and seek financial assistance. Requires the Secretary, to the extent possible, to customize that information based on students' geographical location and family income.

Gives priority for demonstration program participation to high-need schools that have little or no access to postsecondary education counseling services.

Directs the Secretary to evaluate, and report to Congress on, the effectiveness of the demonstration program in increasing the likelihood that students will apply to an IHE, apply for financial aid, enroll in an IHE, and receive financial aid.

Authorizes appropriations under title V of the ESEA for FY2014-FY2018.

Title VI: Promoting Flexibility; Rural Education - (Sec. 6101) Redesignates title VI (Flexibility and Accountability) of the ESEA as title VI (Promoting Flexibility; Rural Education). Replaces part A (Improving Academic Achievement) of title VI with a new part A (Transferability) that allows states to transfer up to 100% of the funds they are allotted for state-level activities by an ESEA formula grant to other state formula grant programs under the ESEA.

Allows LEAs to transfer up to 100% of the funds they are allotted for local-level activities by an ESEA formula grant to other LEA formula grant programs under the ESEA.

Allows rural LEAs to transfer up to 100% of the funds they are allotted for local-level activities by an ESEA formula grant to: (1) other LEA formula grant programs under the ESEA, or (2) carry out activities under formula grant programs for states.

Prohibits states from transferring any funds that originate in titles I or III, and prohibits LEAs from transferring any funds that originate in title I, III, VII (part A), or VIII, out of each respective title.

(Sec. 6102) Amends part B (Rural Education Initiatives) of title VI of the ESEA. Amends the small, rural school achievement (SRSA) program, under subpart 1 of part B, to strike LEA funding flexibility provisions that are superseded by those in part A of title VI.

Increases the minimum and maximum amount of SRSA program funds a rural LEA may receive if appropriations under part B exceed a specified amount.

Updates the locale codes used in determining LEA eligibility for SRSA program funds and funds under the Rural and Low-Income School (RLIS) program, under subpart 2 of part B, as rural LEAs.

Allows LEAs to use RLIS program funds on local-level activities.

Gives LEAs that qualify for funding under both the SRSA and RLIS programs the option to choose the program for which they would prefer to receive funding.

Authorizes appropriations under title VI of the ESEA for FY2014-FY2018.

Title VII: Indian, Native Hawaiian, and Alaska Native Education - Part A: Indian Education - Subpart 1: Formula Grants to Local Educational Agencies - (Sec. 7101) Amends title VII (Indian, Native Hawaiian, and Alaska Native Education) of the ESEA to restate the purposes of such title to include providing support to ensure the academic achievement of American Indian and Alaska Native students by meeting their unique cultural, language, and educational needs.

(Sec. 7111) Amends subpart 1 (Formula Grants to Local Educational Agencies) of part A (Indian Education) of title VII to allow Indian tribes and Indian organizations to receive such grants if an eligible LEA fails to establish a committee of tribal representatives, Indian students and their family members, and teachers to participate in the development of an Indian education program. Allows Indian community-based organizations to apply for such grants if those entities do not.

Allows eligible LEAs, Indian tribes, and Indian organizations to form consortia with other eligible LEAs, Indian tribes, and Indian organizations to apply for the formula grants and operate the grant programs.

Increases the minimum amount of such grant.

(Sec. 7115) Adds to the list of grant uses: (1) support for Native American language immersion and restoration programs, which may be taught by traditional leaders; (2) education to prevent violence, suicide, and substance abuse; (3) the incorporation of culturally and linguistically relevant curriculum content into classroom instruction that is responsive to the unique learning styles of Indian and Alaska Native children; and (4) dropout prevention strategies and strategies that meet the needs of at-risk Indian students in correctional facilities and those transitioning out of those facilities into schools.

Prohibits the use of the grant funds for long-distance travel for training that is available locally or regionally.

(Sec. 7116) Directs the Secretary, when reporting to Congress on demonstration projects that allow subpart 1 grantees to integrate education and related services to Indians, to identify those integrative practices that are best at improving academic outcomes for Indian and Alaska Native students.

(Sec. 7117) Requires the Secretary to provide technical assistance, upon request, to grantees to support subpart 1 services and activities.

Subpart 2: Special Programs and Projects to Improve Educational Opportunities for Indian Children and Youth - (Sec. 7121) Amends subpart 2 (Special Programs and Projects to Improve Educational Opportunities for Indian Children and Youth) of part A of title VII to revise the program awarding grants to states, LEAs, and Indian entities and schools for the improvement of educational opportunities for Indian children and youth.

(Sec. 7122) Allows the Secretary to award such grants for up to three years and renew them for two additional years. (Currently, they may be awarded for up to five years but must be shown to be effective within one year to be continued.)

Allows the use of program grants for high-quality early childhood education programs that are effective in preparing young children to achieve sufficient academic growth by the end of grade three.

(Sec. 7123) Amends the program awarding grants to IHEs, states or LEAs in consortia with IHEs, and Indian entities and schools for the professional development of teachers and education professionals to require grant applicants to describe how they will: (1) recruit qualified Indians to become teachers and principals; (2) use the grant funds to support the recruitment, preparation, and training of Indian teachers or principals in LEAs that serve a high proportion of Indian students; and (3) assist program participants in meeting their service obligations.

Allows the Secretary to award such grants for up to three years and renew them for two additional years. (Currently, they may be awarded for up to five years.)

Subpart 3: National Activities - (Sec. 7131) Preserves the national research activities under subpart 3 (National Activities) of part A of title VII, but strikes: (1) the in-service training for teachers of Indian children program, (2) the fellowships for Indian students program, (3) the gifted and talented Indian students program, (4) the grants to tribes for education administrative planning and development program, and (5) the improvement of educational opportunities for adult Indians program.

Establishes a new program requiring the Secretary to award grants to states, LEAs, and Indian entities for: (1) Native American language programs, and (2) Native American language restoration programs.

Directs the Secretary to conduct a study to improve the collaboration between states and LEAs, other relevant state and local agencies, and Indian tribes in the provision of services to Indian students.

Subpart 4: Federal Administration - (Sec. 7141) Directs the National Advisory Council on Indian Education to advise the Secretary and the Secretary of the Interior concerning the funding and administration of any program under their jurisdiction that includes as participants, or that may benefit, Indian children or adults. (Currently, the Council is only required to advise the Secretary.)

Subpart 5: Definitions; Authorization of Appropriations - (Sec. 7151) Defines "traditional leaders" as Native Americans who have special expertise in Native American culture and languages. Requires their incorporation into activities that support the unique cultural and educational needs of Indian children under subparts 1 and 2.

Authorizes appropriations under part A for FY2014-FY2018.

Part B: Native Hawaiian Education; Alaska Native Education - (Sec. 7201) Places the Native Hawaiian Education program in a subpart 1 of part B of title VII. Moves the Alaska Native Education program from part C of title VII to a subpart 2 of part B of title VII. Subpart 1: Native Hawaiian Education - (Sec. 7202) Revises the Native Hawaiian Education program.

(Sec. 7204) Requires the Native Hawaiian Education Council to be composed of 15 members who: (1) are from certain educational, governmental, Trust, and grant-making entities; and (2) demonstrate at least five years of experience as consumers or providers of Native Hawaiian education or cultural activities.

Sets the term of the federal grant to the Council at five years.

Directs the Council to:

 provide technical assistance to Native Hawaiian organizations that apply for or receive Native Hawaiian Education program grants; assess and define the educational needs of Native Hawaiians; assess the programs and services available to address those needs; gather information regarding, and evaluate the effectiveness of, the grant programs under subpart 1; provide direction and guidance to appropriate federal, state, and local agencies to improve the use of resources relating to Native Hawaiian student education; and hire an executive director to enable the Council to carry out these activities. Requires the Council to hold at least one community consultation each year on each of the islands of Hawaii, Maui, Molokai, Lanai, Oahu, and Kauai regarding subpart 1 grants and other Native Hawaiian education issues.

Eliminates the requirement that the Council meet at least four times each year with an island council composed of parents, students, and other Native Hawaiian education stakeholders.

(Sec. 7205) Includes charter schools as eligible recipients of Native Hawaiian Education program grants, in addition to Native Hawaiian education organizations, Native Hawaiian community-based organizations, and public and private nonprofit entities. Gives grant priority to programs that: (1) meet the educational priorities recommended by the Council; (2) meet the unique cultural and linguistic needs of Native Hawaiian students in order to help them meet the college and career ready state academic content and achievement standards; and (3) involve states, LEAs, or IHEs in partnerships or consortia.

Includes workforce preparation and training for Native Hawaiian youth among the approved uses of grant funds.

Requires the Secretary to use subpart 1 funds to support:

 the development of a body of Native Hawaiian law; the repair and renovation of public schools that serve high concentrations of Native Hawaiian students; informal education programs that present traditional Hawaiian knowledge, science, astronomy, and environmental education through state museums or learning centers; public charter schools serving high concentrations of Native Hawaiian students; and the perpetuation of, and expansion of access to, Hawaiian culture and history through digital archives. Authorizes appropriations under subpart 1 for FY2014-FY2018.

Subpart 2: Alaska Native Education - (Sec. 7301) Revises the Alaska Native Educational Equity, Support, and Assistance Act under subpart 2 of part B. (The Act provides grants to Alaska Native organizations and educational, cultural, and community-based entities experienced in developing or operating Alaska Native programs.)

Makes the following entities eligible for Alaska Native education grants only if they are partnered with an Alaska Native organization: (1) states, (2) LEAs, (3) educational entities with experience in developing or operating Alaska Native educational programs or instructional programs conducted in Alaska Native languages, and (4) cultural and community-based organizations with experience in developing or operating Alaska Native education programs.

Requires grant recipients to: (1) develop and implement plans, methods, and strategies to improve the education of Alaska Natives; and (2) collect data to assist in the evaluation of Alaska Native education programs.

Revises the list of activities for which Alaska Native Education grants may be used to:

 eliminate the designation of specific organizations to conduct the cultural education and exchange programs; include both students and teachers in that exchange program, which is designed to facilitate cultural relationships between urban and rural Alaskans; include education programs for at-risk urban Alaska Native students in kindergarten through grade 12 that are operated by tribes or tribal organizations; include statewide programs providing technical assistance and support to schools and communities to engage adults in promoting the education and well-being of Alaska Native people; and include regional leadership academies to promote Alaska Native students' efforts to pursue and successfully complete higher education or career training. Directs the Secretary to award the grants using a point system that gives at least 15% of the total points to applications from Alaska Native organizations. Requires those organizations to have a meaningful role in the development, implementation, and evaluation of the grant programs.

Authorizes appropriations under subpart 2 for FY2014-FY2019.

Title VIII: Impact Aid - (Sec. 8002) Amends title VIII (Impact Aid) of the ESEA to alter methods used and considerations made in determining whether LEAs are eligible for Impact Aid payments. (The Impact Aid program compensates LEAs for the financial burden of federal activities affecting their school districts.)

Allows certain LEAs formed by the consolidation of two or more former school districts to have their eligibility for Impact Aid payments due to federal ownership of property within their jurisdiction determined on the basis of one or more of those former school districts if at least one of those school districts was eligible for such payments for the fiscal year preceding that consolidation.

Allows the Secretary to use original records or other records that the Secretary determines to be appropriate and reliable to determine the assessed value of federal property within an LEA.

(Sec. 8003) Alters the formula for determining the payments due LEAs for eligible federally-connected children. Includes in average daily attendance not only children but also those enrolled pursuant to a state open enrollment policy. Considers children who have a parent who is on active duty and who are residing in leased off-based property to be federally-connected children if that property is: (1) within the fenced security perimeter of the military facility; or (2) is attached to, and under any type of force protection agreement with, the military installation where the housing is situated.

Alters requirements for LEAs to qualify for Impact Aid payments as heavily impacted LEAs, which are those that serve high percentages of military, Native American, or other federally-connected children.

Continues a heavily impacted LEA's eligibility for such payments while activities associated with military base closures and realignments or force structure changes or relocations are ongoing.

Allows the calculation of Impact Aid payments using current student counts instead of prior fiscal year data when LEAs experience a specified influx of new federally-connected students due to federal activities or the closure of an LEA that was receiving Impact Aid due to federally-connected children.

(Sec. 8004) Provides Impact Aid construction payment eligibility to heavily impacted LEAs that are receiving basic support payments for federally-connected students but not the support payments available to heavily impacted LEAs.

(Sec. 8007) Includes the Coast Guard in the definition of "Armed Forces" for purposes of the Impact Aid program.

(Sec. 8009) Considers: (1) five specified Illinois school districts to be LEAs for purposes of the Impact Aid program, and (2) federally-connected students in such districts to be attending schools in North Chicago Community Unit School District 187 for the purpose of making that District eligible for Impact Aid. Conditions such treatment on the agreement of the five school districts to apportion such assistance equitably among all five of them and to use it only for direct educational services.

 (Sec. 8010) Amends the Impact Aid Improvement Act of 2012, under the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2013, to make permanent the amendments that Act made to the Impact Aid program that:

require the valuation of the federal property located within the boundaries of an LEA by calculating the valuation, for property tax purposes, of all property within the LEA's boundaries and then multiplying that value by the proportion of that property that is federal property; 
 alter the formula for determining the foundation payments due LEAs for federal ownership of property when appropriations for a fiscal year are insufficient to provide them with full compensation; 
 alter the formula for determining the payments due LEAs for eligible federally-connected children who are displaced from federal property or Indian lands due to housing renovation or rebuilding; and 
 direct the Secretary to complete Impact Aid payments to eligible LEAs within three fiscal years of their appropriation. 
 
 Authorizes appropriations for the Impact Aid program for FY2014-FY2018.

 Title IX: General Provisions - (Sec. 9101) Amends title IX (General Provisions) of the ESEA to establish additional definitions for terms that are applicable throughout the ESEA.

Defines an "advanced placement or international baccalaureate course" as: (1) postsecondary-level instruction provided to middle or secondary school students that terminates in an AP or IB examination; or (2) another highly-rigorous, evidence-based, postsecondary preparatory program terminating in an examination or courses that are widely accepted for credit at IHEs or another such examination approved by the Secretary.

Defines "high-need LEAs" as LEAs: (1) that serve at least 10,000 children from families below the poverty line; (2) at least 20% of whose children are from from families with incomes below the poverty line; or (3) that are in the highest quartile of LEAs in the state, based on student poverty.

Defines "high-need schools" as: (1) elementary or middle schools in which at least 50% of the enrolled students are children from low-income families; or (2) high schools in which at least 40% of the enrolled students are children from low-income families, which percentage may be calculated using comparable data from feeder schools.

Renames "pupil services personnel" and "pupil services" as "specialized instructional support personnel" and "specialized instructional support services," respectively. Includes school nurses as specialized instructional support personnel.

(Sec. 9102) Allows students who are threatened by, or the victim of, a criminal offense at their public school to attend a safe public school within the LEA's jurisdiction. (Currently, this unsafe school choice option is available only to students attending schools identified as persistently dangerous or those who become victims of a criminal offense at their public school.)

(Sec. 9103) Requires the Secretary to ensure geographic diversity when awarding competitive grants under the ESEA.

(Sec. 9104) Authorizes the Secretary to reserve for evaluation activities not less than 1% and not more than 3% of the amount appropriated to carry out each categorical program and demonstration project authorized by the ESEA, but requires the Secretary to reserve 1% of the funds appropriated to carry out title I for such activities.

Title X: Commission on Effective Regulation and Assessment Systems for Public Schools - Commission on Effective Regulation and Assessment Systems for Public Schools Act - (Sec. 10013) Establishes, under a new title X of the ESEA, a Commission on Effective Regulation and Assessment Systems for Public Schools to: (1) examine federal, state, and local regulatory requirements for elementary and secondary education; (2) make recommendations on how to align and improve those regulations; (3) examine the quality and purpose of current federal, state, and local assessment requirements; and (4) make recommendations to improve and align assessment systems to provide meaningful information and improve student achievement, teacher performance, and innovation. Requires the Commission to be composed of specified governmental and educational occupations.

Title XI: Amendments to Other Laws; Miscellaneous Provisions - Part A: Amendments to Other Laws - Subpart 1: Mckinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act - McKinney-Vento Homeless Education Reauthorization Act of 2013 - (Sec. 11012) Amends the program under subtitle B (Education for Homeless Children and Youth) of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act that awards grants to states and, through them, subgrants to LEAs for the education of homeless youth, including to:

alter the formula used in determining the minimum allotment to each state; 
 require each state to use at least 75% of its grant for subgrants to LEAs, even if it only receives its minimum allotment; 
 focus on the identification of homeless youth; 
 eliminate an exception to the prohibition on grant recipients segregating homeless youth in a separate school or program within a school that allowed certain separate schools already in existence to continue operating; 
 require homeless youth to be given the opportunity to meet the same college and career ready achievement standards to which other students are held; 
 ensure that homeless youth receive credit for full or partial coursework satisfactorily completed while attending prior schools or while attending a new school; 
 require states and LEAs to provide homeless youth the same access to academic and extracurricular activities that is available to non-homeless students; 
 require public preschool programs to identify and prioritize homeless children for enrollment and to comply with subtitle B requirements; 
 require LEAs to consider student-centered factors before placing a homeless youth in a school; 
 require schools to enroll homeless youth immediately despite unpaid fines or fees or missed application or enrollment deadlines; 
 protect the privacy of information about a homeless youth's living situation; and 
 require LEAs to coordinate services provided to homeless and disabled youth. 
 
 Requires that, in addition to their existing duties, LEA liaisons for homeless children and youth ensure that: (1) homeless youth are certified as eligible for free meals under the school lunch and breakfast programs; (2) school personnel providing services to homeless youth receive professional development and other support; and (3) unaccompanied youth are enrolled in school, have opportunities to meet the same state academic standards to which other students are held, and are informed of their status as independent students for financial aid purposes.

Directs the Secretary to award emergency disaster grants to LEAs and their states to increase the capacity of those LEAs to respond to major disasters that increase their enrollment of homeless youth. (This replaces a program providing emergency assistance to states and, through them, LEAs to provide services to youth and their families who have become homeless due to foreclosure.)

Allows LEAs to use subgrants to defray the costs of the LEA liaisons for homeless children and youth.

Directs the Secretary to establish or designate a Federal Office of the Coordinator for Education of Homeless Children and Youths to carry out subtitle B responsibilities.

Includes in the Secretary's duties under the program: (1) the provision of support and technical assistance to states in areas in which barriers to a free appropriate public education persist, and (2) the public dissemination of information regarding the academic progress being made by homeless children and youth.

Reauthorizes appropriations for the Education for Homeless Children and Youth program through FY2020.

Subpart 2: Advanced Research Projects Agency-Education - (Sec. 11021) Amends the Department of Education Organization Act to establish in the Department of Education an Advanced Research Projects Agency-Education (ARPA-ED). Requires the ARPA-ED to pursue breakthrough research and development in educational technology and provide for its effective use by:

identifying and promoting revolutionary advances in fundamental and applied sciences and engineering that could be translated into new learning technologies; 
 developing such technologies and facilitating their effective use; 
 developing, testing, and evaluating the impact and efficacy of those technologies; 
 accelerating transformational technological advances in areas in which the private sector, by itself, is unlikely to do so; 
 coordinating activities with nongovernmental entities to demonstrate technologies and research applications to facilitate technology transfer; and 
 encouraging educational research using new technologies and the data produced by those technologies. 
 
 Authorizes the Secretary to award grants, contracts, cooperative agreements, and cash prizes and to enter into other transactions in pursuit of these objectives.

Allows the Secretary to reserve up to 30%, but no more than $100 million, of the funds appropriated each fiscal year for the Programs of National Significance, under part I of title IV of the ESEA, to carry out ARPA-ED activities.

Part B: Miscellaneous Provisions - (Sec. 11211) Makes technical and conforming amendments to other Acts.</summary>
</bill>
