<bill session="113" type="h" number="4388" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-04-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-04-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Indian Trust Responsibility Review Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the American Indian Trust Review Commission, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412397"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412407" joined="2014-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400077" joined="2014-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412549" joined="2014-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400128" joined="2014-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400141" joined="2014-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2014-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412286" joined="2014-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400259" joined="2014-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412568" joined="2014-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412192" joined="2014-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2014-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400606" joined="2014-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412399" joined="2014-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412405" joined="2014-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="2014-04-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee Indian and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII24" subcommittee="Indian and Alaska Native Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/3/2014--Introduced.
American Indian Trust Responsibility Review Act of 2014 - Establishes the American Indian Trust Review Commission to: (1) conduct a comprehensive review of the unique trust relationship between the United States and federally recognized Indian tribes, and (2) report to Congress within two years of this Act's enactment.

Requires the study to analyze:

 the attributes of that relationship; the policies, practices, structure, and effectiveness of the federal agencies that have trust responsibilities toward Indian tribes; the feasibility of authorizing willing Indian tribes to assume duties currently performed by the federal government; the data necessary for the Commission to get a better understanding of tribal needs; the feasibility of creating high-level federal positions to increase tribal participation in policy formation and program development; the viability of a mechanism to ensure the continuation of critical programs for Indian tribes; the appropriate role of state and local governments in federal activities affecting Indian tribes; and modifications to laws, procedures, regulations, policies, and practices that might further the federal government's trust relationship with Indian tribes.</summary>
</bill>
