<bill session="113" type="h" number="5184" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Regulatory Budget Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a National Regulatory Budget, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412261"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412531" joined="2014-07-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, Ways and Means, Rules, and Appropriations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-24">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-24">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-24">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-24">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-24">
      <text>Referred to House Appropriations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU05" subcommittee="Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2153"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/24/2014--Introduced.
National Regulatory Budget Act of 2014 - Establishes the Office of Regulatory Analysis in the executive branch as an independent establishment. Requires the Director of the Office to submit an annual report to specified congressional committees that includes: (1) regulatory costs imposed on regulated entities; (2) an analysis of any major changes in estimation methodology used by the Office since its last annual report; (3) an analysis of any major estimate changes caused by improved or inadequate data; (4) recommendations on how regulations may be streamlined, simplified, and modernized; and (5) recommendations for repealing regulations and reducing the cost of regulations without diminishing their effectiveness.

Requires the Director to publish a regulatory analysis of each proposed covered federal rule (a rule, an information collection requirement, guidance, or a directive that imposes not less than $25 million in annual costs on regulated entities) and each proposed withdrawal or modification of a covered federal rule by an executive agency that imposes or reduces costs on a regulated entity. 

Requires Congress to pass an annual bill establishing a National Regulatory Budget that sets an overall regulatory cost cap and an agency regulatory cost cap for each executive agency for the fiscal year.

Requires agencies to provide the information that the Director requests and imposes sanctions for failing to cooperate.

 Prohibits an executive agency that exceeds the annual agency regulatory cost cap imposed by the National Regulatory Budget for a fiscal year from promulgating a new covered federal rule that increases regulatory costs.</summary>
</bill>
