<bill session="113" type="s" number="1690" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-18">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-11-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Second Chance Reauthorization Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Second Chance Reauthorization Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reauthorize the Second Chance Act of 2007.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300065"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412493" joined="2013-12-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2014-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412598" joined="2014-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2013-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2014-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2014-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412390" joined="2014-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2013-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2013-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2013-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412200" joined="2014-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412582" joined="2014-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412545" joined="2013-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2013-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2013-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2013-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412194" joined="2013-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400325" joined="2013-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412491" joined="2014-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2014-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2014-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2014-04-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-11-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8001-8002"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8002-8006" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-09-18" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-10-01">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Reported by Senator Leahy under authority of the order of the Senate of 09/18/2014 with amendments. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-10-01" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="580">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 580.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="3465"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Adult education and literacy"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Homelessness and emergency shelter"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Separation, divorce, custody, support"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/1/2014--Reported to Senate amended.
Second Chance Reauthorization Act of 2013 - Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 and the Second Chance Act of 2007 to revise and expand requirements for grant programs for adult and juvenile offender state and local reentry demonstration projects.

(Sec. 2) Extends through FY2018 the authorization of appropriations for grants for: (1) family-based substance abuse treatment, (2) the technology careers training demonstration program, and (3) the offender reentry substance abuse and criminal justice collaboration program.

Renames the program of mentoring grants to nonprofit organizations for offender reentry as the program of community-based mentoring and transitional service grants to nonprofit organizations. Provides for transitional services under such program to assist in the reintegration of offenders into the community. Reauthorizes the program through FY2018.

Directs the Attorney General to identify and publish best practices relating to academic and vocational education for offenders in prisons, jails, and juvenile facilities.

(Sec. 3) Requires the Inspector General of the Department of Justice (DOJ) to periodically conduct audits of not less than 5% of all recipients of specified offender reentry grants under the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 and the Second Chance Act of 2007. Prohibits: (1) a grantee that is found to have an unresolved audit finding from receiving grant funds; and (2) the use of grant funds for lobbying DOJ representatives or representatives of a federal, state, local, or tribal government regarding the award of grant funding.

(Sec. 4) Amends the Second Chance Act of 2007 to: (1) modify and extend through FY2018 grant programs for reentry of federal prisoners into the community, including the program for placing elderly offenders (not less than 60 years of age) in home detention; (2) repeal programs under such Act relating to responsible reintegration of offenders, the study of the effectiveness of depot naltrexone for heroin addiction, and the satellite tracking and reentry training program; and (3) establish a program for partnering faith-based or community-based nonprofit organizations with prisons to conduct recidivism reduction activities.

(Sec. 5) Directs the Attorney General to establish an interagency task force on federal programs and activities for the reentry of offenders into the community. Requires the task force to: (1) identify and evaluate methods for improving such programs and activities, and (2) submit to Congress and annually update a report on barriers faced by offenders in reentering the community.

(Sec. 6) Amends the Prison Rape Elimination Act of 2003 to exclude from the scope of such Act grant programs administered by the Office of Violence Against Women or funded under certain provisions of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 or the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974 during the four-year period after enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
