<bill session="113" type="h" number="4051" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-02-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-02-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-02-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">REFUEL Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Renewable Fuel Utilization, Expansion, and Leadership Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 to establish a competitive grant program for renewable fuel infrastructure, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412209"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412208" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412537" joined="2014-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412535" joined="2014-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400234" joined="2014-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="408211" joined="2014-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400316" joined="2014-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412585" joined="2014-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412214" joined="2014-02-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-02-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-11">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-11">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Energy, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG15" subcommittee="Conservation, Energy, and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Energy revenues and royalties"/>
    <term name="Hybrid, electric, and advanced technology vehicles"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/11/2014--Introduced.
Renewable Fuel Utilization, Expansion, and Leadership Act or the REFUEL Act - Amends the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 to direct the Secretary of Agriculture to establish a renewable and alternative energy infrastructure competitive grant program.

Makes eligible for such grants projects that are: (1) for new infrastructure or retrofitting existing infrastructure for the dispensing of covered renewable or alternative energy for retail consumption, and (2) capable of dispensing fuel containing an amount of covered renewable or alternative energy that is higher than ordinarily found in commerce.

Requires that priority be given to projects in rural areas and that entities receiving grants provide at least a 30% match of federal funds.

Dedicates to the grant program 1% of amounts received as royalties for production of oil from oil and gas leases under the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act. Defines "covered renewable or alternative energy" as renewable energy, energy intended for use in electric vehicle charging, and hydrogen and fuel cells.</summary>
</bill>
