<bill session="113" type="h" number="3460" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-11-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-11-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-11-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Education and Energy Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Mineral Leasing Act to require that a portion of revenues from new Federal mineral and geothermal leases be paid to States for use to supplement the education of students in kindergarten through grade 12 and public support of institutions of higher education, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412405"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-11-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-12">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-12">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Training" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Energy revenues and royalties"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/12/2013--Introduced.
Education and Energy Act of 2013 - Amends the Mineral Leasing Act to require a portion of the revenue deposited into the general fund of the Treasury from new mineral and geothermal leases to be provided to the states to supplement the education of students in kindergarten through grade 12 and to supplement public support of institutions of higher education..

Restricts the revenue from which that portion is to be derived to the revenue from new leases that is in excess of the Congressional Budget Office's previous estimate of the revenue that those leases would yield in a fiscal year.</summary>
</bill>
