<bill session="113" type="s" number="2420" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Budget and Accounting Transparency Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 to increase transparency in Federal budgeting, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412556"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Budget.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBU" name="Senate Budget" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1872"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government corporations and government-sponsored enterprises"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/3/2014--Introduced.
Budget and Accounting Transparency Act of 2014 - Amends the Federal Credit Reform Act of 1990 (FCRA) (title V of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974) to revise the budgetary treatment of federal direct loans and loan guarantees to account for them on a fair value basis. 

 Requires the President's budget to reflect the costs of direct loan and loan guarantee programs by including the planned level of new direct loan obligations or loan guarantee commitments associated with each appropriations request. Requires agency estimates with and without a risk component that reflects the impact of using a fair value estimate to account for market risk.

Requires new budget authority and funding limitations for the cost of new direct loan obligations or loan guarantee commitments to be provided in advance. Prohibits modifications that increase costs unless budget authority has been provided in advance. Defines "cost" to include the risk component. Includes exemptions.&#160;







Amends the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 to permit adjustment of discretionary spending limits for this Act.



Changes the budgetary treatment of the Federal National Mortgage Association (Fannie Mae) and the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation (Freddie Mac).</summary>
</bill>
