<bill session="113" type="hr" number="720" updated="2015-09-01T10:18:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the condolences of the House of Representatives to the families of James Foley and Steven Sotloff, and condemning the terrorist acts of the Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412219"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412250" joined="2014-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412385" joined="2014-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2014-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412557" joined="2014-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2014-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400623" joined="2014-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412412" joined="2014-09-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="sr" number="538"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/11/2014--Introduced.
Condemns the terrorist acts of the Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant (ISIL), including the barbaric murders of James Foley and Steven Sotloff.

 Mourns the deaths of James Foley and Steven Sotloff and expresses the Senate's condolences to their families.

 Salutes James Foley and Steven Sotloff for their courageous pursuit of journalistic excellence under the most dangerous of conditions.

 Supports efforts to bring to justice those responsible for the murders of James Foley and Steven Sotloff.

Demands the release of all hostages being held by ISIL.

Calls on the United States and the international community, working in partnership with the governments and citizens of the Middle East, to address the ISIL threat.

States that nothing in this resolution shall be construed as a declaration of war or authorization to use force.</summary>
</bill>
