<bill session="113" type="h" number="3683" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-12-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-12-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-12-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 to improve United States-Israel energy cooperation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400414"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412250" joined="2013-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412544" joined="2014-01-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="2013-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400195" joined="2014-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400244" joined="2014-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400400" joined="2013-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="2013-12-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-12-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, and Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-10">
      <text>Referred to House Science, Space, and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-10">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-10">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-10">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-05T12:39:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 113-341, Part I.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY20" subcommittee="Energy" name="House Science, Space, and Technology"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3677"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1491"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/5/2014--Reported to House without amendment, Part I.
(Sec. 1) Amends the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 to authorize the Secretary of Energy to: (1) enter into cooperative agreements supporting dialogue and planning involving international partnerships between the Department of Energy (DOE), including DOE National Laboratories, and the government of Israel and its ministries, offices, and institutions; and (2) establish a joint United States-Israel Center based in an area of the United States with offshore energy development expertise to develop academic cooperation in energy innovation technology and engineering, water science, technology transfer, and analysis of geopolitical implications of new natural resource development.

Extends the grant program to support U.S.-Israel research, development, and commercialization of renewable energy or energy efficiency (as well as the related advisory committee) through September 30, 2024.

Expands the scope of covered program energy to include natural gas energy, water desalination improvement, and other water treatment technologies.

(Sec. 2) Expresses the sense of Congress that open dialogue and continued mechanisms for regular engagement encourages further U.S.-Israel public, academic, and private cooperation on energy security issues.

Directs the Secretary of Energy and the Secretary of State to seek to establish an Energy Cooperation Working Group within the semi-annual United States-Israel Strategic Dialogue.

States that the Group's purpose shall be to strengthen U.S.-Israel dialogue on: (1) advancing research, development, and deployment of renewable energy and energy efficiency; (2) identifying policy priorities associated with Israel's natural resources development; (3) identifying best practices for energy infrastructure cybersecurity; (4) leveraging natural gas resources to impact regional stability positively; (5) developing technical and environmental management of deep-water exploration and production; and (6) implementing coastal protection and restoration.</summary>
</bill>
