<bill session="113" type="h" number="5680" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans' Toxic Wounds Research Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to establish a registry for certain toxic exposures, to direct the Secretary to include certain information in the electronic health records of veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412214"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412565" joined="2014-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2014-11-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-10-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR03" subcommittee="Health" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Bosnia and Herzegovina"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Digestive and metabolic diseases"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="HIV/AIDS"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Hearing, speech, and vision care"/>
    <term name="Hereditary and development disorders"/>
    <term name="Immunology and vaccination"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Musculoskeletal and skin diseases"/>
    <term name="North Carolina"/>
    <term name="Philippines"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Somalia"/>
    <term name="U.S. territories and protectorates"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/19/2014--Introduced.
Veterans' Toxic Wounds Research Act of 2014 - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) to establish a master registry of veterans who experienced toxic exposures while serving in the Armed Forces. Includes in the master registry the registries for:

 Agent Orange; exposure to toxins relating to a deployment during the Persian Gulf War; exposure to toxins relating to a deployment during Operation Iraqi Freedom, Operation New Dawn, Operation Enduring Freedom, or the Global War on Terror; exposure to toxins relating to a deployment to Bosnia, Somalia, or the Philippines; and exposure to toxins relating to being stationed at a military installation potentially contaminated by toxic substances. Directs the Secretary to enter into an agreement with the National Academy of Sciences (NAS) to review published scientific information and studies, and make recommendations for future research, on the health effects: (1) of the toxic exposures covered in those registries, and (2) on the children and grandchildren of veterans who had a toxic exposure covered in those registries. Requires those reviews to inform the Secretary's selection of research to be conducted or funded by the VA.

Establishes a presumption of a service connection, for the purpose of veterans' disability and survivor benefits, for an illness that:

 the Secretary determines warrants such a presumption by reason of having a positive association with exposure to a toxic substance covered in the master registry; and becomes manifest, within the period the Secretary prescribes, in a veteran who experienced such exposure while serving in the Armed Forces. Requires the Secretary's service connection determinations to be based on sound medical and scientific evidence that a positive association exists between: (1) the exposure of humans or animals to a toxic substance covered in the master registry, and (2) the occurrence of a diagnosed or undiagnosed illness in humans or animals.

Directs the Secretary, in implementing the VA's electronic health record system, to include specified information in each individual's electronic health record, including whether the individual served in the Armed Forces and, if so, the locations and dates of such service.</summary>
</bill>
