<bill session="113" type="s" number="2639" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Affairs Health Workforce Enhancement Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to increase the number of graduate medical education residency positions at medical facilities of the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400013"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3230"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4942"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/22/2014--Introduced.
Veterans Affairs Health Workforce Enhancement Act of 2014 - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) to establish medical residency programs, or ensure a sufficient number of residency positions in medical residency programs, at any VA medical facility that the Secretary determines is experiencing a shortage of physicians.

Requires the Secretary to determine the specialty of health care professionals that each such facility is experiencing a shortage of and allocate residency programs and positions based on such determination.

Directs the Secretary, during the five-year period beginning on the enactment of this Act, to increase the number of graduate medical education residency positions at VA medical facilities by not less than 2,000 positions, giving priority to medical facilities that: (1) do not have a medical residency program, and (2) are located in a community in which there is a high need for health care for veterans.</summary>
</bill>
