<bill session="113" type="s" number="2340" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-05-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Simplifying Financial Aid for Students Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require the Secretary to provide for the use of data from the second preceding tax year to carry out the simplification of applications for the estimation and determination of financial aid eligibility, to increase the income threshold to qualify for zero expected family contribution, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412598"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412200" joined="2014-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412582" joined="2014-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2014-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2014-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2014-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2014-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2014-07-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4982"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/14/2014--Introduced.
Simplifying Financial Aid for Students Act of 2014 - Amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require the Secretary of Education to provide for the use of data from the second preceding tax year when and to the extent necessary to carry out the simplification of applications used in estimating and determining financial aid eligibility. Requires such simplification to include data sharing between the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) and the Department of Education, pursuant to taxpayer consent.

 Increases (from $23,000 to $30,000) the limit on the adjusted gross income that parents, in the case of dependent students, and students and their spouses, in the case of independent students with dependents other than a spouse, may make if those students are to be considered as having zero expected family contribution in the determination of their need for financial aid.</summary>
</bill>
