<bill session="113" type="hr" number="705" updated="2015-09-01T10:18:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Recommending the designation of a Presidential Special Envoy to the Balkans to evaluate the successes and shortcomings of the implementation of the Dayton Peace Accords in Bosnia and Herzegovina, to provide policy recommendations, and to report back to Congress within one year.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412498"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400074" joined="2014-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2014-12-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1287"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Europe, Eurasia, and Emerging Threats.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA14" subcommittee="Europe, Eurasia, and Emerging Threats" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="sr" number="131"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Bosnia and Herzegovina"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="European Union"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2014--Introduced.
Supports the sovereignty, territorial integrity, and legal continuity of Bosnia-Herzegovina (BiH) as well as the equality of its three constituent peoples and others within an integrated multi-ethnic country.

Welcomes steps taken by BiH towards Euro-Atlantic integration, and emphasizes that BiH, as well as its internal political entities, work toward creation of an effective state.

Reiterates that constitutional reform in BiH take the Dayton Peace Accords as its basis, while advancing the principles of political, economic, legal, and religious equality.

Stresses the importance of privatization of the publicly owned enterprises in close cooperation with the European Union (EU) and the Office of the High Representative (OHR).

Commends U.S. support for a strong civil society in BiH.

Reiterates that BiH reforms should take into account protection of the constitutional rights of all, including the Bosnian Croats who are the smallest of the three recognized constituent peoples in BiH.

States that the United States should: (1) work with the EU in implementing an accession process for BiH which would link BiH internal integration with its phased EU integration; (2) designate a Presidential Special Envoy to the Balkans to work with the OHR, the EU, the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO), political leaders in Bosnia and Herzegovina, and neighboring countries to facilitate governmental and societal reforms in BiH; and (3) support countries of the region, together with other international actors, in ending the refugee and internal-displacement situation in Southeast Europe.

Urges the Presidential Special Envoy to report to Congress on ways to overcome any remaining political, economic, legal, or religious inequalities in BiH.</summary>
</bill>
