<bill session="113" type="h" number="3654" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-12-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-12-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-12-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Renewable Electricity Standard Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a renewable electricity standard, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412308"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412571" joined="2014-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412557" joined="2013-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400230" joined="2014-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412293" joined="2013-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412219" joined="2014-05-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-12-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="s" number="1595"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/4/2013--Introduced.
Renewable Electricity Standard Act of 2013 - Amends the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 (PURPA) to require a retail electric supplier to submit to the Secretary of Energy (DOE) for 2014 and thereafter one or more of the following: (1) specified federal renewable energy credits, (2) certification of the renewable energy generated and electricity savings, and (3) specified alternative compliance payments. Prescribes, for 2014 through 2039, a schedule of graduated annual percentages of a retail electric supplier's base amount that shall be generated from renewable energy resources (increasing from 6% in 2014 to 25% in 2025).

Directs the Secretary to establish a program to: (1) verify and issue federal renewable energy credits to generators of renewable energy; (2) track the sale, exchange, and retirement of the credits; and (3) enforce the federal renewable energy credits program.

Directs the Secretary to issue a generator of electric energy one federal renewable energy credit for each kilowatt hour of electric energy generated by the use of a renewable energy resource at an eligible facility.

Prescribes rules for federal renewable energy credit trading and for borrowing and repayment of federal renewable energy credits.

Provides that this Act does not diminish the authority of a state or its political subdivision to: (1) adopt or enforce any law (including regulations) respecting renewable energy, or (2) regulate the acquisition and disposition of federal renewable energy credits by retail electric suppliers.

Permits an electric utility that has sales of electric energy subject to rate regulation to recover the full cost of renewable energy obtained to comply with this Act.

Establishes in the Treasury a state renewable energy account for a grant program for promoting renewable energy production and providing energy assistance and weatherization services to low-income consumers.</summary>
</bill>
