<bill session="113" type="h" number="4860" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Students from Failing Institutions Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To clarify that a closure of a branch or campus of an institution of higher education may qualify a borrower for loan discharge under the Higher Education Act of 1965, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412498"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412404" joined="2014-12-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E979-980"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5735"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Training" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/12/2014--Introduced.
Protecting Students from Failing Institutions Act - Amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require the Secretary of Education to discharge a borrower's liability on a loan under the Federal Family Education Loan (FFEL) program if the student borrower, or the student on whose behalf a parent borrowed, is unable to complete the program in which such student is enrolled due to the closing of a campus or branch of the institution of higher education (IHE).

Prohibits a student's period of attendance at a campus or branch that closed and prevented the student from completing the student's course of study from: (1) being considered in calculating the student's period of eligibility for additional assistance under title IV, or (2) counting towards the student's duration limit for Federal Pell Grants.

Provides such liability discharge and eligibility protections to borrowers who withdraw from an IHE no more than 120 days before the closure of the campus or branch of the IHE at which they are enrolled if that closure would have prevented them from completing the program in which they were enrolled.

Allows a borrower who receives a Federal Pell Grant for an academic year for enrollment in a program at an IHE campus or branch that closes to use the remaining amount of the Federal Pell Grant for such academic year at another IHE even if the borrower is considered able to complete the program in which the borrower is enrolled.</summary>
</bill>
