<bill session="113" type="h" number="4756" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-05-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">BRAVE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bullying Redress and Verified Enforcement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require reporting of bullying to appropriate authorities and assist with equal protection claims against entities who fail to respond appropriately to bullying, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412571"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2014-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400274" joined="2014-05-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2014-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412520" joined="2014-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412412" joined="2014-06-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/29/2014--Introduced.
Bullying Redress and Verified Enforcement Act or the BRAVE Act - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA) to require the employees of local educational agencies (LEAs) who become aware of bullying to report to an LEA-designated individual, within seven business days: (1) the acts that constituted bullying; (2) the protected characteristic of the victim if the bullying included a reference to or was motivated by such an actual or perceived protected characteristic; and (3) the response of the LEA's employees.

Requires the LEA-designated individual, within 60 days after receiving such a report, to inform all the LEA's employees of the acts described and the response of the LEA's employees.

Requires each LEA to annually review its policies on bullying.

Directs each LEA to publish and make available to all of its students and their parents a quarterly report that: (1) summarizes the bullying reported since the previous quarterly report, (2) summarizes the responses to such bullying by the LEA's employees, (3) excludes any personally identifiable information of any student involved, and (4) informs the public of the right to file a complaint with the Office of Civil Rights for the Department of Education regarding the LEA's failure to comply with this Act's requirements.

Directs the Assistant Secretary who heads the Office of Civil Rights to: (1) establish the complaint procedure and publish it on the Department's website; (2) investigate each complaint to determine if the LEA complied with this Act's requirements; (3) withhold ESEA funds from, issue a complaint against, or enter into a compliance agreement with a noncompliant LEA to bring it into compliance; and (4) make information about each complaint available on the Department's website.

Conditions each LEA's receipt of ESEA funds on the LEA: (1) annually certifying to the Secretary of Education in writing that it is in compliance with this Act's requirements; and (2) submitting its four most recent quarterly reports on bullying.</summary>
</bill>
