<bill session="113" type="s" number="2060" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-02-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-02-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-02-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">TEACH Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Technology, Equality and Accessibility in College and Higher Education Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Architectural and Transportation Barriers Compliance Board to develop accessibility guidelines for electronic instructional materials and related information technologies in institutions of higher education, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412542"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412493" joined="2014-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412330" joined="2014-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="2014-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2014-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412491" joined="2014-06-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-02-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="3505"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Access Board"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/27/2014--Introduced.
Technology, Equality and Accessibility in College and Higher Education Act or the TEACH Act - Directs the Access Board to develop accessibility guidelines for electronic instructional materials and related information technologies in institutions of higher education (IHEs).

Requires those guidelines to: (1) include performance criteria to ensure that electronic instructional materials and related information technologies are accessible to the blind and disabled; (2) be consistent with the standards for technical and functional performance criteria issued pursuant to the Rehabilitation Act of 1973; and (3) be, to the extent practicable, consistent with national and international accessibility standards for those materials and technologies.

Directs the Access Board to review and, as appropriate, amend the guidelines every three years to reflect technological advances or changes in electronic instructional materials and related information technologies.

Deems IHEs that use electronic instructional materials and related information technologies that comply with the guidelines to be in compliance with nondiscrimination provisions under the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 and the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990.</summary>
</bill>
