<bill session="113" type="h" number="3005" updated="2015-09-01T10:19:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medical Testing Availability Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend chapter V of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to permit the sale of, and access to, "research use only" products in diagnostic tests.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400052"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412516" joined="2013-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="2013-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400157" joined="2013-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400641" joined="2013-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2013-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412523" joined="2013-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412259" joined="2013-08-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-08-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/2/2013--Introduced.
Medical Testing Availability Act of 2013 - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act with respect to labeling in the shipment or delivery of an in vitro diagnostic product for an investigation exempt from compliance with a performance standard or the requirement of premarket approval.

Declares that such a product whose labeling states "For Research Use Only. Not for use in diagnostic procedures." may not be deemed misbranded on the basis that its manufacturer or distributor: (1) sells the product to an end user who uses the product in a manner inconsistent with such statement, or (2) engages in business communications regarding the product with an end user.

Defines "business communications": (1) as oral, written, or electronic contact between a manufacturer or distributor of such a product and an end user regarding the product's functioning; and (2) includes any such contact consisting of technical support, customer service, assistance with the installation of such product, communication relating to ensuring the performance of the product, and other similar contacts.</summary>
</bill>
