<bill session="113" type="h" number="4313" updated="2015-09-01T17:49:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-03-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-03-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-03-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Flood Insurance Premium Parity Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure fairness in premium rates for coverage for business properties and second homes under the National Flood Insurance Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412603"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412250" joined="2014-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412195" joined="2014-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412529" joined="2014-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412527" joined="2014-05-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-03-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="includes" session="113" type="h" number="3370"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/26/2014--Introduced.
Flood Insurance Premium Parity Act of 2014 - Amends the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (NFIA) to prohibit the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Administration (FEMA) from estimating reduced (subsidized) risk premium rates for flood insurance for residential property that is neither the primary residence of an individual (as under current law) nor the secondary residence of the property owner.

Directs FEMA to establish standards for a residential property to qualify as a secondary residence eligible for subsidized risk flood insurance premium rates that: (1) require the owner to occupy the property for an appropriate minimum period of time each year, and (2) limit subsidized risk premium rates to but a single property of the owner.

Repeals the prohibition against estimating subsidized risk premium rates for business property (thus qualifying business property for such rates).

Directs FEMA to refund directly to insureds any flood insurance premiums collected in excess of the rates required under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
