<bill session="113" type="h" number="3614" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-11-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-11-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-11-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Military Skills to Careers Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the recognition by States of skills learned in the military by a veteran when issuing licenses and credentials.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400660"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-11-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-25">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSVR10" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3007"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="492"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="495"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="944"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1950"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1982"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/21/2013--Introduced.
Military Skills to Careers Act - Requires a state, as a condition for receipt of a grant or contract from the Department of Labor to employ disabled veterans' outreach program specialists and local veterans' employment representatives, to establish a program under which that state administers an examination and issues a license or credential to a veteran without requiring any training or apprenticeship if such veteran: (1) receives a satisfactory score on such examination, (2) has been awarded a military occupational specialty that is substantially equivalent to or exceeds the state requirements for such license or credential, (3) has engaged in active practice of such occupation for at least two of the five years preceding the date of application for such license or credential, and (4) pays any fees required by the state for such license or credential. Requires the state to report annually to the Secretary of Labor on the exams administered, the number of veterans who completed such exams, and exam results, disaggregated by occupational field.

Allows the Secretary to waive the requirement that a state establish such a program if the state certifies that it: (1) takes into account previous military training or testing; (2) permits veterans to satisfy through examination training or testing requirements for which a veteran has previously completed military training; and (3) substantially reduces training time, based on the military training received by a veteran, required to satisfy requirements the veteran is unable to completely satisfy through examination.

Requires an annual report from the Secretary to Congress and the Secretary of Defense on administered exams and exam results.</summary>
</bill>
