<bill session="113" type="h" number="4517" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-04-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-04-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Examination of Exposures to Environmental Hazards During Military Service and Health Care for Atsugi Naval Air Facility Veterans and their Families Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the provision of health care for certain individuals exposed to environmental hazards at Atsugi Naval Air Facility, to establish an advisory board to examine exposures to environmental hazards at such Air Facility, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412315"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412501" joined="2014-11-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-29">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-29">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR03" subcommittee="Health" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Japan"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/29/2014--Introduced.
Examination of Exposures to Environmental Hazards During Military Service and Health Care for Atsugi Naval Air Facility Veterans and their Families Act of 2014 - Directs the Secretaries of Defense (DOD) and Veterans Affairs (VA) to jointly establish the Advisory Board on Environmental Exposures at Atsugi Naval Air Facility to provide expert advice to DOD and VA on matters relating to exposure of current and former members of the Armed Forces (members) and their dependents to environmental hazards at Atsugi Naval Air Facility, Japan, during the period beginning in 1983 in which the air, water, or soil at such facility was contaminated due to an incinerator.

Requires the Board to: (1) consider and study cases of such exposure, (2) evaluate submitted exposure claims, and (3) recommend to such Secretaries that either a claim is insufficient to warrant further consideration or is sufficient to warrant health care or compensation. Authorizes the Board to convene a science panel to consider exposure claims and report results to the Board.

Authorizes the Secretary of Defense (Secretary) to provide to such members and dependents the health care benefits recommended by the Board.

Requires the Secretary to: (1) compile a list of individuals exposed to environmental hazards at the facility during the period in which the air, water, or soil was contaminated; and (2) report to the armed services and veterans' affairs committees on the compilation of such list.

Directs the Secretary to report annually to such committees on health care and other benefits provided under this Act, including a description of procedures used to identify exposed individuals.</summary>
</bill>
