<bill session="113" type="h" number="4364" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-04-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-04-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Motor Vehicle Safety Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide greater transparency, accountability, and safety authority to the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400425"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412208" joined="2014-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400616" joined="2014-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412571" joined="2014-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="2014-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400101" joined="2014-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="2014-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400663" joined="2014-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400308" joined="2014-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="2014-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2014-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412319" joined="2014-04-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF17" subcommittee="Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2559"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Business ethics"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/1/2014--Introduced.
Motor Vehicle Safety Act of 2014 - Revises early warning reporting requirements for manufacturers of motor vehicles regarding possible defects of motor vehicles and motor vehicle equipment.

Authorizes the Secretary of Transportation (DOT) to issue regulations establishing categories of information that must be made available to the public. Requires the public disclosure of possible defects of motor vehicles or related equipment reported to the Secretary by motor vehicle manufacturers (Early Warning data).

Directs the Secretary to require a manufacturer in cases where the defect has caused a fatality to provide, and make public, certain additional information in its report to the Secretary.

Directs the Secretary to give public notice on the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration (NHTSA) website of all inspections and investigations conducted by the Secretary to enforce a motor vehicle safety requirement or order, or that are related to a motor vehicle accident due to a possible defect.

Directs the Secretary to: (1) take specified actions to improve public accessibility to vehicle safety information on NHTSA's website, and (2) promulgate rules requiring the senior senior official for safety for a corporation to be responsible for requests for information in NHTSA safety or compliance investigations.

Requires the DOT Office of the Inspector General to study NHTSA use of Early Warning data.

Prohibits certain vehicle safety officials, for the one-year period after termination of NHTSA employment, from knowingly making any communication to or appearance before NHTSA on behalf of a manufacturer subject to NHTSA regulation in connection with any matter involving vehicle safety on which such person seeks official action by a NHTSA officer or employee.

Establishes the Vehicle Safety Fund to meet U.S. obligations in carrying out NHTSA vehicle safety programs. Requires the Secretary to assess and collect, for deposit in the Fund, a vehicle safety user fee from the manufacturer for each motor vehicle certified compliant with applicable motor vehicle safety standards.

Increases civil penalties for persons who violate federal motor vehicle safety requirements.

Requires the Secretary to: (1) notify manufacturers of motor vehicles or motor vehicle equipment whose defect or noncompliance with federal motor vehicle safety standards presents a substantial likelihood of death or serious injury to the public, and (2) expedite proceedings for a decision and issuance of an imminent hazard order. Directs the Secretary to issue procedures for the issuance and enforcement of such orders.

Prohibits the Secretary from promulgating motor vehicle safety regulations that address preemption of state tort law without congressional authorization.</summary>
</bill>
