<resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="H3D77FAFA3750427490AE4A7DCD8E4B95" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HRES 733 IH: Expressing support for designation of the month of September as “Clinical Research Innovation Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-09-17</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 733</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20140917">September 17, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters of California</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001270">Ms. Bass</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Expressing support for designation of the month of September as <quote>Clinical Research Innovation Month</quote>.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas>
      <text>Whereas Clinical Research Organizations (CROs) provide specially designed services which are
			 fundamental to the development of drugs, biologics, and medical devices
			 that improve the general health and well-being of the people of the United
			 States;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas CROs have more than doubled in size over the past decade;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the number of studies conducted by CROs has increased by over 500 percent over the past 8
			 years;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas CROs conduct 80 percent of the experimental research for innovative new drugs;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas CROs contribute more than 100,000 professional research jobs to the global innovation
			 economy;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas these cutting-edge research organizations undertake approximately two-thirds of business
			 activity for biopharmaceutical development, demonstrating their critical
			 involvement in the pharmaceutical, biotech, and medical device industries;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas of the 88 new drugs to receive <cato:entity-ref entity-id="7524" entity-type="federal-body">Food and Drug Administration</cato:entity-ref> and Emergency Medical
			 Associates approval last year, 85 of them were manufactured by CROs;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas CROs research medical solutions to combat diseases such as breast cancer, Alzheimer’s
			 Disease, hepatitis, diabetes, asthma, and hypertension;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas CROs have conducted thousands of clinical trials involving over 1,000,000 patients as they
			 strive to tackle the world’s most pressing medical issues through
			 innovative clinical research; and</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the month of September would be an appropriate time to designate as <quote>Clinical Research Innovation Month</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text>
    </whereas>
  </preamble>
	<resolution-body id="H769EDCD04C41490F87D5CB82831EBB23" style="traditional">
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE0F6D409A655408AB94628DEFC8D68F1" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="0050" entity-type="federal-body">House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
			<paragraph id="H297C85FD60E044D0B001744EF2065DC0">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports the designation of <quote>Clinical Research Innovation Month</quote>;</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HF774EA385218428D8AE53887EB8C3F00">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>recognizes the considerable contributions of Clinical Research Organizations to the United States;
			 and</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H3C509806CB864311A112F094BE98E634">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <text>honors these organizations, which will continue to inspire innovation in future generations.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>