<bill session="113" type="h" number="3051" updated="2015-09-01T10:19:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Coastal States Extension Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To extend State jurisdiction over submerged lands and to allow States to grant oil and natural gas leases in the extended area.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400607"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-08-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-02">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-02">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU05" subcommittee="Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="Public Lands and Environmental Regulation" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII22" subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="General public lands matters"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/2/2013--Introduced.
Coastal States Extension Act of 2013 - Amends the Submerged Lands Act to extend state jurisdiction over submerged lands from 3 geographical miles to 12 nautical miles distant from the coast line of a state.

Authorizes a state admitted subsequent to the date of enactment of this Act to assert its seaward boundaries to a line 12 nautical miles distant from its coast line.

States that any oil lease and natural gas lease executed by the Secretary of the Interior that is in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act, and which covers an area within lands transferred to states under this Act, shall remain in full force and effect until it either expires pursuant to its terms or is cancelled pursuant to the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (OCSLA).

Authorizes a state in whose territory the leased area is situated to grant oil and natural leases in such area.

Prohibits a state from granting a lease in an area transferred to it under OCSLA until the Secretary of Commerce determines that the state has either an approved management program, or is making satisfactory progress in developing such a program, pursuant to certain administrative grant requirements of the Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972.</summary>
</bill>
