<bill session="113" type="h" number="5151" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Student Loan Transparency for Success Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require certain information be included in loan disclosure statements prior to disbursement, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412527"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412314" joined="2014-07-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/17/2014--Introduced.
Student Loan Transparency for Success Act - Amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require institutions of higher education and loan originators, servicers, and collectors participating in the William D. Ford Federal Direct Loan program to include in the information they are required to provide Direct Loan borrowers prior to disbursement:

 the total aggregate amount of Direct Loans borrowed by the borrower; the estimated number of payments and total amount to be paid to repay such a loan based on a standard repayment plan; and the estimated average income and percentage of employment in the borrower's state for persons with a high school diploma or its equivalent, persons with some post-secondary education without completion of a degree or certificate, persons with a bachelor's degree, and persons with a post-baccalaureate degree.</summary>
</bill>
