<bill session="113" type="s" number="1938" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-01-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-01-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-01-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Quadrennial Energy Review Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Department of Energy Organization Act to replace the current requirement for a biennial energy policy plan with a Quadrennial Energy Review, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300080"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300002" joined="2014-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2014-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400040" joined="2014-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412390" joined="2014-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412281" joined="2014-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2014-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2014-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2014-01-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-01-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="552"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="General energy matters"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/16/2014--Introduced.
Quadrennial Energy Review Act of 2014 - Amends the Department of Energy Organization Act to direct the President to establish an interagency energy coordination council to coordinate the Quadrennial Energy Review to provide an integrated view of national energy objectives and federal energy policy, including maximum practicable alignment of research programs, incentives, regulations, and partnerships.

 Requires the President to report to Congress on the Quadrennial Energy Review, including an integrated view of short-, intermediate-, and long-term objectives for federal energy policy in the context of economic, environmental, and security priorities.

Authorizes the President to prepare and publish interim reports as part of the Quadrennial Energy Review.

Directs the Secretary of Energy to provide the Quadrennial Energy Review with an Executive Secretariat who shall make available the necessary analytical, financial, and administrative support for the conduct of each Quadrennial Energy Review.</summary>
</bill>
