<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE amendment-doc PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/amend.dtd//EN" "amend.dtd">
<amendment-doc amend-degree="first" amend-type="engrossed-amendment"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HR 3212 EAS: Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2014-07-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<engrossed-amendment-form>
<congress display="no">113th CONGRESS</congress><session display="no">2d Session</session><legis-num display="no">H.R. 3212</legis-num><current-chamber display="yes">In the Senate of the United States,</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20140707">July 16, 2014.</action-date></action><legis-type display="yes">Amendment:</legis-type></engrossed-amendment-form><engrossed-amendment-body><section id="id9f59ac213fb14abb821c4cf7031767c3" section-type="resolved"><text>That the bill from the House of Representatives (H.R. 3212) entitled <quote>An Act to ensure compliance with the 1980 Hague Convention on the Civil Aspects of International
			 Child Abduction by countries with which the United States enjoys
			 reciprocal obligations, to establish procedures for the prompt return of
			 children abducted to other countries, and for other purposes.</quote>, do pass with the following</text></section><amendment><amendment-instruction blank-lines-after="0"><text>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert:</text></amendment-instruction><amendment-block blank-lines-after="1" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic"><section id="id5bfca26a-56dc-4886-b0cd-3b81f3f73c63" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title and table of contents</header><subsection id="ideffc5380-7f7b-4996-b28e-c8322db27330"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Sean and David Goldman International Child Abduction Prevention and Return Act of 2014</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id49435146-664a-46a5-a6a2-dd2b1f9d95bd"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc changed="not-changed"><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 1. Short title and table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 2. Findings; sense of Congress; purposes.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 3. Definitions.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="title">TITLE I—Department of State actions</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 101. Annual report.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 102. Standards and assistance.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 103. Bilateral procedures, including memoranda of understanding.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 104. Report to congressional representatives.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="title">TITLE II—Actions by the Secretary of State</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 201. Response to international child abductions.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 202. Actions by the Secretary of State in response to patterns of noncompliance in cases of
			 international child abductions.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 203. Consultations with foreign governments.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 204. Waiver by the Secretary of State.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 205. Termination of actions by the Secretary of State.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="id329525DA96B44308BD84ED026FC8A6E3" level="title">TITLE III—Prevention of International Child Abduction</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="id511C2CB3AEFC4A06B8054B2BE921EDC9" level="section">Sec. 301. Preventing children from leaving the United States in violation of a court order.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="id0025fe9b6bbd41b2a8776152e689b317" level="section">Sec. 302. Authorization for judicial training on international parental child abduction.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><section id="id5fc5da88-c783-4a00-8318-03bcd2ed9fc7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings; sense of Congress; purposes</header><subsection id="id807f3471-a67d-4107-b2f9-5399f10a6acb"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="id198502d9-3f53-4b97-8c38-2390b34c4db2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Sean Goldman, a United States citizen and resident of New Jersey, was abducted from the United
			 States in 2004 and separated from his father, David Goldman, who spent
			 nearly 6 years battling for the return of his son from Brazil before
			 Sean was finally returned to Mr. Goldman’s custody on December 24, 2009.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idee03336b-970f-4b56-95e3-9687f9735267"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Department of State’s Office of Children’s Issues, which serves as the Central Authority of the
			 United States for the purposes of the 1980 Hague Convention on the Civil
			 Aspects of International Child Abduction (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Hague Abduction Convention</quote>), has received thousands of
			 requests since 2007 for assistance in the return to the United States of
			 children who have been wrongfully abducted by a parent or other legal
			 guardian to
			 another country.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9DB4ACB92DA94902BBFB2810ECB899D7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>For a variety of reasons reflecting the significant
			 obstacles to the recovery of abducted children, as well as the legal and
			 factual complexity involving such cases, not all cases are reported to the
			 Central Authority of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id83cf0c0d-ca22-4576-9a08-8e382773336a"><enum>(4)</enum><text>More than 1,000 outgoing international child abductions are reported every year to the Central
			 Authority of the United States, which depends solely on proactive
			 reporting of abduction cases.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc908d1b4-54dc-43a7-ac89-3e441fd9bda1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Only about one-half of the children abducted from the United States to countries with which the
			 United
			 States enjoys reciprocal obligations under the Hague Abduction Convention
			 are returned to the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9b137f50-a540-47e1-af5f-ba0db8b8e2d7"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The United States and other Convention countries have expressed their desire, through the Hague
			 Abduction
			 Convention, <quote>to protect children internationally from the harmful effects of their wrongful removal or retention
			 and to establish procedures to ensure their prompt return to the State of
			 their habitual residence, as well as to secure protection for rights of
			 access.</quote></text></paragraph><paragraph id="id94d9d4c4-45b4-44d4-9428-2b26a9c87193"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Compliance by the United States and other Convention countries depends on the actions of their
			 designated
			 central authorities, the performance of their judicial systems as
			 reflected in
			 the legal process and decisions rendered to enforce or effectuate the
			 Hague Abduction Convention, and the ability and willingness of their law
			 enforcement authorities to ensure the swift enforcement of orders rendered
			 pursuant to
			 the Hague Abduction Convention.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb1b2e30b-ed02-4c8e-84dc-0b09fdb4e91c"><enum>(8)</enum><text>According to data from the Department of State, approximately 40 percent
			 of abduction cases involve children taken from the United
			 States to countries with which the United States does not have reciprocal
			 obligations under the Hague
			 Abduction Convention or other arrangements relating to the
			 resolution of abduction cases.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id41484d64-a9b6-4f15-9d17-718ec0e7639c"><enum>(9)</enum><text>According to the Department of State’s April 2010 Report on Compliance with the Hague Convention on
			 the Civil Aspects of International Child Abduction, <quote>parental child abduction jeopardizes the child and has substantial long-term consequences for both
			 the child and the left-behind parent.</quote></text></paragraph><paragraph id="id53533ad8-60f6-46a5-bc72-1b71f2a5995d"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Few left-behind parents have
			 the extraordinary financial resources necessary—</text><subparagraph id="id31F2C1963C4D47379EE0063FF171AA5C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to pursue individual civil
			 or criminal remedies in both the United States and a foreign country, even
			 if such remedies are available; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7F3CB8799B094F8BA09C463B88D424E9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to engage in repeated foreign travel to attempt to
			 obtain the return of their children through diplomatic or
			 other channels.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idd6af422e-8c37-400d-a3df-ca4ee712ad33"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Military parents often face additional complications in resolving abduction
			 cases because of the challenges presented by their military obligations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf00140cd75f14569ab25985324a19a48"><enum>(12)</enum><text>In addition to using the Hague Abduction Convention to achieve the return of abducted children, the
			 United States has an array of Federal, State, and local law enforcement,
			 criminal justice, and judicial tools at its disposal to prevent
			 international abductions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8de7fbf2c38e4ed98c81a991bee80d43"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Federal agencies tasked with preventing international abductions have indicated that the most
			 effective way to stop international child abductions is while they are in
			 progress, rather than after the child has been removed to a foreign
			 destination.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6749973f4f854cbfba153c4682715840"><enum>(14)</enum><text>Parental awareness of abductions in progress, rapid response by relevant law enforcement, and
			 effective coordination among Federal, State, local, and international
			 stakeholders are critical in preventing such abductions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id477445221942486eb6e70d3f6a104316"><enum>(15)</enum><text>A more robust application of domestic tools, in cooperation with international law enforcement
			 entities and appropriate application of the Hague Abduction Convention
			 could—</text><subparagraph id="id32BDC4F65D4D4AFCBFAA7D061910FB9C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>discourage some parents from attempting abductions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2D7D4546E0664A73B372DBB332AA135C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>block attempted abductions at ports of exit; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id338FFC804AE6414BA14E6E60DAA10347"><enum>(C)</enum><text>help achieve the return of more abducted children.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id11f1ef23-c26e-47c7-95f7-0fc5b920b62f"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that the United States should set a strong example for other Convention
			 countries in the timely location and prompt resolution of cases involving
			 children abducted abroad and brought to the
			 United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="id55ced1bd-c904-474d-bf3d-22019b2af880"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of this Act are—</text><paragraph id="id50986b94-2f71-4b81-a937-62830b14fd86"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to protect children whose habitual residence is the United States from wrongful
			 abduction;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idAFED81D4729646E9AC53EE926382EC7F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to assist left-behind parents in quickly resolving cases and maintaining safe and predictable
			 contact with their
			 child while an abduction case is pending;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb37b46ea-92b7-40a4-bdfe-21907c6f122a"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to protect the custodial rights of parents, including military parents, by providing the parents,
			 the judicial  system, and law enforcement authorities with the
			 information they need to prevent unlawful abduction before it occurs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id720885DD6B3D4F7EAFEA3CCBC6705DA2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to enhance
			 the prompt resolution of abduction and access cases;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7ab3532c-5bef-450f-aed4-fed54f839ae4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to detail an appropriate set of actions to be undertaken by the Secretary of State
			 to address persistent problems in the resolution of abduction cases;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6c19241aa6b544f8bf9b5e4583f819b1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to establish a program to prevent wrongful abductions; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id53FCF4909A184E69AF664DB095F4AF60"><enum>(7)</enum><text>to increase interagency coordination in preventing international child abduction by convening a
			 working group composed of presidentially appointed and Senate confirmed
			 officials from the Department of State, the Department of Homeland
			 Security, and the Department of Justice.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ide7ac587c-dd8d-48ba-b55c-2f9bd116e580"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="idfa1e1650-ae6b-46a6-a402-53c2d4697388"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Abducted child</header><text>The term <term>abducted child</term> means a child who is the victim of international child abduction.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcdb7b576-3a07-41a6-89e7-cc2be117e554"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Abduction</header><text>The term <term>abduction</term> means the alleged wrongful removal of a child from the child’s country of habitual residence, or
			 the wrongful retention of a child outside such country, in
			 violation of a left-behind parent’s custodial rights, including the rights
			 of a military parent.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idab4bd7a2-ef5a-4d8c-aac8-e08e1565f1b0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Abduction case</header><text>The term <term>abduction case</term> means a case that—</text><subparagraph id="idDDAAB79FEA3E451FA9E47C5386F1A3B5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has been reported to the Central Authority of the United States by a
			 left-behind parent for the resolution of an abduction; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idDDAE6ABD4A9140C08845E4614B2A377C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>meets the criteria for an international child abduction under the Hague Abduction
			 Convention, regardless of whether the country at issue is a Convention
			 country.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4e6e956d-3795-4ec4-8853-01fa8e8fc758"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Access case</header><text>The term <term>access case</term> means a case involving an application filed with the Central Authority of the United States by a
			 parent seeking rights of access.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb7f6db0c-bd77-4b2e-a051-15cc80bd7f69"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>The term <term>Annual Report</term> means the Annual Report on International Child Abduction required under section 101.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id40da2a5f-36bc-484a-bd03-f1ecf3948568"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Application</header><text>The term <term>application</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id1631ecbf-52fa-4577-a443-bfd2be56257c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of a Convention country, the application required pursuant to article 8 of the Hague
			 Abduction Convention;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id29c97789-9ce9-460c-bfb2-00249f870103"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of a bilateral procedures country, the formal document required, pursuant to the
			 provisions of the
			 applicable arrangement, to request the return of an abducted child or to
			 request
			 rights of access, as applicable; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb3df3aa5-a802-4991-aef5-f067f0c3f203"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in the case of a non-Convention country, the formal request by the Central Authority of the United
			 States
			 to the Central Authority of such country requesting the return of an
			 abducted child or for rights of contact with an abducted child.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id235baecd-e80e-42fb-a536-4d4418bb1b6b"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</committee-name> and the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</committee-name>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id38DA05F692B74875AD939501FEC02E06"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Bilateral procedures</header><text>The term <term>bilateral procedures</term> means any procedures established by, or pursuant to, a bilateral arrangement, including a
			 Memorandum of Understanding  between the United States
			 and another
			 country, to resolve abduction and access cases,
			 including procedures to address interim contact matters.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3125244c-2f47-4cd5-a4ef-bd1c853f3a1f"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Bilateral procedures country</header><text>The term <term>bilateral procedures country</term> means a country with which the United States has entered into bilateral procedures, including
			 Memoranda of Understanding, with respect to child abductions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1c9f7756-fc06-4360-8d16-6e04a9dc8535"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Central authority</header><text>The term <term>Central Authority</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id0b50b0dc-ce84-4399-a202-c640dbacf605"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of a Convention country, the meaning given such term in article 6 of the Hague
			 Abduction Convention;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idFC0BC784B7084BC493A5A5238819956A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a bilateral procedures country, the official entity designated by the government of
			 the bilateral procedures country within the applicable memorandum of
			 understanding pursuant to section 103(b)(1) to discharge the duties
			 imposed on the entity; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id16bc0e20-20c7-412d-9722-99879b5b8aba"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in the case of a non-Convention country, the foreign ministry or other appropriate authority of
			 such country.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idce878ff5-1eab-4dba-a7bf-2ef529dbb81c"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Child</header><text>The term <term>child</term> means an individual who has not attained 16 years of age.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2fe887a8-6367-48cc-a991-7e907160d40f"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Convention country</header><text>The term <term>Convention country</term> means a country for which the Hague Abduction Convention has entered into force with respect to
			 the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id12180b7b-7747-4fa2-a0d4-6ce18a192f1a"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Hague abduction convention</header><text>The term <term>Hague Abduction Convention</term> means the Convention on the Civil Aspects of International Child Abduction, done at The Hague
			 October 25, 1980.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idABBBD4FA1BFF40D58710EC3591B7B145"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Interim contact</header><text>The term <term>interim contact</term> means the ability of a left-behind parent to communicate with or visit an abducted child during
			 the pendency of an abduction case.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id21e750c2-ba54-4d8b-8f67-8478f37b7047"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Left-behind parent</header><text>The term <term>left-behind parent</term> means an individual or legal custodian who alleges that an abduction has
			 occurred that is in breach of rights of custody attributed to such
			 individual.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8e72c7a6-9008-4664-9f1a-3b0968a3a13f"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Non-convention country</header><text>The term <term>non-Convention country</term> means a country in which the Hague Abduction Convention has not entered into force with respect to
			 the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id201E20C9434248F7871961236D1F2530"><enum>(17)</enum><header>Overseas military dependent child</header><text>The term <term>overseas military dependent child</term> means a child whose habitual residence is the United States according to United States law even
			 though the child is residing outside the United States with a military
			 parent.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd165aeed-278d-4b73-80d2-a060beb2e520"><enum>(18)</enum><header>Overseas military parent</header><text>The term <term>overseas military parent</term> means an individual who—</text><subparagraph id="id48F6E0B0FC3F4863A667247441C7BDFF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has custodial rights with respect to a child; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idAB2814CD8F9D496AB2A6DDF1FEA05441"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is serving outside the United
			 States as a member of the United States Armed Forces.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id21659669-9d20-4bbc-ae13-afe44c7b5d79"><enum>(19)</enum><header>Pattern of noncompliance</header><subparagraph id="idb786a26b-4cf7-4435-8ba8-769811eda891"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>pattern of noncompliance</term> means the persistent failure—</text><clause id="id62b8b8bd-2a49-4535-a9ef-c8a8ed35771f"><enum>(i)</enum><text>of a Convention country to implement and abide by provisions of the Hague Abduction Convention;</text></clause><clause id="ide708ec11-b096-492f-b731-216ec7037054"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>of a non-Convention country to abide by bilateral procedures that have been
			 established between the United States and such country; or</text></clause><clause id="idC60A7C53DAE748298A34475C72BDC8E9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>of a non-Convention country to work with the Central Authority of the United States to resolve
			 abduction cases.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id65059A2F4792466B9B4E55CC184F88AA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Persistent failure</header><text>Persistent failure under subparagraph (A) may be evidenced in a given country by the presence of 1
			 or more of the following criteria:</text><clause id="id1e59fd6d-6f2c-452a-996c-118dd38f088e"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Thirty percent or more of the total abduction cases in such country are unresolved abduction cases.</text></clause><clause id="id64769c96-12ce-48a4-be5a-8a5f467dff89"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The Central Authority regularly fails to fulfill its responsibilities pursuant to—</text><subclause id="id9DC38459C96C4678B284675A5B2CD66B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the
			 Hague Abduction Convention; or</text></subclause><subclause id="id228F7399A4354745BCCD19A77270456E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any bilateral procedures between the United States and such country.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id103f9bbd-1591-4f1f-936d-23230f8fb70b"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The judicial or administrative branch, as applicable, of the national government of
			 a Convention country or a bilateral procedures country fails to
			 regularly implement and comply with the provisions of the Hague
			 Abduction Convention or bilateral procedures, as applicable.</text></clause><clause id="id5678719b-2dfb-4578-b7fa-d9a3980bc30c"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Law enforcement authorities regularly fail to enforce return orders or
			 determinations of rights of access rendered by the judicial or
			 administrative authorities of the government of the country in
			 abduction cases.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5cb51fb3-de7f-4046-9a26-e94524538ff0"><enum>(20)</enum><header>Rights of access</header><text>The term <term>rights of access</term> means the establishment of rights of contact between a child and a parent seeking access in
			 Convention countries—</text><subparagraph id="id338956528A7645FFB41EFC1E397C4C1D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by operation of law;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0A6641E7A912444A8114A9A7F4552A96"><enum>(B)</enum><text>through a judicial or administrative determination; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idAD654D652E75466DB24D453757EACDAF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>through a legally enforceable arrangement between the parties.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2bd4c0d2-715e-45e7-83bd-3112c02f223d"><enum>(21)</enum><header>Rights of custody</header><text>The term <term>rights of custody</term> means rights of care and custody of a child, including the right to determine the place
			 of residence of a child, under the laws of the country in which
			 the child is a habitual resident—</text><subparagraph id="id783577fa-84e4-42d7-ae2a-717ff1423631"><enum>(A)</enum><text>attributed to an individual or legal custodian; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ideecc2b2d-0bdd-47e7-addf-5d948a1b088d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>arising—</text><clause id="id7E9217DA705141A5A27B98897298637E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by operation of law; or</text></clause><clause id="id49C1551F502C4DD480A4A97A325126B2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>through a judicial or administrative decision; or</text></clause><clause id="id4A46EC648F4344EF9E727E9F1930FE32"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>through a legally enforceable arrangement between the parties.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida1bb89a1a12e4055a068536495927768"><enum>(22)</enum><header>Rights of interim contact</header><text>The term <term>rights of interim contact</term> means the rights of contact between a child and a left-behind parent, which has been provided as a
			 provisional measure while an abduction case is pending, under the laws of
			 the country in which the child is located—</text><subparagraph id="id5E4C599E054E4A3482C57042FFDD4A42"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by operation of law; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF68C6851407F4408827A7B8E34759221"><enum>(B)</enum><text>through a judicial or administrative determination; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC36C9B6596FF4C94956F123DD47D196A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>through a legally enforceable arrangement between the parties.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idad88d42f-8e44-4bbf-a5e6-b45a41e4e61c"><enum>(23)</enum><header>Unresolved abduction case</header><subparagraph id="idb5e5e330-bf37-4fe6-a264-a978d092f77a"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), the term <term>unresolved abduction case</term> means an abduction case that remains unresolved for a period that exceeds 12 months after the date
			 on which the completed application for return of the child is submitted
			 for determination to the judicial or administrative authority, as
			 applicable, in the country in which the child is located.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4a5884f4-2aa6-4120-b49d-c58a607e119a"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Resolution of case</header><text>An abduction case shall be considered to be resolved if—</text><clause id="id1c75a28e-582a-4b0c-af3d-70bee4dbb02e"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the child is returned to the country of habitual residence, pursuant to the Hague Abduction
			 Convention or other appropriate bilateral procedures, if applicable;</text></clause><clause id="idb86f87fd-15a9-47e0-9f66-a2a80c28670d"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the judicial or administrative branch, as applicable, of the government of the country in
			 which the child is located has implemented, and is complying with, the
			 provisions of the Hague Abduction Convention or other bilateral
			 procedures, as applicable;</text></clause><clause id="idCEF4C8F989384970ABB31D3A4D237FF4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the left-behind parent reaches a voluntary arrangement with the other  parent;</text></clause><clause id="id123473afcdba44c5bac754d6a1016258"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the left-behind parent submits a written withdrawal of the application or the request for
			 assistance to the Department of State;</text></clause><clause id="idf5cf78bf172a41aa832d6d61c6b2b362"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the left-behind parent cannot be located for 1 year despite the documented efforts of the
			 Department of State to locate the parent; or</text></clause><clause id="ide3db0dcf81ba4600a2e2149b5628b550"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the child or left-behind parent is deceased.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></section><title id="id6b98dbdc-11a5-489f-9a39-1dbe065cf6f6"><enum>I</enum><header>Department of State actions</header><section id="id9caf7c49-d3ee-4cef-8e7a-13da758e031f"><enum>101.</enum><header>Annual report</header><subsection id="idcaafd1fc-f4fb-489f-9e99-a7e77b02c640"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than April 30 of each year, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate
			 congressional committees an Annual Report on International Child
			 Abduction. The Secretary shall post the Annual Report to the publicly
			 accessible website of the Department of
			 State.</text></subsection><subsection id="id064c4001-8a22-405b-8e42-3e62c1af3501"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each Annual Report shall include—</text><paragraph id="iddd0863a5-9d9d-4e17-97a1-1c078a88eec6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a list of all countries in  which there were 1 or more abduction cases, during the
			 preceding calendar year, relating to a child whose habitual residence is
			 the United States, including a description of whether each such country—</text><subparagraph id="id6E848F27AA6F4C2199F87383710D34A6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is a
			 Convention
			 country;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id14FA8A4DD5614BF38DBF5DCBC3C7A4EB"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is a bilateral procedures country;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD308658BC5424427B7F29CC16B148054"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has other procedures for resolving such abductions; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA2631DD7445D48A889ED00D07C58347F"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">adheres to no protocols with respect to child abduction;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4380bc78-29de-4dc0-8ebd-881d0a0b961f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for each country with respect to which there were 5 or more pending abduction cases, during the
			 preceding
			 year,	relating to a child whose habitual residence is the United States—</text><subparagraph id="id6c85573c-780c-4d21-9422-a2f4d3a55e06"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of such new abduction and access cases reported during the
			 preceding year;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4845ccbe-918e-4d36-a779-034f7f690d72"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for Convention and bilateral procedures countries—</text><clause id="id373F7924EEBA494C97BF3D8221015A5A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of abduction and access cases that the Central Authority of the United States
			 transmitted
			 to the Central Authority of
			 such country; and</text></clause><clause id="idD634900D69164897B1E7BA1BEDDD8D07"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the number of abduction and access cases that were not submitted by the Central Authority to the
			 judicial or administrative authority, as applicable, of such country;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6CCF67E331234ED29B312A6D28DEF6DA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the reason for the delay in submission of each case identified in subparagraph	(B)(ii) by the
			 Central
			 Authority of such country to the judicial or administrative authority of
			 that country;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7527600a-700b-4718-a651-450f658e7f57"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the number of unresolved abduction and access cases, and the length of time each case has been
			 pending;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2a842acc-12a6-416b-a0aa-50fd5137bd26"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the number and percentage of unresolved abduction cases in which law
			 enforcement authorities have—</text><clause id="id07D1839754934149857D225ADCDF83AC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>not located the abducted child;</text></clause><clause id="id023A460B29DA422AB174CF6AABB65799"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>failed to undertake serious efforts to locate the abducted child; and</text></clause><clause id="id8ED00FCAE6934D6CB113BB75E3F1BEF0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>failed to enforce a return
			 order rendered by the judicial or administrative authorities of such
			 country;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddc273fd3-9d16-4b65-a469-06fca8ff9c3b"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the total number and the percentage of the total number of abduction and access cases,
			 respectively, resolved during the preceding year;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida5cd034f-b3f3-4d04-9436-52acc89e9418"><enum>(G)</enum><text>recommendations to improve the resolution of abduction and access cases; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC6746DD2F8D5450488BD476B80985E02"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the average time it takes to locate a child;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id42db6827-0055-4a8b-9ddf-2a2bbe76242f"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the number of abducted children whose habitual residence is in the United States and who were
			 returned to the United States from—</text><subparagraph id="id2EC4011363F748D194102B1E1DE784CA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Convention countries;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id97079DCE2BE248BCBD5B789F131D52C1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>bilateral procedures countries;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id057DA238A37849128612F5B66E0B9994"><enum>(C)</enum><text>countries having other procedures for resolving such abductions; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id012AEF9354A24A15A8A90FD9ED5C932B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>countries adhering to no protocols with respect to child abduction;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4cfaf9d7-79c6-4ee6-9360-8474a1af7e00"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a list of Convention countries and bilateral procedures countries that have failed to
			 comply with any of their
			 obligations under the Hague Abduction Convention or bilateral procedures,
			 as
			 applicable, with respect to the resolution of abduction and access
			 cases;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2bb547fa-73a9-497d-8eb0-8561e47d8f5a"><enum>(5)</enum><text>a list of countries demonstrating a pattern of noncompliance and a description of the
			 criteria on
			 which the determination of a pattern of noncompliance for each country is
			 based;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id80c3e59a-676c-4ecf-b915-dc21b19e8563"><enum>(6)</enum><text>information on efforts by the Secretary of State to encourage non-Convention countries—</text><subparagraph id="idDEAD16C9310B4E4A8204754312B3D012"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to ratify or accede to the Hague Abduction Convention;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id22D676DE816F4F2885A48036F3E22103"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to enter into or implement other bilateral procedures, including memoranda of understanding, with
			 the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idFED757A8A3F943699FC0ED7BFCC68065"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to address pending abduction
			 and access cases;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id990223eb-5483-48c7-9518-7487fb737568"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of cases resolved without abducted children being returned to
			 the United States from Convention countries, bilateral
			 procedures countries, or
			 other non-Convention 
			 countries;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id57C986D1D14044268E607D389DD16453"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a list of countries that became Convention countries with respect to the United States during
			 the preceding year; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idA6DDE9FAFAF64C898B1F30CDA30C96B8"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information about efforts to seek resolution of abduction cases of children whose habitual
			 residence is in the United States and whose abduction occurred before the
			 Hague Abduction Convention entered into force with respect
			 to the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idba2af67d-ebb8-4746-b730-b2d19453a422"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>Unless a left-behind parent provides written permission to the Central Authority of the United
			 States to include personally identifiable information about the parent or
			 the child in the Annual Report, the
			 Annual Report may not include any personally identifiable information
			 about any such parent, child, or party to an abduction or access case
			 involving such parent or child.</text></subsection><subsection id="id90903fec-cbaa-4e1a-86d4-f6f67a9a79f1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Additional sections</header><text>Each Annual Report shall also include—</text><paragraph id="id1258d14e-3b6d-4dcd-a029-2a681bb34b1e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>information on the number of unresolved abduction cases affecting military parents;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id591004D05B9C48D093E305769FA304EC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of the assistance offered to such military parents;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id762e40c7-c009-43a4-b266-3da9f9d901cf"><enum>(3)</enum><text>information on the use of airlines in abductions, voluntary airline practices to prevent
			 abductions, and recommendations for best airline practices to prevent
			 abductions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id778a008f-0ba5-4bf2-989f-f66e4edbfd9d"><enum>(4)</enum><text>information on actions taken by the Central Authority of the United States to train domestic judges
			 in the application of the Hague Abduction Convention; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2fde81e2-1c0c-4869-b6a3-5aa10c93bde4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>information on actions taken by the Central Authority of the United States to train United States
			 Armed Forces legal assistance personnel, military chaplains, and military
			 family support center personnel about—</text><subparagraph id="idCE30DB5C5BC14A968C01F39002CD7F91"><enum>(A)</enum><text>abductions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD53041044A164225A96662350C291182"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the risk of loss of
			 contact with children; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7575E50060EC46BDA9D9CDBB0C04C46F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the legal means available to resolve such
			 cases.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id66b133d8-625a-44c7-b5ca-af8e2098d3ab"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Repeal of the Hague Abduction Convention Compliance Report</header><text>Section 2803 of the Foreign Affairs Reform and Restructuring Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11611">42 U.S.C. 11611</external-xref>) is repealed.</text></subsection><subsection id="id60b9c4bba4ce406ab4764cffb28cf942"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Notification to Congress on countries in noncompliance</header><paragraph id="id17B49DEE07B448ADA0AB1F99257E631E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of State shall include, in a separate section of the
			 Annual
			 Report, the Secretary’s determination, pursuant to the provisions under
			 section 202(b), of whether each country listed in
			 the report has engaged in a pattern of
			 noncompliance in cases of child abduction during the preceding 12 months.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idEE578B79E239499986603B909A3ACA4E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The section described in paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="id8193BFEFF13D472C85D1091B1E3A2DA2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall identify any action or actions described in section 202(d) (or commensurate action as
			 provided in section 202(e)) that have been taken by the Secretary with
			 respect to each country;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id08F08060407D4927886CD45B1E570C97"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall describe the basis for the Secretary’s determination of the pattern of noncompliance by each
			 country;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id145B2EC12FAC485E9920A5F7A159E86F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>shall indicate whether noneconomic policy options designed to resolve the pattern of
			 noncompliance
			 have reasonably been
			 exhausted, including the consultations required under section 203.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id52938abd-b47f-40b1-84c4-830f86e4a5a7"><enum>102.</enum><header>Standards and assistance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of State shall—</text><paragraph id="id9821AA02E4974B56BBBC36E78DF4A7BF"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure that United States diplomatic and consular missions abroad—</text><subparagraph id="idCCBE581B26184429BC7E015BAD700E19"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">maintain a consistent reporting standard with respect to abduction and access cases;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD4AEDA1FDBD14F5A8F29827108E08628"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">designate at least 1 senior official in each such mission, at the discretion of the Chief of
			 Mission, to assist left-behind parents from the United
			 States who are visiting such country or otherwise seeking to resolve
			 abduction or access cases; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB5E6BFE53AE3456194D76EC18F43AC62"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">monitor developments in abduction and access cases; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9fd19410b2244a48b90b521e61cde31b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop and implement written strategic plans for engagement with any Convention or non-Convention
			 country in which there are 5 or more cases of international child
			 abduction.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id1f1eac1d-c868-4f20-b687-7ae016e2008e"><enum>103.</enum><header>Bilateral procedures, including memoranda of understanding</header><subsection id="id7E3581338A06468FB69FB3492FFA98D8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Development</header><paragraph id="id5C6CD5FF804D4CBF93EF5243EFE621A2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall
			 initiate a process to develop and enter into appropriate bilateral
			 procedures, including
			 memoranda of understanding, as appropriate, with non-Convention
			 countries that are unlikely to become Convention countries in the
			 foreseeable
			 future, or with Convention countries that have unresolved abduction cases
			 that occurred before the Hague Abduction Convention entered into force
			 with respect to the United States or that country.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idFA3D956CA3404FA0B738F66FB7613B55"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prioritization</header><text>In carrying out paragraph (1), the Secretary of State shall give priority to countries with
			 significant abduction cases and related issues.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1BA1C2C4419147FEB6143CE18F038C62"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The bilateral procedures described in subsection (a) should include provisions relating to—</text><paragraph id="id6ff3f61b-458b-4d81-9d91-3fb5b9694018"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the identification of—</text><subparagraph id="id4AF8AEBDB05E451A9CEC7E3ABF5D156F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Central Authority;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9b53c5978b9a4e78b56e1aa81a15d904"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the judicial or administrative authority that will promptly adjudicate abduction and access cases;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb359da5d3c254ae7bd2f622bb15ae0b1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the law enforcement agencies; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id85080CA5A90D4CD99AC2C255D717ACBB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the implementation of procedures to ensure the
			 immediate enforcement of an order issued by the authority identified
			 pursuant to subparagraph (B) to return an abducted child to a left-behind
			 parent, including by—</text><clause id="idffd3801857fe436489d0d745058d9ae3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>conducting an investigation to ascertain the location of the abducted child;</text></clause><clause id="ida1c0eeeab0f64230a04fcca01e14e2a3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>providing protection to the abducted child after such child is located; and</text></clause><clause id="id59e190cb038c4c898a9b9a61cec68690"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>retrieving the abducted child and making the appropriate arrangements for such child to be returned
			 to the child’s country of habitual residence;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0c8a0f23-3987-4694-b1a3-b2f6f4ea35f3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the implementation of a protocol to effectuate the return of an abducted child identified in an
			 abduction case not later than 6 weeks after the application with respect
			 to the abduction case has been submitted to the judicial or administrative
			 authority, as applicable, of the country in which the abducted child is
			 located;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id64944280-9ba7-4f60-80e6-e23a61466f29"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the implementation of a protocol for the establishment and protection of the rights of interim
			 contact during pendency of
			 abduction cases; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide3835e7a-6bae-4daf-bd21-27daf067dbee"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the implementation of a protocol to establish periodic visits between a United States embassy or
			 consular official and an
			 abducted child, in order to allow the official to ascertain the child’s
			 location and
			 welfare.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id8c958807-b634-41eb-a650-c7ca6655d661"><enum>104.</enum><header>Report to congressional representatives</header><subsection id="id1e68d035-b247-4470-84c6-85144c3c6b2d"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Notification</header><text>The Secretary of State shall submit written notification to the Member of
			 Congress and Senators, or Resident Commissioner or Delegate, as
			 appropriate, representing the legal residence of a left-behind
			 parent if such parent—</text><paragraph id="idC40D7B8AB6B9468A864163AAD086CB95"><enum>(1)</enum><text>reports an abduction to the Central Authority of
			 the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id82618D52641648FF9306A48483553271"><enum>(2)</enum><text>consents to such notification.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idEB0491EC8CB24DFF90CDFAF6C3682682"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Timing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At the request of any person who is a left-behind parent, including a left-behind parent who
			 previously reported an abduction to the Central Authority of the United
			 States before the date of the enactment of this Act, the notification
			 required under subsection (a) shall be
			 provided as soon as is practicable.</text></subsection></section></title><title id="idd68b7c16-8016-4846-b845-1bd24c4c6f4d"><enum>II</enum><header>Actions by the Secretary of State</header><section id="id2edbdec5-58c3-4dda-b171-4b64585d9ee8"><enum>201.</enum><header>Response to international child abductions</header><subsection id="idef2f1fd6-ee6c-4be6-a4a6-5db522db0eea"><enum>(a)</enum><header>United States policy</header><text>It is the policy of the United States—</text><paragraph id="idb077a3a0-f1af-4c92-b5ed-29d565ee6fdf"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to promote the best interest of children wrongfully abducted from the United States by—</text><subparagraph id="idECC232F1C7534A79B50D74A945010B7A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establishing legal
			 rights
			 and procedures for their prompt return; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9D4D667E4B2F47EE953BFA2F9442C592"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensuring the enforcement of reciprocal
			 international obligations under the Hague Abduction Convention or
			 arrangements under bilateral procedures;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id75F1344BE5644BB0A5DBA26710370E1B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to promote the timely resolution of abduction cases through 1 or more of the actions described in
			 section 202; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc9119eec-19e5-4b0a-87bf-c7a6a275e1c2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to ensure appropriate coordination within the Federal Government and between Federal, State, and
			 local agencies involved in abduction prevention, investigation, and
			 resolution.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1456869B520F46E7B338DB2BE07D4267"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Actions by the Secretary of State in response to unresolved cases</header><paragraph id="id79bac7b8-264a-471e-932f-fbac302f453d"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Determination of action by the secretary of state</header><text>For each abduction or access case relating to a child whose habitual residence is in the United
			 States that remains pending or is otherwise unresolved on the date that is
			 12 months after the date on which the Central Authority of the United
			 States submits such case to a foreign country,  the Secretary of State
			 shall determine whether the government of such foreign country has failed
			 to take
			 appropriate steps to resolve the case. If the Secretary of State
			 determines that such failure occurred, the Secretary should, as
			 expeditiously as
			 practicable—</text><subparagraph id="id399A5F94865844AE81793C40FF1042AE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>take 1 or more of the actions described in subsections (d) and (e) of section 202; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0E54AD5AE87B450FACD1DB30D194C68F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>direct the Chief of Mission in that foreign country to directly address the resolution of the case
			 with senior officials in the foreign government.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idb5cc1a22-6135-45a4-bd2f-ef627aae1edc"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authority for delay of action by the secretary of state</header><text>The Secretary of State may delay any action described in paragraph (1) if the Secretary determines
			 that an additional period
			 of time, not to exceed 1 year, will substantially assist in resolving the
			 case.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idFEB3D932C124472FA769C2F86DD4B403"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report</header><text>If the Secretary of State delays  any action pursuant to paragraph (2) or decides not to take an
			 action described in subsection (d) or (e) of section 202 after making the
			 determination described in paragraph (1), the Secretary,  not later than
			 15 days after such delay or decision, shall provide a report to the
			 appropriate
			 congressional committees that details the reasons for delaying action or
			 not taking action, as appropriate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idFCA5845CAAA643C9ACFB8B90371D9017"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Congressional briefings</header><text>At the request of the appropriate congressional committees, the Secretary of State shall provide a
			 detailed briefing, including a written report, if requested, on actions
			 taken to resolve a case or the cause for delay.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idff98af31-2426-4dc3-9db0-d13f0745c2ce"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Implementation</header><paragraph id="id8494ef7b-ee7c-4e2a-921b-4de357277498"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out subsection (b), the Secretary of State should—</text><subparagraph id="id88843497-63e8-4f8b-ba08-ff1a9640fece"><enum>(A)</enum><text>take 1 or more actions that most appropriately respond to the nature and severity of the
			 governmental failure
			 to resolve the unresolved abduction case; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ided0d88ed-f883-477b-8a33-49637a24ffd8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>seek, to the fullest extent possible—</text><clause id="id0FC7A1746E0C47C88EF8B011EBDF21AE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to initially respond by communicating with the
			 Central Authority of the country; and</text></clause><clause id="id20F329A5CDFD447D970D767442649E45"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if clause (i) is unsuccessful, to target subsequent actions—</text><subclause id="id026F3C2FD16A4ACFADFD9C695CA2A24D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>as narrowly as
			 practicable, with respect to the
			 agencies or instrumentalities of the foreign government that are
			 responsible for such failures; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id3C82950440F94483893EE74E23238099"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in ways that respect the separation of
			 powers and independence of the judiciary of the country, as applicable.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id16af8801-b8dd-4970-9467-a3e49c259a3c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Guidelines for actions by the secretary of state</header><text>In addition to the guidelines under paragraph (1), the Secretary of State, in determining whether
			 to take
			 1 or more actions under paragraphs (5) through (7) of section 202(d) or
			 section 202(e), shall seek to
			 minimize any adverse impact on—</text><subparagraph id="id46e28f16-db6e-44bc-9b9f-f2a236dc722a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the population of the country whose government is targeted by the action or actions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id372f8553-db93-4139-9eea-9aff25064f86"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the humanitarian activities of United States and nongovernmental organizations in the
			 country; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0EF37111EA55407F8D18B353AD678E17"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the national security interests of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id2a492550-51c6-4f74-8726-d337873b6dcb"><enum>202.</enum><header>Actions by the Secretary of State in response to patterns of noncompliance in cases of
			 international child
			 abductions</header><subsection id="idd1b4ff81-f268-4c3f-8ef1-375b7a449f91"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Response to a pattern of noncompliance</header><text>It is the policy of the United States—</text><paragraph id="id56b29df1-6e61-4544-8b86-8d056e72c4f9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to oppose institutional or other systemic failures of foreign governments to fulfill their
			 obligations
			 pursuant to the Hague Abduction Convention or bilateral procedures, as
			 applicable, to
			 resolve abduction and access cases;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id40b8a48c-c72c-4235-a757-f47fc0e9aa76"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to promote reciprocity pursuant to, and in compliance with, the Hague Abduction Convention or
			 bilateral procedures, as appropriate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3CD7F03970544DD2AC43E191F65954E6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to directly engage with senior foreign government officials to most effectively address patterns of
			 noncompliance.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id104f017d-1a53-4e1e-9ce9-0a01b8775339"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Determination of countries with patterns of noncompliance in cases of international child abduction</header><paragraph id="id12845286-9bcb-48bb-aa01-9345888fb855"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Annual review</header><text>Not later than April 30 of each year, the Secretary of State shall—</text><subparagraph id="idFB4EB4A7303C44969996F4352CA61EA0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>review the status of abduction
			 and
			 access cases in each foreign country in order to determine whether the
			 government
			 of such country has engaged in a pattern of noncompliance during the
			 preceding 12 months; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id883ADC02E81E4A71922DF9D7E8DB6915"><enum>(B)</enum><text>report such determination pursuant to section 101(f).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7b9f55b5-838d-448b-906b-cc20ceb0f6c1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Determinations of responsible parties</header><text>The Secretary of State shall seek to determine the
			 agencies or
			 instrumentalities of the government of each country determined to have
			 engaged in a pattern of noncompliance under
			 paragraph (1)(A) that are responsible for such pattern
			 of noncompliance—</text><subparagraph id="idB0788865E9504547BE956789DF2DB3BD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to appropriately target
			 actions in response to such noncompliance;  and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id934510A9C14B4A0FA69DD6AD6EE46B56"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to engage with senior foreign government officials to effectively address such noncompliance.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id19a17853-7197-4689-8c8e-8f359e7850e1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Actions by the Secretary of State with respect to a country with a pattern of noncompliance</header><paragraph id="ide3beafe2-1ef9-405d-95cb-39f5dd5f2edd"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later
			 than 90 days (or 180 days in case of a delay under paragraph (2)) after a
			 country is determined to have been engaged in a pattern
			 of noncompliance under subsection (b)(1)(A), the Secretary of State shall—</text><subparagraph id="id032564B31EB945959367B92D83B5F298"><enum>(A)</enum><text>take
			 1 or more of the actions described in subsection
			 (d);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD3CEA005734E455AB86F30D723355AD6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>direct the Chief of Mission in that country to directly address the systemic problems that led to
			 such determination; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id52FAB0ACD99D48A9BC5ED386C368B6A5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>inform senior officials in the foreign government of the potential repercussions related to such
			 designation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id62b6ba01-1d09-4b54-a183-bc1c8f6eb840"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authority for delay of actions by the secretary of state</header><text>The Secretary shall not be required to take action under paragraph (1) until the expiration of a
			 single, additional period of up to 90 days if, on or before the date on
			 which the Secretary of State is required to take such action, the
			 Secretary determines and certifies to the appropriate congressional
			 committees that 
			 such additional period is necessary—</text><subparagraph id="iddc49f313-0f5b-42a0-a772-17eb02492258"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for a continuation of negotiations that have been commenced with the government of a country
			 described in paragraph (1) in order to bring about a cessation of the
			 pattern of
			 noncompliance by such country;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id48612bb4-d470-4183-8f83-1b38f5633134"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for a review of corrective action taken by a country after the designation of such country as being
			 engaged in a
			 pattern of noncompliance under subsection (b)(1)(A); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5DA9E7C1B2214A1390A0F0E07738C4FD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in
			 anticipation that corrective action will be taken by such country during
			 such 90-day period.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id56087a08-e3b9-4b5a-a6da-50416d7c79df"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exception for additional action by the secretary of state</header><text>The Secretary of State shall not be required to take additional action under paragraph (1) with
			 respect to a
			 country
			 determined to have been engaged in a persistent pattern of noncompliance
			 if the Secretary—</text><subparagraph id="id4E713C5B369E4BF1926C1A280348AAEA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has taken action pursuant to paragraph (5), (6), or (7) of subsection (d) with respect to such
			 country in the
			 preceding year and such action continues to be in effect;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id771092F317E34F36B4A488ADBAF16DE0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>exercises the waiver under section 204 and briefs the appropriate congressional committees; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB135A6DC669F49309D43DFD810E54643"><enum>(C)</enum><text>submits a report to the appropriate congressional committees that—</text><clause id="id96057B24D03643D5A2B4EF09623B9010"><enum>(i)</enum><text>indicates that such country is subject to multiple,
			 broad-based sanctions; and</text></clause><clause id="id8E7BD7670EDD47DC993D70FC266CC84D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>describes how such sanctions satisfy the requirements under this subsection.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idbb38afc3e5b542f0bf488f3c510b59d7"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Report to congress</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the submission of the Annual Report, the Secretary shall submit a
			 report to Congress on the specific actions taken against countries
			 determined to have been engaged in a
			 pattern of noncompliance under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8419e01b2e48485dbd26d5b387f4475d"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Description of actions by the Secretary of State in Hague Abduction Convention countries</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (f), the actions by the Secretary of State referred to in this
			 subsection are—</text><paragraph id="idd76a3cd4818c4fa58e76bbdbf195e065"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a demarche;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide000034f8815498a9a55fa53adabb2c6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an official public statement detailing unresolved cases;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf9ebd5f9e1cc4e4a91aee05c413879e2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a public condemnation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3e422b07f7364f89afc44b6ce9fd515d"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a delay or cancellation of 1 or more bilateral working, official, or state visits;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5438cb666bf94cf5898bea45615b8608"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the withdrawal, limitation, or suspension of United States development assistance in accordance
			 with section 116 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2151n">22 U.S.C. 2151n</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf0869d9e0e734de6af87e0847ba653d6"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the withdrawal, limitation, or suspension of United States security assistance in accordance with
			 section 502B of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2304">22 U.S.C. 2304</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5567b711e1e543178e42a87d0baaa2e8"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the withdrawal, limitation, or suspension of assistance to the central government of a country
			 pursuant to chapter 4 of part II of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (22
			 U.S.C. 2346 et seq.; relating to the Economic Support Fund); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8d325058be8649cca85761ec74954ddd"><enum>(8)</enum><text>a formal request to the foreign country concerned to extradite an individual who is engaged in
			 abduction and who has been formally accused of, charged with, or convicted
			 of an extraditable offense.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide770c12de6824312b5134c73b770fa41"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Commensurate action</header><paragraph id="idbc98949c982d4ea0b873c5f5fd1625b1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (f), the Secretary of State may substitute any other action
			 authorized by law for any action described in subsection (d) if the
			 Secretary determines that such
			 action—</text><subparagraph id="id1a0d4d4876684914b71c9722fde0aece"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is commensurate in effect to the action substituted; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id377937b25f124e1387f32dc46672a29c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>would substantially further the purposes of this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide855581ff4e546679cc356e9ac196e87"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notification</header><text>If commensurate action is taken pursuant to this subsection, the Secretary shall submit a report to
			 the appropriate congressional committees that—</text><subparagraph id="id514CF2870D4A466BB482DF3E7776CA0F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>describes such action;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8C45379C22E34414BDC647C9B7544F31"><enum>(B)</enum><text>explains the reasons for taking such action; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8B13F13E98B440A198B2ED09A640359B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>specifically describes the basis for the Secretary’s determination under paragraph (1) that such
			 action—</text><clause id="id1A15C90D93604CA18D23925107CA2143"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is commensurate with the action substituted; and</text></clause><clause id="id0C4A97D1DD594788BC1784BA54FB287C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>substantially furthers the purposes of this Act.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id6991d3b9632543fcbc5871c23edae8ea"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Resolution</header><text>The Secretary of State shall seek to take all appropriate actions authorized by law to
			 resolve the unresolved case or to obtain the cessation of such pattern of
			 noncompliance, as applicable.</text></subsection><subsection id="id82769dd7d7e7443abac8e6031daccf15"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Humanitarian exception</header><text>Any action taken pursuant to subsection (d) or (e) may not prohibit or restrict the provision of
			 medicine, medical equipment or supplies, food, or other life-saving
			 humanitarian assistance.</text></subsection></section><section id="idc4395f02-d80e-4d9f-a074-b38105f75490"><enum>203.</enum><header>Consultations with foreign governments</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">As soon as practicable after the Secretary of State makes a determination under section 201 in
			 response to
			 a failure to resolve unresolved abduction cases or the Secretary takes an
			 action under subsection (d) or (e) of section 202, based on a pattern of
			 noncompliance, the Secretary
			 shall request consultations with the government of such country regarding
			 the situation giving rise to
			 such determination.</text></section><section id="id3244aa3f-472e-4557-b1eb-c1967687d12c"><enum>204.</enum><header>Waiver by the Secretary of State</header><subsection id="id0625cc1d-eac5-4401-aac6-5564691b541d"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subsection (b), the Secretary of State may waive the application of any of the actions
			 described
			 in subsections (d) and (e) of section	202 with respect to a country if
			 the Secretary
			 determines and notifies the appropriate congressional committees
			 that—</text><paragraph id="ide4f09764-aa88-40c5-9406-caef83081716"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the government of such country—</text><subparagraph id="idA4022F6BA672421F9C379C251FB7821C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has satisfactorily resolved the abduction cases giving
			 rise to the
			 application of any of such actions; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD5EC71EA112D4BE18F4520687274EE06"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has ended such country’s pattern of noncompliance; or</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5794582b-7be7-4431-906f-ad967dc00145"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the national security interest of the United States requires the exercise of such waiver
			 authority.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1f3cb7d3-6067-4285-947a-af7bad807692"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Congressional notification</header><text>Not later than the date on which the Secretary of State exercises the waiver
			 authority under
			 subsection (a),  the Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="id575F49FF5C7A4CC495F2D6868D794A6A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>notify the appropriate congressional committees of such waiver; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3F8C994EE38F4C329DB8EF271343EBD7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide such committees with a detailed justification
			 for such waiver, including an explanation of the steps the noncompliant
			 government has taken—</text><subparagraph id="idECA41FEA55D44D85BDF37EC7D6C3719D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to resolve abductions cases; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3B28B713A8D74A5CBECCF2277D4A8C71"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to end its pattern of noncompliance.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id91f529d7-c916-45e9-b243-bba166e3067b"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Publication in Federal Register</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subsection (d), the Secretary of  State shall ensure that each waiver determination
			 under this section—</text><paragraph id="id0B589B42B3604A59BA88634FC56EBDBC"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is published in the Federal Register; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7552B8CEF7BB44C88DD17EF5C79F7C49"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is posted on the Department of State website.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id76c0634660ab45599b86bbaff54d830f"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limited disclosure of information</header><text>The Secretary of State may limit the publication of information under subsection (c) in the
			 same
			 manner and to the same extent as the President may limit the publication
			 of findings and determinations described in section 654(c) of the Foreign
			 Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2414">22 U.S.C. 2414(c)</external-xref>), if the Secretary determines
			 that the publication of such information would be harmful to the national
			 security of the United States and would not further the purposes of this
			 Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="id669dd411-b3b7-4595-9ee5-dbdb976d2d3c"><enum>205.</enum><header>Termination of actions by the Secretary of State</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Any specific action taken under this Act or any amendment made by this Act with respect to a
			 foreign country
			 shall terminate on the date on which the Secretary of State submits a
			 written certification to Congress that the
			 government of such country—</text><paragraph id="id9AAF081EBF694633B7EC781153065006"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has resolved any
			 unresolved abduction case that gave rise to such specific action; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id42DA26B00E484CA4A669F5295A4547D8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has taken substantial and verifiable steps to
			 correct such country’s persistent pattern of noncompliance that gave rise
			 to such specific action, as applicable.</text></paragraph></section></title><title id="id329525DA96B44308BD84ED026FC8A6E3" style="OLC"><enum>III</enum><header>Prevention of International Child Abduction</header><section id="id511C2CB3AEFC4A06B8054B2BE921EDC9"><enum>301.</enum><header>Preventing children from leaving the United States in violation of a court order</header><subsection id="id02886C4722074765A7E765763CC19E6A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subtitle C of title IV of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/231">6 U.S.C. 231 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by
			 adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block changed="added" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD84C972E83AD4EBAB765858CCABB2A1B" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC"><section id="id1FEEFE93A29D4ABEAA78862281D20357"><enum>433.</enum><header>Prevention of international child abduction</header><subsection id="idA478346C69BF4DBFB345EDC7C7E78096"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program established</header><text>The Secretary, through the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection (referred to in this
			 section as <quote>CBP</quote>), in coordination with the Secretary of State,
			 the Attorney General, and the Director of the Federal Bureau of
			 Investigation, shall establish a program that—</text><paragraph id="idD31A32D128694F259880CDA2FEBEC12E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>seeks to prevent a child
			 (as
			 defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/1204">section 1204(b)(1)</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code) from
			 departing from the territory of the United States if a parent
			 or legal guardian of such child presents a court order from a court of
			 competent jurisdiction prohibiting the removal of such child from the
			 United States to a CBP Officer in sufficient time to prevent such
			 departure for the
			 duration of such court order; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idDF5D2EC436D9456A8B74EF4CB8326037"><enum>(2)</enum><text>leverages other existing authorities and processes to address the wrongful removal and return of a
			 child.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id52A7CF635AE14F538D9505462F73AC5C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Interagency coordination</header><paragraph id="id6359AD04BD9145518E9AEC84C04178D1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of State shall convene and chair an interagency working group to prevent
			 international parental child abduction. The group shall be composed of
			 presidentially appointed, Senate confirmed officials from—</text><subparagraph id="idD5453E6AF6524A758A5A792722B77AEF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Department of State;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1392AF2533934D9BBDEF9D1C44A6E1CF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Department of Homeland Security, including U.S. Customs and Border Protection and U.S.
			 Immigration and
			 Customs Enforcement; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id03B2BD13F6334171B77C046D90D6DD3E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Department of Justice, including the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0CE3B3217BD34D5A82FEAD3DB8761438"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Department of defense</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall designate an official within the Department of Defense—</text><subparagraph id="idFCC88F54356B44A7852346ECC361E4CD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to coordinate with the Department of State on international child abduction issues; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF5619B0E666B4310BE42340421F79B4D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to oversee activities designed to prevent or resolve international child abduction cases relating
			 to active duty military service members.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id0808651AD5EA4FF996DAEB488FD68A2A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/101">6 U.S.C. 101</external-xref> note) is amended by adding
			 after the item relating to section 432 the following:</text><quoted-block changed="added" id="id41e56dc4-3163-40e6-81c5-3bc97496b600" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC"><toc changed="not-changed"><toc-entry idref="id1FEEFE93A29D4ABEAA78862281D20357" level="section">Sec. 433. Prevention of international child abduction.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="id0025fe9b6bbd41b2a8776152e689b317"><enum>302.</enum><header>Authorization for judicial training on international parental child abduction</header><subsection id="id57d32a294f954d5d95b08a3e15027a6d"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of State, subject to the availability of appropriations, shall seek to provide
			 training, directly or through another government agency or nongovernmental
			 organizations, on the
			 effective handling of parental abduction cases to the judicial and
			 administrative authorities in countries—</text><paragraph id="id39d88563eea74ec1ae6c3fb8e8a05d03"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in which a significant number of unresolved abduction cases are pending; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id42e2133751af4f8aa5ac60cad05c084b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>that have been designated as having a pattern of noncompliance under section 202(b).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idcd6257fd4a374a4d8b132be0a278b175"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Strategy requirement</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall submit a
			 strategy to carry out the activities described in subsection (a) to—</text><paragraph id="ida6acbc4ac892478fb4596c35e5db79ef"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idF1D1D3797C7E4881B03A7E993A7362DB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</committee-name>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id807D02EC3DB64EA391605C79D00C3D4D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSAP00">Committee on Appropriations of the Senate</committee-name>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id69501b02390d4e7c8e1de5a5412e46d7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives</committee-name>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2318800bca6545abba126abb2b699dc2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><paragraph id="id87288337DAFF42A88073AD3831C588C6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is  authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of State $1,000,000 for each of the
			 fiscal years 2015 and 2016
			 to carry out subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD6F1EA5E16094040B83B29DA879AD2DC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Amounts appropriated for the activities set forth in subsection (a) shall be used pursuant to the
			 authorization and requirements under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></title></amendment-block></amendment></engrossed-amendment-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestor></attestor><role>Secretary</role></attestation-group></attestation><endorsement></endorsement></amendment-doc>


