<bill session="113" type="s" number="1323" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Our Youth from Dangerous Synthetic Drugs Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to address the continued threat posed by dangerous synthetic drugs by amending the Controlled Substances Act relating to controlled substance analogues.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300043"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412493" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2014-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2014-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2013-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2013-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412391" joined="2013-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400325" joined="2013-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2013-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2013-11-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5801-5802"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5802-5803" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-25">
      <text>Committee on United States Senate Caucus on International Narcotics Control. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-14">
      <text>Committee on United States Senate Caucus on International Narcotics Control. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SCNC" name="Senate Caucus on International Narcotics Control" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="U.S. Sentencing Commission"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/18/2013--Introduced.
Protecting Our Youth from Dangerous Synthetic Drugs Act of 2013 - Amends the Controlled Substances Act to include in the definition of a "controlled substance analogue" a substance designated as such by the Controlled Substance Analogue Committee (established by this Act).

Directs the Attorney General to establish such Committee as an interagency committee headed by the Administrator of the Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA) and comprised of scientific experts in the fields of chemistry and pharmacology from DEA, the National Institute on Drug Abuse, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), and any other federal agency determined by the Attorney General to be appropriate.

 Requires the Committee to designate, and establish and maintain a list of, controlled substance analogues determined to be similar to a schedule I or II controlled substance in either chemical structure or predictive effect on the body in such a manner as to make it likely that the substance will, or can be reasonably expected to, have a potential for abuse. Directs the Administrator to publish a description of each designation made by the Committee.

Amends the Controlled Substances Import and Export Act to prohibit the importation of any controlled substance analogue except pursuant to such notification or declaration as the Attorney General may prescribe.

Directs the U.S. Sentencing Commission to review and, if appropriate, amend the federal sentencing guidelines and policy statements to ensure that they provide adequate penalties for any offense involving the unlawful manufacturing, importing, exporting, or trafficking of controlled substance analogues and similar offenses.</summary>
</bill>
