<bill session="113" type="s" number="2296" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-05-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Appeals Improvement Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to employ at least three decision review officers at each regional office of the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412323"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/7/2014--Introduced.
Veterans Appeals Improvement Act of 2014 - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to: (1) ensure that not fewer than three decision review officers are employed at each Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) regional office within one year after enactment of this Act; and (2) submit a notice to the House and Senate veterans' affairs committees when the number of such officers at a regional office declines to fewer than three, including a plan to increase the number to at least three and a description of the measures the Secretary plans to take to ensure that appeals before the Board of Veterans' Appeals are disposed of in a timely manner while fewer than three officers are employed at such office.

Directs the Secretary to report to such committees on the ability of the Board to conduct hearings and dispose of appeals in a timely manner. Requires such report to include: (1) whether the number of members of the Board is sufficient; and (2) an assessment of the feasibility and advisability of increasing the number of decision review officers by 10%, 15%, and 25%.</summary>
</bill>
