<bill session="113" type="h" number="2569" updated="2015-09-01T10:19:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-15T19:23:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-09-15T19:23:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Upper Missisquoi and Trout Wild and Scenic Rivers Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Upper Missisquoi and Trout Wild and Scenic Rivers Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Upper Missisquoi and Trout Wild and Scenic Rivers Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate segments of the Missisquoi River and the Trout River in the State of Vermont, as components of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412239"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-26">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-29">
      <text>Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-29">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-05-29" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-06-30T12:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 113-502.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-06-30T12:17:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="375">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 375.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-09-15T19:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hastings (WA) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-15T19:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7492-7494" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-15T19:13:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2569.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2014-09-15T19:23:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7492-7493" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-09-15T19:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-16">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII10" subcommittee="Public Lands and Environmental Regulation" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="s" number="1252"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1252"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Vermont"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/15/2014--Passed House amended.
Upper Missisquoi and Trout Wild and Scenic Rivers Act - (Sec. 2) Amends the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate specified segments of the Missisquoi River and Trout River in Vermont as components of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System.

(Sec. 3) Requires the river segments designated by this Act to be managed in accordance with the Upper Missisquoi and Trout Rivers Management Plan and any amendments meeting certain criteria.

Requires the Secretary of the Interior to coordinate the management responsibilities with the Upper Missisquoi and Trout Rivers Wild and Scenic Committee.

Authorizes the Secretary to enter into cooperative agreements for the protection, preservation, and enhancement of the river segments with: (1) the state of Vermont; (2) specific municipalities; and (3) local, regional, statewide, or multi-state planning, environmental, or recreational organizations.

States that the designation of the river segments does not: (1) preclude the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) from licensing, relicensing, or otherwise authorizing the operation of specified hydroelectric projects; or (2) limit the modernization, upgrades, or other changes to the projects. Prohibits resource protection, mitigation, or enhancement measures required by FERC hydropower proceedings from being considered project works under this Act. Permits such measures within the segments. Prohibits resource protection, mitigation, or enhancement measures required by FERC hydropower proceedings from being considered project works under this Act. Permits such measures within the segments.

Considers zoning ordinances adopted by specific towns as satisfying provisions in the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act that prohibit the Secretary from acquiring lands by condemnation within a designated Wild and Scenic River boundary when certain local zoning ordinances are in place.

 Limits the authority of the Secretary to acquire lands under this Act to acquisition by donation or exchange and subject to additional management plan criteria.

Prohibits the Secretary from acquiring by condemnation any land or interest in land within the boundaries of the river segments designated by this Act.

Bars the inclusion of any private or non-federal public property within the boundaries of such river segments without the owner's written consent.

Bars the Missisquoi and Trout Rivers from being administered as part of the National Park System.

Declares that nothing in this Act or the Upper Missisquoi and Trout Rivers Management Plan shall be construed to create buffer zones outside the river segment boundaries designated by this Act.</summary>
</bill>
