<bill session="113" type="h" number="4272" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-03-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-03-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-03-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Forest Access in Rural Communities Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To stop implementation and enforcement of the Forest Service travel management rule and to require the Forest Service to incorporate the needs, uses, and input of affected communities before taking any travel management action affecting access to units of the National Forest System derived from the public domain, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400419"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412500" joined="2014-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400029" joined="2014-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412270" joined="2014-07-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412397" joined="2014-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412191" joined="2014-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412294" joined="2014-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412295" joined="2014-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400659" joined="2014-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400313" joined="2014-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400376" joined="2014-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412581" joined="2014-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="2014-06-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-03-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-10">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII10" subcommittee="Public Lands and Environmental Regulation" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="5598"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/14/2014--Introduced.
Forest Access in Rural Communities Act - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA), through the Forest Service, to cease all implementation and enforcement of the travel management rule for units of the National Forest System derived from the public domain to the extent that it will, or can reasonably be expected to, alter public access to such lands.

Requires the Secretary, as a condition on the preparation of an environmental impact statement or environmental assessment under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 for a proposed access travel management action, to consult with affected counties for the purpose of incorporating their needs, uses, and input.

Bars the Secretary from implementing an access travel management action unless and until the Secretary: (1) complies with the consultation requirement imposed by this Act, and (2) obtains the concurrence of each affected county for the implementation of such action.</summary>
</bill>
