<bill session="113" type="h" number="5612" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Tackling Excessive Standardized Testing Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">TEST Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to reduce the testing requirements for part A of title I of such Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400195"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Language arts"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/18/2014--Introduced.
Tackling Excessive Standardized Testing Act of 2014 or the TEST Act of 2014 - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to alter the frequency with which students must take the tests used in determining whether they are making adequate yearly progress (AYP) toward state academic achievement standards in mathematics and reading or language arts. (Currently, students must take those tests in each of grades 3 through 8.) Authorizes a public school to administer the academic assessments in mathematics: (1) in each of grades 4, 6, and 8; or (2) in each of grades 4 and 8 if the school is at the 15th percentile or above for mathematics in the state or its students are making appropriate progress, as determined by the Secretary of Education, toward state mathematics achievement standards. Authorizes a public school to administer the academic assessments in reading or language arts: (1) in each of grades 3, 5, and 7; or (2) in each of grades 3 and 7 if the school is at the 15th percentile or above for reading or language arts or its students are making appropriate progress toward state reading or language arts achievement standards.

Excludes limited English proficient students who are in their first 12 months of enrollment in a public school from the determination as to whether students are making AYP toward state academic achievement standards.

Prohibits the Secretary from waiving the application of any of this Act's provisions.</summary>
</bill>
