<bill session="113" type="h" number="3552" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-11-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-11-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-11-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Emergency Response Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve emergency response activities in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400008"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-11-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/20/2013--Introduced.
Emergency Response Improvement Act - Requires the chief executive officer of a state, to be eligible for assistance under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act on or after October 1, 2014, to maintain a State Office of Emergency Management to coordinate the state response to, and to request federal assistance with respect to, an emergency.

Directs the President, if one or more federal agencies provides assistance to a state in response to an emergency, to designate an individual from one such agency to serve as the federal incident commander for that emergency. Requires such commander to meet with representatives of federal, state, and local entities involved in the response and assist such representatives in: (1) creating a response plan that specifies the responsibilities of each entity, (2) designating an individual to lead the response, and (3) drafting and executing a memorandum of understanding with respect to such plan.

Requires the federal incident commander, in the absence of such a memorandum of understanding, to report to the President and recommend if, and to what extent, the relevant federal agencies should be involved in the response.</summary>
</bill>
