<bill session="113" type="h" number="4417" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-04-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-04-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a special resources study to determine the suitability and feasibility of entering into public-private partnerships to operate federally owned golf courses in the District of Columbia, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400295"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400074" joined="2014-05-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E538-539"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="Public Lands and Environmental Regulation" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation facilities"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/7/2014--Introduced.
Requires the Director of the National Park Service to conduct a special resources study to determine the suitability and feasibility of entering into public-private partnerships with non-federal entities to operate East Potomac Golf Course, Langston Golf Course, and Rock Creek Park Golf Course in the District of Columbia.

Requires the Director to assume that: (1) one of the three golf courses will be a world-class, tournament-quality public course, with commensurate playing fees; and (2) the other two shall be public courses of substantially similar quality to top-ranked courses owned by cities, towns, and counties for which the playing fees shall remain the same as they are on the date of this Act's enactment but shall be indexed annually to the Consumer Price Index.</summary>
</bill>
