<bill session="113" type="hc" number="113" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Amending the Rules of the House of Representatives to require any Member whose Members' Representational Allowance is used to pay for a flight on a private aircraft to report information on the flight not later than 30 days after the flight, and requiring any Senator whose official funds are used to pay for a flight on a private aircraft to report information on the flight not later than 30 days after the flight.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412269"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ethics, and in addition to the Committee on House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-11">
      <text>Referred to House Ethics</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-11">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSO" name="House Ethics" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/11/2014--Introduced.
Amends Rule XXIII (Code of Official Conduct) of the Rules of the House of Representatives to require a Member to file a report with the Clerk of the House if funds in the Member's Representational Allowance are used for a flight for which the aircraft owner or operator is paid the pro rata share of the fair market value of the normal and usual charter fare or rental charge for a comparable plane.

Requires the Member to file this report within 30 days after the flight, including information on:

 the amount paid for the flight from the Representational Allowance; the destinations covered by the flight; and the flight's purpose, including any reasons why the purpose could not be met by taking a flight on an aircraft operated by an air carrier or commercial operator described in the Rule. Requires a Senator to file a similar report with the Secretary of the Senate if funds in the Senator's Official Personnel and Office Expense Account are used for a noncommercial or nongovernment aircraft flight.</summary>
</bill>
