<bill session="113" type="h" number="3900" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-01-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-01-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-01-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Intelligence Community Oversight Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2010 to facilitate access by the Comptroller General of the United States to information in the possession of the intelligence community, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400654"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400361" joined="2014-01-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-01-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select).</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/16/2014--Introduced.
Intelligence Community Oversight Act of 2014 - Amends the Intelligence Authorization Act for FY2010 to require the head of each element of the intelligence community, in carrying out the directive of the Director of National Intelligence (DNI) governing Comptroller General access to information in such element's possession, to:

 provide the Comptroller General with timely access to necessary information concerning programs and activities for any audit, investigation, program evaluation, report, or review; cooperate with the Comptroller General to the fullest extent possible and provide timely responses to requests for information; carefully consider requests for information based on consultation with the Comptroller General; work with the Comptroller General to explore alternative means to accommodate a request if the head determines that such element is unable to provide the Comptroller General with access to the specific information requested; narrowly construe any limitation on access to information by the Comptroller General; and submit to the DNI, the Comptroller General, and Congress, in a timely manner and at the same time the head notifies the Comptroller General of the denial of access to requested information, a written justification for such denial. Requires: (1) the DNI, semiannually, to report to Congress and the Comptroller General on any instances in which a head denied access to requested information; and (2) the Comptroller General, within 30 days of receiving such a report, to submit to Congress any comments in response to such report.</summary>
</bill>
