<bill session="113" type="sr" number="567" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate regarding the possible easing of restrictions on the sale of lethal military equipment to the Government of Vietnam.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300071"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412248" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2014-09-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5797-5798" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="Vietnam"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/18/2014--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of the Senate that: Vietnam is an important emerging partner with which the United States increasingly shares strategic and economic interests; the government of Vietnam has recently taken modest but encouraging steps to improve its human rights record; the President, with congressional consultation, should begin a process to ease the U.S. prohibition on the sale of lethal military equipment to Vietnam; easing such prohibition with regard to maritime and coastal defense would further U.S. national security interests, but steps beyond this would require Vietnam to take significant steps to protect human rights; and the United States should support civil society in Vietnam, and specify what human rights steps Vietnam should take to continue strengthening the bilateral relationship.</summary>
</bill>
