<bill session="113" type="s" number="1729" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-11-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-11-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-11-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Expanded Consumer Choice Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to provide further options with respect to levels of coverage under qualified health plans.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412326"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412554" joined="2014-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412582" joined="2014-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412545" joined="2014-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2014-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412391" joined="2014-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412321" joined="2014-01-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-11-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/19/2013--Introduced.
Expanded Consumer Choice Act - Amends the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to provide a new "copper" level of coverage under qualified health plans, designed to provide benefits that are actuarially equivalent to 50% of the full actuarial value of the benefits provided under the plan. Requires cost-sharing under such a plan to exceed the amount applicable to a plan at the bronze level.

Requires the Secretary of Health Human Services (HHS) to promulgate regulations providing for annual limits on deductibles and cost-sharing for copper-level plans to ensure that the limits are reasonable for every marketplace and to consider the feasibility of the relative plan design in each local insurance marketplace.

Allows qualification of copper-level plans as multi-state plans.</summary>
</bill>
