<bill session="113" type="h" number="4226" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-03-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-03-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-03-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Credit Union Residential Loan Parity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Credit Union Act to exclude a loan secured by a non-owner occupied 1- to 4-family dwelling from the definition of a member business loan, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400348"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412511" joined="2014-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400218" joined="2014-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400290" joined="2014-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400652" joined="2014-04-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-03-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Credit and credit markets"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Real estate business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/13/2014--Introduced.
Credit Union Residential Loan Parity Act - Amends the Federal Credit Union Act to revise the definition of "member business loan," which currently excludes an extension of credit fully secured by a lien on a 1- to 4-family dwelling that is the primary residence of a member.

Removes the condition that the dwelling be a member's primary residence. (Thus denies eligibility for a member business loan to any requested extension of credit that would be fully secured by a lien on a 1- to 4-family dwelling, regardless of whether it is or is not the member's primary residence.)

Declares that this Act does not preclude the National Credit Union Administration (NCUA) from treating an extension of credit fully secured by a lien on a 1- to 4-family dwelling that is not a member's primary residence as a member business loan for purposes other than certain member business loan limitation requirements under the Act.</summary>
</bill>
