<bill session="113" type="h" number="4863" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Guard and Reserve Equal Access to Legal Services Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 10, United States Code, to provide certain members of the reserve components of the Armed Forces who are victims of sex-related offenses with access to a special victims' counsel.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400224"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412216" joined="2014-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400041" joined="2014-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400259" joined="2014-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="408211" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412303" joined="2014-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400316" joined="2014-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="2014-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400411" joined="2014-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412214" joined="2014-06-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2843"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/12/2014--Introduced.
National Guard and Reserve Equal Access to Legal Services Act - Expands eligibility for legal assistance provided by the Armed Forces special victims' counsel for eligible members and dependents who are victims of sex-related offenses to include a member of a reserve component who is a victim of an alleged sex-offense committed by a member of the Armed Forces during: (1) a period in which the individual served on active duty, full-time National Guard duty, or inactive-duty training; or (2) any period, regardless of the duty status of the individual, if the circumstances of the alleged sex-related offense have a nexus to the military service of the individual based on the membership in the Armed Forces of either the victim or the member who allegedly committed such offense.</summary>
</bill>
