<bill session="113" type="h" number="4554" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-22">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-05-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Restricted Securities Relief Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the securities laws to improve private market offerings, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412474"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412548" joined="2014-05-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-09">
      <text>Hearings Held by the Subcommittee on Capital Markets and Government Sponsored Enterprises Prior to Introduction and Referral.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-22">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-05-22" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 29 - 28.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, Markup"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="HSBA16" subcommittee="Capital Markets and Government Sponsored Enterprises" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/1/2014--Introduced.
Restricted Securities Relief Act of 2014 - Directs the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to revise specified regulations to: (1) reduce from six to three months the holding period for restricted securities issued by an issuer that is, and has been for at least 90 days immediately before the sale, subject to certain reporting requirements of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934; and (2) permit a securities issuer with no or nominal operations and no or nominal non-cash assets that has ceased to be such an issuer to sell its securities two years after filing with the SEC a Form 8-K stating that it is no longer an issuer with no or nominal operations and no or nominal non-cash assets.

Amends the Securities Act of 1933 to exempt from any state or local registration or qualification requirements any security offered or sold in compliance with specified conditions for private resales of securities to institutions.</summary>
</bill>
