<bill session="113" type="h" number="3244" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-10-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-10-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">First STEP Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Supporting Training for Employment Potential Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the National Institute of Standards and Technology Act to provide support for organizations to promote the Manufacturing Skills Certification System.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412524"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412571" joined="2014-02-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412412" joined="2013-12-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Research and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY15" subcommittee="Research and Technology" name="House Science, Space, and Technology"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/4/2013--Introduced.
First STEP Act or the Supporting Training for Employment Potential Act - Amends the National Institute of Standards and Technology Act to direct the Secretary of Commerce to provide support and assistance to programs that promote the Manufacturing Skills Certification System (a collaborative federal-private industry effort to create universally recognizable manufacturing employee credentials), including by: (1) promoting collaboration between community colleges, technical schools, and local businesses to help such colleges and schools better understand business needs and and to help businesses better understand the skill sets learned in college and school programs; (2) educating businesses and students on the value of universally recognized credential programs and apprenticeship opportunities; (3) providing support and assistance for state programs looking to implement the System; and (4) providing support and assistance for programs to collaborate at a national level.

Extends through FY2016 a program of assistance for the creation and support of regional centers for the transfer of manufacturing technology.</summary>
</bill>
