<bill session="113" type="h" number="4727" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-05-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To enhance interstate commerce by creating a National Hiring Standard for Motor Carriers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400116"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412400" joined="2014-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412536" joined="2014-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400648" joined="2014-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400158" joined="2014-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412454" joined="2014-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412552" joined="2014-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412568" joined="2014-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412303" joined="2014-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400406" joined="2014-11-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-22">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-22">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW12" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU10" subcommittee="Constitution and Civil Justice" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Life, casualty, property insurance"/>
    <term name="Motor carriers"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/22/2014--Introduced.
Prohibits a state from enforcing a law or imposing liability on an entity that hires a motor carrier for the transportation of property or household goods if the liability arises from a personal injury, death, or cargo or fother property damage claim or cause of action related to the negligent selection of that motor carrier under state law or regulation.

Specifies as such an entity any person acting as a shipper, as a broker, as a consignee, a freight forwarder, a household goods freight forwarder, a Non-Vessel Operating Common Carrier, an ocean freight forwarder, or an ocean transportation intermediary.

Makes an entity eligible for this waiver of liability only if, before tendering a shipment, but not more than 35 days before the hitred motor carrier picks up a shipment, the entity verifies that the motor carrier at the time of verification:

 is registered with and authorized by the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration (FMCSA) to operate as a motor carrier or household goods motor carrier, has the minimum insurance coverage required by federal regulation, and does not have an unsatisfactory safety rating from FMCSA in force at the time of verification.</summary>
</bill>
