<bill session="113" type="s" number="1341" updated="2015-09-01T17:50:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-12-19">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-12-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cabin Fee Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Cabin Fee Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to modify the Forest Service Recreation Residence Program as the program applies to units of the National Forest System derived from the public domain by implementing a simple, equitable, and predictable procedure for determining cabin user fees, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412244"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412251" joined="2013-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300005" joined="2013-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300030" joined="2013-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2013-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2013-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400134" joined="2013-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="2013-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412322" joined="2013-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412602" joined="2014-06-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-20">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands, Forests, and Mining. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 113-342.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-12-19" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-05-22">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Landrieu with an amendment and an amendment to the title. With written report No. 113-171.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-05-22" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="397">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 397.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG03" subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3979"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4873"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="5476"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/22/2014--Reported to Senate amended.
Cabin Fee Act of 2013 - (Sec. 2) Directs the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) to set an annual fee for a special use permit for the use and occupancy of National Forest System land for recreational residence purposes.

Requires the Secretary to complete the current appraisal cycle for the recreational residences within two years in accordance with the Cabin User Fees Fairness Act of 2000. Requires the assessment of an interim annual fee from January 1, 2014, until the current appraisal is completed.

Instructs the Secretary to make a one-time adjustment to the value of each appraised lot on which a recreational residence is located to reflect any change in value occurring after the date of the most recent appraisal. Allows a permitee to arrange for a second appraisal of a lot.

Specifies the annual fee for 11 fee tiers based on the value of the lot on which the recreational residence is located, and requires annual inflation adjustments.

Allows the Secretary to suspend or reduce the annual fee if access to, or the occupancy of, the recreational residence is significantly restricted.

Requires the Secretary to report after ten years on: (1) these annual fees in order to ensure that they reflect fair value for the use of the land for recreational residential purposes, and (2) any recommendations to modify the fee system.

(Sec. 3) Directs the Secretary to establish a transfer fee of $1,200, adjusted annually for inflation, for the issuance of a new recreational residence permit due to a change in ownership of the recreational residence.

(Sec. 4) Prohibits the Secretary from establishing or imposing a fee or condition under this Act for permits in Alaska that is inconsistent with provisions regarding the renewal or continuation of permits and leases for cabins, homesites, or similar structures on federal lands under the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act.

(Sec. 5) Permits the Secretary, beginning in FY2024, to retain and expend any fees collected under this Act without further appropriation. Requires the fees to be used to administer the recreational residence program and other recreation programs carried out on National Forest System land.

(Sec. 6) Repeals the Cabin User Fees Fairness Act of 2000, effective on the date the annual permit fees are assessed under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
