<bill session="113" type="h" number="3768" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-12-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-12-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-12-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Promoting Tourism to Enhance our Economy Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to encourage Canadian tourism to the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412186"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412383" joined="2014-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400606" joined="2013-12-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-12-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-12">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-12">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Border Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/12/2013--Introduced.
Promoting Tourism to Enhance our Economy Act of 2013 - Authorizes the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to admit into the United States as a visitor for pleasure a qualifying Canadian citizen over 55 years old and spouse (who is not required to be over 55 years old) for a period not to exceed 240 days if the person maintains a Canadian residence and owns a U.S. residence or has rented a U.S. accommodation for the duration of such stay.

Requires such visitor also to be not inadmissible or described in any ground of deportability, and requires him or her not to: (1) engage in employment or labor for hire in the United States, or (2) seek any form of assistance or benefit under the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996.</summary>
</bill>
