<bill session="113" type="h" number="2952" updated="2015-09-01T10:19:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-12-18">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-12-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CIRDA Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Critical Infrastructure Research and Development Advancement Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">CIRDA Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Critical Infrastructure Research and Development Advancement Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">CIRDA Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Critical Infrastructure Research and Development Advancement Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Cybersecurity Workforce Assessment Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Cybersecurity Workforce Assessment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to make certain improvements in the laws relating to the advancement of security technologies for critical infrastructure protection, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by senate">An act to require the Secretary of Homeland Security to assess the cybersecurity workforce of the Department of Homeland Security and develop a comprehensive workforce strategy, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412466"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412221" joined="2013-09-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Cybersecurity, Infrastructure Protection, and Security Technologies.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-18">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-18">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-29">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-10-29" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-01-09T19:34:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Homeland Security. H. Rept. 113-324.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-01-09T19:34:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="241">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 241.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-07-28T17:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Meehan moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-28T17:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6922-6925" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-28T17:17:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2952.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2014-07-28T17:29:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6922-6923" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-07-28T17:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-29">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-10">
      <text>Senate Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-10">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6486-6487" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote2" datetime="2014-12-10" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_BACK:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment and an amendment to the Title by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-12-10">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-11T09:57:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Meehan moved that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendments.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9060-9062" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-11T09:57:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 40 minutes of debate on the motion to suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendments to H.R. 2952.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="pingpong" datetime="2014-12-11T10:10:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On motion that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendments Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9060" label="text as House agreed to Senate amendments"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-12-11T10:10:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2014-12-12">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2014-12-18" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="113-246" type="public" datetime="2014-12-18">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 113-246.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSHM08" subcommittee="Cybersecurity, Infrastructure Protection, and Security Technologies" name="House Homeland Security"/>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s4001"/>
    <amendment number="s4002"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>12/18/2014--Public Law.
Cybersecurity Workforce Assessment Act - Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security, within 180 days and annually thereafter for three years, to conduct an assessment of the cybersecurity workforce of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS), which shall include information on:

 the readiness and capacity of such workforce to meet its cybersecurity mission; where cybersecurity workforce positions are located within DHS; which such positions are performed by permanent full-time equivalent DHS employees, by independent contractors, and by individuals employed by other federal agencies; which such positions are vacant; the percentage of individuals within each Cybersecurity Category and Specialty Area who received essential training to perform their jobs; and in cases in which such training was not received, what challenges were encountered regarding the provision of such training. Directs the Secretary to develop, maintain, and update a comprehensive workforce strategy to enhance the readiness, capacity, training, recruitment, and retention of DHS's cybersecurity workforce, which shall include a description of:

 a multi-phased recruitment plan, a 5-year implementation plan, a 10-year projection of the cybersecurity workforce needs of DHS, any obstacle impeding the hiring and development of such workforce, and any gap in the existing DHS cybersecurity workforce and a plan to fill such gap. Requires the Secretary to submit to the appropriate congressional committees: (1) annual updates on such assessment and on the Secretary's progress in carrying out such strategy; and (2) a report on the feasibility, cost, and benefits of establishing a Cybersecurity Fellowship Program to offer a tuition payment plan for individuals pursuing undergraduate and doctoral degrees who agree to work for DHS for an agreed-upon period.</summary>
</bill>
