<bill session="113" type="h" number="5434" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Visa Waiver Program Suspension Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To suspend the visa waiver program in order for the Comptroller General of the United States to assess the national security risks posed by the program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412531"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Border Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/10/2014--Introduced.
Visa Waiver Program Suspension Act of 2014 - Suspends the visa waiver program for 180 days in order for the Government Accountability Office (GAO) to review it for national security risks.

Prohibits the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) from permitting program admissions until: (1) GAO reports on the results of the review, (2) the Secretary certifies that the national security recommendations from the review are implemented, and (3) Congress certifies that these national security recommendations have been met.

Directs GAO to report to Congress on:

 the number of terrorists admitted into the United States from each program country, the current visa overstay rate for each program country, the impact on the travel industry of requiring screening at U.S. consulates for program countries, the cost and feasibility of an automated biometric entry-exit control system, the number of persons permitted to travel without a verified Electronic System for Travel Authorization approval, and the number of persons permitted to travel with a denied Electronic System for Travel Authorization. Directs the Secretary to remove from the program any country: (1) that poses a U.S. national security threat, (2) that exceeds the visa overstay threshold, and (3) whose continued program participation jeopardizes or could jeopardize national security.

Repeals retroactively visa overstay waiver authority.</summary>
</bill>
