<bill session="113" type="h" number="5408" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Terrorist Denaturalization and Passport Revocation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend section 349(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act to add certain acts of allegiance to a foreign terrorist organization to the list of acts for which nationals of the United States lose nationality, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412216"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400032" joined="2014-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412252" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412601" joined="2014-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412508" joined="2014-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400116" joined="2014-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412434" joined="2014-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412191" joined="2014-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412294" joined="2014-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412568" joined="2014-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412474" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400313" joined="2014-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412551" joined="2014-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412309" joined="2014-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412213" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412574" joined="2014-09-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-08">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-08">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Border Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="5406"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="5695"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/8/2014--Introduced.
Terrorist Denaturalization and Passport Revocation Act - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to include among the grounds for loss of U.S. nationality by a native-born or naturalized citizen:

 taking an oath or making a declaration of allegiance to a foreign terrorist organization after attaining the age of 18; entering or serving in the armed forces of a foreign state that harbors a foreign terrorist organization; accepting, serving in, or performing the duties of any office, post, or employment in a foreign terrorist organization after attaining the age of 18; accepting, serving in, or performing the duties of any office, post, or employment in a foreign terrorist organization after attaining the age of 18 for which an oath or declaration of allegiance is required; or accepting, serving in, or performing the duties of any office, post, or employment in a foreign terrorist organization after attaining the age of 18 if the position requires knowing engagement in hostilities against U.S. military or civilian personnel. Amends the Passport Act of 1926 to prohibit, with a discretionary exception for emergency or humanitarian reasons, the Secretary of State from issuing a passport or passport card to an individual who is a member of a foreign terrorist organization engaged in hostilities against the United States or its allies.

Directs the Secretary to revoke a passport or passport card previously issued to any such individual.

Authorizes the Secretary, before revocation, to: (1) limit a previously issued passport or passport card only for return travel to the United States, or (2) issue a limited passport or passport card that only permits return travel to the United States.</summary>
</bill>
