<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H25990AB7684642F2B62E2645F17E2E6D" public-private="public" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HR 4614 IH: Park Partner Enhancement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2014-05-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
<session>2d Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 4614</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20140508">May 8, 2014</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="L000571">Mrs. Lummis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To enhance and clarify the ability of the National Park Service to work cooperatively with Park Partners to better use philanthropic and other non-Federal investments to achieve common objectives, public purposes and benefits, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HC426A3B2C6C74856805665A591774BBC" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HFFCA743E0A214F43B44BDDFAF6B40C0D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Park Partner Enhancement Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HFEAC20054EC04A90AF04EED9DD0763C3" commented="no"><enum>2.</enum><header>Park Partner enhancements</header> 
<subsection id="H1E14AC940EEF406B9618CE341F9E91A9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the National Park Service, may enter into agreements under section 814(g) of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/333">Public Law 104–333</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1f">16 U.S.C. 1f</external-xref>) and section 101(d) of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/208">Public Law 104–208</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1g">16 U.S.C. 1g</external-xref>) with educational institutions and non-profit organizations (referred to in this Act as a <quote>Park Partner</quote>) to advance National Park Service programs and projects including, but not limited to, the following, each of which shall be considered a <quote>public purpose</quote> under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/6305">section 6305</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code:</text> 
<paragraph id="H3B0DA1E426AE4C03A3EBCAECA1B63674"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To cooperatively manage improvements on lands and programs within or related to one or more units of the National Park System.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H83DF79111ADF427C9F2E9474A288BB25" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To assist the National Park Service to plan, design, and construct National Park facilities and trails and restore landscapes and resources within or related to one or more units of the National Park System.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE7506378A3D242E7BFF369FFDCB067CB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>To provide educational and interpretive programs and services within or related to one or more units of the National Park System on a cost-recovery basis.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5CAC7BC88E334DD5AE41A073DC6A6E42"><enum>(4)</enum><text>To develop, produce, publish, distribute, or sell educational and interpretive materials and products.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4AE9F57F814E4D469D3F2A68A992F0D0" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>To raise funds and assets through donation to support National Park Service projects and programs.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5896366732BF4092B4AB545240863F01"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contributions of volunteers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Interior may consider the fair value of services performed by persons who volunteer their services required for the agreement to the National Park Service and who are recruited, trained, and supported by a Park Partner as not more than 50 percent of an in-kind contribution of the Park Partner for purposes of any cost sharing requirement under any agreement entered into under subsection (a).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBA98D9C1A46F4D11B6A5B094AA53155C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Financial contributions</header><text>Any funds donated, proceeds received, or cost-recovery amounts provided through agreements entered into under subsection (a) shall be retained by the Secretary or the Park Partner in accordance with the relevant agreement and such proceeds shall remain available, without future appropriation, until expended for preservation, restoration, operation, maintenance, interpretation, public programs, and related expenses of the National Park Service or Park Partner. </text> </subsection> </section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 

