<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="H365707576D1742AD80E7328F19800456" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HRES 752 IH: Congratulating Marcel Closset, a French citizen and former member of the French Resistance who was instrumental in saving a United States Army Air Corps pilot during World War II, for receiving the French Legion of Honor.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2014-11-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 752</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20141112">November 12, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="O000170">Mr. O’Rourke</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Congratulating Marcel Closset, a French citizen and former member of the French Resistance who was
			 instrumental in saving a United States Army Air Corps pilot during World
			 War II, for receiving the French Legion of Honor.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas><text>Whereas, on September 27, 2014, Marcel Closset, a French citizen and former member of the French
			 Resistance, received the French Legion of Honor in the rank of Knight;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the French Legion of Honor was created by Napoleon Bonaparte in 1802 to recognize the
			 accomplishments of military personnel and civilians for their service to
			 France;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the French Legion of Honor is the highest-ranking order and decoration given in France;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on July 17, 2014, the President of France nominated Marcel Closset for the French Legion
			 of Honor to commemorate the 70th anniversary of the liberation of France
			 during World War II;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Marcel Closset is the current president of L’Amicale des Anciens du maquis de Mazinghien,
			 an association that works to preserve the memory of the members of the
			 French Resistance who fought for the liberation of Mazinghien, France, in
			 1944; and</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Marcel Closset was one of four people who risked their lives to rescue and hide Eliot
			 Shapleigh, Sr., a United States Army Air Corps pilot from El Paso, Texas,
			 who was forced to parachute from his crippled P–51 Mustang into
			 Nazi-occupied France in 1944: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body id="H264820CF825842A586C30C6CBE317DB9" style="traditional">
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H2B11D5481B174D95BD7F18C3BD33ABA3" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives congratulates Marcel Closset for receiving the French Legion of
			 Honor.</text>
		</section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


