<bill session="113" type="h" number="4507" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-04-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-04-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pedestrian Fatalities Reduction Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 23, United States Code, to require a State with an increase in the number of fatalities or serious injuries of pedestrians or users of nonmotorized forms of transportation to include strategies to address the increase in the State's subsequent State strategic highway safety plan, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400087"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2014-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412571" joined="2014-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400076" joined="2014-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400244" joined="2014-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412560" joined="2014-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400366" joined="2014-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412186" joined="2014-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412520" joined="2014-05-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW12" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Pedestrians and bicycling"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/29/2014--Introduced.
Pedestrian Fatalities Reduction Act of 2014 - Requires any state with a per capita increase in the number of fatalities or serious injuries of pedestrians or users of nonmotorized forms of transportation in the state, or a particular county in the state, during the most recent two-year period to include in its subsequent strategic highway safety plan strategies to address that increase. Requires states to take data on such fatalities and injuries into consideration when updating such plans.

Revises any subset the Secretary of Transportation (DOT) establishes of the model inventory of roadway elements (MIRE) for the inventory of roadway safety, and used by state and local departments of transportation to implement their strategic highway safety plans, to include elements that improve safety for pedestrians and users of nonmotorized forms of transportation.</summary>
</bill>
