<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-Senate" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 S2946 RS: Senator Paul Simon Water for the World Act of 2014</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2014-11-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><calendar>Calendar No. 625</calendar><congress>113th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 2946</legis-num><associated-doc role="report">[Report No. 113–286]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20141120">November 19, 2014</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S310">Mr. Corker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S358">Mr. Flake</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSFR00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><action stage="Reported-in-Senate"><action-date>December 8, 2014</action-date><action-desc>Reported by <sponsor name-id="S306">Mr. Menendez</sponsor>, with an amendment</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide improved water, sanitation, and hygiene programs for high priority developing countries,
			 and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC"><section changed="deleted" committee-id="SSFR00" id="HF2A66389A4FD41ADB195D7429EC76917" reported-display-style="strikethrough" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Senator Paul Simon Water for the World Act of 2014</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section changed="deleted" committee-id="SSFR00" id="H3427761A5FD2449ABC0AAD902DCCE241" reported-display-style="strikethrough"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="HCC001EAD5E79425EAB75A0A2C2A55057"><enum>(1)</enum><text>water and sanitation are critically important resources that impact many other aspects of human
			 life;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5AE18F7C5B7849348A4F32E15AD0F9D4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the United States should be a global leader in helping
			 provide sustainable access to clean water and sanitation for the world’s
			 most vulnerable populations; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H99B7AA81989642DDABD073018D3BCC4A"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <quote>USAID Water and Development Strategy, 2013–2018</quote>, which was released by the United States Agency for International Development in May 2013—</text><subparagraph id="id157B30B40FFD40D1903A511B6469D34F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improves USAID’s capacity to provide sustainable water, sanitation,
			 and hygiene assistance;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id36CED9F2DDD54CDBA9E92F355F0E60F4"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">advances implementation of portions of the Senator
			 Paul Simon Water for the Poor Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/121">Public Law 109–121</external-xref>; 119 Stat.
			 2533), and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id66FFAC8144A14DA89AFFD3A70E1D2DD8"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">should inform the Global Water Strategy required under section
			 136(j) of the Foreign Assistance  Act of 1961, as added by
			 section 6 of this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section changed="deleted" commented="no" committee-id="SSFR00" id="HB216DB02DF424814837221C558BB89F3" reported-display-style="strikethrough"><enum>3.</enum><header>Clarification of assistance to provide safe water and sanitation to include hygiene</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Chapter 1 of part I of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 is amended—</text><paragraph id="H3415F68820934487BF73C498C84C2B83"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating section 135 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2152h">22 U.S.C. 2152h</external-xref>), as added by section 5(a) of the Senator Paul Simon
			 Water for the Poor Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/121">Public Law 109–121</external-xref>; 22
			 U.S.C. 2152h note), as section 136; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H7E99B92E71C94DD4A562EFE8A1D86059"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 136, as redesignated—</text><subparagraph id="HA78AA32002B6463DADFF55AC53B91117"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the section heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">and sanitation</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">, sanitation, and hygiene</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H6406A5A0F16342C2BF35B517573E7F51"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by striking <quote>and sanitation</quote> and inserting <quote>, sanitation, and hygiene</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section changed="deleted" committee-id="SSFR00" id="HF7B4DCC3E32A4B0286FD9ECD942CA884" reported-display-style="strikethrough"><enum>4.</enum><header>Improving coordination and oversight of safe water, sanitation and hygiene projects and activities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 136 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, as redesignated and amended by this Act, is
			 further amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block changed="deleted" committee-id="SSFR00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEA45C8F3979A4EBCA3AA166B7FB842EF" reported-display-style="strikethrough" style="OLC"><subsection id="H3FBF75EAE68045019B024A0493B0E3F6"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Coordination and oversight</header><paragraph id="HB4B5B53D702345228417E5455174530C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>USAID global water coordinator</header><subparagraph id="H7FB11EF3F72A48888306E637CEA3F575"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>The Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development (referred to in this
			 paragraph as <quote>USAID</quote>) or the Administrator’s
			 designee,  who shall be a current USAID employee serving in a career or
			 non-career position in the Senior Executive Service or at the level of a
			 Deputy Assistant Administrator or higher, shall serve concurrently as the
			 USAID Global Water Coordinator (referred to in this subsection as the <quote>Coordinator</quote>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H75F77F37DFA74E2DBE5E2B1AA892BA8E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Specific duties</header><text>The Coordinator shall—</text><clause id="id42BC831666FC4719A3E4C5B93163EDB1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provide direction and guidance to, coordinate, and oversee the projects and
			 programs of USAID authorized under this section;</text></clause><clause id="HDE190213299D4E189D338F82492C25C5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>lead the implementation and revision, not less frequently than once every 5 years, of USAID’s
			 portion of the
			 Global Water Strategy required under subsection (j);</text></clause><clause id="H3EBE364BCAC94EE6B149A8E99CADF3B4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>seek—</text><subclause id="id5917D5CF501D4653B32A306A082484B2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to expand the capacity of USAID, subject to the availability of appropriations, including through
			 the designation of a lead subject matter expert selected from among USAID
			 staff in each high priority country
			 designated pursuant to subsection (h);</text></subclause><subclause id="id7BA3EBE311144EC1AFB1D1F059D802A2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to implement such programs and
			 activities;</text></subclause><subclause id="id3AF8D29D534A495480828B79541A5049"><enum>(III)</enum><text>to take advantage of economies of scale; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id7D23EE8310FB40D882C0C3B07E3FB8DD"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>to conduct more
			 efficient and effective projects and programs;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H96DD57165DC54E179D5D2DB66C5DC98B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>coordinate with the Department of State and USAID staff in each high priority country designated
			 pursuant to subsection (h) to ensure that USAID activities and projects,
			 USAID program planning and budgeting documents, and USAID country
			 development strategies reflect and seek to implement—</text><subclause id="H133BAE8AF281434582086EE18C183A69"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the safe water, sanitation, and hygiene objectives established in the strategy required under
			 subsection (j), including objectives relating to the management of water
			 resources; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H767D236ED6DE42669179B1554FC81E3C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>international best practices relating to—</text><item id="idF3F702F1CF1947FFB2F5975C62779703"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>increasing access to safe water and sanitation;</text></item><item id="id517759F679CE4E698B1BE5DA20407DF0"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>conducting
			 hygiene-related activities; and</text></item><item id="id2FE9694F9231418FAEBA8900CF90EFDB"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>ensuring appropriate management of water
			 resources; and</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="HACC22FF1FAFC46E9B0B3E3DD7FCB27BD"><enum>(v)</enum><text>develop appropriate benchmarks, measurable goals, performance metrics, and monitoring and
			 evaluation plans for USAID projects and programs authorized under this
			 section.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H51D3541D235C451AA9229C53F1971155"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Department of state special coordinator for water resources</header><subparagraph id="H4C4B52DEDF064098875DE23CE5B434F0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>The Secretary of State or the Secretary’s designee,  who shall be a current employee of the
			 Department of
			 State
			 serving in a career or non-career position in the Senior Executive Service
			 or at the level of a Deputy Assistant Secretary or higher, shall serve
			 concurrently as the Department of State Special Advisor for Water
			 Resources (referred to in this paragraph as the <quote>Special Advisor</quote>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFBEE37052B704EC9BF9E61F5E1C55558"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Specific duties</header><text>The Special Advisor shall—</text><clause id="idB7B654A742AB4FD8AFA28FF95C36A1EF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provide direction and guidance to, coordinate, and oversee the projects and
			 programs of the Department of State authorized under this section;</text></clause><clause id="H94E22034D1CC42398CC1C9CCA60A78D2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>lead the implementation and revision, not less than every 5 years, of the Department of State’s
			 portion of the Global Water Strategy required under subsection (j);</text></clause><clause id="HEB01EF9A7DE8447F8B28F5D44511A319"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>prioritize and coordinate the Department of State’s international engagement on the allocation,
			 distribution, and access to global fresh water resources and policies
			 related to such matters;</text></clause><clause id="H99AFC73EE982424FBBE2017E6048415F"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>coordinate with United States Agency for International Development and Department of State staff in
			 each
			 high priority country designated pursuant to subsection (h) to ensure that
			 United States diplomatic efforts related to safe water, sanitation, and
			 hygiene, including efforts related to management of water resources and
			 watersheds and the resolution of intra- and trans-boundary conflicts over
			 water resources, are consistent with United States national interests; and</text></clause><clause id="H1363E61DCDB74726B63E8FD3F1B1C48D"><enum>(v)</enum><text>represent the views of the United States Government on the allocation, distribution, and access to
			 global fresh water resources and policies related to such matters in key
			 international fora, including key diplomatic, development-related, and
			 scientific organizations.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H885447B096E340C59722A569E955AAED"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Additional nature of duties and restriction on additional or supplemental compensation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The responsibilities and specific duties of the Administrator of the United States Agency for
			 International Development (or the Administrator’s designee) and the
			 Secretary of State (or the Secretary’s designee) under paragraph (2) or
			 (3), respectively, shall be in addition to any other
			 responsibilities or specific duties assigned to such individuals. Such
			 individuals shall receive no additional or supplemental compensation as a
			 result of carrying out such responsibilities and specific duties under
			 such paragraphs.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section changed="deleted" committee-id="SSFR00" id="H61D4C219B53F4DC0982BFDF913669B66" reported-display-style="strikethrough"><enum>5.</enum><header>Promoting the maximum impact and long-term sustainability of USAID safe water, sanitation, and
			 hygiene-related projects and programs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 136 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, as redesignated and amended by this Act, is
			 further amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block changed="deleted" committee-id="SSFR00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H42CCBB1E12B74C6AAE89BCF620F22BE2" reported-display-style="strikethrough" style="OLC"><subsection id="H5F678171D3B7435A8892CAD81EA97C4E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Priorities and criteria for maximum impact and long-Term sustainability</header><text>The Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development shall ensure that the
			 Agency for International Development’s projects and programs authorized
			 under this section are designed to achieve maximum impact and
			 long-term sustainability by—</text><paragraph id="H47F5616EA418435A923E663B795EE5C9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>prioritizing countries on the basis of the following clearly defined criteria and
			 indicators, to the extent sufficient data are available—</text><subparagraph id="H41F938962F1F4EC6BB8EB7963AF7E9C2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the proportion of the population using an unimproved drinking water source;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1EFEB923EDD1494CABB9C6B4C1BBE585"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the total population using an unimproved drinking water source;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEF475F5490DB40D88F96A46715559B54"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the proportion of the population without piped water access;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC60BA8E5FDF840A9A8CC105C9E32F525"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the proportion of the population using shared or other unimproved sanitation facilities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H144B28EAF76743FCAE60C56B9862971D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the total population using shared or other unimproved sanitation facilities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBE301DA23F3941A98D0F4F141139E313"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the proportion of the population practicing open defecation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA08BD41A3F3D42ADA36EEC0DF992516A"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the total number of children younger than 5 years of age who died from diarrheal disease;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC55517DE354F47F3A3FFCA560FFD5105"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the proportion of all deaths of children younger than 5 years of age resulting from diarrheal
			 disease;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H42EAD147B95D4008891F47F1E6DA4818"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the national government’s capacity, capability, and commitment to work with the United States to
			 improve access to safe water, sanitation, and hygiene, including—</text><clause id="id0B4004B39554418F8B92E25A28E881C4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the
			 government’s capacity and commitment to developing the indigenous capacity
			 to provide safe water and sanitation without the assistance of outside
			 donors; and</text></clause><clause id="idD2F6FBC1AC1743D7826A1C5BA9A6FFC0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the degree to which such government—</text><subclause id="id165BBFFC21CD4BB089DC2C36995F51C6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>identifies such efforts as
			 a priority; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id5AFFD00FA726413BA19529F3E962CD1A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>allocates resources to such efforts;</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H771291E70D1E47C09C997D3D74D1B9C3"><enum>(J)</enum><text>the availability of opportunities to leverage existing public, private, or other donor investments
			 in the water, sanitation, and hygiene sectors, including investments in
			 the management of water resources; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4A411962879845DB8937F2FDA4232192"><enum>(K)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the likelihood of making significant improvements on a per capita basis on the health
			 and
			 educational opportunities available to women as a result of increased
			 access to safe water, sanitation, and hygiene, including access to
			 appropriate facilities at primary and secondary educational institutions
			 seeking to ensure that communities benefitting from such projects and
			 activities develop the indigenous capacity to provide safe water and
			 sanitation without the assistance of outside donors;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFA18A0468B554AF19EF40E9AF6A38743"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prioritizing and measuring, including through rigorous monitoring and evaluating mechanisms, the
			 extent to which such project or program—</text><subparagraph id="H43476A9F38314631B6E3EF7C0D39F1C2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>furthers significant improvements in—</text><clause id="HC5403479A3474D81B09921E90844A8FA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the criteria set forth in subparagraphs (A) through (H) of paragraph (1);</text></clause><clause id="HACF77D8022FA4A71AD9F219EE7E016CB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the health and educational opportunities available to women as a result of increased access to safe
			 water, sanitation, and hygiene, including access to appropriate facilities
			 at primary and secondary educational institutions; and</text></clause><clause id="HE9E17F0CF8BE4AF9BA2558716DE33FC6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the indigenous capacity of the host nation or community to provide safe water and sanitation
			 without the assistance of outside donors;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6C4DE483CE0345F18778B6FBB3B84D96"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is designed, as part of the provision of safe water and sanitation to the local community—</text><clause id="HCA30ECC0997F4EF4847B9862C8935D55"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to be financially independent over the long term, focusing on local ownership and sustainability;</text></clause><clause id="idADE389F6FDBD451B96425F5E821A2E88"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to be undertaken in conjunction with relevant public institutions or private
			 enterprises;</text></clause><clause id="HDA68570D6D6C48699C2B51384E5D9612"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to identify and empower local individuals or institutions to be responsible for the effective
			 management and maintenance of such project or program; and</text></clause><clause id="H8BFA72FE76614CABB8D2338592D23FC2"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>to provide safe water or expertise or capacity building to those identified parties or institutions
			 for the purposes of developing a plan and clear responsibilities for the
			 effective management and maintenance of such project or program;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H238862509F1D4F5ABD7DADADB0D95AFA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>leverages existing public, private, or other donor investments in the water, sanitation, and
			 hygiene sectors, including investments in the management of water
			 resources;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA77BD7A75C254AF89627CAE5072FE4B3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>avoids duplication of efforts with other United States Government agencies or departments or those
			 of other nations or nongovernmental organizations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H33EB67D1A56E40DEA1F70667D55CC473"><enum>(E)</enum><text>coordinates such efforts with the efforts of other United States Government agencies or departments
			 or those of other nations or nongovernmental organizations directed at
			 assisting refugees and other displaced individuals; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE9A9081A2AA14328B52BBC03DEC5C868"><enum>(F)</enum><text>involves consultation with appropriate stakeholders, including communities directly affected by the
			 lack of access to clean water, sanitation or hygiene, and other
			 appropriate nongovernmental organizations;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9BCF8A12EB864261A98BD9FE7F3A29D3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>seeking to further the <quote>USAID Water and Development Strategy, 2013–2018</quote> through 2018; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7870E084973E4C82BC4CDF7F6308966E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>seeking to further the strategy required under subsection (j) after 2018.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H314D93425488439DB84E26C174182A98"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Use of improved data collection and review of new standardized indicators</header><paragraph id="H4E7D8EB3A1A64CF6AE430D018AB7B527"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development is authorized to use
			 improved data collection—</text><subparagraph id="idA74B85B035194965BB6FFBE8051EA142"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to meet the health-based
			 prioritization criteria established pursuant to subsection (f)(1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id45BDE6B1979E461C81E8FA77049F7957"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to
			 review new standardized indicators in evaluating progress towards meeting
			 such criteria.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE6A522C109FE473885672D6E29A0C91D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation and notice</header><text>The Administrator shall—</text><subparagraph id="id93035ADC83674610800F1A897E27F2A1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>regularly consult with the appropriate congressional committees; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idFCD95E7AB328490D9E006B0DA5B2866B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>notify such committees not later 30 days before using improved
			 data collection and review of new standardized indicators under paragraph
			 (1) for the purposes of carrying out this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF4DC1CABB4524649A8FA9C08C52FFE15"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Designation of high priority countries</header><paragraph id="H977E3F3C93484C22B84178B0F54F3154"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial designation</header><text>Not later than October 1, 2015, the President shall—</text><subparagraph id="id715CD17822E04445B27DE86813DF721A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>designate, on the basis of the criteria set
			 forth in subsection (f)(1) and in furtherance of the <quote>USAID Water and Development Strategy, 2013–2018</quote>, not fewer than 10 countries as high priority countries to be the primary recipients of United
			 States
			 Government assistance authorized under this section during fiscal year
			 2016; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id50860944A3454C7891254C6AD1CFEB0F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>notify the appropriate congressional committees of
			 such designations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF6506CC40AF048ACB668A0654D9050F6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annual designations</header><subparagraph id="id580C3CCBFE9B456CBB97E253AB3CBBDC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the President shall annually make new designations pursuant
			 to the criteria set forth in paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB2159A0E9DDD44C18CF788D03DFFD1EC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Designations after fiscal year 2018</header><text>Beginning with fiscal year 2019, designations under paragraph (1) shall be made—</text><clause id="idBBA20EE5B9BC47D9BBEFC7A2966C847D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>based upon the criteria set forth in subsection (f)(1); and</text></clause><clause id="idEC6AB21385BD40ABAD4EA8C73514DB41"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in furtherance of the strategy
			 required under subsection (j).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE493AC23AA42460F883A7418736E71D7"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Targeting of projects and programs to areas of greatest need</header><paragraph id="id523CDD7B4ACD421AAC66809379686AB1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 15 days before the obligation of any funds for water, sanitation,
			 or hygiene projects or programs pursuant to this section in countries that
			 are not ranked in the top 50 countries based upon the
			 WASH Needs Index, the Administrator of the United States
			 Agency for International Development shall notify the appropriate
			 congressional committees of the planned obligation of such
			 funds.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id89E88A66F1464E29B6D5036E9C656FF3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Defined term</header><text>In this subsection and in subsection (j), the term <term>WASH Needs Index</term> means the needs index for water, sanitation, or hygiene projects or programs authorized under this
			 section that has been developed using the criteria and indicators
			 described in subparagraphs (A)
			 through (H) of subsection (f)(1).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section changed="deleted" committee-id="SSFR00" id="H3CF5A6A6806E478695864D83DC0F3FB7" reported-display-style="strikethrough"><enum>6.</enum><header>United States strategy to increase appropriate long-term sustainability and access to safe water,
			 sanitation, and hygiene</header><subsection id="H7B0BE383900842C3B831CDC344783841"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 136 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, as redesignated and amended by this Act, is
			 further amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block changed="deleted" committee-id="SSFR00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8AC312F8FE0545068484663B6E6D59A8" reported-display-style="strikethrough" style="OLC"><subsection id="H113288D23C764F8D9C6F18B2BAD45667"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Global water strategy</header><paragraph id="HB2660E472D4D4904929FCECCA7AE9888"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than October 1, 2017, and every 5 years thereafter, the President,
			 acting through the Secretary of State, the Administrator of the United
			 States Agency for International Development, and the heads of other
			 Federal departments and agencies, as appropriate, shall submit a single
			 government-wide Global Water Strategy to the appropriate
			 congressional committees 
			 that provides a detailed description of how the United States intends—</text><subparagraph id="H2D95497CAB0944AE9DC1181C2CD5D225"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to increase access to safe water, sanitation, and hygiene in high priority countries designated
			 pursuant to subsection (h), including a summary of the WASH Needs Index
			 and the specific weighting of data and other assumptions used to develop
			 and rank countries on the WASH Needs Index;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H02EEEC4B4FAA42BC8A458BB60122EBD3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to improve the management of water resources and watersheds in such countries; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H21464F43E4354111A8AD7A5CFA7C0AAB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to work to prevent and resolve, to the greatest degree possible, both intra- and trans-boundary
			 conflicts over water resources in such countries.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFE6A493C48DC475CA0366DE0ADC7943C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Agency-specific plans</header><text>The Global Water Strategy shall include an agency-specific plan—</text><subparagraph id="H796E5CCEEA2C413498BE7E2CAAD89D3C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>from the United States Agency for International Development that describes specifically how the
			 Agency for International Development will—</text><clause id="HA394D7B061BC4151B7B7BB4C05BD3FAA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>carry out the duties and responsibilities assigned to the Global Water Coordinator under subsection
			 (e)(1);</text></clause><clause id="HBDC2B50AAB7840358B07892774841B20"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ensure that the Agency for International Development’s projects and programs authorized under this
			 section are designed to achieve maximum impact and long-term
			 sustainability, including by implementing the requirements described in
			 subsection
			 (f); and</text></clause><clause id="H39919D13EC3343768759B74917BAA0D1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>increase access to safe water, sanitation, and hygiene in high priority countries designated
			 pursuant to subsection (h);</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6526E9D9C3FF4136BA387FE7B75705D8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>from the Department of State that describes specifically how the Department of State will—</text><clause id="H5DF2006BEE6E48F7B6B4088528F296BC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>carry out the duties and responsibilities assigned to the Special Coordinator for Water Resources
			 under subsection (e)(2); and</text></clause><clause id="H316F2A1F24D346BCA0A0D49A3A22AADD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ensure that the Department’s activities authorized under this
			 section are designed—</text><subclause id="id07A738F44BA34A80ACA6007A707C5BAA"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to improve management of water resources and
			 watersheds in countries designated pursuant to subsection (h); and</text></subclause><subclause id="idFB0CE022BAD548E8AD8B463C038850A6"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to
			 prevent and resolve, to the greatest degree possible, both intra- and
			 trans-boundary conflicts over water resources in such countries; and</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H73F25BF240C6400486FBE6D01DDBAA18"><enum>(C)</enum><text>from other Federal departments and agencies, as appropriate, that describes the contributions of
			 the
			 departments and agencies to implementing the Global Water Strategy.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFE53EC9493BB4B5B986463DCF8C8F662"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Individualized plans for high priority countries</header><text>For each high priority country designated pursuant to subsection (h), the Administrator of the
			 United States Agency for International Development shall—</text><subparagraph id="id10712E1F81BB4819898140149F231CB1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>develop a costed,
			 evidence-based, and results-oriented plan that—</text><clause id="id7AB209DD4DC346878A97594EBC133D50"><enum>(i)</enum><text>seeks to achieve the
			 purposes of this section; and</text></clause><clause id="id065EB1D9E1634502BAA469B730C68B4E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>meets the requirements under subsection (f); and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idECB13ACEED764CADBACD10FA7E7E5FCA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include such plan in an appendix to the Global Water Strategy
			 required under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF6A9499F664B4410828AC339BE6113F7"><enum>(4)</enum><header>First time access reporting requirement</header><text>The Global Water Strategy shall specifically describe the target
			 percentage of funding for each fiscal year covered by such strategy to be
			 directed toward projects aimed at providing first-time access to safe
			 water and sanitation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H44485208CEF94395BF1C35030A6A3665"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Performance indicators</header><text>The Global Water Strategy shall include specific and measurable goals, benchmarks,
			 performance metrics, timetables, and monitoring and evaluation plans
			 required to be developed by the Administrator of the United States Agency
			 for International Development pursuant to subsection (e)(1)(B)(v).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6AF69F11884D4A9299F9ED862D247775"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Consultation and best practices</header><text>The Global Water Strategy shall—</text><subparagraph id="idDB216091ED254F15B9EE1E9C103739E0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be developed in consultation with the heads of other
			 appropriate Federal departments and agencies; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idBB4CDCC3151A47209FFD1C2209AC6843"><enum>(B)</enum><text>incorporate best
			 practices from the international development community.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0642B466A9414D61B344AA1A49756616"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><paragraph id="H8D5F5300B8AE4295872CE12BA9EBB1DE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2DFBDE9BE04F4AAE815175C6733FDC57"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSAP00">Committee on Appropriations of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id790DC6ECE65E4FDA8AEC22AF2D07C160"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</committee-name>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idDDEBC6579F0844E283F407FB3590F7ED"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives</committee-name>.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HE595FC8760F34378B6C6F8B7607E7D3E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Department of State agency-Specific plan</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall
			 submit an agency-specific plan to the appropriate congressional committees
			 (as defined in section 136(k) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, as
			 added by subsection (a)) that meets the requirements of section
			 136(j)(2)(B) of
			 such Act, as added by subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="H14DDBE28DCDA4330B64AE5CFAC848907"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 6 of the Senator Paul Simon Water for the Poor Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/121">Public Law 109–121</external-xref>; 22 U.S.C.
			 2152h note) is repealed.</text></subsection></section></legis-body><legis-body display-enacting-clause="no-display-enacting-clause"><section changed="added" committee-id="SSFR00" id="idf5560db1-9d82-464e-8f7d-52228e9d99e7" reported-display-style="italic" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Senator Paul Simon Water for the World Act of 2014</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section changed="added" committee-id="SSFR00" id="id62234906-41cb-4ff0-acfb-37327e146b46" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="id460d1a4a-dbe9-47f0-93df-cfe286178df5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>water and sanitation are critically important resources that impact many other aspects of human
			 life; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7ccaacae-b84c-4d31-a57b-e3ebcf75c162"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the United States should be a global leader in helping
			 provide sustainable access to clean water and sanitation for the world’s
			 most vulnerable populations.</text></paragraph></section><section changed="added" commented="no" committee-id="SSFR00" id="idf32ba4a7-7ee6-4538-98c7-8bc6583baa24" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>3.</enum><header>Clarification of assistance to provide safe water and sanitation to include hygiene</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Chapter 1 of part I of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 is amended—</text><paragraph id="id9155bd59-44a2-4ed3-bb69-998a8cca571c"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating section 135 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2152h">22 U.S.C. 2152h</external-xref>), as added by section 5(a) of the Senator Paul Simon
			 Water for the Poor Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/121">Public Law 109–121</external-xref>; 22
			 U.S.C. 2152h note), as section 136; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id7068933e-1145-411e-a768-b729cb77e434"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 136, as redesignated—</text><subparagraph id="id2a5089ac-a72c-4979-8c7e-b52ba6dcdb35"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the section heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">and sanitation</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">, sanitation, and hygiene</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id50a8f4c2-3831-4a5f-9bff-7f0c422f2976"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by striking <quote>and sanitation</quote> and inserting <quote>, sanitation, and hygiene</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section changed="added" committee-id="SSFR00" id="idfcc689e5-7010-41fa-9439-f27593e904fd" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>4.</enum><header>Improving coordination and oversight of safe water, sanitation and hygiene projects and activities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 136 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, as redesignated and amended by this Act, is
			 further amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="SSFR00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id820c34cc-f780-4dc9-9952-2313b4347fe2" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC"><subsection id="id46315745-5680-4952-ae4c-908e6d7235c0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Coordination and oversight</header><paragraph id="id4ea57dc3-39aa-4210-9130-15091efd9af7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>USAID global water coordinator</header><subparagraph id="idc0c3fb22-f466-4a82-bd80-3a5a3dbc4a70"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>The Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development (referred to in this
			 paragraph as <quote>USAID</quote>) or the Administrator’s
			 designee,  who shall be a current USAID employee serving in a career or
			 non-career position in the Senior Executive Service or at the level of a
			 Deputy Assistant Administrator or higher, shall serve concurrently as the
			 USAID Global Water Coordinator (referred to in this subsection as the <quote>Coordinator</quote>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6be18178-9888-4c9a-b334-2e49f96c1521"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Specific duties</header><text>The Coordinator shall—</text><clause id="idcd551297-bbb4-4893-bb46-8d22ef0db717"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provide direction and guidance to, coordinate, and oversee the projects and
			 programs of USAID authorized under this section;</text></clause><clause id="idf8c9027a-603d-4832-b758-0f9fb16e003a"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>lead the implementation and revision, not less frequently than once every 5 years, of USAID’s
			 portion of the
			 Global Water Strategy required under subsection (j);</text></clause><clause id="id6091e32f-df51-48ea-b4ce-7edb9e481e07"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>seek—</text><subclause id="id314ebd78-212e-4ca2-b4a3-3e8d4c0ccdda"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to expand the capacity of USAID, subject to the availability of appropriations, including through
			 the designation of a lead subject matter expert selected from among USAID
			 staff in each high priority country
			 designated pursuant to subsection (h);</text></subclause><subclause id="ida69422c3-a9cf-470d-a7b7-ef3a1f8de7fd"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to implement such programs and
			 activities;</text></subclause><subclause id="id923d5f16-1b68-4cf6-9fb8-8be63d2504f1"><enum>(III)</enum><text>to take advantage of economies of scale; and</text></subclause><subclause id="idc6a2f4f5-25ba-430d-b05e-c85460d50f3e"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>to conduct more
			 efficient and effective projects and programs;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idfbc224ab-9656-4dbd-8d89-5fed01e1e986"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>coordinate with the Department of State and USAID staff in each high priority country designated
			 pursuant to subsection (h) to ensure that USAID activities and projects,
			 USAID program planning and budgeting documents, and USAID country
			 development strategies reflect and seek to implement—</text><subclause id="ida24a817f-a4df-4b13-bf47-7e587b16bdad"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the safe water, sanitation, and hygiene objectives established in the strategy required under
			 subsection (j), including objectives relating to the management of water
			 resources; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id4b849a67-e68b-489d-a0e6-b59c78bf5fe5"><enum>(II)</enum><text>international best practices relating to—</text><item id="id5cae4f7e-5d07-4913-b798-480ac2bf24e7"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>increasing access to safe water and sanitation;</text></item><item id="id8b94ebbc-5f2e-4721-b2dc-737aede86e54"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>conducting
			 hygiene-related activities; and</text></item><item id="id6479437f-d4ee-4ef8-8015-d007026c335b"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>ensuring appropriate management of water
			 resources; and</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="id38cff943-eb6c-42cd-8700-f819f996c84f"><enum>(v)</enum><text>develop appropriate benchmarks, measurable goals, performance metrics, and monitoring and
			 evaluation plans for USAID projects and programs authorized under this
			 section.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id673d7567-cf08-49b0-97fc-4aaff9bf7ed4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Department of state special coordinator for water resources</header><subparagraph id="id52e13356-e5d1-4841-81a0-c459c2e5bf97"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>The Secretary of State or the Secretary’s designee,  who shall be a current employee of the
			 Department of
			 State
			 serving in a career or non-career position in the Senior Executive Service
			 or at the level of a Deputy Assistant Secretary or higher, shall serve
			 concurrently as the Department of State Special Advisor for Water
			 Resources (referred to in this paragraph as the <quote>Special Advisor</quote>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb44a18e4-3b2c-4a08-bbf3-2a96ef31a09a"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Specific duties</header><text>The Special Advisor shall—</text><clause id="id7a59cbf4-fb1c-479e-9bfc-65f5516f5e90"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provide direction and guidance to, coordinate, and oversee the projects and
			 programs of the Department of State authorized under this section;</text></clause><clause id="idc813722b-8ced-4716-935f-a9135bc05c22"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>lead the implementation and revision, not less than every 5 years, of the Department of State’s
			 portion of the Global Water Strategy required under subsection (j);</text></clause><clause id="id8c1a6140-68d3-477c-8fa4-a3adf5b17064"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>prioritize and coordinate the Department of State’s international engagement on the allocation,
			 distribution, and access to global fresh water resources and policies
			 related to such matters;</text></clause><clause id="id1e3c746c-178d-47e0-9538-e1d21d24eb9c"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>coordinate with United States Agency for International Development and Department of State staff in
			 each
			 high priority country designated pursuant to subsection (h) to ensure that
			 United States diplomatic efforts related to safe water, sanitation, and
			 hygiene, including efforts related to management of water resources and
			 watersheds and the resolution of intra- and trans-boundary conflicts over
			 water resources, are consistent with United States national interests; and</text></clause><clause id="id1865aae1-40b3-4cab-8443-97d2ada32dee"><enum>(v)</enum><text>represent the views of the United States Government on the allocation, distribution, and access to
			 global fresh water resources and policies related to such matters in key
			 international fora, including key diplomatic, development-related, and
			 scientific organizations.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida0184f9c-b27c-4014-93ad-e9f27533b22d"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Additional nature of duties and restriction on additional or supplemental compensation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The responsibilities and specific duties of the Administrator of the United States Agency for
			 International Development (or the Administrator’s designee) and the
			 Secretary of State (or the Secretary’s designee) under paragraph (2) or
			 (3), respectively, shall be in addition to any other
			 responsibilities or specific duties assigned to such individuals. Such
			 individuals shall receive no additional or supplemental compensation as a
			 result of carrying out such responsibilities and specific duties under
			 such paragraphs.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section changed="added" committee-id="SSFR00" id="id40e6d993-389c-4135-8697-f6a0a2c48fd8" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>5.</enum><header>Promoting the maximum impact and long-term sustainability  of USAID safe water, sanitation, and
			 hygiene-related projects and programs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 136 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, as redesignated and amended by this Act, is
			 further amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="SSFR00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id94f38833-fed7-42df-9dd9-ccf93122d004" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC"><subsection id="id7930717c-b3a4-432d-b8f6-02c2059c2f01"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Priorities and criteria for maximum impact and long-Term sustainability</header><text>The Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development shall ensure that the
			 Agency for International Development’s projects and programs authorized
			 under this section are designed to achieve maximum impact and
			 long-term sustainability by—</text><paragraph id="id1502067f-12eb-41c0-b5a9-bc4ecc691d45"><enum>(1)</enum><text>prioritizing countries on the basis of the following clearly defined criteria and
			 indicators, to the extent sufficient empirical data are available—</text><subparagraph id="id2ec9cc4b-f4fc-4948-bd09-d7ab065bf3ec"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the proportion of the population using an unimproved drinking water source;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id97ac591f-2238-40ae-9de8-93db37fa5a36"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the total population using an unimproved drinking water source;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id229b1e76-d3aa-4597-8009-68dd1dce58d4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the proportion of the population without piped water access;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id391945f8-da87-421a-b6e4-99c623d9e868"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the proportion of the population using shared or other unimproved sanitation facilities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id898f0358-b69e-4900-bc3d-7744590e7485"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the total population using shared or other unimproved sanitation facilities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2ae817c5-f37e-4089-8c80-bc079e48a084"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the proportion of the population practicing open defecation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddb09d932-395d-4efe-8716-769094f3ee18"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the total number of children younger than 5 years of age who died from diarrheal disease;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6cae81cf-1f8b-4527-b9dc-54dc7e53c9f4"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the proportion of all deaths of children younger than 5 years of age resulting from diarrheal
			 disease;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id03bd6fcf-cd20-4fba-922a-2814249c965a"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the national government’s capacity, capability, and commitment to work with the United States to
			 improve access to safe water, sanitation, and hygiene, including—</text><clause id="id2c50e320-354f-4197-87af-ae2dc4619ede"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the
			 government’s capacity and commitment to developing the indigenous capacity
			 to provide safe water and sanitation without the assistance of outside
			 donors; and</text></clause><clause id="id553eaeea-fd2e-42d9-9f80-1761305cf939"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the degree to which such government—</text><subclause id="id43cebd22-2fe8-401c-aaff-8106c960313e"><enum>(I)</enum><text>identifies such efforts as
			 a priority; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id832bec14-f53e-4233-8aa5-d96373af001a"><enum>(II)</enum><text>allocates resources to such efforts;</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd500c8ff-1e34-4c48-a8cf-068cbe720d95"><enum>(J)</enum><text>the availability of opportunities to leverage existing public, private, or other donor investments
			 in the water, sanitation, and hygiene sectors, including investments in
			 the management of water resources; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id61ed85db-53f2-4c7e-9510-8fb1ecf53069"><enum>(K)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the likelihood of making significant improvements on a per capita basis on the health
			 and
			 educational opportunities available to women as a result of increased
			 access to safe water, sanitation, and hygiene, including access to
			 appropriate facilities at primary and secondary educational institutions
			 seeking to ensure that communities benefitting from such projects and
			 activities develop the indigenous capacity to provide safe water and
			 sanitation without the assistance of outside donors;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id25c5cfb1-9670-4d36-a0f8-62d8fa5d3ba3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prioritizing and measuring, including through rigorous monitoring and evaluating mechanisms, the
			 extent to which such project or program—</text><subparagraph id="id1dc275f5-9663-4385-a143-90916c2f339e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>furthers significant improvements in—</text><clause id="id5ea4d2d1-f3bf-441c-954e-69178e212764"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the criteria set forth in subparagraphs (A) through (H) of paragraph (1);</text></clause><clause id="id8031d995-2e7b-4c80-8ae8-63737084f763"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the health and educational opportunities available to women as a result of increased access to safe
			 water, sanitation, and hygiene, including access to appropriate facilities
			 at primary and secondary educational institutions; and</text></clause><clause id="id0025b9d0-3f2c-447b-adb2-65410172ed05"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the indigenous capacity of the host nation or community to provide safe water and sanitation
			 without the assistance of outside donors;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id48719f65-15b6-4ebd-b7b0-b783dd76d3f6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is designed, as part of the provision of safe water and sanitation to the local community—</text><clause id="id436dcb32-8bc5-41fb-a10b-f602454b85d0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to be financially independent over the long term, focusing on local ownership and sustainability;</text></clause><clause id="idc3eed37a-4282-4e6a-8805-bebc41e23dcf"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to be undertaken in conjunction with relevant public institutions or private
			 enterprises;</text></clause><clause id="id83c24cb5-674e-43d2-8f08-3d4dd3986fd0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to identify and empower local individuals or institutions to be responsible for the effective
			 management and maintenance of such project or program; and</text></clause><clause id="id2dd5d966-2f44-4b04-ab65-e989f10ac989"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>to provide safe water or expertise or capacity building to those identified parties or institutions
			 for the purposes of developing a plan and clear responsibilities for the
			 effective management and maintenance of such project or program;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1a9a0ee0-5e79-46fa-94c2-1c849083e49c"><enum>(C)</enum><text>leverages existing public, private, or other donor investments in the water, sanitation, and
			 hygiene sectors, including investments in the management of water
			 resources;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id274773ca-339e-417b-a489-7dc30575e6b9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>avoids duplication of efforts with other United States Government agencies or departments or those
			 of other nations or nongovernmental organizations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide7fbcbc4-1608-4329-b697-3f502444a01c"><enum>(E)</enum><text>coordinates such efforts with the efforts of other United States Government agencies or departments
			 or those of other nations or nongovernmental organizations directed at
			 assisting refugees and other displaced individuals; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida635f872-7245-4c6f-b47b-6b73cb64387a"><enum>(F)</enum><text>involves consultation with appropriate stakeholders, including communities directly affected by the
			 lack of access to clean water, sanitation or hygiene, and other
			 appropriate nongovernmental organizations; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idfcf3d9d0-d9c1-48c4-b53a-e70fa0eebe7f"><enum>(3)</enum><text>seeking to further the strategy required under subsection (j) after 2018.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id645c16dc-b37d-4544-b8a3-af760ccf8dac"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Use of current and improved empirical data collection and review of new standardized indicators</header><paragraph id="ida7827592-92cb-40e0-8554-6f01161bbe36"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development is authorized to use
			 current and improved empirical data collection—</text><subparagraph id="idac127596-9ffd-443c-ac35-64371bc5fe44"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to meet the health-based
			 prioritization criteria established pursuant to subsection (f)(1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id298165cc-cf83-4a1c-b109-fa091bfebd7c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to
			 review new standardized indicators in evaluating progress towards meeting
			 such criteria.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id73e2752a-35cc-49e1-afe0-133e61ca7ba9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation and notice</header><text>The Administrator shall—</text><subparagraph id="idacbac8a7-cdd0-4811-b6c4-87f3ac1fc400"><enum>(A)</enum><text>regularly consult with the appropriate congressional committees; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide7027806-0d08-433f-a16e-a8d2b976a76a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>notify such committees not later than 30 days before using current or improved empirical
			 data collection for the review of any new standardized indicators under
			 paragraph
			 (1) for the purposes of carrying out this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id10103ec5-7e40-4a20-bdbb-ee92c485da7a"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Designation of high priority countries</header><paragraph id="id1ae2021c-cee7-46d1-9001-02bd6c548242"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial designation</header><text>Not later than October 1, 2015, the President shall—</text><subparagraph id="ida59e8970-1be5-43a3-ba46-85dc9c2ad6ea"><enum>(A)</enum><text>designate, on the basis of the criteria set
			 forth in subsection (f)(1) not fewer than 10 countries as high priority
			 countries to be the primary recipients of United
			 States
			 Government assistance authorized under this section during fiscal year
			 2016; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5e24d354-b5b5-4cda-8671-1771a6ef9ac9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>notify the appropriate congressional committees of
			 such designations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1256b851-893a-4687-9a19-7893ba63965d"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annual designations</header><subparagraph id="id71085760-1b6f-480a-bd48-070e415fa7fe"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the President shall annually make new designations pursuant
			 to the criteria set forth in paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ideb6864c1-d1ae-443e-9044-96aa5c852237"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Designations after fiscal year 2018</header><text>Beginning with fiscal year 2019, designations under paragraph (1) shall be made—</text><clause id="id85507e5a-9c3c-4e74-8788-791376bd11db"><enum>(i)</enum><text>based upon the criteria set forth in subsection (f)(1); and</text></clause><clause id="id61eeba19-ab20-4fbc-b9db-e26742acac2f"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in furtherance of the strategy
			 required under subsection (j).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0806c495-7c73-46bd-8cea-97d28d970103"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Targeting of projects and programs to areas of greatest need</header><paragraph id="idcda3d00d-3fbd-4aef-93d1-dbb1fab5d97d"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 15 days before the obligation of any funds for water, sanitation,
			 or hygiene projects or programs pursuant to this section in countries that
			 are not ranked in the top 50 countries based upon the
			 WASH Needs Index, the Administrator of the United States
			 Agency for International Development shall notify the appropriate
			 congressional committees of the planned obligation of such
			 funds.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id33e9f0ee-5201-4f56-a793-0898ac7ccdad"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Defined term</header><text>In this subsection and in subsection (j), the term <term>WASH Needs Index</term> means the needs index for water, sanitation, or hygiene projects or programs authorized under this
			 section that has been developed using the criteria and indicators
			 described in subparagraphs (A)
			 through (H) of subsection (f)(1).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section changed="added" committee-id="SSFR00" id="id239811c4-5349-4ae1-be31-8b650df6bc5a" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>6.</enum><header>United States strategy to increase appropriate long-term sustainability and access to safe
			 water,
			 sanitation, and hygiene</header><subsection id="id206e4fe3-4e75-4ce7-9ec9-02e790261959"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 136 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, as redesignated and amended by this Act, is
			 further amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="SSFR00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcb0c1a73-d7ce-483a-83cc-3e795f415922" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC"><subsection id="id45a3fa98-5117-45e4-9d6e-d23740bb61b8"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Global water strategy</header><paragraph id="idd54fe48d-ad3c-467c-adca-b60389e50f4a"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than October 1, 2017, and every 5 years thereafter, the President,
			 acting through the Secretary of State, the Administrator of the United
			 States Agency for International Development, and the heads of other
			 Federal departments and agencies, as appropriate, shall submit a single
			 government-wide Global Water Strategy to the appropriate
			 congressional committees 
			 that provides a detailed description of how the United States intends—</text><subparagraph id="id458715e6-736b-47ce-b8c2-ac5ac4e85ef1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to increase access to safe water, sanitation, and hygiene in high priority countries designated
			 pursuant to subsection (h), including a summary of the WASH Needs Index
			 and the specific weighting of empirical data and other definitions used
			 to develop
			 and rank countries on the WASH Needs Index;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9b937ba8-75f1-415e-ad18-b5613df58ed3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to improve the management of water resources and watersheds in such countries; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9e08e0f8-2a2f-4134-84f9-b1730171fe2a"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to work to prevent and resolve, to the greatest degree possible, both intra- and trans-boundary
			 conflicts over water resources in such countries.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0e2d2eb8-cdb5-4eeb-a2ae-3f7498b58882"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Agency-specific plans</header><text>The Global Water Strategy shall include an agency-specific plan—</text><subparagraph id="id161e0e11-0e4e-4081-a9c7-de28c5e736cb"><enum>(A)</enum><text>from the United States Agency for International Development that describes specifically how the
			 Agency for International Development will—</text><clause id="id5203eeb8-e240-40eb-b745-e46340753a7d"><enum>(i)</enum><text>carry out the duties and responsibilities assigned to the Global Water Coordinator under subsection
			 (e)(1);</text></clause><clause id="ida358a031-a84b-483b-830f-05f6c799e311"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ensure that the Agency for International Development’s projects and programs authorized under this
			 section are designed to achieve maximum impact and long-term
			 sustainability, including by implementing the requirements described
			 in
			 subsection
			 (f); and</text></clause><clause id="id765828d9-f84f-4e4a-a892-2c9446ce59f1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>increase access to safe water, sanitation, and hygiene in high priority countries designated
			 pursuant to subsection (h);</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida3166815-e638-42c2-8af9-cbd5d0dd7121"><enum>(B)</enum><text>from the Department of State that describes specifically how the Department of State will—</text><clause id="id85af80e9-d37a-4edd-a789-2390496092ca"><enum>(i)</enum><text>carry out the duties and responsibilities assigned to the Special Coordinator for Water Resources
			 under subsection (e)(2); and</text></clause><clause id="id90a9647e-5103-4a79-bbee-8ce5ab30e6c9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ensure that the Department’s activities authorized under this
			 section are designed—</text><subclause id="id28d8ef6d-3dca-4e4f-b102-c4bbac22f7eb"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to improve management of water resources and
			 watersheds in countries designated pursuant to subsection (h); and</text></subclause><subclause id="id14bbedd0-a7bc-4c86-9d75-76155258aa6e"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to
			 prevent and resolve, to the greatest degree possible, both intra- and
			 trans-boundary conflicts over water resources in such countries; and</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ided15dc69-4517-415f-b988-8d3b33f827a0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>from other Federal departments and agencies, as appropriate, that describes the contributions of
			 the
			 departments and agencies to implementing the Global Water Strategy.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0a5fbc5d-6e27-4cff-8608-2ee621030397"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Individualized plans for high priority countries</header><text>For each high priority country designated pursuant to subsection (h), the Administrator of the
			 United States Agency for International Development shall—</text><subparagraph id="idba1993b5-f99c-4fd3-8be4-81e8a737c666"><enum>(A)</enum><text>develop a costed,
			 evidence-based, and results-oriented plan that—</text><clause id="id491c6e8e-1ae8-4828-9f51-ac58f14a6eff"><enum>(i)</enum><text>seeks to achieve the
			 purposes of this section; and</text></clause><clause id="id767dc15c-c6b3-4bdc-8b6f-4f2a1a51b41d"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>meets the requirements under subsection (f); and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id129cffe8-a9a8-4cca-9ab6-88efea58ca8f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include such plan in an appendix to the Global Water Strategy
			 required under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0a9c3732-7fce-45c1-8069-99e38a81bc13"><enum>(4)</enum><header>First time access reporting requirement</header><text>The Global Water Strategy shall specifically describe the target
			 percentage of funding for each fiscal year covered by such strategy to be
			 directed toward projects aimed at providing first-time access to safe
			 water and sanitation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida3adfffc-14b9-483c-aaf6-6f8ec97627f1"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Performance indicators</header><text>The Global Water Strategy shall include specific and measurable goals, benchmarks,
			 performance metrics, timetables, and monitoring and evaluation plans
			 required to be developed by the Administrator of the United States Agency
			 for International Development pursuant to subsection (e)(1)(B)(v).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1405990d-3d92-4b50-bdd1-458707fca61f"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Consultation and best practices</header><text>The Global Water Strategy shall—</text><subparagraph id="ide4da7af9-db0c-44d6-9733-5b0f30d462ba"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be developed in consultation with the heads of other
			 appropriate Federal departments and agencies; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida8a409ca-2002-4776-8a7b-f3fa8c4bf1e9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>incorporate best
			 practices from the international development community.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id464a6e66-e6c2-4ef6-baf3-60e7ab474f87"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text><paragraph id="idDBC2135A135046F2BAD6629E4A68027E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="idcc2cd0f5-e5e5-4dd0-a6b5-53ab4fac6b8c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb1d9285c-4a01-47ab-8e4c-00470bb8967e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSAP00">Committee on Appropriations of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc502740a-f668-4289-b637-72ef2e8e45ee"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</committee-name>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id32f6de4e-dfb7-4641-a8b9-b6b93d27cbba"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives</committee-name>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id14b1a8d0910f40be96bb94221da4b730"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>long-term sustainability</term> refers to the ability of a service delivery system, community, partner, or beneficiary to
			 maintain, over time, any water, sanitation, or hygiene project  that
			 receives funding pursuant to the amendments made by the <short-title>Senator Paul Simon Water for the World Act of 2014</short-title>.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id34deb8e6-9b94-428f-bc94-37b089352720"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Department of State agency-Specific plan</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall
			 submit an agency-specific plan to the appropriate congressional committees
			 (as defined in section 136(k) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, as
			 added by subsection (a)) that meets the requirements of section
			 136(j)(2)(B) of
			 such Act, as added by subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="idf64f890e-0f65-4792-8a18-b37d77db4dae"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 6 of the Senator Paul Simon Water for the Poor Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/121">Public Law 109–121</external-xref>; 22 U.S.C.
			 2152h note) is repealed.</text></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement><action-date>December 8, 2014</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment</action-desc></endorsement></bill>


