<bill session="113" type="h" number="3158" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-09-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-09-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-09-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SAFE in Our Schools Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Secure America for Education in Our Schools Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to require recipients of State Homeland Security Grant Program funding to promote preparedness and planning for manmade and natural disasters at educational institutions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412506"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="2013-09-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-09-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Emergency Preparedness, Response and Communications.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM12" subcommittee="Emergency Preparedness, Response, and Communications" name="House Homeland Security"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/20/2013--Introduced.
Secure America for Education in Our Schools Act or the SAFE in Our Schools Act - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to require that each state include in its application for funds under the Homeland Security Grant Program a certification that the state requires each institution of education for kindergarten through 12th grade to develop an emergency response plan that includes provisions for evacuation relocation, family-child reunification, children with special needs, and addressing multiple disasters by the earlier of the beginning of the academic year for 2015 or September 1, 2015.</summary>
</bill>
