<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HA111EAD4DC81422888A5F23B8CF45E5F" public-private="public" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HR 4846 EH: Arapaho National Forest Boundary Adjustment Act of 2014</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress> <session>2d Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 4846</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To adjust the boundary of the Arapaho National Forest, Colorado, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HC8C1ABFB3B4C4BAB868ABCF4437F7457" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD35D5544E6AD40AF804BB871A589E2DE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Arapaho National Forest Boundary Adjustment Act of 2014</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HE18538B0E24F42059B6CDB465F98FBB1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Arapaho National Forest boundary adjustment</header> 
<subsection id="H361730AE17984B3BB5A999DA2FD0CE1E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The boundary of the Arapaho National Forest in the State of Colorado is adjusted to incorporate the approximately 92.95 acres of land generally depicted as <quote>The Wedge</quote> on the map entitled <quote>Arapaho National Forest Boundary Adjustment</quote> and dated November 6, 2013, and described as lots three, four, eight, and nine of section 13, Township 4 North, Range 76 West, Sixth Principal Meridian, Colorado. A lot described in this subsection may be included in the boundary adjustment only after the Secretary of Agriculture obtains written permission for such action from the lot owner or owners.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC8A0DC401E5C45728AE522FEDD306495"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Bowen Gulch Protection Area</header><text>The Secretary of Agriculture shall include all Federal land within the boundary described in subsection (a) in the Bowen Gulch Protection Area established under section 6 of the Colorado Wilderness Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/539j">16 U.S.C. 539j</external-xref>).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF4C27CD00C244569A5860BF191FFED9F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Land and Water Conservation Fund</header><text>For purposes of section 7 of the Land and Water Conservation Fund Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/460l-9">16 U.S.C. 460l–9</external-xref>), the boundaries of the Arapaho National Forest, as modified under subsection (a), shall be considered to be the boundaries of the Arapaho National Forest as in existence on January 1, 1965.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H08797245AEE6478C83A2555E6EBD7C44"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Acquisition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Agriculture is authorized to acquire only by donation or exchange non-Federal lands within the boundary described in subsection (a).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9C035DC4214C450191B03720D6B4944E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Public motorized use</header><text>Nothing in this Act opens privately-owned lands within the boundary described in subsection (a) to public motorized use.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H92997A73468F47FE9397085123F9685D"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Access to non-Federal lands</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding the provisions of section 6(f) of the Colorado Wilderness Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/539j">16 U.S.C. 539j(f)</external-xref>) regarding motorized travel, the owners of any non-Federal lands within the boundary described in subsection (a) who historically have accessed their lands through lands now or hereafter owned by the United States within the boundary described in subsection (a) shall have the continued right of motorized access to their lands across the existing roadway.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20141113" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives November 13, 2014.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation>
<endorsement display="yes"></endorsement>
</bill> 


