<bill session="113" type="s" number="2549" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safe and Affordable Drugs from Canada Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to allow for the personal importation of safe and affordable drugs from approved pharmacies in Canada.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412242"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="2014-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2014-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2014-12-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/26/2014--Introduced.
Safe and Affordable Drugs from Canada Act of 2014 - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (FFDCA) to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to promulgate regulations permitting individuals to safely import into the United States, with exceptions, a prescription drug purchased from an approved Canadian pharmacy that:

 is dispensed by a pharmacist licensed in Canada; is purchased for personal use in quantities not greater than a 90-day supply; is filled using a valid prescription issued by a physician licensed to practice in the United States; and has the same active ingredient or ingredients, route of administration, dosage form, and strength as a prescription drug approved under the FFDCA. Provides criteria for approval of a Canadian pharmacy.

Requires HHS to publish a list of approved Canadian pharmacies, including their website address, from which individuals may purchase prescription drugs in accordance with this Act.</summary>
</bill>
