<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="HDA69D8B312B244D9BB5B65134F85D56E" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Enrolled-Bill" resolution-type="house-concurrent" star-print="no-star-print" key="H" stage-count="1" public-print="no"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title> HCON 119 ENR: Providing for a conditional adjournment of the House of Representatives and a conditional recess or adjournment of the Senate.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2014-11-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form display="yes">
<distribution-code display="no">IV</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">One Hundred Thirteenth Congress of the United States of America</congress> 
<session display="yes">At the Second Session</session><enrolled-dateline display="yes">Begun and held at the City of Washington on Friday, the third day of January, two thousand and fourteen</enrolled-dateline> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. CON. RES. 119</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no"/> 
<action display="yes"> 
<action-date date="20141120" display="yes">November 20, 2014</action-date> 
<action-desc blank-lines-after="0" display="yes">Agreed to</action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type display="yes">CONCURRENT RESOLUTION</legis-type> 
<official-title display="no">Providing for a conditional adjournment of the House of Representatives and a conditional recess or adjournment of the Senate.</official-title> 
</form> 
<resolution-body style="traditional" id="HCF5AB14DECB64E56A10570B54B771F47" display-resolving-clause="yes-display-resolving-clause"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H4DA289B91D3844DB8BA8ED5C81155C06" commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That when the House adjourns on any legislative day from Thursday, November 20, 2014, through Friday, November 28, 2014, on a motion offered pursuant to this concurrent resolution by its Majority Leader or his designee, it stand adjourned until 2:00 p.m. on Monday, December 1, 2014, or until the time of any reassembly pursuant to section 2 of this concurrent resolution, whichever occurs first; and that when the Senate recesses or adjourns on any day from Thursday, November 20, 2014, through Friday, November 28, 2014, on a motion offered pursuant to this concurrent resolution by its Majority Leader or his designee, it stand recessed or adjourned until noon on Monday, December 1, 2014, or such other time on that day as may be specified by its Majority Leader or his designee in the motion to recess or adjourn, or until the time of any reassembly pursuant to section 3 of this concurrent resolution, whichever occurs first.</text></section> <section id="HE02CD1DC3EE04ADEAABB1946911BD944" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum> <subsection id="H73CA8C608860438DB9B09C7AAA70B726" display-inline="yes-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Speaker or his designee, after consultation with the Minority Leader of the House, shall notify Members of the House to reassemble at such place and time as he may designate if, in his opinion, the public interest shall warrant it.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE78FFD55668447AC9765EDFAE65F1334" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After reassembling pursuant to subsection (a), when the House adjourns on a motion offered pursuant to this subsection by its Majority Leader or his designee, the House shall again stand adjourned pursuant to the first section of this concurrent resolution.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H23C15F060AF44751AD56C28D0B2DCE0A" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum> <subsection id="H7CA0CEDD2D8346E4ADBD335EF17648F6" display-inline="yes-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Majority Leader of the Senate or his designee, after concurrence with the Minority Leader of the Senate, shall notify the Members of the Senate to reassemble at such place and time as he may designate if, in his opinion, the public interest shall warrant it.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC1CFF740AC544A9E901D9B592F71EE16" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After reassembling pursuant to subsection (a), when the Senate adjourns on a motion offered pursuant to this subsection by its Majority Leader or his designee, the Senate shall again stand adjourned pursuant to the first section of this concurrent resolution.</text></subsection></section> </resolution-body> <attestation><attestation-group><role>Clerk of the House of Representatives.</role></attestation-group><attestation-group><role>Secretary of the Senate.</role></attestation-group></attestation> </resolution>
