<bill session="113" type="h" number="5507" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reducing Disparities Using Care Models and Education Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for a study by the Institute of Medicine on health disparities, to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to develop guidelines on reducing health disparities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400309"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-17">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-17">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="s" number="2841"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/17/2014--Introduced.
Reducing Disparities Using Care Models and Education Act of 2014 - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to contract with the Institute of Medicine to study: (1) health disparities; (2) existing programs and policies intended to reduce disparities; and (3) priorities for, and expansion of, programs targeting disparities.

Requires the Secretary to develop guidelines for entities to develop and implement programs to reduce health disparities. Directs the Secretary to incorporate these guidelines into HHS activities.

Authorizes the Secretary to award grants for programs to reduce health disparities.

Requires the Innovation Center of the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services (CMS) to test a payment and service delivery model that includes incentives for reducing health disparities.</summary>
</bill>
