<bill session="113" type="s" number="1937" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-04-09">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-04-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-01-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Elections Preparedness Requires Early Planning (Elections PREP) Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Elections Preparedness Requires Early Planning (Elections PREP) Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to require States to develop contingency plans to address unexpected emergencies or natural disasters that may threaten to disrupt the administration of an election for Federal office, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300087"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-01-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-04-09" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Rules and Administration. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-04-10">
      <text>Committee on Rules and Administration. Reported by Senator Schumer without amendment. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-04-10" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="356">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 356.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s3446"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>4/10/2014--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Elections Preparedness Requires Early Planning (Elections PREP) Act - Amends the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to require each state to develop contingency plans to address unexpected emergencies or natural disasters that may threaten to disrupt the administration of an election for federal office.

Requires a plan to contain: (1) alternative ways to notify the public of changes in election procedures; and (2) plans to address disruptions at every step of the voting process, including early voting.</summary>
</bill>
