<bill session="113" type="h" number="5325" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Manufacturing Workforce Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide tax incentives to meet the needs of the American manufacturing workforce, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412517"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400616" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412533" joined="2014-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412535" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412566" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400352" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412579" joined="2014-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Training" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Adult education and literacy"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Industrial policy and productivity"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2014--Introduced.
American Manufacturing Workforce Act of 2014 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow, through 2020, tax credits for: (1)&#160;up to $1,000 of the&#160;expenses for tuition, fees, and course materials paid or incurred&#160;for the training of a worker to develop or improve skills for a manufacturing position; and (2) up to 20% of the first $1,000 of education or training expenses for manufacturing under the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 or a curriculum approved by the Employment and Training Administration for individuals employed in manufacturing positions.

Establishes the Presidential Award for Business Leadership in Manufacturing Job Training to recognize companies and other organizations for extraordinary efforts in assisting their employees and members to develop or improve manufacturing skills and training and increase productivity.

Directs the Secretary of Labor to periodically collect and disseminate best practices for manufacturing job training.</summary>
</bill>
