<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 S2446 IS: Truth in Obamacare Accounting Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2014-06-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 2446</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20140605">June 5, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S345">Mr. Johnson of Wisconsin</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBU00">Committee on the Budget</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To require the Congressional Budget Office to annually report changes in direct spending and
			 revenue associated with the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
			<text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the
		  <quote><short-title>Truth in Obamacare Accounting Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="id0EE841ADEC3E4DF5A71D09ED254A1ACF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Congressional Budget Office reporting on the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congressional Budget Office shall include in each annual report on the budget and economic
			 outlook, and each revision of such a report, prepared under section 202(e)
			 of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/602">2 U.S.C. 602(e)</external-xref>), information on
			 the net effect that the enactment and implementation of the Patient
			 Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/148">Public Law 111–148</external-xref>) and the Health
			 Care and Education Reconciliation Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/152">Public Law 111–152</external-xref>) had on
			 direct spending and revenue, including the net impact that such enactment
			 and implementation had on deficit, both on-budget and off-budget.  Such
			 information shall be disclosed in a manner similar to that provided for in
			 table 2 of the Congressional Budget Office’s March 20, 2010, estimate of
			 the budgetary effects of the Health Care and Education Reconciliation Act
			 of 2010 and the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


