<bill session="113" type="sr" number="385" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-03-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-03-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-03-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution expressing the Sense of the Senate regarding the use of electronic devices on the floor of the Senate.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412247"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2014-03-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-03-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1662" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/13/2014--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of the Senate that:

 certain uses of electronic devices by Senators on the floor of the Senate are necessary and proper in the conduct of official Senate business, would not distract, interrupt, or inconvenience the business of Members of the Senate, and should therefore be permissible; necessary and proper uses of electronic devices on the floor of the Senate do not include: (1) transmitting sound for any purpose other than through earphones or in such a manner as would not disturb proceedings on the floor of the Senate for the purpose of assisting a person with a disability; (2) using telephones or other devices for voice communication; or (3) using desktop computers, laptop computers, or other large devices; the Senate Committee on Rules and Administration should consider an amendment to the Rules for the Regulation of the Senate Wing consistent with the principles stated above; and any amendment to the Rules should take into account possible future changes in technology.</summary>
</bill>
