<bill session="113" type="h" number="5103" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Chinese Communist Economic Espionage Sanctions Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To impose sanctions on Chinese state-owned enterprises and any person who is a member of the board of directors, an executive officer, or a senior official of a Chinese state-owned enterprise for benefitting from cyber and economic espionage against the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400343"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400352" joined="2014-07-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-14">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-14">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-14">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Border Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Foreign property"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Trade secrets and economic espionage"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/14/2014--Introduced.
Chinese Communist Economic Espionage Sanctions Act - Expresses the sense of Congress that the Chinese Communist Party and the government of China should be condemned for conducting cyber and economic espionage against the United States.

Directs the President to prohibit transactions in property and property interests of a covered Chinese state-owned enterprise or a person who is a member of the board of directors, an executive officer, or a senior official of a covered Chinese state-owned enterprise if such property and property interests are in the United States, come within the United States, or are within the possession or control of a U.S. person.

Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to require each financial institution that is a U.S. person and has within its possession or control such assets that are in the United States to certify to the Secretary that the financial institution has frozen these assets.

Makes an alien who is a member of the board of directors, an executive officer, or a senior official of a covered Chinese state-owned enterprise ineligible for U.S. admission.</summary>
</bill>
