<bill session="113" type="s" number="2842" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Caregiver Corps Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to establish a Caregiver Corps program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412246"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Adult day care"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Allied health services"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/17/2014--Introduced.
Caregiver Corps Act of 2014 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to contract with a nonprofit to develop an online toolkit and guidance providing for the establishment and implementation of Caregiver Corps volunteer programs in which volunteers provide assistance to individuals who are in need of assistance to remain in the community and are either aged 65 or older, or eligible for Social Security Disability Insurance.

Requires Caregiver Corps volunteers to provide assistance by giving an informal caregiver respite from caregiving duties, serving as a companion, or providing other assistance for which the volunteer is qualified. Prohibits volunteers from providing personal care or administering prescription medications.

Allows the Secretary to award grants for the operation of local Corps programs.

Requires local Corps programs to screen, train, and supervise volunteers.

Directs local Corps programs to appropriately recognize volunteers. Allows programs to provide compensation to volunteers.</summary>
</bill>
