<bill session="113" type="s" number="2200" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-04-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-04-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Consumer Debit Card Protection Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide debit card holders with consumer protections equivalent to those available to credit card holders, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412321"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400222" joined="2014-04-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/2/2014--Introduced.
Consumer Debit Card Protection Act of 2014 - Amends the Electronic Fund Transfer Act to require a financial institution to recredit a consumer's account within 7 days (currently, 10 days) after receiving notice of an error in the manner of an electronic debit transaction.

Limits consumer liability for unauthorized use of a debit card to the following circumstances:

 the debit card is an accepted debit card; the liability does not exceed $50; the issuer has given the consumer a description of a means by which the issuer may be notified of loss or theft of the card; the unauthorized use occurs before the issuer has been notified of that fact or that an unauthorized use may occur as the result of loss, theft, or otherwise; and the issuer has provided a method whereby the card user can be identified as the person authorized to use the card. States that an issuer has been notified when reasonable steps have been taken to give the issuer the pertinent information, whether or not any particular officer, employee, or agent of the issuer does in fact receive that information.

Places the the burden of proof upon the issuer to show that: (1) the use was authorized, or (2) the conditions of liability for the unauthorized use of a debit card have been met.</summary>
</bill>
