<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 S1755 IS: Dignified Interment of Our Veterans Act of 2013</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2013-11-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>113th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1755</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20131121">November 21, 2013</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S351">Mr. Toomey</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to conduct a study on matters relating to the claiming and interring of unclaimed remains of veterans, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="idACEC10841B6D4704A6606B453CE6C74F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Dignified Interment of Our Veterans Act of 2013</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id3C770AA21C4E4BCA98124BFEC8310BC4" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Department of Veterans Affairs study on matters relating to claiming and interring unclaimed remains of veterans</header><subsection id="id84160B9ABE3E4A8F858C2C9FD08CF1ED"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study and report required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall—</text><paragraph id="id2DF3E1E445D74748BFFC8FD2A12275AC"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">complete a study on matters relating to the identification, claiming, and interring of unclaimed remains of veterans; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4980930C2DB346D5B1E9946288B9DBC7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit to Congress a report on the findings of the Secretary with respect to the study required under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idDA25F333DB114A92A983F1A1B2D18B73"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Matters studied</header><text>The matters studied under subsection (a)(1) shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="idcce24fc4acd34e93bba001fbc6dec2e9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Determining the scope of issues relating to unclaimed remains of veterans, including an estimate of the number of unclaimed remains of veterans on the day before the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1A51F79732744778B3B2711CDE4B146F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Assessing the effectiveness of the procedures of the Department of Veterans Affairs for claiming and interring unclaimed remains of veterans.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id62EA988062BB40DFB16C3DEBEE1DA286"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Identifying and assessing State and local laws that affect the ability of the Secretary to identify, claim, and inter unclaimed remains of veterans.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id26DE397652BF4B978B7FF6F2B3697D4E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Developing recommendations for such legislative or administrative action as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


