<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HEF6FD55A038A4606B6FEA3329957C3F5" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HR 5868 IH: To provide for a study by the Transportation Research Board of the National Academies on the impact of diverting certain freight rail traffic to avoid urban areas, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2014-12-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 5868</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20141211">December 11, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To provide for a study by the Transportation Research Board of the National Academies on the impact
			 of diverting certain freight rail traffic to avoid urban areas, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H489FE13395FD4517BA20819A76DCC14B" style="OLC">
		<section id="HDEB530F59F41452BBB572B49C6200B90" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
			<paragraph id="H9E3B7770AE89431084014C0FB73BD929"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The volume of crude oil transported by rail has significantly increased from—</text>
				<subparagraph id="HFB4B8BF8DA784960A0CCE87DF0506D59"><enum>(A)</enum><text>21,000 barrels a day in 2009 to 1.1 million barrels a day in 2014; and</text>
				</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H763DA99AD99D4F27BECD5C593621BDC5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>9,500 rail-carloads in 2008 to 415,000 rail-carloads in 2013.</text>
				</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H53BFAA58D7AD44969EF602F887D7F4A0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>At any given time, more than 2.5 million gallons of crude oil is being transported across the
			 country to refineries totaling a distance of more than 1000 miles.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H7357CFCB472E43CA9AFB104C9D39DCDA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>More oil was spilled in 2013 from freight traffic than in the previous 4 decades combined.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H657369AD7DA240AC8F794DCB6EF1FD0A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Increased spills result in catastrophes that have significantly and adversely impacted the
			 following communities:</text>
				<subparagraph id="H63C8CB695EFB4ECDB66AD2399961F901"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Minnesota, in March 2013, when 30,000 gallons of crude oil spilled because of derailed cars.</text>
				</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7FE2C209F69B4EF58A49D00828C9F646"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Lac-Mégantic, Canada, in July 2013, when 1.6 million gallons of crude oil spilled, igniting a fire
			 and exploding, killing 47 people and forcing 2,000 people from their
			 homes.</text>
				</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAF94F64798774C1393CA7ADB8721B9BD"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">North Dakota, in December 2013, when 400,000 million gallons of crude oil spilled, igniting a fire
			 and forcing 65 percent of residents from their homes.</text>
				</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6FCD876663644D2F8B8D97347DBBF682"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Virginia, in March 2014, when thousands of gallons of oil spilled, contaminating the James River
			 and requiring the evacuation of 78,000 people in the downtown of the city.</text>
				</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H88FC9CDD62884CE39FCCF7B3DC8E8E8A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Hazardous materials must be properly classified for transportation, according to requirements from
			 the Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration (PHMSA).</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H0240F5A00B16449E9DA659F73AA645ED"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Crude oil is categorized as a Class 3 flammable liquid in either Packing Group (PG) I or II.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HF5368AA46D4D40339A198C451C8A5D44"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Due to serious mislabeling practices, the Department of Transportation’s Emergency Order (Docket
			 No. DOT–OST–2014–0025) from February 2014 has forbidden the labeling of
			 crude oil as PG III for transport and handling until further notice;
			 shipments must be labeled as either PG I (most serious hazard) or PG II
			 (moderate hazard) for proper handling and transport of crude oil.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HC9037263458A4DD0B8F4AD3ADF379B9E"><enum>(8)</enum><text>PHMSA has found that crude oil from the Bakken region (in North Dakota, Montana, and Canada) is <quote>more volatile than most other types of crude,</quote> and subsequently, more flammable.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HAC28568429504ADB872416863920CA5D"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The samples that PHMSA tested from the Bakken region <quote>displayed characteristics consistent with those of a Class 3 flammable liquid, PG I or II, with a
			 predominance to PG I, the most dangerous class of Class 3 flammable
			 liquids</quote>.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HD12E8A783BB14293A3280FE39DE5B372"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The oil industry group North Dakota Petroleum Council has recommended that Bakken crude oil be
			 labeled as PG I hazardous materials for transportation.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HC426D96E80C644CE91CE1684CD64E8E3"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Oil from the Bakken region accounts for about 12 percent of total domestic production.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H12A8F749E90042A1A96D1B7B5210B9AA"><enum>(12)</enum><text>The National Transportation Safety Board (NTSB) has expressed concern <quote>that major loss of life, property damage and environmental consequences can occur when large
			 volumes of crude oil or other flammable liquids are transported on a
			 single train involved in an accident</quote>.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H3DDA4B0A48144B20AA75550007309C1A"><enum>(13)</enum><text>The NTSB has recommended that routes transporting hazardous materials present the fewest overall
			 safety and security risks by avoiding populated areas.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H551CC1582DF44BB7BB8A217EDA4AD9B1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Study on impact of diverting certain freight rail to avoid urban areas</header>
			<subsection id="H280D5CAB844C4CB0969B726F5A133F3A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 3 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation
			 shall make appropriate arrangements with the Transportation Research Board
			 of the National Academies under which the Board shall conduct a study on
			 the cost and impact of rerouting freight rail traffic containing hazardous
			 material to avoid transportation of such hazardous material through urban
			 areas.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H7359D5202F6A480DA2D9D028DAF5795D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents of study</header><text>The study described under subsection (a) shall include—</text>
				<paragraph id="HFC2282DE5F184F5283697399962407A4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the benefits of rerouting freight rail traffic containing hazardous material to alternate existing
			 railroad routes that avoid urban areas, including benefits to the health
			 and safety of the individuals living in such urban areas;</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H30C94B07F55341AA916D05AE0079401F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the benefits of construction of alternative railroad routes that avoid urban areas for
			 transportation of freight rail containing hazardous material;</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H9D0D5F143C1143D0BD9540DA0698D6FB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the logistical feasibility of the actions described in paragraphs (1) and (2); and</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HA73EBD94507C48129AF824CA0FA74915"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the costs of taking the actions described in paragraphs (1) and (2).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H134625D1ED124FCC8BD8A8B0CCAD5489"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In entering into an arrangement under subsection (a), the Secretary shall request that the Board
			 transmit to Congress a report on the results of the study not later than
			 21 months after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HA6BFADD725124A21844BA27E96D0358B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header>
				<paragraph commented="no" id="H031CB75A86D244ECAE3E10D5C1363DCA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Hazardous material</header><text>The term <quote>hazardous material</quote> has the meaning given such term in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/5102">section 5102</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H1117986080B04172AB06FC09B311E1A8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Urban area</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>urban area</quote> means an urban area, as designated by the Bureau of the Census, with a population of greater than
			 30,000.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7298CF7703EE4077B8D61FB461CD5F8D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated $850,000 to carry out this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


