<bill session="113" type="hr" number="489" updated="2015-09-01T10:18:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-02-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-02-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-02-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of Congress regarding the need to facilitate and promote a robust response to the looming global crisis of Alzheimer's and other forms of dementia.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400380"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2014-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="2014-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400052" joined="2014-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412571" joined="2014-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2014-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400130" joined="2014-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412382" joined="2014-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412530" joined="2014-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412444" joined="2014-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400195" joined="2014-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400219" joined="2014-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2014-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412552" joined="2014-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2014-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2014-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412308" joined="2014-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400326" joined="2014-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412489" joined="2014-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412186" joined="2014-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400422" joined="2014-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="2014-06-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-02-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-25">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-25">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/25/2014--Introduced.
States that it should be the policy of the U.S. government to encourage and facilitate the following efforts concerning Alzheimer's disease and other forms of dementia:

 entry by the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) into negotiations with the World Health Organization to develop a Global Alzheimer's and Dementia Action Plan; involvement of all other nations that have adopted national Alzheimer's and/or dementia plans or strategies; development of the foundation for a Global Alzheimer's Fund that would provide resources to support implementation of specific strategies of the Global Plan and assignment of a high-level person to lead and coordinate initiatives; investigation by the G8 nations of systems to monitor and provide care to persons with Alzheimer's and other forms of dementia in developing countries to help build care delivery capacity; investigation by the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) of the foreign aid implications of Alzheimer's and other forms of dementia and inform Congress of the need for possible changes to health care-related foreign assistance; and encouragement and facilitation of partnerships with the private sector, such as the current partnership between the National Institutes of Health (NIH) and 10 pharmaceutical companies to identify new approaches to treat Alzheimer's and other medical conditions.</summary>
</bill>
