<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Enrolled-Bill" dms-id="H8258F7F40A6C42219622D28FE2FA0D3D" public-private="public" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title> HR 1092 ENR: To designate the air route traffic control center located in Nashua, New Hampshire, as the “Patricia Clark Boston Air Route Traffic Control Center”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">IB</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">One Hundred Thirteenth Congress of the United States of America</congress> <session display="yes">At the First Session</session><enrolled-dateline>Begun and held at the City of Washington on Thursday, the third day of January, two thousand and thirteen</enrolled-dateline> 
<legis-num>H. R. 1092</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no"></current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To designate the air route traffic control center located in Nashua, New Hampshire, as the <quote>Patricia Clark Boston Air Route Traffic Control Center</quote>.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H2BDEBC15811C424BBD0F4E2C21350F18" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H3D1D650D513243E8AD2C58799488E1BF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Designation of Patricia Clark Boston Air Route Traffic Control Center</header> 
<subsection id="HA94EFD43AF82463B8C67A3654F29DF71"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The air route traffic control center located in Nashua, New Hampshire, and any successor air route traffic control center at that location, shall be known and designated as the <quote>Patricia Clark Boston Air Route Traffic Control Center</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1BC76F4863C243589809EC9F09BD57E9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>References</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any reference in a law, map, regulation, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the air route traffic control center referred to in subsection (a) shall be deemed to be a reference to the <quote>Patricia Clark Boston Air Route Traffic Control Center</quote>.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><role>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</role></attestation-group><attestation-group><role>Vice President of the United States and President of the Senate.</role></attestation-group></attestation>
</bill> 


