<bill session="113" type="h" number="4259" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-03-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-03-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-03-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">E-BOOK Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Electronic Books Opening Opportunity for Knowledge Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to lower the cost of college education by establishing pilot programs to expand student access to digital course materials.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412505"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412571" joined="2014-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412454" joined="2014-03-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-03-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Training" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/14/2014--Introduced.
Electronic Books Opening Opportunity for Knowledge Act of 2014 or the E-BOOK Act of 2014 - Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to authorize the Secretary of Education to award competitive grants to up to 10 institutions of higher education (IHEs) to conduct pilot programs to reduce the cost of attendance for undergraduate students by expanding their access to digital course materials.

Directs the Secretary to give a preference to applications that demonstrate a commitment to serving disadvantaged students.

Requires grantees to make digital course materials available to undergraduate students in at least two different academic departments.

Allows the IHEs to use the grant funds to:

 purchase and maintain the electronic equipment or software their pilot programs need; purchase and maintain the digital and online content that instructors or students will use; hire staff to administer their pilot programs, with priority given to hiring enrolled undergraduate students; build or acquire extra storage space for pilot program equipment; and revise and adapt academic curricula as needed to implement their pilot programs.</summary>
</bill>
