<bill session="113" type="s" number="2400" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-05-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Field EMS Innovation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for improvement of field emergency medical services, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412330"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300030" joined="2014-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2014-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412471" joined="2014-06-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="809"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/22/2014--Introduced.
Field EMS Innovation Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to designate the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) as the primary federal agency for emergency medical services (EMS) and trauma care. Establishes the Office of Emergency Medical Services and Trauma (or Office of EMS and Trauma) within HHS. Gives the Office responsibilities related to emergency medical services and authorizes the Secretary of HHS to delegate additional responsibilities related to EMS.

Requires the Director of the Office to: (1) implement a national EMS strategy; (2) establish the EQUIP grant program to promote excellence, quality, universal access, innovation, and preparedness in field EMS; and (3) establish the SPIA grant program to improve EMS system performance, integration, and accountability, to ensure preparedness, to enhance oversight and data collection, and to promote standardization of certifications.

Defines "field EMS" to mean emergency medical services provided to patients (including transport by ground, air, or otherwise) prior to or outside a medical facility or other clinical setting.

Requires the Director to improve medical oversight of field EMS, including by: (1) promoting the development and adoption of national guidelines for medical oversight, and (2) convening a Field EMS Medical Oversight Advisory Committee.

Directs the Comptroller General (GAO) to study issues related to emergency medical care in field EMS.

Authorizes the Administrator of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration (NHTSA) to maintain, improve, and expand the National EMS Information System.

Sets forth reporting requirements relating to data collection and electronic health records.

Declares that the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (HIPAA) shall not be construed to prohibit certain exchanges of information between field EMS practitioners, hospital personnel, state EMS offices, and the National EMS Database. Requires the Secretary to establish guidelines for the exchange of information between field EMS practitioners and hospital personnel.

Authorizes the Director of the Office to make grants for the development, availability, and dissemination of field EMS education programs and courses that improve the quality and capability of field EMS personnel.

Requires the Director to conduct or support demonstrations projects relating to alternative dispositions of field EMS patients.

Amends title XI (General Provisions, Peer Review, and Administrative Simplification) of the Social Security Act to include field EMS as a model for testing by the Center for Medicare and Medicaid Innovation.

Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary to conduct research and evaluation relating to field EMS through the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ) and the Center for Medicare and Medicaid Innovation.

Requires the Director of AHRQ to establish a Field EMS Evidence-Based Practice Center.

Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) establish the Emergency Medical Services Trust Fund, and (2) allow taxpayers to designate a portion of any income tax overpayment and make additional contributions to finance such Fund.</summary>
</bill>
