<bill session="113" type="h" number="3341" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-10-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-10-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">VALUE Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Verifying Agencies' Lasting Use of Expenditures Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 5, United States Code, to provide for the consideration of costs and benefits during rule making and for the review of existing rules.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400221"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU05" subcommittee="Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/24/2013--Introduced.
Verifying Agencies' Lasting Use of Expenditures Act of 2013 or the VALUE Act of 2013 - Requires a federal agency, when making a rule, to: (1) clearly identify the nature and source of the problem that the proposed rule is designed to address, (2) assess the costs and benefits of the rule, and (3) identify and assess available alternatives to the rule.

Allows a rule that does not meet such requirements to take effect temporarily only if the President makes a determination by executive order that such rule is: (1) necessary because of an imminent threat to health or safety or other emergency, (2) necessary for the enforcement of criminal laws, (3) necessary for national security, or (4) issued to implement an international trade agreement.

Requires the Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB), every five years, to: (1) review the rules of each agency; (2) assess the costs and benefits of such rules to determine whether any such rules are outmoded, ineffective, insufficient, or excessively burdensome; and (3) report to the head of each agency on such review.</summary>
</bill>
