<bill session="113" type="s" number="1911" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-01-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-01-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-01-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SKILLS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Supporting Knowledge and Investing in Lifelong Skills Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reform and strengthen the workforce investment system of the Nation to put Americans back to work and make the United States more competitive in the 21st century, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412471"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2014-01-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2014-01-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2014-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412322" joined="2014-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2014-04-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-01-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="803"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2038"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Adult education and literacy"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Labor-management relations"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Migrant, seasonal, agricultural labor"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Oceania"/>
    <term name="Palau"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Temporary and part-time employment"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
    <term name="Youth employment and child labor"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/9/2014--Introduced.
SKILLS Act or Supporting Knowledge and Investing in Lifelong Skills Act - Amends the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 (WIA) to revise requirements and reauthorize appropriations for: (1) WIA title I, workforce investment systems for job training and employment services; and (2) WIA title II, adult education and family literacy education programs.

Revises requirements to: (1) eliminate representatives of labor organizations from state workforce investment boards, and (2) specify that representatives of business on a board represent large and small businesses each of which has immediate and long-term employment opportunities in an in-demand industry or other occupation important to the state economy.

Requires a state board to assist the state governor by developing: (1) policies and programs that support a comprehensive statewide workforce development system, and (2) a statewide workforce and labor market information system.

Revises requirements for: (1) a state workforce development plan; (2) local workforce investment areas, boards, and plans; (3) one-stop delivery systems; and (4) the allotment of federal funds among states for employment and training activities.

Eliminates specific funding for adult and dislocated worker employment and training. Specifies state use of federal funds to set up a Workforce Investment Fund.

Revises requirements for: (1) within state allocations of funds; and (2) the use of funds for state and local employment and training activities, including statewide rapid response, individuals with barriers to employment grants, and adults with barriers to employment grants.

Converts the national emergency grants program into a national dislocated worker grants program. Authorizes the Secretary of Labor to award national dislocated worker grants to spouses of active duty members of the Armed Forces or full-time duty members of the National Guard (or members who recently separated from such duties) and are in need of employment and training assistance to obtain or retain employment.

Requires the Employment and Training Administration of the Department of Labor to be the principal agency to administer WIA title I workforce investment systems for job training and employment services.

 Prohibits the use of funds for lobbying (with specified exceptions) and political activities (including voter registration activities).

Adult Education and Family Literacy Education Act - Revises requirements for the state unified plan for adult education and literacy programs.

Amends the Wagner-Peyser Act to eliminate the U.S. Employment Service. Replaces the nationwide employment statistics system, which the Secretary is required to oversee, with a nationwide workforce and labor market information system.

Repeals the Youth Conservation Corps Act of 1970 and specified other laws.

Amends the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 to require employment and training services to eligible members of households participating in the supplemental nutrition assistance program be provided through the statewide workforce development system, including the one-stop delivery system.

Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act (INA) with respect to employment and training services for refugees, and the Second Chance Act of 2007 as well as the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 with respect to such services through the statewide workforce investment system for federal, state, and local prisoner reentry programs.

Amends the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (RA73) to: (1) redesignate the Commissioner of the Rehabilitation Services Administration the Director; and (2) require an eligible state to use a certain percentage of the federal share of the cost of vocational rehabilitation services to award grants to pay for the federal share of the cost of carrying out collaborative programs, create practical job and career readiness and training programs, and provide job placements and career advancement.

Repeals the authority of the Commissioner of the Rehabilitation Services Administration in the Department of Education to make grants and contracts for: (1) vocational rehabilitation services to individuals with disabilities who are migrant or seasonal farmworkers, (2) recreational programs for such individuals, and (3) in-service training of vocational rehabilitation personnel.

Repeals title VI (Employment Opportunities for Individuals with Disabilities) of the RA73.

Revises requirements and reauthorizes appropriations for vocational rehabilitation services under the RA73.

Directs the Comptroller General (GAO) to report to Congress regarding: (1) whether, before receiving workforce investment system training services, adults and dislocated workers have first exhausted funds received through the Federal Pell Grant program under title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965; and (2) a determination of the amount of administrative costs savings at the federal and state levels as a result of workforce investment system programs repealed or consolidated under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
