<bill session="113" type="h" number="5682" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-11-14T12:53:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-11-14T12:53:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-11-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To approve the Keystone XL Pipeline.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412269"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412469" joined="2014-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412465" joined="2014-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400279" joined="2014-11-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-11-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, and Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-12">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-12">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-12">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-12T19:27:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 748 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 5682 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-13T17:46:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 748 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-13T17:52:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 748.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7965-7972" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-13T17:52:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 5682 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-13T17:52:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 5682.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-13T18:50:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7971" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-13T18:51:00-05:00">
      <text>Mrs. Capps moved to recommit with instructions to the Committee on Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7971-7972" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7971" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-13T18:52:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Capps motion to recommit with instructions, pending reservation of a point order. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment requiring TransCanada, the developer of the Keystone XL pipeline, to certify to the President that the oil or other products derived from Canadian oil sands that are transported through the pipeline will be treated similarly to conventional crude oil for the purposes of determining contributions that fund the Oil Spill Liability Trust Fund. Companies that transport oil are required to pay 8-cents per barrel into the trust fund that is used by the federal government to respond to oil spills. Oil sands crude is currently exempt from making such contributions. Subsequently, the reservation of a point of order was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-13T18:58:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7972" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-13T18:58:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - Pursuant to clause 1(c) of rule 19, further proceedings on the motion to recommit with instructions to H.R. 5682 were postponed until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-14T12:13:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7965" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-14T12:43:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 192 - 224 (Roll no. 518).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="519" datetime="2014-11-14T12:53:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 252 - 161, 1 Present (Roll no. 519).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 11/13/14 H7965" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-11-14T12:53:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-17">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="113" type="hr" number="748"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="s" number="2280"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2314"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2554"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2554"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Federal appellate courts"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Nebraska"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/14/2014--Passed House without amendment.
Authorizes TransCanada Keystone Pipeline, L.P. to construct, connect, operate, and maintain the pipeline and cross-border facilities specified in an application filed by TransCanada Corporation to the Department of State on May 4, 2012.

Deems the Final Supplemental Environmental Impact Statement regarding the pipeline issued by the Secretary of State in January 2014 to fully satisfy the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969, and any law that requires federal agency consultation or review, including the Endangered Species Act of 1973.

Declares any applicable federal permit or authorization issued before enactment of this Act to remain in effect.

Restricts any legal challenges regarding a federal agency action and such facilities to judicial review on direct appeal to the U.S. Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit.

Declares that this Act does not alter any federal, state, or local process or condition in effect on the date of enactment of this Act that is necessary to secure access from an owner of private property to construct the pipeline and cross-border facilities.</summary>
</bill>
