<bill session="113" type="sr" number="251" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-09-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-09-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-09-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate that the United States Preventive Services Task Force should reevaluate its recommendations against prostate-specific antigen-based screening for prostate cancer for men in all age groups in consultation with appropriate specialists.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300088"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2013-11-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2013-11-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2013-11-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2013-10-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-09-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6684-6685" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/23/2013--Introduced.
Calls for the U.S. Preventive Services Task Force to: (1) reevaluate its recommendation against prostate-specific antigen-based screening for prostate cancer for men in all age groups, (2) seriously engage and consult with specialists as it reevaluates its recommendation, and (3) identify areas for additional research and evaluation of methods of treatment of, and screening procedures for, prostate cancer.

Expresses the sense of the Senate that: (1) prostate cancer screening decisions should be made by each individual patient and his physician, taking into account the patient's risk factors and desire for treatment; and (2) steps should be taken to raise awareness of, and increase public knowledge about, prostate cancer, the benefits of early detection, and the appropriateness of screening tests.</summary>
</bill>
