<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="HD273F35CF5014ECA9184C423CACDC13F" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HRES 699 IH: Welcoming African leaders to the first United States–Africa Leaders’ Summit and African trade ministers to the 13th Forum of the African Growth and Opportunity Act (AGOA).</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2014-07-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 699</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20140731">July 31, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C000071">Mr. Camp</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000263">Mr. Levin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000053">Mr. Rangel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000181">Mr. Nunes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000487">Mr. Royce</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000179">Mr. Engel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001270">Ms. Bass</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000911">Ms. Brown of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001251">Mr. Butterfield</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson of Indiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000380">Mrs. Christensen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001049">Mr. Clay</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000537">Mr. Clyburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000984">Mr. Cummings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Danny K. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000290">Ms. Edwards</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000043">Mr. Fattah</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000455">Ms. Fudge</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Al Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001066">Mr. Horsford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000294">Mr. Jeffries</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000126">Ms. Eddie Bernice Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000287">Mr. Lewis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000588">Mr. Richmond</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001157">Mr. David Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000187">Ms. Waters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000064">Mr. Young of Indiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001255">Mr. Boustany</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M000404">Mr. McDermott</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Welcoming African leaders to the first United States–Africa Leaders’ Summit and African trade
			 ministers to the 13th Forum of the African Growth and Opportunity Act
			 (AGOA).</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas><text>Whereas the United States Congress enacted the African Growth and Opportunity Act (AGOA) in 2000,
			 with broad bipartisan support and with a view to expanding growth and
			 opportunity in Africa;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas in the original AGOA legislation, Congress encouraged the establishment of more regular
			 high-level dialogues, including regular meetings by the President with his
			 African counterparts;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the people of Africa share the hopes and aspirations of the people of the United States for
			 peace and prosperity, and are both committed to strengthening economic
			 relations;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas it is in the national interest of the United States to support the reduction of poverty in
			 the continent of Africa;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas greater opportunities for mutually beneficial trade and investments promote economic
			 growth, development, poverty reduction, democracy, the rule of law, and
			 stability;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas good governance, including respecting constitutional term limits, human rights, and
			 ensuring that civil society organizations are able to function freely
			 contribute to enduring economic and social development in Africa;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the countries in Africa are important economic partners of the United States;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Africa has today 6 of the 10 fastest growing economies in the world, over 1,000,000,000
			 people, 60 percent of the world’s uncultivated agricultural land, and
			 expanding democracies;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Africa is rich through the youth of its population, enjoying a demographic advantage over
			 all other regions of the world, and is likely to replace China as the
			 biggest contributor to the global workforce by 2050;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas it is in the economic interest of the United States to engage and compete in emerging
			 African markets, boost United States-Africa trade and investment, support
			 greater capacity building for Africa, and invest in Africa’s youth and
			 leadership development;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas exports from sub-Saharan Africa to the United States under AGOA have increased over
			 three-fold from $7,600,000,000 in 2001 to $24,800,000,000 in 2013;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas United States exports to sub-Saharan Africa have increased from $6,900,000,000 to
			 $23,900,000,000 and United States investment in sub-Saharan Africa has
			 increased six-fold;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas per capita income in sub-Saharan Africa has more than tripled to $1,624 annually since
			 Congress first passed AGOA, yet nearly half the population in sub-Saharan
			 Africa lives in poverty;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas timely renewal of AGOA, which expires September 30, 2015, is critical to the maintenance
			 and promotion of investment opportunities in the region;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas regional integration should be strengthened to improve the full utilization of AGOA
			 preferences, and elimination of barriers to trade and investment in
			 Africa, such as high tariffs, forced localization requirements,
			 restrictions on investment, and customs barriers, among others, will
			 strengthen and improve regional and global integration;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas it remains the goal of United States policy to support the diversification of sub-Saharan
			 exports in terms of products and countries that utilize AGOA;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the members of the World Trade Organization (WTO) adopted several important Decisions and
			 Declarations in Bali, Indonesia, in December 2013, including the Agreement
			 on Trade Facilitation and specific results on agriculture and development,
			 with the protocol of amendment for the Agreement on Trade Facilitation to
			 be adopted on July 31, 2014;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas full implementation of the Agreement on Trade Facilitation will help to address supply-side
			 constraints in Africa, promote regional integration on the continent, and
			 facilitate integration into global supply chains;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the House of Representatives introduced on June 27, 2013, and passed on May 8, 2014, the
			 Electrify Africa Act, to make it a national policy of the United States to
			 promote the electrification of Sub-Saharan Africa to more than double the
			 number of people with access to power in order to improve health and
			 education outcomes and stimulate economic opportunity; and</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on June 30, 2013, in Cape Town, South Africa, President Barack Obama announced the Power
			 Africa Initiative, to significantly increase the number of people with
			 access to power in Sub-Saharan Africa: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body id="HCCD79395EDAB49E59A1697A576538388" style="traditional">
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H31451A8B5E9848909278CA8FFA7DD92B" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the House of Representatives—</text>
			<paragraph id="H3713EC076A19465D937A26F244E3DBE8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">welcomes African leaders to the first United States–Africa Leaders’ Summit in Washington, DC;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H3E3290FF3C864790A226234C064DF371"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">welcomes African trade ministers to the 13th African Growth and Opportunity Act (AGOA) Forum;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HA6F2A674E6B44FDC938E3104BCF16B39"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recognizes the significant progress and hope that modern Africa represents today in global affairs
			 and economic advancement with its booming demographics, increasing
			 modernization, dynamic youth, and vast resources;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H33DAD713A4844E52927742320A7F18EC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>acknowledges the vast opportunities to boost cultural, trade, and economic relations and
			 partnerships between the United States and Africa;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HD79405FE5BE94149A136E1DCCD96C3DB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>recognizes the importance of renewing the AGOA program well before its expiration in September
			 2015;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H838713108CFA48F48348468C46CD73A4"><enum>(6)</enum><text>supports studying potential changes to the program to improve its effectiveness and utilization and
			 exploring how Africa can address barriers to become more attractive to
			 trade and investment within Africa as well as globally;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H6A776A78CC744D24BB6E47DE127135D2"><enum>(7)</enum><text>encourages the prompt and full implementation of the World Trade Organization (WTO) Trade
			 Facilitation Agreement as one important way to address supply-side
			 barriers and encourage greater trade and investment in Africa; and</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HFC1768D978584C2EABB25DC8DC2A2A99"><enum>(8)</enum><text>welcomes that the African Leaders at the African Union Summit on June 27, 2014, reaffirmed their
			 commitments to all the decisions the Ministers took in Bali, including
			 emphasizing that assistance and support for capacity building should be
			 provided as envisaged in the Agreement on Trade Facilitation, and that the
			 Agreement should be implemented in line with the decision Trade Ministers
			 took in Bali, which provides that a protocol be adopted by July 31, 2014,
			 and definitive entry into force by July 31, 2015.</text>
			</paragraph></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


