<bill session="113" type="h" number="5422" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Litigation Oversight Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 to require the EEOC to approve commencing or intervening in certain litigation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412213"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412550" joined="2014-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412426" joined="2014-09-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED10" subcommittee="Workforce Protections" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (EEOC)"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/9/2014--Introduced.
Litigation Oversight Act of 2014 - Amends the Civil Rights Act of 1964 to require the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (EEOC) to approve or disapprove by majority vote whether the EEOC shall commence or intervene in litigation involving: (1) multiple plaintiffs, or (2) an allegation of systemic discrimination or a pattern or practice of discrimination. Provides EEOC members with the power to require the EEOC to approve or disapprove by majority vote whether the EEOC commences or intervenes in any litigation.

Requires the EEOC, within 30 days after commencing or intervening in litigation pursuant to such an approval, to post on its public website: (1) information regarding the case, including the allegations and causes of action; and (2) each Commissioner's vote on commencing or intervening in the litigation.</summary>
</bill>
