<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="HC479C9120A404BED9CE04513AD7B2B3A" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Engrossed-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HRES 17 EH: Electing Members to certain standing committees of the House of Representatives</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2013-01-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress display="no">113th CONGRESS</congress> 
<session display="no">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 17</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="yes">In the House of Representatives, U. S.,</current-chamber>
<action>
<action-date date="20130104">January 4, 2013</action-date>
</action> 
<legis-type display="yes">RESOLUTION</legis-type> 
<official-title display="no">Electing Members to certain standing committees of the House of Representatives</official-title> 
</form> 
<resolution-body style="traditional" id="H1B6464DBC9CC4CA0BD023E9D85D20971"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H67449B1353F0436BAF678210DC465EF3"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That following named Members be, and are hereby, elected to the following standing committees of the House of Representatives:</text> 

<committee-appointment-paragraph><header>Committee on Agriculture:</header><text>Mr. Goodlatte; Mr. King of Iowa; Mr. Neugebauer; Mr. Rogers of Alabama; Mr. Conaway; Mr. Thompson of Pennsylvania; Mr. Gibbs; Mr. Austin Scott of Georgia; Mr. Tipton; Mr. Southerland; Mr. Crawford; Mrs. Roby; Mr. DesJarlais; Mr. Gibson; Mrs. Hartzler; Mr. Ribble; Mrs. Noem; Mr. Benishek; Mr. Denham; Mr. LaMalfa; Mr. Hudson; Mr. Rodney Davis of Illinois; Mr. Collins of New York; and Mr. Yoho.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph>

<committee-appointment-paragraph><header>Committee on Appropriations:</header><text>Mr. Young of Florida; Mr. Wolf; Mr. Kingston; Mr. Frelinghuysen; Mr. Latham; Mr. Aderholt; Mrs. Emerson; Ms. Granger; Mr. Simpson; Mr. Culberson; Mr. Crenshaw; Mr. Carter; Mr. Alexander; Mr. Calvert; Mr. Bonner; Mr. Cole; Mr. Diaz-Balart; Mr. Dent; Mr. Graves of Georgia; Mr. Yoder; Mr. Womack; Mr. Nunnelee; Mr. Fortenberry; Mr. Rooney; Mr. Fleischmann; Ms. Herrera Beutler; Mr. Joyce; and Mr. Valadao.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph>

<committee-appointment-paragraph><header>Committee on Armed Services:</header><text>Mr. Thornberry; Mr. Jones; Mr. Forbes; Mr. Miller of Florida; Mr. Wilson of South Carolina; Mr. LoBiondo; Mr. Bishop of Utah; Mr. Turner; Mr. Kline; Mr. Rogers of Alabama; Mr. Franks of Arizona; Mr. Shuster; Mr. Conaway; Mr. Lamborn; Mr. Wittman; Mr. Hunter; Mr. Fleming; Mr. Coffman; Mr. Rigell; Mr. Gibson; Mrs. Hartzler; Mr. Heck of Nevada; Mr. Runyan; Mr. Austin Scott of Georgia; Mr. Palazzo; Mrs. Roby; Mr. Brooks of Alabama; Mr. Nugent; Mrs. Noem; Mr. Cook; Mr. Bridenstine; Mr. Wenstrup; and Mrs. Walorski.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph>

<committee-appointment-paragraph><header>Committee on Education and the Workforce:</header><text>Mr. Petri; Mr. McKeon; Mr. Wilson of South Carolina; Ms. Foxx; Mr. Price of Georgia; Mr. Marchant; Mr. Hunter; Mr. Roe of Tennessee; Mr. Thompson of Pennsylvania; Mr. Walberg; Mr. Salmon; Mr. Guthrie; Mr. DesJarlais; Mr. Rokita; Mr. Bucshon; Mr. Gowdy; Mr. Barletta; Mrs. Roby; Mr. Heck of Nevada; Mrs. Brooks of Indiana; Mr. Hudson; and Mr. Messer.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph>

<committee-appointment-paragraph><header>Committee on Energy and Commerce:</header><text>Mr. Hall; Mr. Barton; Mr. Whitfield; Mr. Shimkus; Mr. Pitts; Mr. Walden; Mr. Terry; Mr. Rogers of Michigan; Mr. Murphy of Pennsylvania; Mr. Burgess; Mrs. Blackburn; Mr. Gingrey of Georgia; Mr. Scalise; Mr. Latta; Mrs. McMorris Rodgers; Mr. Harper; Mr. Lance; Mr. Cassidy; Mr. Guthrie; Mr. Olson; Mr. McKinley; Mr. Gardner; Mr. Pompeo; Mr. Kinzinger of Illinois; Mr. Griffith of Virginia; Mr. Bilirakis; Mr. Johnson of Ohio; Mr. Long; and Mrs. Ellmers.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph>

<committee-appointment-paragraph><header>Committee on Financial Services:</header><text>Mr. Bachus; Mr. King of New York; Mr. Royce; Mr. Lucas; Mr. Gary G. Miller of California; Mrs. Capito; Mr. Garrett; Mr. Neugebauer; Mr. McHenry; Mr. Campbell; Mrs. Bachmann; Mr. McCarthy of California; Mr. Pearce; Mr. Posey; Mr. Fitzpatrick; Mr. Westmoreland; Mr. Luetkemeyer; Mr. Huizenga of Michigan; Mr. Duffy; Mr. Renacci; Mr. Hurt; Mr. Grimm; Mr. Stivers; Mr. Fincher; Mr. Stutzman; Mr. Mulvaney; Mr. Hultgren; Mr. Ross; Mr. Pittenger; Mrs. Wagner; Mr. Barr; and Mr. Cotton.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph>

<committee-appointment-paragraph><header>Committee on Foreign Affairs:</header><text>Mr. Smith of New Jersey; Ms. Ros-Lehtinen; Mr. Rohrabacher; Mr. Chabot; Mr. Wilson of South Carolina; Mr. McCaul; Mr. Poe of Texas; Mr. Salmon; Mr. Marino; Mr. Duncan of South Carolina; Mr. Kinzinger of Illinois; Mr. Brooks of Alabama; Mr. Cotton; Mr. Cook; Mr. Holding; Mr. Weber of Texas; Mr. Perry; Mr. Stockman; Mr. DeSantis; Mr. Radel; Mr. Collins of Georgia; Mr. Meadows; Mr. Yoho; and Mr. Messer.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph>

<committee-appointment-paragraph><header>Committee on Homeland Security:</header><text>Mr. Smith of Texas; Mr. King of New York; Mr. Rogers of Alabama; Mr. Broun of Georgia; Mrs. Miller of Michigan; Mr. Meehan; Mr. Duncan of South Carolina; Mr. Marino; Mr. Chaffetz; Mr. Palazzo; Mr. Barletta; Mr. Stewart; Mr. Rothfus; Mr. Hudson; Mr. Daines; Mrs. Brooks of Indiana; and Mr. Perry.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph>

<committee-appointment-paragraph><header>Committee on the Judiciary:</header><text>Mr. Sensenbrenner; Mr. Coble; Mr. Smith of Texas; Mr. Chabot; Mr. Bachus; Mr. Issa; Mr. Forbes; Mr. King of Iowa; Mr. Franks of Arizona; Mr. Gohmert; Mr. Jordan; Mr. Poe of Texas; Mr. Chaffetz; Mr. Marino; Mr. Gowdy; Mr. Amodei; Mr. Labrador; Mr. Farenthold; Mr. Holding; Mr. Collins of Georgia; Mr. DeSantis; and Mr. Rothfus.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph>

<committee-appointment-paragraph><header>Committee on Natural Resources:</header><text>Mr. Young of Alaska; Mr. Gohmert; Mr. Bishop of Utah; Mr. Lamborn; Mr. Wittman; Mr. Broun of Georgia; Mr. Fleming; Mr. McClintock; Mr. Thompson of Pennsylvania; Mrs. Lummis; Mr. Benishek; Mr. Duncan of South Carolina; Mr. Tipton; Mr. Gosar; Mr. Labrador; Mr. Southerland; Mr. Flores; Mr. Harris; Mr. Runyan; Mr. Amodei; Mr. Mullin; Mr. Stewart; Mr. Daines; Mr. Cramer; and Mr. LaMalfa.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph>

<committee-appointment-paragraph><header>Committee on Oversight and Government Reform:</header><text>Mr. Mica; Mr. Turner; Mr. Duncan of Tennessee; Mr. McHenry; Mr. Jordan; Mr. Chaffetz; Mr. Walberg; Mr. Lankford; Mr. Amash; Mr. Gosar; Mr. Meehan; Mr. DesJarlais; Mr. Gowdy; Mr. Farenthold; Mr. Hastings of Washington; Mrs. Lummis; Mr. Woodall; Mr. Massie; Mr. Collins of Georgia; Mr. Meadows; Mr. Bentivolio; and Mr. DeSantis.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph>

<committee-appointment-paragraph><header>Committee on Science, Space, and Technology:</header><text>Mr. Sensenbrenner; Mr. Hall; Mr. Rohrabacher; Mr. Lucas; Mr. Neugebauer; Mr. McCaul; Mr. Broun of Georgia; Mr. Palazzo; Mr. Brooks of Alabama; Mr. Harris; Mr. Hultgren; Mr. Bucshon; Mr. Stockman; Mr. Posey; Mrs. Lummis; Mr. Schweikert; Mr. Massie; Mr. Cramer; Mr. Bridenstine; Mr. Weber of Texas; and Mr. Stewart.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph>

<committee-appointment-paragraph><header>Committee on Small Business:</header><text>Mr. Chabot; Mr. King of Iowa; Mr. Coffman; Mr. Luetkemeyer; Mr. Mulvaney; Mr. Tipton; Ms. Herrera Beutler; Mr. Hanna; Mr. Huelskamp; Mr. Schweikert; Mr. Bentivolio; Mr. Collins of New York; and Mr. Rice of South Carolina.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph>

<committee-appointment-paragraph><header>Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure:</header><text>Mr. Young of Alaska; Mr. Petri; Mr. Coble; Mr. Duncan of Tennessee; Mr. Mica; Mr. LoBiondo; Mr. Gary G. Miller of California; Mr. Graves of Missouri; Mrs. Capito; Mrs. Miller of Michigan; Mr. Hunter; Mr. Harris; Mr. Crawford; Mr. Barletta; Mr. Farenthold; Mr. Bucshon; Mr. Gibbs; Mr. Meehan; Mr. Hanna; Mr. Webster of Florida; Mr. Southerland; Mr. Denham; Mr. Ribble; Mr. Massie; Mr. Daines; Mr. Rice of South Carolina; Mr. Mullin; Mr. Williams; Mr. Radel; Mr. Meadows; Mr. Perry; and Mr. Rodney Davis of Illinois.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph>

<committee-appointment-paragraph><header>Committee on Veterans’ Affairs:</header><text>Mr. Lamborn; Mr. Bilirakis; Mr. Roe of Tennessee; Mr. Flores; Mr. Denham; Mr. Runyan; Mr. Benishek; Mr. Huelskamp; Mr. Amodei; Mr. Coffman; Mr. Wenstrup; Mr. Cook; and Mrs. Walorski.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph>

<committee-appointment-paragraph><header>Committee on Ways and Means:</header><text>Mr. Sam Johnson of Texas; Mr. Brady of Texas; Mr. Ryan of Wisconsin; Mr. Nunes; Mr. Tiberi; Mr. Reichert; Mr. Boustany; Mr. Roskam; Mr. Gerlach; Mr. Price of Georgia; Mr. Buchanan; Mr. Smith of Nebraska; Mr. Schock; Ms. Jenkins; Mr. Paulsen; Mr. Marchant; Mrs. Black; Mr. Reed; Mr. Young of Indiana; Mr. Kelly; and Mr. Griffin of Arkansas.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph>

</section> 
</resolution-body> 
<attestation><attestation-group><attestor display="no">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation>
</resolution> 


