<bill session="113" type="s" number="2823" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">North American Energy Infrastructure Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require approval for the construction, connection, operation, or maintenance of oil or natural gas pipelines or electric transmission facilities at the national boundary of the United States for the import or export of oil, natural gas, or electricity to or from Canada or Mexico, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412494"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412205" joined="2014-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412391" joined="2014-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2014-09-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5632-5634"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3301"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4286"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="5360"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2170"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC)"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Maine"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Michigan"/>
    <term name="Minnesota"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="New Hampshire"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="North Dakota"/>
    <term name="Ohio"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="Vermont"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/16/2014--Introduced.
North American Energy Infrastructure Act - Prohibits any person from constructing, connecting, operating, or maintaining a cross-border segment of an oil or natural gas pipeline or electric transmission facility at the national boundary of the United States for the import or export of oil, natural gas, or electricity to or from Canada or Mexico without obtaining a certificate of crossing under this Act.

Requires the Secretary of State, with respect to oil pipelines, or the Secretary of Energy (DOE), with respect to electric transmission facilities, to issue a certificate of crossing for the cross-border segment within 120 days after final action is taken under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969, unless it is not in U.S. public interest.

Directs DOE, as a condition of issuing a certificate, to require that the cross-border segment be constructed, connected, operated, or maintained consistent with specified policies and standards.

Amends the Natural Gas Act to require the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) to approve within 30 days after receipt any application for the importation or exportation of natural gas to or from Canada or Mexico.

 Declares that no presidential permit shall be necessary for the construction, connection, operation, or maintenance of an oil or natural gas pipeline or electric transmission facility, including any cross-border segment.</summary>
</bill>
