<bill session="113" type="h" number="4038" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-02-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-02-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-02-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Benefits Administration Information Technology Improvement Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to make certain improvements in the information technology of the Veterans Benefits Administration of the Department of Veterans Affairs to process claims more efficiently, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412480"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-02-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-25">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSVR10" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/11/2014--Introduced.
Veterans Benefits Administration Information Technology Improvement Act of 2014 - Requires the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) to make such changes and improvements to the information technology system of the Veterans Benefits Administration to ensure that: (1) all original and supplemental claims for veterans educational assistance are adjudicated electronically, and (2) rules-based processing is used to make decisions with respect to such claims with little human intervention.

Requires the Secretary to reduce redundancy and inefficiencies in the use of information technology to process claims for rehabilitation programs by: (1) ensuring that payments of subsistence allowance for veterans participating in a rehabilitation program are processed and paid out of only one corporate information technology system, and (2) enhancing the information technology system supporting veterans participating in such a program to support more accurate accounting of services and outcomes.</summary>
</bill>
