<bill session="113" type="h" number="5020" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Indian Tribal Self-Determination in Land Consolidation Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Indian Land Consolidation Act to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to contract with eligible Indian tribes to manage land buy-back programs, to authorize that certain amounts be deposited into interest bearing accounts, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412549"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400077" joined="2014-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412555" joined="2014-09-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee Indian and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-29">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII24" subcommittee="Indian and Alaska Native Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/8/2014--Introduced.
Indian Tribal Self-Determination in Land Consolidation Act of 2014 - Amends the Indian Land Consolidation Act to require the Secretary of the Interior: (1) at the request of a tribal government, to enter into agreements to allow the tribal government to carry out some or all of the Secretary's fractional interest acquisition program; and (2) to make payments to carry out the agreements and authorize the use of interest earned to acquire a fractional interest or permanent improvements on land that already has trust or restricted fractional interests.

Amends the Claims Resolution Act of 2010 to make amounts in the Trust Land Consolidation Fund available to Interior during a 15-year period (under current law, a 10-year period).

Requires annual reports to Congress that assess the implementation of the Trust Land Consolidation Fund.</summary>
</bill>
