<bill session="113" type="s" number="2480" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-30">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nevada Native Nations Land Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Nevada Native Nations Land Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of the Interior to convey certain Federal land to Elko County, Nevada, and to take land into trust for certain Indian tribes, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300082"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412218" joined="2014-06-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3722-3723" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-09">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 113-419.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4394-4395"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-07-30" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-08-26">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Reported by Senator Tester under authority of the order of the Senate of 08/05/2014 with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-08-26" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="545">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 545.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-12-01">
      <text>By Senator Tester from Committee on Indian Affairs filed written report. Report No. 113-278.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2455"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2455"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Pedestrians and bicycling"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation facilities"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/26/2014--Reported to Senate amended.
Nevada Native Nations Land Act -Title I: Elko Motocross Land Conveyance - (Sec. 102) Directs the Secretary of the Interior to convey to Elko County, Nevada, without consideration, approximately 275 acres of land managed by the Bureau of Land Management (BLM), Elko District, Nevada. Requires the land conveyed to be used only: (1) as a motocross, bicycle, off-highway vehicle, or stock car racing area; or (2) for any other public purpose consistent with the Recreation and Public Purposes Act.

Title II: Conveyance of Land to Indian Tribes - (Sec. 201) Holds in trust the following lands:

 for the Te-Moak Tribe of Western Shoshone Indians of Nevada (the Elko Band), approximately 373 acres of BLM land; for the Fort McDermitt Paiute and Shoshone Tribe of the Fort McDermitt Indian Reservation, approximately 19,094 acres of BLM land; for the Shoshone Paiute Tribes of the Duck Valley Indian Reservation, approximately 82 acres of Forest Service land; for the Summit Lake Paiute Tribe, approximately 941 acres of BLM land; for the Reno-Sparks Indian Colony, approximately 13,434 acres of BLM land; and for the Pyramid Lake Paiute Tribe, approximately 11,719 acres of BLM land. Makes the lands held for the Tribes part of their respective Reservations.

(Sec. 202) Requires the Secretary of the Interior to complete a survey to establish boundary lines of the land taken into trust for each Indian tribe.

Restricts gaming on lands held in trust under this Act.

Permits the Secretary, in consultation with the applicable Indian tribe, to carry out any fuel reduction and other landscape restoration activities (including restoration of the sage grouse habitat) on the land that is beneficial to the tribe and BLM.</summary>
</bill>
