<bill session="113" type="h" number="5220" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">No More Land Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Land and Water Conservation Fund to limit the use of funds available from the Land and Water Conservation Fund Act of 1965 to use for maintenance.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400158"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-28">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-28">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-08-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-08-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-08-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Energy, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="Public Lands and Environmental Regulation" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII22" subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG15" subcommittee="Conservation, Energy, and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="General public lands matters"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/28/2014--Introduced.
No More Land Act - Amends the Land and Water Conservation Fund Act of 1965 to prohibit the Land and Water Conservation Fund from being used for acquisition.

Directs the heads of the Bureau of Land Management (BLM), the Fish and Wildlife Service, the Forest Service, and the National Park Service to reduce the value of backlogged maintenance that exists on lands under the administrative jurisdiction of that agency by at least 20% in five years, with additional decreases in the backlog for subsequent years.

Instructs each agency to publish reports to Congress that document the progress made by reducing the backlogs.

Requires each agency to submit to Congress a report that prioritizes lands owned by the federal government and under the administrative jurisdiction of that agency by order of importance to the success of agency programs.</summary>
</bill>
