<bill session="113" type="h" number="4138" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-03-12T17:04:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-03-12T17:04:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-03-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ENFORCE the Law Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Executive Needs to Faithfully Observe and Respect Congressional Enactments of the Law Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">ENFORCE the Law Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Executive Needs to Faithfully Observe and Respect Congressional Enactments of the Law Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">ENFORCE the Law Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Executive Needs to Faithfully Observe and Respect Congressional Enactments of the Law Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To protect the separation of powers in the Constitution of the United States by ensuring that the President takes care that the laws be faithfully executed, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412473"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="2014-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412478" joined="2014-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400071" joined="2014-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412270" joined="2014-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412531" joined="2014-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412472" joined="2014-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400137" joined="2014-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400141" joined="2014-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400147" joined="2014-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400154" joined="2014-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400196" joined="2014-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412226" joined="2014-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412465" joined="2014-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412419" joined="2014-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400652" joined="2014-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412483" joined="2014-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400365" joined="2014-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400367" joined="2014-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412596" joined="2014-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400381" joined="2014-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412548" joined="2014-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400627" joined="2014-03-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-03-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-05">
      <text>Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-05">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-03-05" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 18 - 14.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-03-07T20:20:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 113-377.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-03-07T20:20:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="281">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 281.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-03-11T19:21:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 511 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4138 and H.R. 3973. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-12T13:56:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 511.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2319-2340" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-12T13:56:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4138 and H.R. 3973. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-12T13:56:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 511 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-12T13:56:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Glenn Thompson to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-12T13:56:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 4138.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-12T15:15:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 511, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Conyers Part A amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-12T15:24:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Conyers Part A amendment No. 1, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Conyers demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-12T15:25:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 511, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Nadler Part A amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-12T15:37:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Nadler Part A amendment No. 2, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Nadler demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-12T15:37:00-04:00">
      <text>The Committee rose informally to receive a message from the President of the United States, and resumed its sitting afterwards.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-12T15:38:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 511, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Jackson Lee Part A amendment No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-12T15:47:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Jackson Lee Part A amendment No. 3, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Jackson Lee demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-12T15:48:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 511, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Cicilline Part A amendment No. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-12T15:54:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question on adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-12T16:36:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 4138.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-12T16:38:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2337" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-12T16:38:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2329-2330" label="text of amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-12T16:39:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Ruiz moved to recommit with instructions to Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2338-2339" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2338" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-12T16:40:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ruiz motion to recommit with instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to add at the end of the bill Section 3, Protecting States' Rights, and adding Section 4, Restoring Unemploymnet Benefits for America's Job Seekers. Pending a reservation of a point of order. Subsequently, the reservation was removed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-12T16:49:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2338" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-12T16:58:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 187 - 228 (Roll no. 123).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2339" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="124" datetime="2014-03-12T17:04:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 233 - 181 (Roll no. 124).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-03-12T17:04:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-13">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSJU10" subcommittee="Constitution and Civil Justice" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hr" number="511"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="113" type="hr" number="511"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2118"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional-executive branch relations"/>
    <term name="Constitution and constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h589"/>
    <amendment number="h590"/>
    <amendment number="h591"/>
    <amendment number="h592"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>3/12/2014--Passed House amended.
Executive Needs to Faithfully Observe and Respect Congressional Enactments of the Law Act of 2014 or the ENFORCE the Law Act of 2014 - Authorizes either chamber of Congress, upon adoption of a resolution declaring that the President or any officer or employee of the United States has established or implemented a policy, practice, or procedure to refrain from enforcing, applying, following, or administering any federal statute, rule, regulation, program, policy, or other law in violation of the constitutional requirement that the President faithfully execute the laws of the United States, to bring a civil action for a declaratory judgment to that effect.

Grants jurisdiction to a three-judge panel of a U.S. district court to hear such civil action and provides for an expedited direct appeal to the U.S. Supreme Court.

Requires the Comptroller General (GAO) to submit quarterly reports to the congressional judiciary committees on the costs of any civil action brought under this Act, incuding any&#160;attorney fees paid in connection with any such action.</summary>
</bill>
