<bill session="113" type="h" number="5306" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Social Security 2100 Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To protect our Social Security system and improve benefits for current and future generations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400233"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400063" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2014-08-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Education and the Workforce, and the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED02" subcommittee="Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1029"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="500"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Employment taxes"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Income tax rates"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Social Security Administration"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2014--Introduced.
Social Security 2100 Act - Amends title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to:

 increase the primary insurance amount formula factor from 90% to 93% for all eligible beneficiaries, beginning in 2015; revise computation of cost-of-living adjustments (COLAs) to use the Consumer Price Index for Elderly Consumers (CPI-E); increase the special minimum primary insurance amount (25% above the federal poverty line) for lifetime low earners based on years in the workforce. Amends the Internal Revenue Code (IRC) to increase the gross income threshold for taxation of Social Security benefits from $25,000 to $50,000 for single taxpayers and from $32,000 to $100,000 for married taxpayers filing joint returns, beginning in 2015.

Amends the IRC and SSA title II to impose the employment tax on all wage income above $400,000, effective in 2015. Requires incremental increases, up to 14.4% in 2037, in the employment and self-employment taxes.

Amends SSA title II to include 2% of an individual's excess average indexed monthly earnings (over $400,000 per annum) in the formula for determining primary insurance amounts.

Amends IRC to increase the Social Security tax rate on employees and employers and with respect to self-employment income.

Amends SSA title II to establish an Independent Social Security Investment Oversight Board to:

 set up a Common Stock Old-Age Investment Fund in the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and a Common Stock Disability Investment Fund in the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund, and prescibe rules for the investment of the Common Stock Investment Funds in common stock. Requires reallocation of a portion of employment tax revenues from the OASDI Trust Fund to the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund for wages paid after 2014.</summary>
</bill>
