<bill session="113" type="s" number="1169" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-11-14">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-11-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Limestone Hills Training Area Withdrawal Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Limestone Hills Training Area Withdrawal Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to withdraw and reserve certain public land in the State of Montana for the Limestone Hills Training Area, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300005"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2013-06-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-30">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands, Forests, and Mining. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 113-85.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-11-14" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-05-14">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Landrieu with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 113-160.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-05-14" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="377">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 377.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG03" subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1672"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1960"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/14/2014--Reported to Senate amended.
Limestone Hills Training Area Withdrawal Act of 2014 - (Sec. 2) Withdraws 18,644 acres of public lands and interests in Broadwater County, Montana.

Reserves the withdrawn land for the Army for: (1) training for active and reserve forces; (2) construction and operation of support and maintenance facilities for those forces; (3) training by the Montana Department of Military Affairs; (4) training by state and local law enforcement agencies, civil defense organizations, and public education institutions; and (5) other defense-related purposes.

Prohibits anything in this Act from being construed as altering any rights reserved for an Indian tribe for tribal use of land within the military land withdrawal area by treaty or federal law. Requires the Army to consult with any Indian tribes in the vicinity of the withdrawal area before taking action affecting tribal rights or cultural resources protected by treaty or federal law.

(Sec. 4) Subjects the withdrawn federal land to regulations related to locatable mineral activities and mining.

Prohibits the Army from restricting mining on the land.

Directs the Army to remove unexploded ordnance on land subject to mining. Requires the Army and the Department of the Interior to enter into an agreement regarding coordination of defense-related uses and mining and the ongoing removal of unexploded ordnance.

(Sec. 5) Gives Interior authority to issue grazing permits and leases on this land.

(Sec. 6) Terminates this withdrawal and reservation on March 31, 2039.

(Sec. 7) Permits hunting, fishing, and trapping on the withdrawn land.

(Sec. 8) Declares that nothing in this Act shall be construed to: (1) establish a reservation in favor of the United States with respect to any water or water right on withdrawn land, or (2) authorize the appropriation of water on such land except in accordance with applicable state law.

(Sec. 9 ) Requires the Army to take necessary precautions to prevent, and actions to, suppress brush and range fires occurring as a result of military activities on the land.

Requires Interior, at the Army's request, to assist in the suppression of such fires, and be reimbursed by the Army.

(Sec. 10) Instructs the Secretary of the Army to maintain a program of decontamination on the land for defense-related contamination.

(Sec. 11) Prescribes a procedure for extending the withdrawal after its termination date.

(Sec. 12) Declares that, upon termination of the withdrawal under this Act, the previously withdrawn land shall not be open to any form of appropriation under the public land laws, including the mining laws and the mineral leasing and geothermal leasing laws, until Interior publishes an appropriate order specifying when such land will be restored to the public domain and opened for such purposes.

(Sec. 13) Prescribes a procedure for the Army to relinquish any or all of the lands.

Requires the Army to decontaminate the relinquished land if practicable and economically feasible.

Absolves Interior of any obligation to accept contaminated land or any land determined not suitable for return to the public domain.</summary>
</bill>
