<bill session="113" type="h" number="2672" updated="2015-09-01T10:19:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-06T17:09:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-05-06T17:09:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CFPB Rural Designation Petition and Correction Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Helping Expand Lending Practices in Rural Communities Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act to provide for an application process for interested parties to apply for a county to be designated as a rural area, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by house">To amend the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act to provide for an application process for interested parties to apply for an area to be designated as a rural area, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412541"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400179" joined="2013-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412284" joined="2014-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412487" joined="2014-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400441" joined="2014-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400313" joined="2014-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412239" joined="2014-04-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-04">
      <text>Hearings Held by the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit Prior to Referral.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-14">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-03-14" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 55 - 1.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-05-06T16:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Mrs. Capito moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-06T16:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3420-3422" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-06T16:48:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2672.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2014-05-06T17:09:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3420" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-05-06T17:09:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-07">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-16">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, Markup"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Financial Services"/>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1916"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Consumer Financial Protection Bureau"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/6/2014--Passed House amended.
Helping Expand Lending Practices in Rural Communities Act - Directs the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB) to establish an application process under which a person who lives or does business in a state may apply to have an area in the state identified as a rural area if it has not yet been so designated by the CFPB for purposes of federal consumer financial law.

 Prescribes criteria for the CFPB to consider when evaluating the application. Requires the CFPB to: (1) grant or deny the application within 90 days after the public comment period ends; and (3) publish the grant or denial in the Federal Register, including an explanation of the factors upon which the CFPB relied in making its determination.

Sunsets this Act two years after its date of enactment.</summary>
</bill>
