<bill session="113" type="s" number="1583" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-10-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-10-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Mental Health Support for Veteran Families and Caregivers Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to conduct an education program and peer support program for the education and training of family members and caregivers of veterans with mental health disorders.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400357"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-30">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 113-280.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1950"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/28/2013--Introduced.
Mental Health Support for Veteran Families and Caregivers Act of 2013 - Requires the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) to: (1) enter into contracts to conduct a 4-year program (with authorization for a 4-year extension) to provide a course of education to family members and caregivers of veterans on matters relating to coping with veterans' mental health disorders; (2) carry out such program in at least 10 VA medical centers, 10 VA clinics, and 10 centers for readjustment counseling and related mental health services for veterans (vet centers); (3) expand such program (within 2 years) to include at least 10 additional medical centers, clinics, and vet centers; and (4) select VA mental health care providers to monitor the progress of the instruction provided under such education program.

Requires the Secretary to: (1) establish a program to provide peer support to family members and caregivers of veterans on matters relating to coping with veterans mental health disorders; (2) provide such peer support, through group meetings conducted at least twice each calendar quarter, at each facility in which the education program is provided; (3) select an individual who has completed the education program to serve as a peer support coordinator for each facility; and (4) select a VA mental health care provider to serve as a mentor to each coordinator.

Directs the Secretary to conduct a survey of the satisfaction of program participants.</summary>
</bill>
