<bill session="113" type="h" number="3536" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-11-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-11-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-11-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">S.O.S. Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Support Our Students Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to support teacher and school professional training on awareness of student mental health conditions and suicide prevention efforts.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412565"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412571" joined="2013-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2014-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400130" joined="2014-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412209" joined="2013-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2013-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412396" joined="2013-11-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-11-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="648"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational guidance"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/19/2013--Introduced.
Support Our Students Act of 2013 or the S.O.S. Act of 2013 - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to direct the Secretary of Education to award grants to states and, through them, subgrants to local educational agencies (LEAs) to support or develop programs that will train teachers, school personnel, and specialized instructional support personnel regarding mental health conditions in children.

Includes as grant and subgrant recipients, states and LEAs that partner with a mental health organization, family advocacy organization, or community nonprofit organization.

Requires subgrantees to utilize school counselors, school psychologists, school social workers, or community organizations with experience in mental illness and suicide prevention in developing and conducting the training.

Requires the training program to include an annual in-service training component that enables teachers, school personnel, and specialized instructional support personnel to: (1) better understand mental health conditions and the early warning signs in children and adolescents; (2) effectively communicate their mental health concerns with families and consider family perspectives; (3) identify classroom strategies for working effectively with troubled children; and (4) understand school specific information, including links to mental health services and supports in the school and community.

Directs the Secretary to develop outcome measures that the Secretary is to use to conduct an in-depth evaluation of the effectiveness of the training programs.</summary>
</bill>
