<bill session="113" type="s" number="2860" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fast Track to College Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Secretary of Education to make grants to support early college high schools and other dual or concurrent enrollment programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412390"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412324" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2014-09-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="551"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/18/2014--Introduced.
Fast Track to College Act of 2014 - Authorizes the Secretary of Education to award matching six-year grants to local educational agencies (LEAs) that partner with institutions of higher education (IHEs) to establish or support dual or concurrent enrollment programs, such as early college high schools, that allow secondary school students to earn credit simultaneously toward a secondary school diploma and a postsecondary degree or certificate.

Gives grant priority to applicants: (1) that propose to establish or support a dual or concurrent enrollment program for a student body at least 40% of which is impoverished; and (2) from states that provide assistance to dual or concurrent enrollment programs, such as assistance defraying the costs of higher education.

Requires applicants to make assurances that: (1) students will not be required to pay tuition or fees for postsecondary courses, and (2) those courses will be taught by faculty that meet their partner IHE's normal standards.

Authorizes the Secretary to award matching five-year grants to states to: (1) plan and implement statewide strategies to make dual or concurrent enrollment programs more accessible to students who are underrepresented in postsecondary education; (2) provide technical assistance to dual or concurrent enrollment programs; and (3) engage in outreach, assessment, and teacher training activities designed to strengthen such programs.

Directs the Secretary to: (1) contract for an independent evaluation of this Act's programs, and (2) provide technical assistance to LEAs and their partners and disseminate information concerning best practices in dual or concurrent enrollment programs.</summary>
</bill>
