<bill session="113" type="sj" number="46" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-12-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-12-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-12-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Declaration of War against the Organization known as the Islamic State</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A joint resolution to declare that a state of war exists between the organization referring to itself as the Islamic State and the Government and the people of the United States, and to make provisions to prosecute the same.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412492"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-12-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/3/2014--Introduced.
Declaration of War against the Organization known as the Islamic State - Declares, pursuant to article I, section 8, clause 11 of the Constitution, that a state of war exists between the United States and the organization referring to itself as the Islamic State, also known as the Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant (ISIL) and the Islamic State of Iraq and Syria (ISIS) (ISIL/ISIS).

Authorizes and directs the President to use the U.S. Armed Forces to protect U.S. personnel and facilities in Iraq and Syria from ISIL/ISIS.

States that nothing in this Act shall be construed as declaring war or authorizing force against any organization: (1) other than ISIL/ISIS, or (2) based on affiliation with ISIL/ISIS.

States that nothing in this Act shall be construed as authorizing the use of ground combat forces except for:

 protection or rescue of U.S. Armed Forces members or U.S. citizens from imminent danger posed by ISIL/ISIS, limited operations against high value targets, or advisory and intelligence gathering operations. States that: (1) this Act is intended to constitute specific statutory authorization within the meaning of section 5(b) of the War Powers Resolution, and (2) nothing in this resolution supersedes any requirement of the War Powers Resolution.

Repeals the authorization for the Use of Military Force Against Iraq Resolution of 2002.

States that The Authorization for the Use of Military Force (Public Law 107-40) does not authorize the use of military force against ISIL/ISIS, and shall not be construed as providing such authority.

Sunsets one year after the date of enactment of this joint resolution: (1) The Authorization for the Use of Military Force, and (2) the declaration and authorization in this joint resolution.</summary>
</bill>
