<bill session="113" type="h" number="3783" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-12-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-12-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-12-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rate Protection Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend section 1101 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to extend for one year the high risk health insurance pool program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412558"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-12-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/16/2013--Introduced.
Rate Protection Act of 2013 - Amends the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to extend, from January 1, 2014, to January 1, 2015, the temporary high risk health insurance pool program providing health insurance coverage to uninsured individuals who have a preexisting condition.

Appropriates additional funds to the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to pay claims that exceed the amount of premiums collected from the high risk pool's enrollees.

Prohibits individuals who were not enrolled in the high risk health insurance pool program at the close of 2013 from enrolling in the program in 2014, but requires the Secretary to enable individuals to enroll in the federal government's high risk pool program if they are enrolled until the day before a high risk pool that was operated by a state or nonprofit private entity as of December 31, 2013, is terminated in 2014.</summary>
</bill>
