<bill session="113" type="s" number="2273" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-04-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-04-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Defense Energy Security Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve energy savings by the Department of Defense, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400412"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2014-05-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="4536"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/30/2014--Introduced.
Department of Defense Energy Security Act of 2014 - Amends the National Energy Conservation Policy Act to authorize agencies to enter into energy savings performance contracts to reduce the costs of fuel supply, delivery, or transport for nonbuilding applications.

 Prohibits payments by agencies to entities that supply, deliver, or transport fuel under such contracts from exceeding the amounts that the agencies would have paid entities without the contracts.

Authorizes the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering to: (1) carry out research to improve military vehicle technology to increase fuel economy or reduce fuel consumption of military vehicles used in combat; and (2) establish an online, centralized repository for all Department of Defense (DOD) operational energy-related research and development efforts.

Directs the Secretary of Defense to establish: (1) a DOD executive agent for warrior power to align and advance efforts to measure and manage the development and evaluation of man-portable tactical power generation systems to power tactical communications equipment, weapons systems, and other troop equipment; and (2) a program to foster secure and reliable sources of energy for military installations, including incorporation of advanced energy metering, renewable energy, energy storage, and redundant power systems.

Establishes in the Treasury the Department of Defense Alternative Fuel Vehicle Infrastructure Fund to support installing, operating, and maintaining alternative fuel dispensing stations for use by DOD's alternative fueled vehicles and other infrastructure necessary to fuel the vehicles.</summary>
</bill>
