<bill session="113" type="s" number="1454" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-08-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-08-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Empowering Encore Entrepreneurs Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Small Business Administrator to establish a grant program to empower encore entrepreneurs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300063"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300078" joined="2013-12-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4613"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Business education"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Credit and credit markets"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Self-employed"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/1/2013--Introduced.
Empowering Encore Entrepreneurs Act of 2013 - Directs the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) to establish a program under which the Administrator may enter into contracts or cooperative agreements with, or make grants to, nonprofit organizations to provide technical assistance, mentoring, and other specialized training activities for encore entrepreneurs.

Defines "encore entrepreneur" to mean an entrepreneur, business person, or owner of a small business concern who: (1) is seeking to start a new small business concern or expand an existing one, and (2) is at least age 50 or has at least 20 years of experience in a workplace.

Directs the Administrator to give special consideration to applications seeking funding for programs for: (1) members of the Armed Forces impacted by base closures or realignment, or (2) encore entrepreneurs unemployed for a period of not less than one year.

Terminates the program on September 30, 2017.

Requires the Administrator to submit to specified congressional committees a report that describes the barriers and obstacles faced by encore entrepreneurs in starting new small business concerns or expanding existing small business concerns.</summary>
</bill>
