<bill session="113" type="s" number="2956" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-11-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-11-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-11-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Phone Scam Prevention Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prevent caller ID spoofing, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300078"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412598" joined="2014-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2014-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412205" joined="2014-11-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-11-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6207-6208"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6208-6209" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3670"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2787"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission (FCC)"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/20/2014--Introduced.
Phone Scam Prevention Act of 2014 - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to require voice communications service providers to offer subscribers the option to designate a list of approved telephone numbers for which calls originating from those numbers are permitted to connect directly with the subscriber's telephone and other customer premises equipment.

 Requires providers to ensure that any call for termination that is not from a number on the subscriber's list is processed according to the subscriber's preferences, including by limiting or disabling the ability of an incoming call to connect with the subscriber's equipment.

Exempts government and public interest calls from being subject to a subscriber's preferences.

Requires the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to develop authentication standards for providers to validate caller information so that subscribers may obtain secure assurances of a call's origin, including the calling party's number and identification.

Extends the prohibition on the provision of inaccurate caller identification information to persons outside the United States if the recipient is within the United States.

Expands the definition "caller identification information" to include text messages.

Revises caller identification requirements to make standards applicable to voice communications using resources from the North American Numbering Plan (currently, the requirements apply to telecommunications or IP-enabled voice services).</summary>
</bill>
