<bill session="113" type="s" number="753" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-11-14">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-11-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for national security benefits for White Sands Missile Range and Fort Bliss.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412281"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2013-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2013-04-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-30">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands, Forests, and Mining. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 113-85.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-11-14" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-05-14">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Landrieu with an amendment. With written report No. 113-159.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-05-14" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="376">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 376.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG03" subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/14/2014--Reported to Senate amended.
Withdraws 5,100 acres of land near White Sands Missile Range in New Mexico. Reserves the land for use by the Army for military purposes. Requires the Secretary of the Army to reimburse the Secretary of the Interior for any costs in implementing this Act with respect to this land.

Withdraws 37,600 acres of land near Fort Bliss in Texas and New Mexico. Allows the issuance of oil and gas pipeline rights of way on part of this land.

Revokes the withdrawal of 2,050 acres of land (part of Fillmore Canyon located in New Mexico) that was reserved for the Army's use. Gives the Secretary of the Interior authority for managing this land.</summary>
</bill>
