<bill session="113" type="h" number="3623" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-03-14">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-03-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-11-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improving Access to Capital for Emerging Growth Companies Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend certain provisions of the securities laws relating to the treatment of emerging growth companies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412479"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412544" joined="2013-11-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-23">
      <text>Hearings Held by the Subcommittee on Capital Markets and Government Sponsored Enterprises Prior to Introduction and Referral.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1756"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-14">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-03-14" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 56 - 0.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, Markup"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="HSBA16" subcommittee="Capital Markets and Government Sponsored Enterprises" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="5405"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/22/2013--Introduced.
Improving Access to Capital for Emerging Growth Companies Act - Amends the Securities Act of 1933 (Act) to reduce from 21 to 15 the number of days before a "road show" that an emerging growth company (EGC), before its initial public offering (IPO) date, may publicly file a draft registration statement for confidential nonpublic review by Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) staff.

(A financial "road show" is an offer [other than a statutory prospectus or a portion of one] that contains a presentation regarding an offering by one or more members of the issuer's management and includes discussion of one or more of the issuer, such management, and the securities being offered. Typically, a road show is a series of meetings across different cities, often before an IPO, in which top executives from a company have the opportunity to talk with current or potential investors.)

Prescribes a grace period during which an issuer that was an EGC at the time it filed a confidential registration statement for confidential SEC review, but is no longer one, shall continue to be treated as one.

Authorizes an EGC, within one year of its IPO, to submit confidentially to the SEC a draft registration statement for any securities to be issued subsequent to its IPO (follow-on offerings) for confidential nonpublic review by SEC staff before publicly filing a registration statement, if the initial confidential submission, including amendments, is publicly filed with the SEC within two days before it issues those follow-on offerings.

 Amends the Jumpstart Our Business Startups Act to direct the SEC to revise its general instructions on Form S-1 to prescribe conditions under which a registration statement that is filed by an issuer (or submitted for confidential review) before its IPO may omit financial disclosure information for historical periods otherwise required.</summary>
</bill>
