<bill session="113" type="s" number="2916" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-11-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-11-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-11-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Restoring America's Watersheds Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Omnibus Public Land Management Act of 2009 to promote watershed health, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412281"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2014-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2014-11-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-11-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/12/2014--Introduced.
Restoring America's Watersheds Act of 2014 - Directs the Forest Service to establish a Water Source Protection Program within the region of the National Forest System west of the 100th Meridian.

Authorizes the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) to enter into water source investment partnerships with specified end water users to protect and restore the condition of National Forest watersheds that provide water to non-federal partners.

Allows the Secretary to produce a water source management plan.

Directs the Secretary to establish a Forest Service Legacy Roads and Trails Remediation Program within such region to:

 carry out critical maintenance and urgent repairs and improvements on National Forest System roads, trails, and bridges; restore fish and other aquatic organism passage by removing or replacing unnatural barriers to the passage of fish and other aquatic organisms; decommission unneeded roads and trails; and carry out associated activities. Requires the Chief of the Forest Service to develop a national strategy to implement the Remediation Program.

Directs the Forest Service to establish a Watershed Condition Framework within such region to:

 evaluate and classify the condition of watersheds, identify for restoration up to five priority watersheds in each National Forest and up to two priority watersheds in each national grassland, develop a watershed restoration action plan for each priority watershed, prioritize restoration activities for each watershed restoration action plan, implement each watershed restoration action plan, and monitor the effectiveness of restoration actions and indicators of watershed health. Reauthorizes the Collaborative Forest Landscape Restoration Fund for FY2015-FY2024.</summary>
</bill>
