<bill session="113" type="s" number="1561" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-10-30">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-10-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-09-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CHIMP Act Amendments of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">CHIMP Act Amendments of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">CHIMP Act Amendments of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to improve provisions relating to the sanctuary system for surplus chimpanzees.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300051"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300002" joined="2013-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2013-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2013-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2013-10-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-09-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-10-30" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-10-30">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Reported by Senator Harkin with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-10-30" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="228">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 228.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2013-10-30" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7684-7685" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S7685" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-10-31">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-12T14:06:00-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Animal protection and human-animal relationships"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Mammals"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/30/2013--Passed Senate amended.
CHIMP Act Amendments of 2013 - Amends the Public Health Service Act, with respect to the lifetime care of chimpanzees used in federally conducted or supported medical research, to: (1) require the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to reserve appropriations through FY2023 for the sanctuary system and other compliant facilities, and (2) allow reservation of funds beyond a total of $30 million if the Secretary determines that doing so would enable the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to operate more efficiently and economically by decreasing the overall federal cost of supporting and maintaining chimpanzees from FY2014-FY2023. Requires such a determination to be reported to Congress and include biennial updates regarding the care and maintenance of the chimpanzees and related costs.

Removes construction and renovation of sanctuary system facilities as a purpose of expenditure of the reserved funds. Requires the use of funds for other compliant facilities to be determined by the Secretary (rather than, as under current law, by the board of directors of the nonprofit entity operating the facility).

Requires the Comptroller General (GAO) to evaluate: (1) the research status of NIH-owned or supported chimpanzees, (2) the cost for the care and maintenance of such chimpanzees, (3) the extent to which requirements that a nonprofit private entity match funding have been met, and (4) any options for cost savings for support and maintenance that may be identified.</summary>
</bill>
