<bill session="113" type="h" number="3993" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-02-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-02-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-02-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Spending Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for a 15 percent reduction in the rates of pay of Members of Congress for pay periods occurring during a year if a Federal budget deficit existed during the most recent fiscal year.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412547"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412436" joined="2014-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412525" joined="2014-02-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-02-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-05">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-05">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/5/2014--Introduced.
Spending Accountability Act - Amends the Legislative Reorganization Act of 1946 to provide that if the total outlays of the government during a fiscal year exceed its total revenues for that fiscal year (federal budget deficit), as determined by the Congressional Budget Office (CBO):

 each annual rate of pay for each Member of Congress shall be reduced by 15% for all pay periods during the next calendar year which begins after that fiscal year, and no adjustment may be made under the Act in any such rate of pay during such calendar year.</summary>
</bill>
