<bill session="113" type="sr" number="587" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-11-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-11-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-11-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution encouraging reunions of Korean-Americans who were divided by the Korean War from their relatives in North Korea.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400222"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412321" joined="2014-11-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-11-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="S6210-6211" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="North Korea"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="South Korea"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/20/2014--Introduced.
Recognizes the significance of North Korea's past willingness to resume reunions of divided family members between North Korea and South Korea.

 Acknowledges North Korea's release in November 2014 of incarcerated American citizens Kenneth Bae and Matthew Miller.

Encourages North Korea to permit reunions between Korean Americans and their relatives in North Korea.

Calls on the Department of State to further prioritize efforts to reunite Korean Americans with their divided family members.

Acknowledges the efforts of the American Red Cross to open channels of communication between Korean Americans and their family members in North Korea.

Encourages the government of South Korea to include U.S. citizens in future family reunions planned with North Korea.

Praises humanitarian efforts to reunite all individuals of Korean descent with their relatives and engender a lasting peace on the Korean Peninsula.</summary>
</bill>
