<bill session="113" type="h" number="3637" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-12-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-12-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-12-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Labor-Management Reporting and Disclosure Act of 1959 to provide whistleblower protection for union employees.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400606"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412216" joined="2013-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412547" joined="2013-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400029" joined="2013-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412395" joined="2013-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412555" joined="2013-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412526" joined="2013-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412477" joined="2013-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412275" joined="2013-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400651" joined="2013-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412397" joined="2013-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412434" joined="2013-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412429" joined="2013-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412226" joined="2013-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400220" joined="2013-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412510" joined="2013-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412569" joined="2013-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400626" joined="2013-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412399" joined="2013-12-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-12-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED10" subcommittee="Workforce Protections" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED02" subcommittee="Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Labor-management relations"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/3/2013--Introduced.
Amends the Labor-Management Reporting and Disclosure Act of 1959 to prescribe whistleblower protections that prohibit a labor organization from discriminating against any of its employees who has: (1) provided information to the labor organization, the Department of Labor, or any other state, local, or federal government authority or law enforcement agency regarding any violation of the Act or any Department or National Labor Relations Board (NLRB) order; (2) testified in any Department or NLRB administrative or enforcement proceeding; (3) filed or instituted any such proceeding; or (4) refused to perform an assigned task that the employee reasonably believed to be in violation of any law, order, or prohibition enforced by the Department or the NLRB.

Prescribes procedures for filing and processing complaints for violations of this Act.

Declares that nothing in this Act shall be construed to: (1) limit employees to remove elected or appointed union officials through a democratic election; or (2) preempt a state or local government from providing additional protections to such employees who allege a violation, provided such protections do not limit the ability of those employees to remove such officials through a democratic ballot.</summary>
</bill>
