<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Placed-on-Calendar-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H2E2C6770256F47FD87E094444C534643" public-private="public" stage-count="1">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HR 3583 PCS: Malala Yousafzai Scholarship Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<calendar>Calendar No. 603</calendar><congress>113th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3583</legis-num>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action><action-date>November 20, 2014</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and placed on the calendar</action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To expand the number of scholarships available to Pakistani women under the Merit and Needs-Based
			 Scholarship Program.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H0A40EBDAC8B541ECB8604BD8FDD735EE" style="OLC">
		<section id="H6709E02E4C1D44379AE018EA853F5379" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Malala Yousafzai Scholarship Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="HDFDDB12F1F8343849E2AE24C3AC4FF4F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header>
			<subsection id="H3F2BC9A175B14C40819AAA017833196E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress makes the following findings:</text>
				<paragraph id="HA527900D45674FE7B1292C6554095E8A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>On October 9, 2012, Malala Yousafzai was shot in the head by Pakistani Taliban on her way home from
			 school.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HEF1E3FE06DBB471DB8A169876F1C08D4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In late 2008, Malala began writing a blog for BBC Urdu under a pseudonym pressing the case for
			 access to education for women and girls despite objections from the
			 Pakistani Taliban.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HEB5E2ACA24894081A341FED808704E37"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Malala’s advocacy for the education of women and girls made her a target of the Taliban.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H87EF124EBFE44B5F89FC4CE53F5B722C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Taliban called Malala’s efforts to highlight the need for education for women and girls an <quote>obscenity</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HD871CB6595684B519C0791F64A6BFA30"><enum>(5)</enum><text>On July 12, 2013, Malala celebrated her 16th birthday by delivering a speech before the United
			 Nations General Assembly in which she said, <quote>So let us wage a glorious struggle against illiteracy, poverty, and terrorism. Let us pick up our
			 books and our pens. They are the most powerful weapons. One child, one
			 teacher, one book, and one pen can change the world. Education is the only
			 solution.</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HD1DBA6F19F5340EBAF01900A53CBA7FC"><enum>(6)</enum><text>According to the United Nation’s 2012 Education for All Global Monitoring Report, <quote>Pakistan has the second largest number of children out of school [in the world]</quote> and <quote>nearly half of rural females have never been to school.</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HBC9B80800DC44B9CBA434AFAF3D3308C"><enum>(7)</enum><text>According to the World Bank, <quote>The benefits of women’s education go beyond higher productivity for 50 percent of the population.
			 More educated women also tend to be healthier, participate more in the
			 formal labor market, earn more income, have fewer children, and provide
			 better health care and education to their children, all of which
			 eventually improve the well-being of all individuals and lift households
			 out of poverty. These benefits also transmit across generations, as well
			 as to their communities at large.</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HCE41C5FF11D542E1AEDAE2EC37FA735F"><enum>(8)</enum><text>According to United Nation’s 2012 Education For All Global Monitoring Report, <quote>education can make a big difference to women’s earnings. In Pakistan, women with a high level of
			 literacy earned 95 percent more than women with no literacy skills.</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H52C09E34491B4785BA1AE9399CFA317F"><enum>(9)</enum><text>In January 2010, Secretary of State Hillary Rodham Clinton stated, <quote>We will open the doors of education to all citizens, but especially to girls and women * * * We are
			 doing all of these things because we have seen that when women and girls
			 have the tools to stay healthy and the opportunity to contribute to their
			 families</quote> well-being, they flourish and so do the people around them.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HC997EB23BE5C47E6A0898785174EFCB8"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The United States provides critical foreign assistance to Pakistan’s education sector to improve
			 access to and the quality of basic and higher education.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HDF667902B1B249389928F4CC0746CBD4"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The Merit and Needs-Based Scholarship Program administered by the United States Agency for
			 International Development (USAID) awards scholarships to academically
			 talented, financially needy Pakistani students from all regions, including
			 remote areas of the country, to pursue bachelor’s or master’s degrees at
			 participating Pakistani universities.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H8D5F8D6565FB463D998BC521B5C155B4"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Fifty percent of the 974 Merit and Needs-Based Scholarships awarded during fiscal year 2013 were
			 awarded to Pakistani women. Historically, only 25 percent of such
			 scholarships have been awarded to women. Starting in the fall of 2013,
			 USAID has committed to provide 50 percent of all scholarships to women.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HA019C6F6F49A46EB9270D2303690B30D"><enum>(13)</enum><text>The United Nations declared July 12, 2013, as <quote>Malala Day</quote>—a global day of support for and recognition of Malala’s bravery and courage in promoting women’s
			 education.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HAD7036E310D54B0FABD05DE6B73586AC"><enum>(14)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On October 10, 2014, Malala Yousafzai became the co-recipient of the Nobel Peace Prize for her <quote>struggle against the suppression of children and young people and for the right of all children to
			 education</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H34BD64F021D14A64A6F930B17F04A5A1"><enum>(15)</enum><text>On December 10, 2012, the United Nations and the Government of Pakistan launched the <quote>Malala Fund for Girls’ Education</quote> to improve girls’ access to education worldwide, with Pakistan donating the first $10,000,000 to
			 the Fund.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H4A63FFF01F14489FA36E46CC87AA4F16"><enum>(16)</enum><text>More than 1,000,000 people around the world have signed the United Nations Special Envoy for Global
			 Education petition calling on the Government of Pakistan to enroll every
			 boy and girl in primary school.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H0436941079AD4274A4376FD7F0E9BA4D"><enum>(17)</enum><text>Pakistani civil society organizations collected almost 2,000,000 signatures from Pakistanis on a
			 petition dedicated to Malala’s cause of education for all.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H7E2B1AA761ED4248BDC050BC76BB33A3"><enum>(18)</enum><text>Engagement with Pakistani diaspora communities in the United States, who have unique perspectives,
			 access, and opportunities to contribute to stability and economic growth
			 in Pakistan, will be a critical element of a successful United States
			 program to promote greater access to education for women and girls.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HA11346C1338F44339283D10489DBA7D3"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header>
			<subsection id="H87CDB6BEAD9F4FB4956406D187F259E5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text>
				<paragraph id="H54EAF4FBB90A4D50B69DE6F4DAB8BBA5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>every individual should have the opportunity to pursue an education;</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HE47028FF53CF4B79A261565D1B891B98"><enum>(2)</enum><text>every individual, regardless of gender, should have the opportunity to pursue an education without
			 fear of discrimination;</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H67E9BB1DD6FF4F98BCAD84A16D2E2076"><enum>(3)</enum><text>educational exchanges promote institutional linkages between the United States and Pakistan; and</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HB891288230514F7E862D794DDBAD3EFF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>recipients of scholarships referred to in section 4 should commit to improving their local
			 communities.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB6CDB6E95E754A29AA1868064FA7BE31"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Continued Support for Educational Initiatives in Pakistan</header><text>Congress encourages the Department of State and the United States Agency for International
			 Development to continue their support for initiatives led by the
			 Government of Pakistan and Pakistani civil society that promote education
			 in Pakistan, especially education for women.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HDF763B578F9B41C9A8B0C25F408109D1"><enum>4.</enum><header>Merit and needs-based scholarship program</header>
			<subsection id="H4D4EFA9C00134347A489171842B5718D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development (referred to in this
			 Act as the <quote>USAID Administrator</quote>) shall award at least 50 percent of the number of scholarships under the Merit and Needs-Based
			 Scholarship Program (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Program</quote>) to women for each of the calendar years 2014 through 2016.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H277495ECF0BA48E9A1696442E49A5E0C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitations</header>
				<paragraph id="H816F4563BDCF4D82B2A340DC5A393015"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Criteria</header><text>The scholarships available under subsection (a) may only be awarded in accordance with other
			 scholarship eligibility criteria already established by USAID.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H38D570C6518241FC9A2085FD7CD78C3D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Academic disciplines</header><text>Scholarships authorized under subsection (a) shall be awarded for a range of disciplines to improve
			 the employability of graduates and to meet the needs of the scholarship
			 recipients.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HFE10BE52F62A4C3CB057C521004D7AFB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Other scholarships</header><text>The USAID Administrator shall make every effort to award 50 percent of the scholarships available
			 under the Program to Pakistani women.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA2F3812F54DF4A948216D31CCAD34806"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Leveraging investment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The USAID Administrator shall, to the greatest extent practicable, consult with and leverage
			 investments by the Pakistani private sector and Pakistani diaspora
			 communities in the United States as part of USAID’s greater effort to
			 improve the quality of, expand access to, and ensure sustainability of
			 education programs in Pakistan.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H53ED369D06354671982DF4260795155E"><enum>5.</enum><header>Annual congressional briefing</header>
			<subsection id="HEF74107D5E864608AB47BA8B44CECBA5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The USAID Administrator shall designate appropriate USAID officials to brief the appropriate
			 congressional committees, not later than 1 year after the date of
			 enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for the next 3 years, on
			 the implementation of section 4.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H0728C40BFC954B8696EAB2AE522AAD62"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The briefing described in subsection (a) shall include, among other relevant information, for the
			 most recently concluded fiscal year—</text>
				<paragraph id="H39D2AB3322CB4D98B52390848BE110BB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the total number of scholarships that were awarded through the Program, including a breakdown by
			 gender;</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H9F31491ED9674F8A9243C186EA6FA33B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the disciplines of study chosen by the scholarship recipients;</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H2CF40DF363404244B943A277CAA08DFD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the percentage of the scholarships that were awarded to students seeking a bachelor’s degree or a
			 master’s degree, respectively;</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H4F0A0932F48B44B6A93CE6BFB0A17DE8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the percentage of scholarship recipients who voluntarily dropped out of school or were
			 involuntarily pushed out of the program for failure to meet program
			 requirements; and</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H0A9DA9CE898A416EB9154F095B11780A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the percentage of scholarship recipients who dropped out of school due to retaliation for seeking
			 an education, to the extent that such information is available.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
	<attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date chamber="House" date="20141119">Passed the House of Representatives November 19, 2014.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk</role></attestation-group></attestation>
	<endorsement display="yes"><action-date>November 20, 2014</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and placed on the calendar</action-desc></endorsement>
</bill>


