<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 S2988 IS: Regulatory Cost Assessment Act of 2014</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2014-12-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 2988</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20141208">December 8, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S346">Mr. Lee</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to establish a Federal regulatory budget and to
			 impose cost controls on that budget, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
			<text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the
		  <quote><short-title>Regulatory Cost Assessment Act of 2014</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="ID518F5DA3416440C8BD6AED8AADC2C174">
			<enum>2.</enum>
			<header>Amendments to the Congressional Budget Act of 1974</header>
			<subsection id="IDDC690FFB495948AB99A04A915FD507BA">
				<enum>(a)</enum>
				<header>Federal regulatory budget cost control system</header>
				<text>Title III of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 is amended—</text><paragraph id="idF8707E4715C74FEE95F7FCA18B71C0ED"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by inserting before section 300 the
			 following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idFBDA228AF4614CB58F0A7209E31AFF7E" style="traditional"><part id="idE85E62A6644146E5830635B2AE1A9398" style="OLC"><enum>A</enum><header>General provisions</header></part><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">and</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="idDE2D37EDDDA743EFA3AE9519E4449835"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new part:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID60123FF28E49468EAE74BCB3D437D0DF" style="OLC">
						<part id="ID5F478B3A1AF043AB9D1673C026B7D611">
							<enum>B</enum>
							<header>Federal regulatory budget cost control</header>
							<section id="ID37A99A93AC8B4867833D6C764314A116">
								<enum>321.</enum>
								<header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this part—</text><paragraph id="idC72D320F9C1744348DA90FCFAFE87564">
									<enum>(1)</enum>
									<text>the term <term>CBO</term> means the Congressional Budget Office;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8982C3265B36405D94434B92B392DF11"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>direct cost of Federal regulation</term> means all costs incurred by, and expenditures required of,  the Federal Government in issuing and
			 enforcing Federal regulations,
			 rules,
			 statements, and legislation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9969B50F76B948E28EF9094F0A9E781D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>Federal regulation,
			 rule,
			 statement, or legislation</term>—</text><subparagraph id="id904D32462DC748F4ADD30D682F3565AC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>includes any guidance document issued after notice and an opportunity for comment in accordance
			 with the requirements for the promulgation of a rule under chapter 5 of
			 title 5, United States Code; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2671D97CD79A47268BFE1F6CF730EAE7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include a Federal regulation,
			 rule,
			 statement, or legislation applying to—</text><clause id="id8682D570F8144FFD8A81B74A2F2C3C7B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the
			 military; or</text></clause><clause id="idCE42A6830EB74FB993157EBEC4CDAB9E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>agency organization, management, or personnel;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id3E5BF03AF2234AEDB9D43696F563B334"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>Federal regulatory cost</term>—</text><subparagraph id="id5D695A2FF5014227A32E956D14FFFE74"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means all costs incurred by, and expenditures required of, the private sector in complying with
			 any Federal regulation, rule,
			 statement, or legislation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0B3A0996E9484953ADC0509B129F8011"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include the value of any benefit under the Federal regulation, rule,
			 statement, or legislation;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idcdf62417afc74478bd463e134cc860bc"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the term <term>gross domestic product</term> means the gross domestic product of the United States during a fiscal year,  consistent with
			 Department of Commerce definitions;</text>
								</paragraph><paragraph id="idD980B7CBEF924D20B2A929263CDD3F2B">
									<enum>(6)</enum>
									<text>the term <term>OMB</term> means the Office of Management and Budget; and</text>
								</paragraph><paragraph id="id5024CBA3BD5B4359B5296770E542B309"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the term <term>regulatory baseline</term> means the projection described in section 323(a) of the Federal regulatory cost for the fiscal
			 year after
			 the date of the projection and the outyears.</text></paragraph></section><section id="idEDA95E92483C4D78B9B509485B870B75"><enum>322.</enum><header>OMB–CBO reports</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, and not later than September
			 15th of each odd-numbered year thereafter, OMB and CBO shall jointly
			 submit to the President,
			 the Senate, and the House of Representatives a report that includes—</text><paragraph id="IDABDEA94F78B74359BBD20F737B10FDB7">
									<enum>(1)</enum>
									<text>a projection of the  direct cost of Federal regulation and the Federal regulatory cost for the
			 first fiscal year beginning after the
			 date of the report and at least each of the 4 ensuing fiscal years;</text>
								</paragraph><paragraph id="ID957F8A6D53724CADAC83A6FF7A8DBCE4">
									<enum>(2)</enum>
									<text>a calculation of the estimated direct cost of Federal regulation  and Federal regulatory cost as a
			 percentage of the
			 gross
			 domestic
			 product;</text>
								</paragraph><paragraph id="ID51FEA64450544A708F089B8013CFFC4E">
									<enum>(3)</enum>
									<text>the reduction in estimated gross domestic product attributable to private sector compliance with
			 all Federal regulations, rules,
			 statements, or legislation;</text>
								</paragraph><paragraph id="ID0D6A0CC7A4184FEF8684B12C3062FC53">
									<enum>(4)</enum>
									<text>a detailed description of the effect on the economy of the United States of Federal regulations,
			 rules,
			 statements, and legislation, which shall be categorized as relating to—</text><subparagraph id="id1AA02CE937374A919465340071DC4161"><enum>(A)</enum><text>regulation of the economy;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id943A6F1667434CA79B00C71F4A628B3C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>security, including homeland security;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB8530566075F4752A534597D14B1E220"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the environment;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE409791B29324D938F69629AF287F997"><enum>(D)</enum><text>health and safety; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5D1A1A5ABB1A40F09620DED69EB3AE47"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Federal budget;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID81DFFEEE43934387AEB3AFF4B04E18B1"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a discussion of the expected reduction in personnel, administrative overhead, and programmatic
			 costs that would be achieved by Federal agencies that issue regulations,
			 rules, or statements with a Federal regulatory cost if the Federal
			 agencies
			 reduced
			 the Federal regulatory cost by 5 percent;
			 and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="IDA6A0ED22676441938BAD7806C48A1457">
									<enum>(6)</enum>
									<text>recommendations for budgeting, technical, and estimating changes to improve the Federal regulatory
			 budgeting process.</text>
								</paragraph></section><section id="IDACC0E2EEB130479DBD2B1820EB0731A3">
								<enum>323.</enum>
								<header>Regulatory baseline</header>
								<subsection id="ID0AA74C48EBB24F73AF513621AD6A4495">
									<enum>(a)</enum>
									<header>In general</header>
									<text>For the first fiscal year that
			 begins at least 120 days after the date of enactment of this section and
			 for every second
			 fiscal year thereafter, CBO, in consultation with OMB, shall submit to the
			 President,
			 the Senate, and the House of Representatives a regulatory
			 baseline, consisting of a
			 projection of the Federal regulatory cost for the fiscal year and at
			 least each of the 4 ensuing fiscal years. In preparing the projection of
			 the regulatory baseline under this subsection, for the second
			 fiscal year covered under the projection and each fiscal year thereafter,
			 CBO shall adjust the baseline for the estimated growth
			 during that fiscal year in the gross domestic product.</text>
								</subsection><subsection id="ID84486FE51475423D97BE6CB038FDD5FB">
									<enum>(b)</enum>
									<header>Deadlines</header><text>The CBO shall submit the regulatory baselines required under subsection (a)—</text><paragraph id="id70ACC7FDDE8541E89CAE407AA12B4F35"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for the first regulatory baseline, not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of
			 this section; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1A8C2EA274B84E289BA89851AB4C6465"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for the second regulatory baseline and each regulatory baseline thereafter, not
			 later than September 15 of the fiscal year before the first fiscal year
			 covered under the regulatory baseline.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="IDAAD09C1E459448A28EB2AEA0575D85C8">
								<enum>324.</enum>
								<header>Establishment of level and allocations</header>
								<subsection id="ID3DA2086BAA7C4B7E8D08ECD833892523">
									<enum>(a)</enum>
									<header>Establishment of level</header><paragraph id="id770DAC8F0CC04051A525FC53CBB7F509"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In addition to the requirements under section 301, a concurrent resolution on the budget for a
			 fiscal year shall set forth the appropriate level for the Federal
			 regulatory cost  for the fiscal year and for at least each of the 4
			 ensuing fiscal years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id822C25906A3C4446AD82B5FD40B2F322"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Default total</header><text>If there is not a level for the Federal regulatory cost that is in effect for a fiscal year under a
			 concurrent resolution on the budget—</text><subparagraph id="idA40F862ACBEB4EEFA67749590536F7D5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for the first fiscal year that
			 begins at least 120 days after the date of enactment of this section, the
			 appropriate level for the Federal regulatory cost for the fiscal year
			 shall be the amount of the first regulatory baseline submitted under
			 section 323; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idBA4B0416EFC14246BE440E08440E98D5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for each fiscal year after the fiscal year described in subparagraph (A), the appropriate level for
			 the Federal regulatory cost for the fiscal year shall be the level for the
			 most recent fiscal year for which such a level was in effect (under
			 subparagraph (A), this subparagraph, or a concurrent resolution on the
			 budget).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="IDD043250204044D8DBB2ECD6CF06545E0">
									<enum>(b)</enum>
									<header>Allocation of totals</header><paragraph id="ID037E3066E71C4D059B5F3D0611248C52">
										<enum>(1)</enum>
										<header>In general</header><text>For the first fiscal year that
			 begins at least 120 days after the date of enactment of this section, and
			 each fiscal year thereafter, the Committee on the Budget of the Senate and
			 the
			 Committee on the Budget of the House of Representatives shall each
			 allocate
			 among each committee of its House
			 and by major functional category the Federal regulatory cost in effect
			 under subsection (a) for such	fiscal year and at
			 least each of the 4 ensuing fiscal years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="IDC1BD6F8CA0C7450091F4D77F3597C865">
										<enum>(2)</enum>
										<header>Suballocations</header><text>As soon as practicable after receiving an allocation under paragraph (1), each committee shall
			 subdivide its allocation among its subcommittees or among programs over
			 which the committee has jurisdiction.</text>
									</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="IDE052BF95ADF84C4483CF735AAF2ADC0A">
									<enum>(c)</enum>
									<header>Point of order</header><paragraph id="IDCE3E9B300A1D40969804F99628C9BAD0">
										<enum>(1)</enum>
										<header>In general</header><text>It shall not be in order in the Senate or the  House of Representatives to consider any bill or
			 resolution, or amendment thereto, which would cause an allocation or
			 suballocation of the Federal regulatory cost made under subsection (b)
			 for a fiscal year to be exceeded.</text>
									</paragraph><paragraph id="ID8D644C18DF4047E1B6D075E3D95BBAFF">
										<enum>(2)</enum>
										<header>Waiver</header>
										<text>A point of order under paragraph (1) may only be waived by the affirmative vote of three-fifths of
			 the Members, duly chosen and sworn.</text>
									</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="IDA9B1FB2D7B954BEB89C200F9A184C561">
									<enum>(d)</enum>
									<header>Determinations by budget committees</header>
									<text>For purposes of this section, the amount of the Federal regulatory cost for a fiscal year and the
			 amount of the Federal regulatory cost of a bill or
			 resolution, or amendment thereto, shall be
			 determined by the Committee on the Budget of the Senate or the Committee
			 on the Budget of the House of Representatives, as the case may be.</text>
								</subsection></section><section id="ID4EEEF61138C140AC83D1A932176558EB">
								<enum>325.</enum>
								<header>Analysis of Federal regulatory cost by congressional budget office</header><subsection id="id43DE51271C0F423EAB0AD72FF66F19C6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header>
									<text display-inline="yes-display-inline">CBO shall prepare for each bill or resolution of a public character reported by any committee of
			 the Senate or the House of Representatives (except the Committee on
			 Appropriations of each House), and submit to such committee—</text>
									<paragraph id="IDDD2187F357DA418EB33773698A9C2A16">
										<enum>(1)</enum>
										<text>an estimate of the costs which would be incurred by the private sector in carrying out or complying
			 with such bill or resolution in the fiscal year in which it is to become
			 effective and in each of the 4 fiscal years following such fiscal year,
			 which shall include a discussion of the methodology used to prepare, and
			 the basis for, each such estimate; and</text>
									</paragraph><paragraph id="IDFDFAABEE2A2548CA951CE52BBD249174">
										<enum>(2)</enum>
										<text>a comparison of the estimate of costs described in paragraph (1) with any available estimates of
			 costs made by such committee or by any Federal agency.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idE1BFB5956DBA4400867A397196D75038"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Look-Back reviews</header><text>CBO shall periodically submit to Congress a report that—</text><paragraph id="id5C980A1F1EE24F13B4DC28AE9B598550"><enum>(1)</enum><text>reviews a sample of laws of a public character for which an estimate was prepared under subsection
			 (a)(1); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id28C1B75AF34F4008883C3B5ADE9AF7AB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>compares the estimates of the costs described in paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a) and the
			 actual costs incurred by the private sector in carrying out or complying
			 with the law in the fiscal year in which it took effect and in each of the
			 4 fiscal years following such fiscal year.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID41B1181D13BF43F7A7DA768FCDE6CF5A">
			<enum>3.</enum>
			<header>President's annual budget submissions</header>
			<text display-inline="no-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/1105">Section 1105(a)</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="id69742d0e565e425d9df29e7949e9f022"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating the second paragraph designated as paragraph (37), relating to outdated or
			 duplicative plans and reports, as added by section 11 of the GPRA
			 Modernization Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/352">Public Law 111–352</external-xref>; 124 Stat. 3881), as
			 paragraph (39); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7b8b476931854b4ba148844ecebade9e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID4246D4CF97DB481B9885A05A947577CA" style="OLC">
					<paragraph id="ID33C8036752DB4BA79D8790BF86B32C67">
						<enum>(40)</enum>
						<text>a regulatory authority budget analysis of the Federal regulatory cost (as defined in section 321 of
			 the
			 Congressional Budget Act of 1974) of
			 complying with all current and proposed Federal regulations and proposals
			 for complying with section 324 of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 for
			 the fiscal year for which the budget is submitted and the 4 fiscal years
			 after that year.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section><section id="IDDA9449B731024E3895073BD13098EE33">
			<enum>4.</enum>
			<header>Estimation and disclosure of costs of federal regulation</header>
			<subsection id="ID6DC402B544DB498291950D094D2177D8">
				<enum>(a)</enum>
				<header>Costs to private sector of new federal regulations</header>
				<text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/6">Chapter 6</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, popularly known as the <quote>Regulatory Flexibility Act</quote>, is amended—</text>
				<paragraph id="IDE8696BA6ED3243F8B4F3FEBA15E7EBA5">
					<enum>(1)</enum>
					<text>in section 603—</text><subparagraph id="idFCC5DBB26349419B8DB304661776EB2B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a), in the second sentence, by inserting before the period the following: <quote>and shall discuss in detail whether the cost to businesses of complying with the proposed rule will
			 vary depending on the size of the business and, if so, to what extent	the
			 cost will vary and what factors contribute to the variation</quote>;</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID5E6DB278272445D1B81A02FEB1058304">
						<enum>(B)</enum>
						<text>in subsection (c)—</text><clause id="id94587517AAEC49E8AB8B0E6BF1917D83"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (1), (2), (3), and (4) as subparagraphs (A), (B), (C), and (D),
			 respectively, and adjusting the margin accordingly;</text></clause><clause id="idA01CF6EF2FA44694BE514A7A811BE94D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>(1)</quote> after <quote>(c)</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="id544CDE6A4ACF40E8A1C92E4BF8F83C08"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Consistent with the</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB698BFADA56940DFA6A46F5B9D1982F8" style="OLC"><paragraph id="idF25CA2499ED54E02B241EFC61CCD5667" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The analysis of significant alternatives to the proposed rule shall include a detailed analysis of
			 the costs and benefits of the proposed rule and each alternative, which
			 shall separately address the costs and benefits for each industry.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idE33E097DAE204D48936D112A53CADE6C" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Consistent with the</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idEEFB6A34E1A44F6584B1078D35553DCA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="IDA87E8E57EA874CE885B6715CF27E1A6B" style="OLC">
							<subsection id="IDD26C1C50EACF4118B5C356539F0C66E1">
								<enum>(e)</enum>
								<text>Each initial regulatory flexibility analysis shall also contain a description of the nature and
			 amount of monetary costs that will be incurred by small entities, other
			 businesses, and individuals in complying with the proposed rule.</text>
							</subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID6070EE67D6D44816AC661873102A9ED1">
					<enum>(2)</enum>
					<text>in section 604(a)—</text><subparagraph id="idd0d78da3a1c14cff91b6742640860d0b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the first paragraph designated as paragraph (6) (relating to minimization of significant
			 economic impacts), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idCC9BDB8AAE26436C9A4B250E496FAD63"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating the second paragraph (6) (relating to covered agencies), as paragraph (8); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="IDDF348E7CF27F428AB9F4E3929DC5DD09">
						<enum>(C)</enum>
						<text>by inserting after paragraph (6) the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID3E16B606980047679EEDE07E12627740" style="OLC">
							<paragraph id="IDC24EAFA0AC864FD6BE50F31889BB6760">
								<enum>(7)</enum>
								<text>a statement of the nature and amount of monetary costs that will be incurred by small entities,
			 other businesses, and individuals in complying with the rule; and</text>
							</paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID525259422B2E4931A108B7937014E5E4">
					<enum>(3)</enum>
					<text>in section 607, by inserting before the period the following: <quote>, except that estimates of monetary costs under sections 603(d) and 604(a)(7) shall only be in the
			 form of a numerical description</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID798C68ACA97C44F78594C66F6AA4A53C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Agency reports</header><text>Each agency that prepares an initial regulatory flexibility analysis under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/6">chapter 6</external-xref> of title 5,
			 United States Code, shall, at the same time submit to each House of
			 Congress, the Congressional Budget Office, and the Office of Management
			 and Budget a cost estimate and cost benefit analysis of
			 any new proposed regulations, rules,
			 or statements that would have a Federal regulatory cost (as defined in
			 section 321
			 of
			 the Congressional Budget Act of 1974, as added by this Act) of at least
			 $10,000,000 for any fiscal year.</text>
			</subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idBF3DD17454FF420CB6473680C7F194A2"><enum>5.</enum><header>Guidance documents</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id57B69F88627D4FD38FC989A47DF2E517"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idCDBFD3321A8D432E87A5C157A59875E7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the terms <term>agency</term> and <term>rule</term> have the meanings given such terms in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/551">section 551</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id449CD272781646EE9E8ECE37D8458069"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>guidance document</term> means an agency statement of general applicability and future effect, other than a rule, that sets
			 forth a policy on a statutory, regulatory,  or technical issue or an
			 interpretation of a statutory or regulatory issue.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE92E6A00847247DF9C4BD5CC42B7F740"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation on guidance documents</header><text>An agency may not issue a guidance document unless the agency—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC7B8A8B201154A9EB508EDEFF3541DA5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>issues the guidance document after notice and an opportunity for comment in accordance with the
			 requirements for the promulgation of a rule under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 5,
			 United States Code; or</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4A3645DEF5F24BFC8EB6C7E2830C6587"><enum>(2)</enum><text>before the effective date of the guidance document, submits to Congress a report that—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4583B3F29CF246DF89C19C6E202BA62D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>certifies that the guidance document is not a rule; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC8736C1ECF494BCCBDD3C09ACABE2647"><enum>(B)</enum><text>explains in detail why the guidance document does not satisfy the definition of a rule.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id93351363514A4E14BBBCD0075199B82B"><enum>6.</enum><header>Study of nonmajor rules</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC692E908D90A4907B8D068624F307E90"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8C0C70A86B8E4A26BFD612D26C3A10D4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>agency</term> has the meaning given that term in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/551">section 551</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD40470872EC840039349A09025AEC698"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>covered guidance document</term> means any guidance document that has resulted or is likely to result in an annual effect on the
			 economy of not less than $10,000,000;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id86DA4D60EDFC408087A645A0FA73EBA7"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>covered nonmajor rule</term> means any rule that has resulted in or is likely to
			 result in   an annual effect on the economy of not less than $10,000,000
			 and not more than $100,000,000;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id87BEF366809D413EAC206C0C917BD9B8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>guidance document</term> means an agency statement of general applicability and future effect, other than a rule, that sets
			 forth a policy on a statutory, regulatory,  or technical issue or an
			 interpretation of a statutory or regulatory issue;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idDB47759B1D414C779CBB8F8504BD62D9"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>Federal regulatory cost</term> has the meaning given that term under section 321 of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974, as
			 added by section 2 of this Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id745BBCC0DFB243D6A659BE32B971BECC"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>rule</term> has the meaning given that term in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/804">section 804</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5F689DA60EAA4F279A1B92531299C07E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act and every 2 years thereafter, the
			 Comptroller General of the
			 United States shall submit
			 to Congress a report regarding covered nonmajor rules and covered
			 guidance documents, which shall
			 include, for the 4-year period immediately preceding the report—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6F82D37D730B4F00B18B443743859744"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of covered nonmajor rules promulgated;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1EE71D649FDB4626903E519DFF0B4DDB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the number of covered nonmajor rules implemented;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idFF1C3A1264D74E3997787CA3E54F9576"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the number of covered guidance documents developed;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9D63DA1E0EE4438B902D99AA48CBADE1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the number of covered guidance documents issued;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddcadf81b110f49159cb1bd57b7369c37"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the Federal regulatory cost of each covered nonmajor rule implemented;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id662369983BCE4DE2AC8CC5E80D7511CA"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the Federal regulatory cost of each covered guidance document issued;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7CA961A309064298A967D1790AA00C16"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the aggregate Federal regulatory cost of all covered nonmajor rules implemented;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6794F2BF15514AE5A6B92B69A163DDB5"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the aggregate Federal regulatory cost of all covered guidance documents issued; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1ADB9449EABC406A8BACB3127DD20D9C"><enum>(9)</enum><text>a discussion of any covered nonmajor rule for which an initial regulatory flexibility analysis was
			 prepared under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/603">section 603</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, a final
			 regulatory flexibility analysis was prepared under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/604">section 604</external-xref> of title 5,
			 United States Code, or a cost benefit analysis was prepared that
			 underestimated the actual Federal regulatory cost of implementing the
			 covered nonmajor rule.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


