<bill session="113" type="s" number="2288" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-05-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Expanding Carbon Capture through Enhanced Oil Recovery Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to expand existing tax credits to encourage the capture, utilization, and sequestration of carbon dioxide.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300084"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412554" joined="2014-11-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/5/2014--Introduced.
Expanding Carbon Capture through Enhanced Oil Recovery Act of 2014 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to revise and expand the tax credit program for carbon dioxide sequestration by directing the Secretary of the Treasury to establish: (1) a process for annual competitive bidding for carbon dioxide sequestration credits, (2) a certification process that guarantees the availability of the credit for private sector companies investing in commercial-scale carbon capture projects, (3) criteria for revoking the certification of a project that does not meet specified timelines for beginning construction and operations and that makes materially inaccurate representations in the bidding process, (4) an external review of the annual competitive bidding process by a panel of independent experts to improve such process and ensure its transparency and effectiveness, and (5) a review process for determining the actual and projected increase in federal revenues attributable to the competitive bidding process and credit allocations under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
