<bill session="113" type="s" number="1916" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-01-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-01-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-01-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HELP Rural Communities Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Helping Expand Lending Practices in Rural Communities Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act to provide for an application process for interested parties to apply for a county to be designated as a rural area, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300072"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412320" joined="2014-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412492" joined="2014-01-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-01-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S326-327"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S327" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-16">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2672"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Consumer Financial Protection Bureau"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/14/2014--Introduced.
Helping Expand Lending Practices in Rural Communities Act of 2014 or the HELP Rural Communities Act of 2014 - Amends the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act to direct the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB) to establish an application process under which a person who lives or does business in a state may apply to have a county designated as a rural area for purposes of a federal consumer financial law.

Prescribes criteria for the CFPB to consider when evaluating such an application.

Requires the CFPB to enter each such application into a sortable, downloadable database publicly accessible through its website.</summary>
</bill>
