<bill session="113" type="s" number="2514" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ORDEAL Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ozone Regulatory Delay and Extension of Assessment Length Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Clean Air Act to delay the review and revision of the national ambient air quality standards for ozone.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400134"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412251" joined="2014-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="402675" joined="2014-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2014-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300030" joined="2014-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2014-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412496" joined="2014-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="2014-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412322" joined="2014-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300088" joined="2014-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2014-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="2014-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2014-06-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-23">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3900-3901"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="4947"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/24/2014--Introduced.
Ozone Regulatory Delay and Extension of Assessment Length Act of 2014 or the ORDEAL Act of 2014 - Amends the Clean Air Act to lengthen from five years to ten years the intervals at which the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) is required to review and revise air quality criteria and primary and secondary national ambient air quality standards (NAAQS). Eliminates the EPA's authority to review and revise criteria or promulgate new standards for ozone concentrations earlier or more frequently than required. Prohibits the EPA from reviewing and revising NAAQS for ozone concentrations before February 1, 2018. Requires the EPA to complete a thorough review of the standards and make revisions not later December 31, 2018.

Lengthens from five years to ten years the intervals at which an independent scientific review committee is required to review air quality criteria and NAAQS and recommend any new standards or revisions to existing criteria and standards. Delays the review by an independent scientific review committee of NAAQS for ozone concentrations until February 1, 2018.</summary>
</bill>
