<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H63421C47739F459F803C0C25212A92F9" public-private="public" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HR 5656 EH: Global Food Security Act of 2014</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress> <session>2d Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 5656</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To authorize a comprehensive strategic approach for United States foreign assistance to developing countries to reduce global poverty and hunger, achieve food security and improved nutrition, promote sustainable agricultural-led economic growth, improve nutritional outcomes, especially for women and children, build resilience among vulnerable populations, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HD5B9DFA04D194F00AF894F45AED3BA31" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9309C66E25BB48D59D72BEAEBE73B1E4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Global Food Security Act of 2014</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H151513EB5F604C28ABFFFED4BF783183"><enum>2.</enum><header>Statement of policy objectives; sense of Congress</header> 
<subsection id="H5A3611D99DBB4DE5A172DBC9261A6E9E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Statement of policy objectives</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is in the national security interest of the United States to promote global food security and nutrition, consistent with national food security investment plans, which is reinforced through programs, activities, and initiatives that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H82A4938E55F649609E2D6507522D0BD9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">accelerate inclusive, agricultural-led economic growth that reduces global poverty, hunger, and malnutrition, particularly among women and children;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H56C38F944E4D4DA6B674DE0F29D0E5A3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>increase the productivity, incomes, and livelihoods of small-scale producers, especially women, by working across agricultural value chains and expanding producer access to local and international markets;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H807C5A60F27448BBAA613DC7E4D08401"><enum>(3)</enum><text>build resilience to food shocks among vulnerable populations and households while reducing reliance upon emergency food assistance;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB84965E4ED094C5B865B367F060C635C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>create an enabling environment for agricultural growth and investment, including through the promotion of secure and transparent property rights; </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H32EAF4313C1849579AE6A738A5E06810"><enum>(5)</enum><text>improve the nutritional status of women and children, with a focus on reducing child stunting, including through the promotion of highly nutritious foods, diet diversification, and nutritional behaviors that improve maternal and child health; </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H05539CE79C724F1D95CE7E77B201AC7A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>align with and leverage broader United States investments in trade, economic growth, science and technology, maternal and child health, and water, sanitation, and hygiene; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2DA365B6F01840E89FF14E6B1224A3F7"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure the effective use of United States taxpayer dollars to further these objectives.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H192A0DAE08584793B4B903C254F100DD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of the Congress that the President, in providing assistance to implement the Global Food Security Strategy, should—</text> 
<paragraph id="H6E544D50AFF34EA7A4375CBEF7C9B0D2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>coordinate, through a whole-of-government approach, the efforts of relevant Federal departments and agencies to implement the Global Food Security Strategy;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFCBA07485738400D80DC042114DA041E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">utilize, to the extent possible, open and streamlined solicitations to allow for the participation of a wide range of implementing partners via the most appropriate contracting mechanism; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFBA00C5611F34851B661A7FDB7EAAA3E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>continue to strengthen existing partnerships between developing country institutions of agricultural sciences with universities in the United States, with a focus on building the capacities of developing nation universities in agriculture.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HC8CEE97EB48A4EA38EE5B8BE8DACC159" commented="no"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H5263AA95E731403BB4E3EFFB629A4550"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agriculture</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>agriculture</term> means crops, livestock, fisheries, and forestries.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H87EAA21E41024456936EF10964E54B83" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HAB08E7576F4F412C960DF3CF6043D811" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0523727B1B344613822F18EC8A5C1BFA" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3F48478979394F8EA79ED088E8754EA0" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Appropriations of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD32E855CD71249CBA831478B6F774258" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1AEDB316DFF84A62A2B87F170481584D" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives</committee-name>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF1028441DB4F43ED94E91C638834284B" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives</committee-name>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1C2A86578F624442AD024D50E15D6290" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Feed the future innovation labs</header><text>The term <term>Feed the Future Innovation Labs</term> means research partnerships led by United States universities that advance solutions to reduce global hunger, poverty, and malnutrition.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6DBF39817B384E68A52B55C75B9D9190" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Global Food Security Strategy</header><text>The term <term>Global Food Security Strategy</term> means the strategy developed and implemented pursuant to section 4(a).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8CA59C469BBE4A0BA741DC1B6B44FB24" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Food and nutrition security</header><text>The term <term>food and nutrition security</term> means access to, and availability, utilization, and stability of, sufficient food to meet caloric and nutritional needs for an active and healthy life.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDDEADEB3FBAB404CAD35ED50838F9DDE" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Malnutrition</header><text>The term <term>malnutrition</term> means poor nutritional status caused by nutritional deficiency or excess.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H38AAD677A5C84C439D3E83825B04D453" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Resilience</header><text>The term <term>resilience</term> means the ability of people, households, communities, countries, and systems to mitigate, adapt to, and recover from shocks and stresses to food security in a manner that reduces chronic vulnerability and facilitates inclusive growth.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H34A02E9B6EBD43CB9A85D310D2BA9F37" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Relevant Federal departments and agencies</header><text>The term <term>relevant Federal departments and agencies</term> means the United States Agency for International Development, the Department of Agriculture, the Department of Commerce, the Department of State, the Department of the Treasury, the Millennium Challenge Corporation, the Overseas Private Investment Corporation, the Peace Corps, the Office of the United States Trade Representative, the United States African Development Foundation, the United States Geological Survey, and any other department or agency specified by the President for purposes of this section.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H022EBB8005B646D5B606E0F123EA398A" commented="no"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Small-scale producer</header><text>The term <term>small-scale producer</term> means farmers, pastoralists, foresters, and fishers that have a low-asset base and limited resources, including land, capital, skills and labor, and, in the case of farmers, typically farm on fewer than 5 hectares of land.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H17525CF3453F4C5AAF155D749EA217B2"><enum>4.</enum><header>Comprehensive global food security strategy</header> 
<subsection id="H958550D70AE241D6B03E4EDD02CCB55F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Strategy</header><text>The President shall coordinate the development and implementation of a United States whole-of-government strategy to accomplish the policy objectives set forth in section 2(a), which shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE5B9C98FD2DC45738DD84F9BE49D635C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>support and be aligned with country-owned agriculture, nutrition, and food security policy and investment plans developed with input from relevant governmental and nongovernmental sectors within partner countries and regional bodies, including representatives of the private sector, agricultural producers, including women and small-scale producers, international and local civil society organizations, faith-based organizations, research institutions, and farmers as reasonable and appropriate;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE09F69EF3F0B4A429798C7A5378402BD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>support inclusive agricultural value chain development, with small-scale producers, especially women, gaining greater access to the inputs, skills, networking, bargaining power, financing, and market linkages needed to sustain their long-term economic prosperity;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H82CBBA42D8D04D3CA546E37AC85178CE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>seek to improve the nutritional status of women and children, particularly during the critical first 1,000-day window until a child reaches 2 years of age, with a focus on reducing child stunting;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4FAC6813187646A8BE4E1B625D0A5E3C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>seek to ensure the long-term success of programs by building the capacity of local organizations and institutions;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8DEDCE65CE60472A862297346A5BE3D2"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">integrate resilience strategies into food security programs, such that chronically vulnerable populations are better able to build safety nets, secure livelihoods, access markets, and access opportunities from longer-term economic growth;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1105F8BECC6F4CBD837227161295C669"><enum>(6)</enum><text>develop community and producer resiliency to natural disasters, emergencies, and natural occurrences that adversely impact agricultural yield;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD891F4B56B4C4B3FA4430D9F0F08810C"><enum>(7)</enum><text>harness science, technology, and innovation, including the research conducted at Feed the Future Innovation Labs, or any successor entities, throughout the United States;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD89006E657FA4DE482814C03EF204503"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">support integrating agricultural development activities among food insecure populations living in proximity to designated national parks or wildlife areas to support wildlife conservation efforts;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB74316097C2146E497F6A3869D790DF7"><enum>(9)</enum><text>leverage resources and expertise through partnerships with the private sector, farm organizations, cooperatives, civil society, faith-based organizations, research entities, and academic institutions;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE09D2B4050FF40FAB72836E06EDD6FB3"><enum>(10)</enum><text>support collaboration, as appropriate, between United States universities and public and private institutions in developing countries to promote agricultural development and innovation;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5AF71773FF6744D4A7C6862293FDEE4F"><enum>(11)</enum><text>set clear and transparent selection criteria for target countries, regions, and intended beneficiaries of assistance to implement the Global Food Security Strategy;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF1EAAB7B91FD476591D41AB3046E9A7F"><enum>(12)</enum><text>set specific and measurable goals, targets, and time frames, and a plan of action consistent with the policy objectives described in section 2(a);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H174258FE03E44C0EAA2DE8010BB46DEF"><enum>(13)</enum><text>seek to ensure that target countries respect and promote the lawful land tenure rights of local communities, particularly those of women and small-scale producers; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBBFBCBBE948D4409A7C93AB2275578A0"><enum>(14)</enum><text>include criteria and methodology for graduating countries from assistance to implement the Global Food Security Strategy once the countries have achieved certain benchmarks.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE0463F29C5634C70BCA020A0CBAFDA8D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>The President shall coordinate, through a whole-of-government approach, the efforts of relevant Federal departments and agencies in the implementation of the Global Food Security Strategy by—</text> 
<paragraph id="H58365BAE185C4AFAB65128E94DAB7912"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establishing monitoring and evaluation systems, coherence, and coordination across relevant Federal departments and agencies; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB27403DE2D7D4D6BB4DF13583DA02E7F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establishing platforms for regular consultation and collaboration with key stakeholders, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7196353DA1874D30B875657CF527F253"><enum>(A)</enum><text>multilateral institutions;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H15CEE53EEB8B454B8A32334EE7AC966D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>private voluntary organizations;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2B67934732ED4B35896526A17E95E6D1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>cooperatives;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H73EF1C20F2AD428FA1805B5EA5087B26"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the private sector;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA6FAAD5E902F4E0286BC21A78FF0F20C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>local nongovernmental and civil society organizations;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9E29B238101642BDAA8EC0CD1ACDADCD"><enum>(F)</enum><text>faith-based organizations;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H47D6346EF41544F9890B03C53588843D"><enum>(G)</enum><text>congressional committees; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2D0034A8E2544D9C9966E78DC7417326"><enum>(H)</enum><text>other stakeholders, as appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> </section> 
<section id="H820AA6EF89054E10A651F08F452E5FA8"><enum>5.</enum><header>Assistance to implement the Global Food Security Strategy</header> 
<subsection id="H30F488C7D1DF416E9877454504BC0602"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President is authorized to provide assistance to implement the Global Food Security Strategy pursuant to the authorities of section 103, section 103A, title XII of chapter 2 of part I, and chapter 4 of part II of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2151a">22 U.S.C. 2151a</external-xref>, 2151a–1, 2220a et seq., and 2346 et seq.) notwithstanding any other provision of law.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6B97D3C3BB5E4EEA9D67044DFD05999F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Monitoring and evaluation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President should seek to ensure that assistance to implement the Global Food Security Strategy is provided under established parameters for a rigorous accountability system to monitor and evaluate progress and impact of the strategy, including by reporting to the appropriate congressional committees and the public on an annual basis.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBA7F62771CB74EFEB5FD259C3060CC73"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the President $1,000,600,000 for fiscal year 2015 to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H106AF606F18F421691ED35ED43FCB3DA"><enum>6.</enum><header>Report</header> 
<subsection id="H6A7446B534AE43839CF4218ED1C3E96E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that describes the status of the implementation of the Global Food Security Strategy.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H43567D5140F34264B070B36D9B3C49D2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Content</header><text>The report required under subsection (a) shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H5C6886DAED4841E79D8129CAF3092DA9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">contain a summary of the Global Food Security Strategy as an appendix;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAF810A90907B45A59537ABC9163D29BF"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify any substantial changes made in the Global Food Security Strategy during the preceding calendar year;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H60BAD494115344D39688A50AF337242B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identify the indicators that will be used to measure results, set benchmarks for progress over time, and establish mechanisms for reporting results in an open and transparent manner;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H802F5A395C9A48CF930BA715DD501566"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">describe the progress made in implementing the Global Food Security Strategy;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5908BD31CFE24165BFC9FFFAAAF795E1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>assess the progress and results of implementing international food and nutrition security programming;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H208D817429E14462B4E2A273B8C5395A"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">contain a transparent, open, and detailed accounting of spending by relevant Federal departments and agencies to implement the Global Food Security Strategy, including by listing all recipients of funding or partner organizations and, to the extent possible, describing their activities;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3321B0721B094CE7AB8B2DBBE8B7043C"><enum>(7)</enum><text>identify any United States legal or regulatory impediments that could obstruct the effective implementation of the programming referred to in paragraph (5);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H990BB8A6CF524280A6E7F1DB5E4D1615"><enum>(8)</enum><text>contain a clear gender analysis of programming that includes established disaggregated gender indicators to better analyze outcomes for food productivity, income growth, equity in access to inputs, jobs and markets, and nutrition;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8D0B346D6EDA4AD3915277492DE7FFF5"><enum>(9)</enum><text>describe the strategies and benchmarks for graduating target countries and monitoring any graduated target countries;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB483A6E59981487CA578A4DCFC5A5E27"><enum>(10)</enum><text>assess efforts to coordinate United States international food security and nutrition programs, activities, and initiatives with—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H8EA0D9F116BC40C384EF1E168AE43E0C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>other bilateral donors;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBF606B591CDB4AB0BAC5EEA2BDF70FB6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>international and multilateral organizations;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA8FABAF6C1274C6B87CC9E26C49AB0F5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>international financial institutions;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H53B90291CFE74C37BE968793D32A6644"><enum>(D)</enum><text>host country governments;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7BBA0FFD7BC14BCFA6DDD8CA0EB1E012"><enum>(E)</enum><text>international and local private voluntary, nongovernmental, faith-based organizations, and civil society organizations; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H05A0D1B693A64C3CA6DF7416102CC0D1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>other stakeholders;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H805E272F8E2D4788B89940DF9DBFAA8D"><enum>(11)</enum><text>assess United States Government-facilitated private investment in related sectors and the impact of private sector investment in target countries;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6EF332509A7D430A8C3D150664BCFE06"><enum>(12)</enum><text>include consultation with relevant United States Government agencies in the preparation of the report; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB9E1C4CA798C4D358264ED2784CF3BB7"><enum>(13)</enum><text>incorporate a plan for regularly reviewing and updating strategies, partnerships, and programs and sharing lessons learned with a wide range of stakeholders.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H52443D0D0BEC4E90BEB0064285E05DC2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Public availability of information</header><text>The information referred to in subsection (b) shall be made publicly accessible in a timely manner on a consolidated website.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20141210" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives December 10, 2014.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation>
<endorsement display="yes"></endorsement>
</bill> 


