<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="H57180087909F48B2AB88BC4A93006FDD" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Engrossed-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HRES 7 EH: Electing Members to certain standing committees of the House of Representatives.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2013-01-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">IV</distribution-code> 
<congress display="no">113th CONGRESS</congress> 
<session display="no">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. RES. 7</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="yes">In the House of Representatives, U. S.,</current-chamber>
<action>
<action-date date="20130103">January 3, 2013</action-date>
</action> 
<legis-type display="yes">RESOLUTION</legis-type> 
<official-title display="no">Electing Members to certain standing committees of the House of Representatives.</official-title> 
</form> 
<resolution-body style="traditional" id="H3C18ED5F6687485194404FFA381311C9"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H043BF641E93742328D9665A62D2ADE3C"><text>That the following named Members be, and are hereby, elected to the following standing committees of the House of Representatives:</text> 
<paragraph id="H5BD2526FD1C44321B451CD1CDAC0EF36"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Committee on Agriculture</header><text>Mr. Peterson, Mr. McIntyre, Mr. David Scott of Georgia, Mr. Costa, Mr. Walz, Mr. Schrader, Mr. Owens, Ms. Fudge, Mr. McGovern, Mrs. Negrete McLeod, Mr. Vela, Ms. Michelle Lujan Grisham of New Mexico, and Ms. Kuster.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HADB2940784B149F8895AB66EDFB60A91" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Committee on Appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Mrs. Lowey, Ms. Kaptur, Mr. Visclosky, Mr. Serrano, Ms. DeLauro, Mr. Moran, Mr. Pastor of Arizona, Mr. Price of North Carolina, Ms. Roybal-Allard, Mr. Farr, Mr. Fattah, Mr. Bishop of Georgia, Ms. Lee of California, Mr. Schiff, Mr. Honda, Ms. McCollum, Mr. Israel, Mr. Ryan of Ohio, Mr. Ruppersberger, Ms. Wasserman Schultz, Mr. Cuellar, and Ms. Pingree of Maine.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H26723D34591C44A5AC6492F37E2C1BC3" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Committee on Armed Services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Mr. Smith of Washington, Ms. Loretta Sanchez of California, Mr. McIntyre, Mr. Brady of Pennsylvania, Mr. Andrews, Mrs. Davis of California, Mr. Langevin, Mr. Larsen of Washington, Mr. Cooper, Ms. Bordallo, Mr. Courtney, Mr. Loebsack, Ms. Tsongas, Mr. Owens, Mr. Garamendi, Mr. Johnson of Georgia, Ms. Hanabusa, Ms. Speier, Mr. Barber, Ms. Shea-Porter, Mr. Maffei, Mr. Kilmer, Mr. Castro of Texas, Ms. Duckworth, Mr. Peters of California, Mr. Enyart, Mr. Gallego, and Mr. Veasey.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4B0F2E71DF6B49C4ADF5B608EEC461DC" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Committee on the Budget</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Mr. Van Hollen, Ms. Schwartz, Mr. Yarmuth, Mr. Pascrell, Mr. Ryan of Ohio, Ms. Wasserman Schultz, Ms. Moore, Ms. Castor of Florida, Ms. Lee of California, Mr. Cicilline, and Mr. Heck of Washington.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H00AF2A76EF174130852FC7E7AAE8CE54" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Committee on Education and the Workforce</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Mr. George Miller of California, Mr. Andrews, Mr. Scott of Virginia, Mr. Hinojosa, Mrs. McCarthy of New York, Mr. Tierney, Mr. Holt, Mrs. Davis of California, Mr. Grijalva, Mr. Bishop of New York, Mr. Loebsack, Mr. Courtney, Ms. Fudge, Mr. Polis, Mr. Sablan, Mr. Yarmuth, Ms. Wilson of Florida, and Ms. Bonamici.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF8FBB1F10B4348B5B0F4570B584A1D5E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Committee on Energy and Commerce</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Mr. Waxman, Mr. Dingell, Mr. Markey, Mr. Pallone, Mr. Rush, Ms. Eshoo, Mr. Engel, Mr. Gene Green of Texas, Ms. DeGette, Mrs. Capps, Mr. Doyle, Ms. Schakowsky, Mr. Matheson, Mr. Butterfield, Mr. Barrow, Ms. Matsui, Mrs. Christensen, Ms. Castor of Florida, Mr. Sarbanes, Mr. McNerney, Mr. Braley of Iowa, Mr. Welch, Mr. Ben Ray Luján of New Mexico, and Mr. Tonko.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7970B417B0404D03BFC38496247B9AD7"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Committee on Ethics</header><text>Ms. Linda T. Sánchez of California.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF86422F8851B445894EE9DF088AB664A" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Committee on Financial Services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Ms. Waters, Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York, Mr. Gutierrez, Ms. Velázquez, Mr. Watt, Mr. Sherman, Mr. Meeks, Mr. Capuano, Mr. Hinojosa, Mr. Clay, Mrs. McCarthy of New York, Mr. Lynch, Mr. David Scott of Georgia, Mr. Al Green of Texas, Mr. Cleaver, Ms. Moore, Mr. Ellison, Mr. Perlmutter, Mr. Himes, Mr. Peters of Michigan, Mr. Carney, Ms. Sewell of Alabama, Mr. Foster, Mr. Kildee, Mr. Murphy of Florida, Mr. Delaney, Ms. Sinema, and Mrs. Beatty.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD30A5F428D384FE48A7EE74599CCF8C2" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Committee on Foreign Affairs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Mr. Engel, Mr. Faleomavaega, Mr. Sherman, Mr. Meeks, Mr. Sires, Mr. Connolly, Mr. Deutch, Mr. Higgins, Ms. Bass, Mr. Keating, Mr. Cicilline, Mr. Grayson, Mr. Vargas, Mr. Schneider, Mr. Kennedy, Mr. Bera, and Mr. Lowenthal.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAB3AC2B13E0D4530969F6521D61FD8B8"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Committee on Homeland Security</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi, Ms. Loretta Sanchez of California, Ms. Jackson Lee of Texas, Ms. Clarke, Mr. Higgins, Mr. Richmond, Mr. Keating, Ms. Hahn, Mr. Barber, Mr. Payne, Mr. O'Rourke, and Ms. Gabbard.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA6D8F0E3BF6D4FFE8E62C211291980D8"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Committee on House Administration</header><text>Mr. Brady of Pennsylvania.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0436922F95D8452B9BDD367DD1DC7F75" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Committee on the Judiciary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Mr. Conyers, Mr. Nadler, Mr. Scott of Virginia, Mr. Watt, Ms. Lofgren, Ms. Jackson Lee of Texas, Mr. Cohen, Mr. Johnson of Georgia, Mr. Pierluisi, Mr. Quigley, Ms. Chu, Mr. Deutch, Ms. Bass, Mr. Richmond, Ms. DelBene, Mr. Garcia, and Mr. Jeffries. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H697065F37E2B4BD0BBDDB0A43AB183B4" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Committee on Natural Resources</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Mr. Markey, Mr. DeFazio, Mr. Faleomavaega, Mr. Pallone, Mrs. Napolitano, Mr. Holt, Mr. Grijalva, Ms. Bordallo, Mr. Costa, Mr. Sablan, Ms. Tsongas, Mr. Pierluisi, Ms. Hanabusa, Mr. Cárdenas, Mr. Horsford, Mr. Huffman, and Mr. Ruiz.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE722AEF3EFED4F9996B5A47171ABCBE8" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Mr. Cummings, Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York, Ms. Norton, Mr. Tierney, Mr. Clay, Mr. Lynch, Mr. Cooper, Mr. Connolly, Mr. Quigley, Ms. Speier, Mr. Cartwright, and Mr. Pocan.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H23E588B07F5B40F7B57E7D3162444E61" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Committee on Rules</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Ms. Slaughter, Mr. McGovern, Mr. Hastings of Florida, and Mr. Polis.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC136E65690B44F65A168DCDF45C3CD3F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Ms. Eddie Bernice Johnson of Texas, Ms. Lofgren, Mr. Lipinski, Ms. Edwards, Ms. Wilson of Florida, Ms. Bonamici, and Mr. Swalwell of California.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H640510F5FA064AB8AEADEBF8F2373918" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(17)</enum><header>Committee on Small Business</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Ms. Velázquez, Mr. Schrader, Ms. Clarke, Ms. Chu, and Ms. Meng.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2EABF9F906B646F3889B4FE7EBDDD2FE" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(18)</enum><header>Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Mr. Rahall, Mr. DeFazio, Ms. Norton, Mr. Nadler, Ms. Brown of Florida, Ms. Eddie Bernice Johnson of Texas, Mr. Cummings, Mr. Larsen of Washington, Mr. Capuano, Mr. Bishop of New York, Mr. Michaud, Mrs. Napolitano, Mr. Lipinski, Mr. Walz, Mr. Cohen, Mr. Sires, Ms. Edwards, Mr. Garamendi, Mr. Carson of Indiana, Ms. Hahn, Mr. Nolan, Mrs. Kirkpatrick, Ms. Titus, Mr. Sean Patrick Maloney of New York, Ms. Esty, Ms. Frankel of Florida, and Mrs. Bustos.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H47699A9FB50447BF9EC1495ADC870AD0" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(19)</enum><header>Committee on Veterans’ Affairs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Mr. Michaud, Ms. Brown of Florida, Mr. Takano, and Ms. Brownley of California.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA0E305DF88BC461194D364BFD22CFC2C" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(20)</enum><header>Committee on Ways and Means</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Mr. Levin, Mr. Rangel, Mr. McDermott, Mr. Lewis, Mr. Neal, Mr. Becerra, Mr. Doggett, Mr. Thompson of California, Mr. Larson of Connecticut, Mr. Blumenauer, Mr. Kind, Mr. Pascrell, Mr. Crowley, Ms. Schwartz, Mr. Danny K. Davis of Illinois, and Ms. Linda T. Sánchez of California.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body> 
<attestation><attestation-group><attestor display="no">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation>
</resolution> 


