<bill session="113" type="h" number="4289" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-08T19:05:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-07-08T19:05:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-03-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Homeland Security Interoperable Communications Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DHS Interoperable Communications Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Department of Homeland Security Interoperable Communications Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">DHS Interoperable Communications Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Department of Homeland Security Interoperable Communications Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">DHS Interoperable Communications Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to require the Under Secretary for Management of the Department of Homeland Security to take administrative action to achieve and maintain interoperable communications capabilities among the components of the Department of Homeland Security, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412506"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412539" joined="2014-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400654" joined="2014-06-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-03-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Emergency Preparedness, Response and Communications.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-27">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-27">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-06-11" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-06-19T23:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Homeland Security. H. Rept. 113-484.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-06-19T23:23:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="360">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 360.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-07-08T17:19:00-04:00">
      <text>Mrs. Brooks (IN) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-08T17:19:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5856-5859" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-08T17:20:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4289.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-08T17:32:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-08T18:58:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5861" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="370" datetime="2014-07-08T19:05:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 393 - 0 (Roll no. 370).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5857" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-07-09">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSHM12" subcommittee="Emergency Preparedness, Response, and Communications" name="House Homeland Security"/>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/8/2014--Passed House without amendment.
Department of Homeland Security Interoperable Communications Act or the DHS Interoperable Communications Act - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to include among the responsibilities of the Under Secretary for Management responsibilities with respect to policies and directives to achieve and maintain interoperable communications among the components of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS).

Requires such Under Secretary to submit to the House and Senate homeland security committees a strategy, which shall be updated as necessary, for achieving and maintaining interoperable communications, including for daily operations, planned events, and emergencies, with corresponding milestones, that includes:

 an assessment of interoperability gaps in radio communications among the DHS components, as of this Act's enactment date; information on DHS efforts and activities, including current and planned policies, directives, and training, since November 1, 2012, to achieve and maintain interoperable communications, and planned efforts and activities to achieve and maintain interoperable communications; an assessment of obstacles and challenges to achieving and maintaining interoperable communications; information on, and an assessment of, the adequacy of mechanisms available to the Under Secretary to enforce and compel compliance with interoperable communications policies and directives of DHS; guidance provided to DHS components to implement interoperable communications policies and directives; the total amount of funds expended by DHS since November 1, 2012, and projected future expenditures, to achieve interoperable communications; and dates upon which DHS-wide interoperability is projected to be achieved for voice, data, and video communications, respectively, and interim milestones. Directs the Under Secretary to submit information on any intra-agency effort or task force that has been delegated responsibilities by the Under Secretary relating to achieving and maintaining interoperable communications within a specified time frame, and on who, within each component, is responsible for implementing policies and directives issued by the Under Secretary to achieve and maintain interoperable communications.

Directs the Under Secretary to report on the status of efforts since the issuance of the strategy to implement such strategy, including: (1) progress on each interim milestone; (2) information on any policies, directives, guidance, and training established by the Under Secretary; (3) an assessment of the level of compliance, adoption, and participation among the DHS components with the policies, directives, guidance, and training established by the Under Secretary; and (4) information on any additional resources or authorities needed by the Under Secretary.</summary>
</bill>
