<bill session="113" type="h" number="3153" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-09-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-09-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-09-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Student Disciplinary Fairness Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974 to establish the Office of School Discipline Policy, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412432"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412404" joined="2014-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412565" joined="2014-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2014-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412571" joined="2014-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412379" joined="2014-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412221" joined="2013-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2014-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400111" joined="2014-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2014-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400271" joined="2014-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2013-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412506" joined="2013-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="2014-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="2013-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412412" joined="2013-12-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-09-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-19">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-19">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Due process and equal protection"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/19/2013--Introduced.
Student Disciplinary Fairness Act of 2013 - Amends the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974 to establish an Office of School and Discipline Policy for the purpose of reducing the number of juveniles who are incarcerated and develop a criminal record based on activity that occurs while the juvenile is at school. Directs the Office to: (1) collect and publish data relating to the arrest and incarceration of juveniles for violations of school policies or rules; (2) work with states, local governments, and nongovernmental organizations to expand the use of alternatives to detention and incarceration programming in schools; and (3) collect and publish data on the relationship between the presence of a school resource officer at a school and the rate of juveniles who are arrested and incarcerated for violations of school rules or policies.

Authorizes the Director of the Office of School and Discipline Policy to make grants to states, local governments, and local educational agencies to reduce the number of juveniles who are incarcerated and develop a criminal record based on activity that occurs while the juvenile is at school.

Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to require state or local government applicants for community policing grants to provide assurances that the administration of juvenile justice in their jurisdictions is consistent with constitutional guarantees of due process and equal protection.

Amends the Violent Crime Control and Law Enforcement Act of 1994 to authorize the Attorney General to issue subpoenas to access documents relating to actions by governmental and law enforcement officials responsible for the administration of juvenile justice or the incarceration of juveniles.

Directs the Secretary of Education to make grants to states, local governments, or juvenile justice agencies to fund training for school personnel in elementary and secondary schools to mitigate delinquent student behavior which may avoid a referral to law enforcement officials.</summary>
</bill>
