<bill session="113" type="h" number="3717" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-12-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-12-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-12-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Helping Families in Mental Health Crisis Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To make available needed psychiatric, psychological, and supportive services for individuals diagnosed with mental illness and families in mental health crisis, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400285"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412500" joined="2014-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="2014-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412469" joined="2014-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412541" joined="2014-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412404" joined="2014-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412436" joined="2014-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412512" joined="2014-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412250" joined="2014-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400030" joined="2014-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412478" joined="2014-05-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400032" joined="2014-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2014-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400636" joined="2014-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412539" joined="2014-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="2014-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412516" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412196" joined="2014-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412601" joined="2014-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="2014-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400061" joined="2014-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412258" joined="2014-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400068" joined="2014-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412269" joined="2013-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412470" joined="2014-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412271" joined="2014-01-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400077" joined="2014-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412563" joined="2014-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412400" joined="2014-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400086" joined="2014-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412403" joined="2014-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400648" joined="2014-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412385" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400108" joined="2014-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400114" joined="2014-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400116" joined="2014-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2014-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412457" joined="2013-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400646" joined="2014-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400640" joined="2013-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412532" joined="2014-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400147" joined="2014-01-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412453" joined="2014-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400151" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412401" joined="2014-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412451" joined="2014-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412278" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412454" joined="2014-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412444" joined="2014-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2014-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412486" joined="2014-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2014-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412283" joined="2014-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400195" joined="2014-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2014-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412561" joined="2014-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412460" joined="2014-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="2013-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2014-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="2014-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412465" joined="2014-01-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400219" joined="2014-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412421" joined="2014-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412286" joined="2014-07-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412510" joined="2014-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412290" joined="2013-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412209" joined="2014-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412445" joined="2014-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412521" joined="2014-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412468" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400257" joined="2014-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400259" joined="2014-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2014-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412487" joined="2014-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412466" joined="2014-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400273" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400274" joined="2014-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400276" joined="2014-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412568" joined="2014-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412518" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2014-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400297" joined="2014-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412302" joined="2014-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412303" joined="2014-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412306" joined="2014-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412551" joined="2014-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2014-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412393" joined="2014-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412432" joined="2014-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412310" joined="2013-12-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412311" joined="2014-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412202" joined="2014-01-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412570" joined="2014-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="2014-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400606" joined="2014-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412314" joined="2014-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412399" joined="2014-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400363" joined="2014-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412396" joined="2014-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="409888" joined="2014-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400376" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412509" joined="2014-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="2014-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412461" joined="2013-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400400" joined="2013-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="2014-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412317" joined="2014-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400411" joined="2014-01-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412522" joined="2014-01-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412538" joined="2014-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412214" joined="2014-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412410" joined="2014-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412564" joined="2014-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400431" joined="2014-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400433" joined="2014-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400074" joined="2014-03-27" withdrawn="2014-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400661" joined="2014-03-27" withdrawn="2014-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="2014-03-27" withdrawn="2014-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412579" joined="2014-03-27" withdrawn="2014-05-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-12-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7697"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, Education and the Workforce, Ways and Means, and Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-12">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-12">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-12">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-12">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-12">
      <text>Referred to House Science, Space, and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Research and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H26-27"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-03">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY15" subcommittee="Research and Technology" name="House Science, Space, and Technology"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="401"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2703"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2734"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="116"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="162"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="955"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1517"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Student records"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/12/2013--Introduced.
Helping Families in Mental Health Crisis Act of 2013 - Creates in the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) an Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use Disorders, who shall supervise and direct the Administrator of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration (SAMHSA).

Directs the Assistant Secretary to establish a National Mental Health Policy Laboratory to: (1) identify and implement policy changes and other trends likely to have the most significant impact on mental health services; (2) collect information from grantees; and (3) evaluate and disseminate to such grantees evidence-based practices and services delivery models, using the best available science shown to reduce program expenditures while enhancing the quality of care furnished to individuals by other such grantees.

Amends the Public Health Service Act (PHSA) to require the Assistant Secretary to establish: (1) an Interagency Serious Mental Illness Coordinating Committee; and (2) a four-year pilot program to award up to 50 grants each year to counties, cities, mental health systems, mental health courts, and any other entities with authority under state law to implement, monitor, and oversee assisted outpatient treatment programs.

Directs the Assistant Secretary to establish a program of tele-psychiatry and primary care physician training grants to states to promote the use of qualified telehealth technology for the identification, diagnosis, mitigation, or treatment of a mental health disorder.

Directs the HHS Secretary (Secretary), in coordination with the Assistant Secretary, to award planning grants to enable up to 10 states to carry out 5-year demonstration programs to improve the provision of behavioral health services by federally qualified community behavioral health clinics.

Requires the Assistant Secretary to certify federally qualified community behavioral health clinics that meet specified criteria.

Requires the caregiver of an individual with a serious mental illness to be treated as the individual's personal representative with respect to protected health information, even though the individual has not consented to disclosure of such information to the caregiver, when the individual's service provider reasonably believes it is necessary for protected health information to be made available to the caregiver in order to protect the individual's health, safety, or welfare or the safety of one or more other individuals.

Amends the General Education Provisions Act to allow an educational agency or institution to disclose to such a caregiver the individual's education record in certain related circumstances.

Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to make available: (1) Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grants for mental health programs and operations by law enforcement or corrections officers, and (2) public safety and community policing grants to provide specialized training to law enforcement officers to recognize and intervene properly with individuals who have mental illness.

Reauthorizes and revises requirements for the Mentally Ill Offender Treatment and Crime Reduction Act of 2004.

Authorizes the Attorney General to award grants to: (1) establish or expand veterans treatment court programs; and (2) enhance the capabilities of a correctional facility to identify, screen, and treat inmates with a mental illness, as well as develop and implement post-release transition plans for them.

Requires any data prepared by or submitted to the Attorney General or the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) with respect to homicides, law enforcement officers killed and assaulted, or individuals killed by law enforcement officers to include data about the involvement of mental illness in such incidences, if any.

Directs the Comptroller General (GAO) to detail the cost of federal. state, or local imprisonment for persons who have serious mental illness.

Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to prohibit a state medical assistance plan from prohibiting payment for a same-day qualifying mental health service or primary care service furnished to an individual at a federally qualified community behavioral health center or a federally qualified health center on the same day as the other kind of service.

Allows states the option to provide medical assistance for inpatient psychiatric hospital services and psychiatric residential treatment facility services for individuals age 21-65.

Amends both SSA titles XIX and XVIII (Medicare) to cover prescription drugs used to treat mental health disorders.

Amends the PHSA to increase funding for the brain initiative at the National Institute of Mental Health.

Transfers responsibility for the administration of community mental health block grants to the Assistant Secretary from the Director of the Center for Mental Health Services (CMHS).

Revises requirements for the funding agreement under a formula block grant to a state for community mental health services to prescribe the general standard under state law for court ordered inpatient or outpatient mental health treatment as well as assisted outpatient treatment.

Requires the Assistant Secretary to evaluate the combined paperwork burden of certain community mental health centers as well as of certified federally qualified community mental health clinics.

 Directs the Secretary of Education, along with the Assistant Secretary, to organize a national awareness campaign to assist secondary school students and postsecondary students in: (1) reducing the stigma associated with serious mental illness; (2) understanding how to assist an individual demonstrating signs of a serious mental illness; and (3) understanding the importance of seeking treatment from a physician, clinical psychologist, or licensed mental health professional when a student believes the student may be suffering from a serious mental illness or behavioral health disorder.

Amends the PHSA to include as health care providers any behavioral and mental health professionals, substance abuse professionals, psychiatric hospitals, certain community mental health centers (including one operated by a county behavioral health agency), and residential or outpatient mental health or substance abuse treatment facilities.

Amends SSA title XVIII (Medicare), with respect to incentives for meaningful use of certified electronic health records (EHR) technology under the pay schedule for physician's services, to include as additional eligible professionals clinical psychologists providing qualified psychologist services and clinical social workers. Subjects any additional eligible professionals, including those under a MedicareAdvantage (MA) plan, to reductions in incentive payments after a certain date for failure to be a meaningful EHR user.

Amends SSA title XIX (Medicaid) to treat as Medicaid providers the following additional Medicaid providers: (1) public and certain private hospitals that are principally psychiatric hospitals, (2) certain community mental health centers, and (3) certain residential or outpatient mental health or substance abuse treatment facilities.

Makes eligible Medicaid professionals certain clinical psychologists providing qualified psychologist services and certain clinical social workers.

Amends the PHSA to accord health care professional volunteers at community mental health centers and federally qualified community behavioral health clinics the liability protections of Public Health Service employees.

Requires the Assistant Secretary to transfer all functions and responsibilities of the Center for Behavioral Health Statistics and Quality to the National Mental Health Policy Laboratory.

Revises the duties of the CMHS Director.

Reauthorizes the Secretary's authority to address priority mental health needs of regional and national significance.

Amends the PHSA to reauthorize and revise requirements for a youth interagency research, training, and technical assistance center to prevent suicides (the Suicide Prevention Technical Assistance Center). Expands the program's focus from youth suicides to suicides among all ages, particularly among groups that are at high risk for suicide. Repeals authority for grants to establish research, training, and technical assistance centers related to mental health, substance abuse and the justice system.

Reauthorizes a program of grants for the development of state or tribal youth suicide early intervention and prevention strategies.

Reauthorizes and revises a grant program to enhance services for students with mental health or substance use disorders at institutions of higher education. Requires the Secretary (who currently is merely authorized), acting through the CMHS Director, to award grants to enhance such services and to develop best practices for the delivery of such services. Permits grant funds to be used for the provision of such services to students and to employ appropriately trained staff. Requires the Secretary to give special consideration to applications for grants that describe programs that demonstrate the greatest need for new or additional mental and substance use disorder services and the greatest potential for replication.

Requires the Assistant Secretary, before making a grant to a public entity for comprehensive community mental health services to children with a serious emotional disturbance, to consult with the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to ensure that the grant recipient will use evidence-based practices. Reauthorizes funding for such grants.

Repeals current authority of the Secretary to carry out directly or through grants, contracts or cooperative agreements with public entities a program to assist local communities in developing ways to assist children in dealing with violence.

Reauthorizes the National Child Traumatic Stress Network. Amends the Protection and Advocacy for Individuals with Mental Illness Act to reduce corresponding funding for protection and advocacy systems for mentally ill individuals.

Prohibits lobbying by any such systems accepting federal funds to protect and advocate the rights of individuals with mental illness.

Prohibits the SAMHSA Administrator from hosting or sponsoring any conference that will not be primarily administered by SAMHSA without giving at least 90 days prior notice to specified congressional committees.

Prohibits the SAMHSA Administrator also from establishing (and the Secretary from delegating to the Administrator responsibility for) any program or project not explicitly authorized or required by statute. Terminates by the end of FY2014 any SAMHSA program or project not so explicitly authorized or required.</summary>
</bill>
