<bill session="113" type="s" number="1885" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-12-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-12-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-12-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Burma Human Rights and Democracy Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to place conditions on assistance to the Government of Burma.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400272"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2013-12-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2014-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412248" joined="2013-12-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412491" joined="2013-12-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-12-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3889"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4377"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Burma"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Military command and structure"/>
    <term name="North Korea"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/20/2013--Introduced.
Burma Human Rights and Democracy Act of 2013 - Prohibits FY2014 Department of Defense (DOD) funds from being made available to the government of Burma unless the Secretary of State certifies to Congress that: (1) Burma has taken steps toward establishing civilian oversight of the armed forces, addressing human rights abuses by the military, and terminating military relations with North Korea; (2) Burma has taken steps to establish a fair and inclusive process to amend the Constitution of Burma, including the full participation of the political opposition and ethnic minority groups; (3) Burma has amended its constitution and laws to ensure civilian control of the military; (4) Burma is promoting peace agreements or political reconciliation and is addressing the resettlement and humanitarian situation of displaced persons; and (5) the Burmese military is improving its human rights record, taking steps to withdraw forces from conflict zones, and implementing a code of conduct.

Directs the Secretary of Defense to report annually to Congress on the status of military-to-military engagement between the U.S. Armed Forces and the Burmese military.</summary>
</bill>
