<bill session="113" type="hr" number="568" updated="2015-09-01T10:18:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-07T15:49:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-05-07T15:49:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Relating to the consideration of House Report 113-415 and an accompanying resolution, and providing for consideration of the resolution (H. Res. 565) calling on Attorney General Eric H. Holder, Jr., to appoint a special counsel to investigate the targeting of conservative nonprofit groups by the Internal Revenue Service.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412409"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-06T22:32:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 113-439, by Mr. Nugent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-06T22:32:00-04:00">
      <text>H. Res. 568 also provides for consideration of House Report 113-415 and an accompanying resolution under a closed rule. If such a resolution is considered, the rule provides for 50 minutes of debate on said resolution followed by one motion to refer, if offered by Representative Cummings or his designee and is debatable for 10 minutes.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-05-06T22:32:00-04:00" state="REPORTED" calendar="House" number="103">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 103.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-05-07T12:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3458-3477" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-07T12:25:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 568.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-07T13:26:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H.Res. 568, the chair put the question on ordering the previous question and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. McGovern demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on ordering the previous question on the resolution until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-07T15:42:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3479-3480" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-07T15:43:00-04:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 223 - 192 (Roll no. 197).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3479" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="198" datetime="2014-05-07T15:49:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 224 - 187 (Roll no. 198).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3458" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-05-07T15:49:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="113" type="hr" number="565"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/7/2014--Reported to House without amendment.
Provides for consideration and debate of House Report 113-415 and the accompanying resolution finding Lois G. Lerner, former Director, Exempt Organizations, Internal Revenue Service (IRS), in contempt of Congress for refusal to comply with a subpoena issued by the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform. Makes it in order, upon adoption of such resolution, without intervention of any point of order, to consider the resolution (H. Res. 565) calling upon Attorney General Eric H. Holder, Jr., to appoint a special counsel to investigate the targeting by IRS&#160;of conservative nonprofit advocacy groups.</summary>
</bill>
