<bill session="113" type="s" number="2401" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-05-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Increasing Medical Oversight in the Department of Veterans Affairs Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to establish the Office of the Medical Inspector within the Office of the Under Secretary for Health of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412244"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2014-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2014-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2014-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2014-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="2014-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412243" joined="2014-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400284" joined="2014-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412602" joined="2014-05-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/22/2014--Introduced.
Increasing Medical Oversight in the Department of Veterans Affairs Act of 2014 - Establishes the Office of the Medical Inspector of the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) within the Office of the Under Secretary for Health. Includes among the functions of the Office to:

 review the quality of health care provided to veterans by the VA generally and by the VA through contracts with non-VA health care providers; review offices of the Veterans Health Administration (VHA) that have an impact on the quality of health care provided to veterans by the VA and the performance of the VA in providing such care; review VHA offices and facilities to ensure that VA and VHA policies and procedures are applied consistently; investigate any systemic issues that arise within VHA, including improper issuance of credentials and privileges to health care providers, impediments to access to VA health care, wait times for appointments at VA medical facilities in excess of VA goals, and intentional falsification by VA employees of information regarding wait times; establish temporary investigative teams to carry out reviews in response to specific incidents or inquiries, including veterans' complaints and potential systemic issues within VHA that may require the conduct of surveys, the collection of data, and the analysis of VA databases; recommend policies to promote economy and efficiency in the administration of, and to prevent and detect criminal activity, waste, abuse, and mismanagement in, VHA programs and operations; and report on problems or deficiencies encountered in VHA programs and operations and recommend corrective actions.</summary>
</bill>
