<bill session="113" type="h" number="5661" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Keep Our PACT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Keep Our Promise to America's Children and Teachers Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require full funding of part A of title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 and the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400415"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412600" joined="2014-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2014-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412521" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400259" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400309" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412307" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400349" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412312" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412520" joined="2014-09-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4136"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/18/2014--Introduced.
Keep Our Promise to America's Children and Teachers Act or the Keep Our PACT Act - Appropriates for each of FY2015-FY2024 an amount that equals the difference between: (1) the amount appropriated for FY2015 for school improvement programs under part A of title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965; and (2) a specified amount for the applicable fiscal year or the full amount authorized to be appropriated for such fiscal year for such programs, whichever is higher.

Amends the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (IDEA) to reauthorize and make appropriations for the grant program to assist states and outlying areas in providing special education and related services to children with disabilities. Sets the amount to be authorized and the amount to be appropriated for each fiscal year from FY2015-FY2023 as the greater of: (1) a specified amount, or (2) a specified percentage of an amount determined pursuant to a formula that multiplies the number of children receiving special education services by the average per-pupil expenditure in public elementary and secondary schools. Authorizes and appropriates funds for FY2024 and each subsequent fiscal year equal to the greater of a specified amount or 40% of the amount determined using such formula.

Requires the amounts appropriated by this Act and its amendments to be expended consistent with pay-as-you-go requirements.</summary>
</bill>
