<bill session="113" type="h" number="5181" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">RECORD Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Retention of Electronic Correspondence Of Regulatory Decisions Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 44, United States Code, to require the retention of records of high level officials, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412259"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412270" joined="2014-07-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/23/2014--Introduced.
Retention of Electronic Correspondence Of Regulatory Decisions Act of 2014 or the RECORD Act of 2014 - Requires the records management program maintained by each federal agency head to provide for: (1) the identification and automatic retention of electronic mail (email) accounts that should be preserved as permanent federal records, including the accounts of such head and specified other agency officials and employees; and (2) the electronic capture, management, and preservation of those email accounts in accordance with records disposal requirements such that electronic records are readily accessible for retrieval through electronic searches and there are mandatory minimum functional requirements for electronic records management systems to ensure compliance with program requirements.

Directs the Comptroller General to evaluate and report to Congress not less than every two years on agency management of email records.

Amends the Inspector General Act to make it the responsibility of each Inspector General to: (1) review legislation and regulations relating to records retention requirements under the Federal Records Act for entity programs and operations, and (2) make recommendations in such Inspector General's semiannual reports concerning compliance with such requirements.</summary>
</bill>
