<bill session="113" type="h" number="5525" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Political Intelligence Transparency Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 to require the disclosure of political intelligence activities, to amend title 18, United States Code, to provide for restrictions on former officers, employees, and elected officials of the executive and legislative branches regarding political intelligence contacts, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400378"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400116" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412523" joined="2014-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412214" joined="2014-09-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-10-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-10-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU10" subcommittee="Constitution and Civil Justice" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Commodities markets"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/18/2014--Introduced.
Political Intelligence Transparency Act of 2014 - Amends the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 (LDA) to require the disclosure of political intelligence activities, particularly relating to information useful for analyzing securities or commodities markets.

Requires political intelligence consultants or their employing organizations to register with the Secretary of the Senate and the Clerk of the House of Representatives, and make quarterly reports on political intelligence activities.

Requires any person or entity that makes an oral or written political intelligence contact with a covered legislative branch or executive branch official on the official's request to: (1) state whether such person or entity is registered under the LDA, (2) identify the client on behalf of whom the contact is made, and (3) state whether such client is a foreign entity, and make any related disclosures.

Amends the federal criminal code to subject to a fine or imprisonment, or both, certain former officers, employees, and elected officials of the executive and legislative branches who knowingly make any communication to or appearance before any officer or employee of a federal or District of Columbia agency or court in violation of certain permanent or temporary restrictions, and with the intent to gain information for use in analyzing securities or commodities markets, or in informing investment decisions in these markets.

Excludes from such prohibition any communication made by a representative of a media organization to gather and disseminate news and information to the public.</summary>
</bill>
