<bill session="113" type="h" number="4739" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-05-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Impaired Waters Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide assistance to communities affected by total maximum daily loads established by the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412393"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412453" joined="2014-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400641" joined="2014-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412527" joined="2014-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2014-06-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation and pollution"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Chesapeake Bay"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/22/2014--Introduced.
Impaired Waters Improvement Act - Authorizes the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to make grants to reduce the discharges of nitrogen, phosphorus, or sediment (pollutants) in an area that is subject to a total maximum daily load (TMDL) for those pollutants under the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act). Makes eligible for grants the owners and operators of: (1) publicly owned treatment works or storm water management practices serving areas subject to the TMDLs, or (2) privately owned farms implementing methods to reduce discharges of those pollutants in those areas.

Directs the Administrator to increase by 5% the civil penalty for violations of the Clean Water Act. Establishes the Impaired Waters Improvement Fund for making expenditures to carry out the grant program. Transfers for each of FY2015-FY2019 the amount attributable to the penalty increase or $100 million, whichever is less, to the Fund.</summary>
</bill>
