<bill session="113" type="s" number="2567" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Record Expungement Designed to Enhance Employment Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">REDEEM Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the sealing or expungement of records relating to Federal nonviolent criminal offenses, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412492"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412598" joined="2014-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2014-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="5158"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/8/2014--Introduced.
Record Expungement Designed to Enhance Employment Act of 2014 or the REDEEM Act - Amends the federal criminal code to provide a process for the sealing or expungement of records relating to nonviolent or juvenile offenses.

Requires a court considering a petition to seal a nonviolent offense to balance factors including the harm of the protected information to the ability of the petitioner to secure and maintain employment.

Sets forth limitations on involuntary room confinements at juvenile detention facilities.

Amends the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 (PRWORA) to remove offenses relating to possession or use of a controlled substance from the categories of drug offenses that result in the convicted individual being ineligible for assistance under: (1) a state program funded with temporary assistance for needy families (TANF) grants under part A of title IV of the Social Security Act; or (2) the supplemental nutrition assistance program (SNAP, formerly the food stamp program) or any state program carried out under the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008.

Prohibits the denial of such assistance and benefits if the convicted individual: (1) committed an offense related to a substance abuse disorder, (2) participates in a substance abuse treatment program, and (3) complies with all court-imposed obligations. Includes employment services among the categories of federal benefits that are not to be denied under PRWORA. Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to allow the Attorney General, in awarding public safety and community policing grants, to give preferential consideration to an applicant in a state with laws similar to this Act.</summary>
</bill>
