<bill session="113" type="s" number="2312" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-05-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Guard Technician Equity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend titles 5, 10, and 32, United States Code, to eliminate inequities in the treatment of National Guard technicians, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300081"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2878"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/8/2014--Introduced.
National Guard Technician Equity Act - Provides a person the right to be employed as a non-dual status technician if: (1) the technician position has been designated to be filled only by a non-dual status technician, or (2) the person occupying the technician position has at least 20 years of service as a dual status military technician.

Repeals: (1) the permanent limitation on the number of non-dual status technicians, and (2) the prohibition against overtime pay for National Guard technicians.

 Allows military technicians who were hired as dual status technicians but are no longer members of the Selected Reserve to continue to receive compensation.

Requires dual status military technicians who are fully qualified for, and properly performing, the duties of such position to be: (1) retained in the Armed Forces, (2) exempt from consideration for involuntary separation by a military retention board, and (3) entitled to re-enlist as enlisted members so as to maintain their eligibility for continued employment as dual status military technicians.

Provides for a technician's rights of grievance, arbitration, appeal, and review beyond the current stage of the adjutant general of the jurisdiction concerned.

Prohibits federal employees who volunteer for active National Guard and Reserve duty from accruing military leave at the rate of 15 days each fiscal year for active duty, inactive duty training, or funeral honors duty in the National Guard or Reserves.

Directs the Comptroller General to evaluate the feasibility of converting military technicians from coverage under the Federal Employees Health Benefits Program (FEHBP) to coverage under the TRICARE Reserve Select option of the TRICARE program.</summary>
</bill>
