<bill session="113" type="h" number="5482" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Enhanced Security Clearance Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To enhance the Office of Personnel Management background check system for the granting, denial, or revocation of security clearances or access to classified information of employees and contractors of the Federal Government.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412465"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select), and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-16">
      <text>Referred to House Intelligence</text>
      <reference ref="Permanent Select"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-16">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1618"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Director of National Intelligence"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Subversive activities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/16/2014--Introduced.
Enhanced Security Clearance Act of 2014 - Requires the Director of National Intelligence (DNI) to implement a plan to eliminate backlogs of overdue periodic reinvestigations of individuals eligible for access to classified information or eligible to hold a sensitive position.

Sets forth time intervals within which periodic reinvestigations updating previously completed background investigations are to occur.

Requires the DNI to direct specified agencies (executive agencies, military departments, and elements of the intelligence community identified in the Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2004) to implement enhanced personnel security programs for security reviews of such individuals. Requires implementation of such programs by the earlier of: (1) five years after enactment of this Act, or (2) the date on which the backlog is eliminated.

Requires agency programs to integrate information from government, publicly available, and commercial data sources, consumer reporting agencies, and social media. Permits information obtained from such sources to include: (1) security or counterintelligence information on any public online website that may suggest ill intent, vulnerability to blackmail, compulsive behavior, allegiance to another country, illegal drug use, criminal activity, material falsification, change in ideology, or a lack of good judgment, reliability, or trustworthiness; and (2) data maintained on any terrorist or criminal watch list maintained by any agency, state or local government, or international organization.

Requires automated record checks at least twice every five years to ensure continued eligibility of individuals employed or contracted with by such agencies.

Directs the DNI to issue guidance defining minor financial or mental health issues.

Requires inspectors general of such agencies to assess the effectiveness and fairness of agency programs.</summary>
</bill>
