<bill session="113" type="h" number="4230" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-03-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-03-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-03-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To limit the retirement of KC-10 aircraft.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412449"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412382" joined="2014-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400403" joined="2014-04-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-03-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Seapower and Projection Forces.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS28" subcommittee="Seapower and Projection Forces" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3657"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/13/2014--Introduced.
Prohibits the obligation or expenditure of Department of Defense (DOD) funds to retire, prepare to retire, or place in storage any KC-10 aircraft until: (1) the Secretary of the Air Force certifies that the four KC-46A test aircraft are all built and fully operational, the initial 18 KC-46A aircraft have been delivered to the Air Force in a fully operational capacity by 2017, the KC-46A aircraft has achieved full operational capability, and a sufficient number of KC-46A aircraft exists in the Air Force's inventory to fully meet the air refueling and cargo support capability and mission requirements of the combatant commands; and (2) the Comptroller General (GAO) submits a report setting forth an assessment of whether each such certification is comprehensive, fully supported, and sufficiently detailed and an identification of any shortcomings, limitations, or other reportable matters that affect the quality or findings of any such certification.</summary>
</bill>
