<bill session="113" type="h" number="3734" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-12-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-12-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-12-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">416d65726963612043616e20436f6465 Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">America Can Code Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a task force to share best practices on computer programming and coding for elementary schools and secondary schools, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412517"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412571" joined="2014-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2013-12-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-12-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Foreign language and bilingual programs"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
    <term name="Women's education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/12/2013--Introduced.
416d65726963612043616e20436f6465 Act of 2013 or the America Can Code Act of 2013 - Expresses the sense of Congress regarding the importance of instruction in coding and computer programming to students' academic and vocational success, innovations in cyberspace, and our national security and economic competitiveness.

Amends the America COMPETES Act to include computer programming language that is critical to the national security and economic competitiveness of our country as a "critical foreign language," the study of which is included in the teacher education programs and Advanced Placement or International Baccalaureate programs funded under that Act.

Amends the Carl D. Perkins Vocational and Technical Education Act of 2006 to provide for: (1) state plans to include coding and computer programming instruction within the career and technical programs of study for which states receive assistance under that Act, and (2) the inclusion of coding and computer programming instruction within the federally-assisted tech prep programs that prepare participants in a career field by providing them with at least two years of secondary education followed by at least two years of postsecondary education or participation in an apprenticeship program.

Directs the Secretary of Education to convene a task force to explore: (1) mechanisms for the development of draft curricula for elementary and secondary computer programming and coding education; (2) a mechanism to collect and share best elementary and secondary school computer programming and coding practices among educators; and (3) a national strategy to ensure competitiveness in emerging science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM) fields, such as computer programming and coding. Requires the task force to establish an information portal that directs users to coordinated and systematic information on promoting coding and computer programming in elementary and secondary schools.</summary>
</bill>
