<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H83CA75CA1EDB42C3AC9880E9F00FE07B" key="H" public-private="public" stage-count="1">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HR 4569 : Disclosure Modernization and Simplification Act of 2014</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2014-12-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 4569</legis-num>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action><action-date date="20141203">December 3, 2014</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To require the Securities and Exchange Commission to make certain improvements to form 10-K and
			 regulation S-K, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H85FA486027654D2D8AE28EC38EE85412" style="OLC">
		<section id="HCC1EEDF1916F418BB6813E31A300D38E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Disclosure Modernization and Simplification Act of 2014</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="HACC67772C4AE47E9B39182665942ADE5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Summary page for form 10-K</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than the end of the 180-day period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act,
			 the Securities and Exchange Commission shall issue regulations to permit
			 issuers to submit a summary page on form 10-K (17 CFR 249.310), but only
			 if each item on such summary page includes a cross-reference (by
			 electronic link or otherwise) to the material contained in form 10-K to
			 which such item relates.</text>
		</section><section id="H2DFE90932C8445A99E0513B9C56FE3AC"><enum>3.</enum><header>Improvement of regulation S-K</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than the end of the 180-day period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act,
			 the Securities and Exchange Commission shall take all such actions to
			 revise regulation S-K (17 CFR 229.10 et seq.)—</text>
			<paragraph id="H86F49EF4CEC4433E836F724FD5FE2E6E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to further scale or eliminate requirements of regulation S-K, in order to reduce the burden on
			 emerging growth companies, accelerated filers, smaller reporting
			 companies, and other smaller issuers, while still providing all material
			 information to investors;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H77A597A8197F4483B62ADAE8D01E01F4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to eliminate provisions of regulation S-K, required for all issuers, that are duplicative,
			 overlapping, outdated, or unnecessary; and</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H29180D5537C048E6903B710C0FA4AB66"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for which the Commission determines that no further study under section 4 is necessary to determine
			 the efficacy of such revisions to regulation S-K.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H5D6266ADA7914811AF4DCDAF2D36290B"><enum>4.</enum><header>Study on modernization and simplification of regulation S-K</header>
			<subsection id="H05F7C7717ECC45AC97C4F5B7E12C8826"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Securities and Exchange Commission shall carry out a study of the requirements contained in
			 regulation S-K (17 CFR 229.10 et seq.). Such study shall—</text>
				<paragraph id="HD603CC00D78E49A7AE0D51678FDA29F0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>determine how best to modernize and simplify such requirements in a manner that reduces the costs
			 and burdens on issuers while still providing all material information;</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HBE1C0B139F6F473FB4DA28E4D19B5BD8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">emphasize a company by company approach that allows relevant and material information to be
			 disseminated to investors without boilerplate language or static
			 requirements while preserving completeness and comparability of
			 information across registrants; and</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H989B5685D8E743B7A9ECEAA9B4FFCD10"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">evaluate methods of information delivery and presentation and explore methods for discouraging
			 repetition and the disclosure of immaterial information.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H28ED6CC5E5C74CEEB6DC7AB437DC40EA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In conducting the study required under subsection (a), the Commission shall consult with the
			 Investor Advisory Committee and the Advisory Committee on Small and
			 Emerging Companies.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H4FD0F47801134729BF91B3C70D22E457"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than the end of the 360-day period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, the
			 Commission shall issue a report to the Congress containing—</text>
				<paragraph id="HC2ACB77B3330474DB327A52394F49401"><enum>(1)</enum><text>all findings and determinations made in carrying out the study required under subsection (a);</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HCD5DFDBEDE8343BF8BFC33D3F97E73DC"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">specific and detailed recommendations on modernizing and simplifying the requirements in regulation
			 S-K in a manner that reduces the costs and burdens on companies while
			 still providing all material information; and</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HD23B241818E24877B6C2BFFE5F373528"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">specific and detailed recommendations on ways to improve the readability and navigability of
			 disclosure documents and to discourage repetition and the disclosure of
			 immaterial information.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H31BBE8DF7C4F4A7AA8F7E193E51D2243"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than the end of the 360-day period beginning on the date that the report is issued to the
			 Congress under subsection (c), the Commission shall issue a proposed rule
			 to implement the recommendations of the report issued under subsection
			 (c).</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H578499CEE9FF46DBA4803F40215B6171"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Revisions made to regulation S-K by the Commission under section 3 shall not be construed as
			 satisfying the rulemaking requirements under this section.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
	<attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date chamber="House" date="20141202">Passed the House of Representatives December 2, 2014.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk</role></attestation-group></attestation>
</bill>


