<bill bill-stage="Enrolled-Bill" dms-id="H675720137CED4E7695E7C70C1FBC97E9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"> HR 5859 ENR: Ukraine Freedom Support Act of 2014</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"/>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>One Hundred Thirteenth Congress of the United States of America</congress> <session>At the Second Session</session>
    <enrolled-dateline>Begun and held at the City of Washington on Friday, the third day of January, two thousand and fourteen</enrolled-dateline> 
<legis-num>H. R. 5859</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no"/> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To impose sanctions with respect to the Russian Federation, to provide additional assistance to Ukraine, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H53A9330D61334D3CA17561CDEBDE35E4" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H0C0BDE23929041CD8835280EAECE1FD5" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title; table of contents</header> 
<subsection id="HD8446EF289BC4A93BAC99EF942436BB6">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Short title</header>
        <text>This Act may be cited as the <quote>
            <short-title>
              <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Ukraine Freedom Support Act of 2014" proposed="true">Ukraine Freedom Support Act of 2014</cato:entity-ref>
            </short-title>
          </quote>.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H96B97C5B30944EF2B1D1DC7EE6D2A9C7">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Table of contents</header>
        <text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text> 
<toc> 
<toc-entry idref="H0C0BDE23929041CD8835280EAECE1FD5" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H134AB01822B643BB8F4406B9142B3249" level="section">Sec. 2. Definitions.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HF13AAD2D504D429DBF93502DC72ACCE5" level="section">Sec. 3. Statement of policy regarding Ukraine.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HDDB8F121F05949578798B16F2378E6F4" level="section">Sec. 4. Sanctions relating to the defense and energy sectors of the Russian Federation.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HEA8995C17E9E4791B209C1938BB29D76" level="section">Sec. 5. Sanctions on Russian and other foreign financial institutions.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HDE7283B0A2114D7D9883EEB04051F688" level="section">Sec. 6. Increased military assistance for the Government of Ukraine.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H30327ED0DEDD4A4EBFF27459FC0A62F8" level="section">Sec. 7. Expanded nonmilitary assistance for Ukraine.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HFDA48738063C4E9196BC972B202D2385" level="section">Sec. 8. Expanded broadcasting in countries of the former Soviet Union.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HC8EF2FAD986442C1812A250CFA992407" level="section">Sec. 9. Support for Russian democracy and civil society organizations.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H45973D246A864AD69E6260D6DCBE4E69" level="section">Sec. 10. Report on non-compliance by the Russian Federation of its obligations under the INF Treaty.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H8AB1841C2EDA42AA90526F81BD735A64" level="section">Sec. 11. Rule of construction.</toc-entry> </toc>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
<section id="H134AB01822B643BB8F4406B9142B3249">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Definitions</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H003C4632DBC049D6B154899F32807E31">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <header>Account; correspondent account; payable-through account</header>
        <text>The terms <term>account</term>, <term>correspondent account</term>, and <term>payable-through account</term> have the meanings given those terms in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/31/5318A">
            <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/5318A">section 5318A</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H75609CA8EDFC43D99A1E68076B0EC6DC">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <header>Appropriate congressional committees</header>
        <text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE315B60DD7724AD7A8B9B2DD73FF2E9D">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="SSFR00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Foreign Relations</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="SSBK00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
        </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD8509330D4F04CCAB23769EE8E3DCCD2">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="HFA00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Foreign Affairs</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="HBA00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H88F17405C3AF41B1B6B543D2F913DF99">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
        <header>Defense article; defense service; training</header>
        <text>The terms <term>defense article</term>, <term>defense service</term>, and <term>training</term> have the meanings given those terms in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Arms Export Control Act/s:47">section 47 of the Arms Export Control Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2794">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/2794">22 U.S.C. 2794</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H42705E0C6BE647CFAE75A7D1731E93F9">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <header>Financial institution</header>
        <text>The term <term>financial institution</term> means a financial institution specified in subparagraph (A), (B), (C), (D), (E), (F), (G), (H), (I), (J), (M), or (Y) of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/31/5312/a/2">
            <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/5312">section 5312(a)(2)</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H25118E9A0D2C4F3187C8C9C598D02887">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
        <header>Foreign financial institution</header>
        <text>The term <term>foreign financial institution</term> has the meaning given that term in <external-xref legal-doc="regulation" parsable-cite="cfr/31/561.308">section 561.308</external-xref> of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations (or any corresponding similar regulation or ruling).</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H90B21102C2604A7C92BA0671344B9DE7">
        <enum>(6)</enum>
        <header>Foreign person</header>
        <text>The term <term>foreign person</term> means any individual or entity that is not a United States citizen, a permanent resident alien, or an entity organized under the laws of the United States or any jurisdiction within the United States.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2F48454B2A054269AB3E48E3EA2C6642">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
        <header>Knowingly</header>
        <text>The term <term>knowingly</term>, with respect to conduct, a circumstance, or a result, means that a person has actual knowledge, or should have known, of the conduct, the circumstance, or the result.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8639B1EBA94147438471EE3057F53934">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
        <header>Russian person</header>
        <text>The term <term>Russian person</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H17B8CB56DFEA4C539A7160AE371AF927">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>an individual who is a citizen or national of the Russian Federation; or</text>
        </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF695B89A080446A1BF21AAC6F568B615">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>an entity organized under the laws of the Russian Federation.</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H553D223EDFBF4D96A5AF6990F555D31C">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
        <header>Special Russian crude oil project</header>
        <text>The term <term>special Russian crude oil project</term> means a project intended to extract crude oil from—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H9C46DB10013E4EF4A7509CCED9C03A65">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
          <text>the exclusive economic zone of the Russian Federation in waters more than 500 feet deep;</text>
        </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB7A8FA5561B84B4FBC78593FFD26942F">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
          <text>Russian Arctic offshore locations; or</text>
        </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB80EB7607E3E43AA9CEDE9A72C0D40F2">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
          <text>shale formations located in the Russian Federation.</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
    </section> 
<section id="HF13AAD2D504D429DBF93502DC72ACCE5">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Statement of policy regarding Ukraine</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States to further assist the Government of Ukraine in restoring its sovereignty and territorial integrity to deter the Government of the Russian Federation from further destabilizing and invading Ukraine and other independent countries in Central and Eastern Europe, the Caucasus, and Central Asia. That policy shall be carried into effect, among other things, through a comprehensive effort, in coordination with allies and partners of the United States where appropriate, that includes economic sanctions, diplomacy, assistance for the people of Ukraine, and the provision of military capabilities to the Government of Ukraine that will enhance the ability of that Government to defend itself and to restore its sovereignty and territorial integrity in the face of unlawful actions by the Government of the Russian Federation.</text>
    </section> 
<section id="HDDB8F121F05949578798B16F2378E6F4">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Sanctions relating to the defense and energy sectors of the Russian Federation</header> 
<subsection id="H8B724189E1354431BF880B59C8533E93">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Sanctions relating to the defense sector</header> 
<paragraph id="HF5A4E79BECC3417D999F4D82AC05D3D2">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Rosoboronexport</header>
          <text>Except as provided in subsection (d), not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall impose 3 or more of the sanctions described in subsection (c) with respect to Rosoboronexport.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEF80280BFD8C4A95B66C25DCF070F2C4">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Russian producers, transferors, or brokers of defense articles</header>
          <text>Except as provided in subsection (d), on and after the date that is 45 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall impose 3 or more of the sanctions described in subsection (c) with respect to a foreign person the President determines—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H884078DF229343C6B5BF18BDA76B072B">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>is an entity—</text> 
<clause id="H0C253F1E3B8C43D5920B0CE388406E7B">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>owned or controlled by the Government of the Russian Federation or owned or controlled by nationals of the Russian Federation; and</text>
            </clause> 
<clause id="HCF735F848BDB46FDBC59625BA0B40526">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>that—</text> 
<subclause id="H7123DBBDF0024A6A84034F225F48929B">
                <enum>(I)</enum>
                <text>knowingly manufactures or sells defense articles transferred into Syria or into the territory of a specified country without the consent of the internationally recognized government of that country;</text>
              </subclause> 
<subclause id="H93AD8C02CC744024AF53C198D87E205A">
                <enum>(II)</enum>
                <text>transfers defense articles into Syria or into the territory of a specified country without the consent of the internationally recognized government of that country; or</text>
              </subclause> 
<subclause id="H6C5ABF0C2E17452BB550F7EDB5618A52">
                <enum>(III)</enum>
                <text>brokers or otherwise assists in the transfer of defense articles into Syria or into the territory of a specified country without the consent of the internationally recognized government of that country; or</text>
              </subclause>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5D595D98C669478389F93C512B8D0AD5">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>knowingly, on or after the date of the enactment of this Act, assists, sponsors, or provides financial, material, or technological support for, or goods or services to or in support of, an entity described in subparagraph (A) with respect to an activity described in clause (ii) of that subparagraph.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H17B1AB57DDFD4B4184D72A4BE5F9D198">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Specified country defined</header> 
<subparagraph id="H78699E91335243198669FC69A7EE7BA1">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
            <text>In this subsection, the term <term>specified country</term> means—</text> 
<clause id="HA749D58C6A77489A914ACE1C08B64E69">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>Ukraine, Georgia, and Moldova; and</text>
            </clause> 
<clause id="HB37B19E46B0346F0AA36FAF2AA463B3E">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>any other country designated by the President as a country of significant concern for purposes of this subsection, such as Poland, Lithuania, Latvia, Estonia, and the Central Asia republics.</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB90651A7B3B742DFA189589A7F41A239">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <header>Notice to congress</header>
            <text>The President shall notify the appropriate congressional committees in writing not later than 15 days before—</text> 
<clause id="HF4434433DE87470FBB5268AE487C60D0">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>designating a country as a country of significant concern under subparagraph (A)(ii); or</text>
            </clause> 
<clause id="H727F139E248541CDBE29C1C9AEF3F097">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>terminating a designation under that subparagraph, including the termination of any such designation pursuant to subsection (h).</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H1F8B1CA9718A46AA8DC204561F1F2C1A">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Sanctions related to the energy sector</header> 
<paragraph id="H063A3CBBE10045C580EB98AC3F951B82">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Development of special Russian crude oil projects</header>
          <text>Except as provided in subsection (d), on and after the date that is 45 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President may impose 3 or more of the sanctions described in subsection (c) with respect to a foreign person if the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> determines that the foreign person knowingly makes a significant investment in a special Russian crude oil project.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9D7FD048FAAF4B8A9C8ECE9C59A0D336">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Authorization for extension of licensing limitations on certain equipment</header>
          <text>The President, through the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1351" entity-type="federal-body">Bureau of Industry and Security of the Department of Commerce</cato:entity-ref> or the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Office of Foreign Assets Control" entity-parent-id="2000">Office of Foreign Assets Control of the Department of the Treasury</cato:entity-ref>, as appropriate, may impose additional licensing requirements for or other restrictions on the export or reexport of items for use in the energy sector of the Russian Federation, including equipment used for tertiary oil recovery.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3BAF58EB03B9407B895D3E9A4EF4EBB9">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Contingent sanction relating to Gazprom</header>
          <text>If the President determines that Gazprom is withholding significant natural gas supplies from member countries of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="19RN" entity-type="federal-body">North Atlantic Treaty Organization</cato:entity-ref>, or further withholds significant natural gas supplies from countries such as Ukraine, Georgia, or Moldova, the President shall, not later than 45 days after making that determination, impose the sanction described in subsection (c)(7) and at least one additional sanction described in subsection (c) with respect to Gazprom.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H9A8C3D12B37D4B49A1F00FCE8CC750E5">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Sanctions described</header>
        <text>The sanctions the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> may impose with respect to a foreign person under subsection (a) or (b) are the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H4228FD91D3A047FE9F4C3FA1D3AF5FCF">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Export-import bank assistance</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> may direct the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="8300" entity-type="federal-body">Export-Import Bank of the United States</cato:entity-ref> not to approve the issuance of any guarantee, insurance, extension of credit, or participation in the extension of credit in connection with the export of any goods or services to the foreign person.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H18DA8A110B1A445ABF7AE0A4D5E448F2">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Procurement sanction</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> may prohibit the head of any executive agency (as defined in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/41/133">
              <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/41/133">section 133</external-xref> of title 41, United States Code</cato:entity-ref>) from entering into any contract for the procurement of any goods or services from the foreign person.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8FB9A8DE81CA4B3387AFE3B667DB7993">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Arms export prohibition</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> may prohibit the exportation or provision by sale, lease or loan, grant, or other means, directly or indirectly, of any defense article or defense service to the foreign person and the issuance of any license or other approval to the foreign person under <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Arms Export Control Act/s:38">section 38 of the Arms Export Control Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2778">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/2778">22 U.S.C. 2778</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity>.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC51A97D22A764F03BAE135647199C589">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <header>Dual-use export prohibition</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> may prohibit the issuance of any license and suspend any license for the transfer to the foreign person of any item the export of which is controlled under the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Export Administration Act of 1979">Export Administration Act of 1979</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc-appendix/50/2401/etseq">50 U.S.C. App. 2401 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity> (as in effect pursuant to the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="International Emergency Economic Powers Act">International Emergency Economic Powers Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/50/1701/etseq">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity>) or the Export Administration Regulations under subchapter C of chapter VII of title 15, Code of Federal Regulations.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0405287BDF864FD4B21525F52ABBB926">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <header>Property transactions</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> may, pursuant to such regulations as the President may prescribe, prohibit any person from—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB9E4D6A5C60448EC8BB7F85B7A4AC490">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>acquiring, holding, withholding, using, transferring, withdrawing, transporting, or exporting any property that is subject to the jurisdiction of the United States and with respect to which the foreign person has any interest;</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFB70A962673D4982BA0C96FFBB85AC30">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>dealing in or exercising any right, power, or privilege with respect to such property; or</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H282C1A8EF53C4AB1B23393EC5E46EFE5">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>conducting any transaction involving such property.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE13E19DA96B445AFBF46B020912430CC">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <header>Banking transactions</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> may, pursuant to such regulations as the President may prescribe, prohibit any transfers of credit or payments between financial institutions or by, through, or to any financial institution, to the extent that such transfers or payments are subject to the jurisdiction of the United States and involve any interest of the foreign person.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEBBCC8D0CB1B4019AC33FF8C2FEE122A">
          <enum>(7)</enum>
          <header>Prohibition on investment in equity or debt of sanctioned person</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> may, pursuant to such regulations as the President may prescribe, prohibit any United States person from transacting in, providing financing for, or otherwise dealing in—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H262A1CD8705A4AF48B76D42E93ACCDF0">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>debt—</text> 
<clause id="H163154C4DAC447DCB796A6BF525A1772">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>of longer than 30 days’ maturity of a foreign person with respect to which sanctions are imposed under subsection (a) or of longer than 90 days’ maturity of a foreign person with respect to which sanctions are imposed under subsection (b); and</text>
            </clause> 
<clause id="H7DA02BF96A344661B4F66B6E4895AB49">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>issued on or after the date on which such sanctions are imposed with respect to the foreign person; or</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7582432556F5448FBF5DAFA13B4B5C4B">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>equity of the foreign person issued on or after that date.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCDEF3E545FE14655AF0B7745DE4DD264">
          <enum>(8)</enum>
          <header>Exclusion from the United States and revocation of visa or other documentation</header>
          <text>In the case of a foreign person who is an individual, the President may direct the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> to deny a visa to, and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7000" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Homeland Security</cato:entity-ref> to exclude from the United States, the foreign person, subject to regulatory exceptions to permit the United States to comply with the Agreement regarding the Headquarters of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="19UN" entity-type="federal-body">United Nations</cato:entity-ref>, signed at Lake Success June 26, 1947, and entered into force November 21, 1947, between the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="19UN" entity-type="federal-body">United Nations</cato:entity-ref> and the United States, or other applicable international obligations.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE6924148B4EA4F4D89ED3F54E45F0E81">
          <enum>(9)</enum>
          <header>Sanctions on principal executive officers</header>
          <text>In the case of a foreign person that is an entity, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> may impose on the principal executive officer or officers of the foreign person, or on individuals performing similar functions and with similar authorities as such officer or officers, any of the sanctions described in this subsection applicable to individuals.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HC0C3C8F89C0A441296EAD411B34AE434">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Exceptions</header> 
<paragraph id="HB642515524754C4AB2B3AE93878EBEDD">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Importation of goods</header> 
<subparagraph id="H26F6E806B0FC4AC69D1CFCE3ADCABB96">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
            <text>The authority to block and prohibit all transactions in all property and interests in property under subsection (c)(5) shall not include the authority to impose sanctions on the importation of goods.</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9A6431434AA04D3C8D1C1121A6CBBCAA">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <header>Good defined</header>
            <text>In this paragraph, the term <term>good</term> has the meaning given that term in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Export Administration Act of 1979/s:16">section 16 of the Export Administration Act of 1979</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc-appendix" parsable-cite="usc-appendix/50/2415">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc-appendix/50/2415">50 U.S.C. App. 2415</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity> (as continued in effect pursuant to the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="International Emergency Economic Powers Act">International Emergency Economic Powers Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/50/1701/etseq">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity>).</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8C9BF7F65BB04D1695F746A9A1890EDF">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Additional exceptions</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall not be required to apply or maintain the sanctions under subsection (a) or (b)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE72BD46008DC41208801E1D7AC22E6D3">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>in the case of procurement of defense articles or defense services under existing contracts, subcontracts, or other business agreements, including ancillary or incidental contracts for goods, or for services or funding (including necessary financial services) associated with such goods, as necessary to give effect to such contracts, subcontracts, or other business agreements, and the exercise of options for production quantities to satisfy requirements essential to the national security of the United States—</text> 
<clause id="HA705C1CB067749D5B6533FAA9E44D478">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>if the President determines in writing that—</text> 
<subclause id="H317A5657441246618B46BF66FB5A61F1">
                <enum>(I)</enum>
                <text>the foreign person to which the sanctions would otherwise be applied is a sole source supplier of the defense articles or services;</text>
              </subclause> 
<subclause id="H7D0E390FB7094C36A1F53435B76D76EB">
                <enum>(II)</enum>
                <text>the defense articles or services are essential;</text>
              </subclause> 
<subclause id="H18CB6B2434F04DF2BDEDE1B84881990F">
                <enum>(III)</enum>
                <text>alternative sources are not readily or reasonably available; and</text>
              </subclause> 
<subclause id="HE9D0225ECF554FEE9B051EE74F915D29">
                <enum>(IV)</enum>
                <text>the national interests of the United States would be adversely affected by the application or maintenance of such sanctions; or</text>
              </subclause>
            </clause> 
<clause id="H73BCEE19EC6A46458227BE4EF928BF96">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>if the President determines in writing that—</text> 
<subclause id="H77097D653814422FAD39C883719F5C53">
                <enum>(I)</enum>
                <text>such articles or services are essential to the national security under defense coproduction agreements; and</text>
              </subclause> 
<subclause id="H32F27887D04A43BBBE354CEFE04F51BD">
                <enum>(II)</enum>
                <text>the national interests of the United States would be adversely affected by the application or maintenance of such sanctions;</text>
              </subclause>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H671575F285D948D6A3BB1B72DD8E8F8B">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>in the case of procurement, to eligible products, as defined in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Trade Agreements Act of 1979/s:308/p:4">section 308(4) of the Trade Agreements Act of 1979</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2518">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/19/2518//4">19 U.S.C. 2518(4)</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity>, of any foreign country or instrumentality designated under <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Trade Agreements Act of 1979/s:301/ss:b/p:1">section 301(b)(1) of that Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2511">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/19/2511/b/1">19 U.S.C. 2511(b)(1)</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity>;</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H871ABC52CA204DA7801A19568CDB4004">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>to products, technology, or services provided under contracts, subcontracts, or other business agreements (including ancillary or incidental contracts for goods, or for services or funding (including necessary financial services) associated with such goods, as necessary to give effect to such contracts, subcontracts, or other business agreements) entered into before the date on which the President publishes in the Federal Register the name of the foreign person with respect to which the sanctions are to be imposed;</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA68FDEE4D75F4F689061E8BA07B15737">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <text>to—</text> 
<clause id="H440C2415784A48A3A029FD81CE656D53">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>spare parts that are essential to United States products or production;</text>
            </clause> 
<clause id="H84865935D2CB49129A580CD2ABDD9A3F">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>component parts, but not finished products, essential to United States products or production; or</text>
            </clause> 
<clause id="HE7A56060317E4AEDAEF807651B45FF52">
              <enum>(iii)</enum>
              <text>routine servicing and maintenance of United States products, to the extent that alternative sources are not readily or reasonably available;</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC270DA65A20F42139F2FF898830C7651">
            <enum>(E)</enum>
            <text>to information and technology essential to United States products or production; or</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD885FC86522D4D5F91298F24527CB7E9">
            <enum>(F)</enum>
            <text>to food, medicine, medical devices, or agricultural commodities (as those terms are defined in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Comprehensive Iran Sanctions, Accountability, and Divestment Act of 2010/s:101">section 101 of the Comprehensive Iran Sanctions, Accountability, and Divestment Act of 2010</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8511">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/8511">22 U.S.C. 8511</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity>).</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H70C3DFD4C834423F97E20F1819F2AC78">
        <enum>(e)</enum>
        <header>National security waiver</header> 
<paragraph id="H3D5059D8A4754783A4D823A6834ADD24">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> may waive the application of sanctions under subsection (a) or (b) with respect to a foreign person if the President—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB9412A4AD9824C3CBB9FA1A3DA7C2065">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>determines that the waiver is in the national security interest of the United States; and</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3AF21A684A2C4CD79C3C6D6B1D4DBD86">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>submits to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the determination and the reasons for the determination.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF7197188BD7C44EFA5D69AFF268C3E4A">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Form of report</header>
          <text>The report required by paragraph (1)(B) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H47CB90DB1CC842498B315C66B18F7649">
        <enum>(f)</enum>
        <header>Transaction-specific national security waiver</header> 
<paragraph id="H9B6CF58D8AB3433D848BA35AC7E5DFE8">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>The President may waive the application of sanctions under subsection (a) or (b) with respect to a specific transaction if the President—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H958A7B238F7D49F6B61C4A284A6FF027">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>determines that the transaction is in the national security interest of the United States; and</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE479893EA91846EC8FDA607D75242C48">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>submits to the appropriate congressional committees a detailed report on the determination and the specific reasons for the determination that a waiver with respect to the transaction is necessary and appropriate.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H51F23904E63243FBBB30094D62B8905C">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Form of report</header>
          <text>The report required by paragraph (1)(B) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H09228353CF8348C9AC8560DFAEF5F5C0">
        <enum>(g)</enum>
        <header>Implementation; penalties</header> 
<paragraph id="HE57FAC1B1B9142FC845D6FEB3470C69D">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Implementation</header>
          <text>The President may exercise all authorities provided under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="International Emergency Economic Powers Act/s:203">sections 203</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="International Emergency Economic Powers Act/s:205">205 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/50/1702">50 U.S.C. 1702</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/50/1704">1704</cato:entity-ref>) to carry out the purposes of this section.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD71DC331C0FC43B6B15D02492B8C7D75">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Penalties</header>
          <text>The penalties provided for in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="International Emergency Economic Powers Act/s:206/ss:b">subsections (b)</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="International Emergency Economic Powers Act/s:206/ss:c">(c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity> shall apply to a person that violates, attempts to violate, or conspires to violate, or causes a violation of, subsection (a) or (b) of this section, or an order or regulation prescribed under either such subsection, to the same extent that such penalties apply to a person that commits an unlawful act described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="International Emergency Economic Powers Act/s:206/ss:a">section 206(a) of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HA04BA1766C7340A6BFCAE89C5E150E76">
        <enum>(h)</enum>
        <header>Termination</header> 
<paragraph id="HF2D744C6AE1E473EA5E67CEA2074F945">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), this section, and sanctions imposed under this section, shall terminate on the date on which the President submits to the appropriate congressional committees a certification that the Government of the Russian Federation has ceased ordering, controlling, or otherwise directing, supporting, or financing, significant acts intended to undermine the peace, security, stability, sovereignty, or territorial integrity of Ukraine, including through an agreement between the appropriate parties.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H616DD5D20B3A4A3FAE335538E0B5575E">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Applicability with respect to Syria</header>
          <text>The termination date under paragraph (1) shall not apply with respect to the provisions of subsection (a) relating to the transfer of defense articles into Syria or sanctions imposed pursuant to such provisions.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
<section id="HEA8995C17E9E4791B209C1938BB29D76">
      <enum>5.</enum>
      <header>Sanctions on Russian and other foreign financial institutions</header> 
<subsection id="H8FDB3325E8FC40AE8648155756F4E82F">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Facilitation of certain defense- and energy-Related transactions</header>
        <text>The President may impose the sanction described in subsection (c) with respect to a foreign financial institution that the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> determines knowingly engages, on or after the date of the enactment of this Act, in significant transactions involving activities described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Ukraine Freedom Support Act of 2014/s:4/ss:a/p:2/sp:A/cl:ii" proposed="true">subparagraph (A)(ii)</cato:entity-ref> or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Ukraine Freedom Support Act of 2014/s:4/ss:a/p:2/sp:B" proposed="true">(B) of section 4(a)(2)</cato:entity-ref> or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Ukraine Freedom Support Act of 2014/s:4/ss:b/p:1" proposed="true">paragraph (1)</cato:entity-ref> or <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Ukraine Freedom Support Act of 2014/s:4/ss:b/p:3" proposed="true">(3) of section 4(b)</cato:entity-ref> for persons with respect to which sanctions are imposed under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Ukraine Freedom Support Act of 2014/s:4" proposed="true">section 4</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HDBA141119C0E4EA4AE76D693570BD05E">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Facilitation of financial transactions on behalf of specially designated nationals</header>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> may impose the sanction described in subsection (c) with respect to a foreign financial institution if the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> determines that the foreign financial institution has, on or after the date that is 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, knowingly facilitated a significant financial transaction on behalf of any Russian person included on the list of specially designated nationals and blocked persons maintained by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Office of Foreign Assets Control" entity-parent-id="2000">Office of Foreign Assets Control of the Department of the Treasury</cato:entity-ref>, pursuant to—</text> 
<paragraph id="HD843A9EC2AC14F6CBB052E04E544E531">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>this Act;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4A15CFF197E241ED9C50991872BEAA20">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>Executive Order No. 13660 (79 Fed. Reg. 13,493), 13661 (79 Fed. Reg. 15,535), or 13662 (79 Fed. Reg. 16,169); or</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8214CA23729B4C9AA5D0CDA8380B4F5A">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>any other Executive order addressing the crisis in Ukraine.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HC1F4DA1461A8444CAD45C807D66BCDD2">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Sanction described</header>
        <text>The sanction described in this subsection is, with respect to a foreign financial institution, a prohibition on the opening, and a prohibition or the imposition of strict conditions on the maintaining, in the United States of a correspondent account or a payable-through account by the foreign financial institution.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HE45191E3A292467DABB7419B15E09791">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>National security waiver</header>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> may waive the application of sanctions under this section with respect to a foreign financial institution if the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref>—</text> 
<paragraph id="H8B5E091D2D774C88AA8D973D2D2A40FC">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>determines that the waiver is in the national security interest of the United States; and</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAC3C236A42C64CEB9AB6131B51868110">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>submits to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the determination and the reasons for the determination.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HB1C785DA3890429FAE18F8D801452F35">
        <enum>(e)</enum>
        <header>Implementation; penalties</header> 
<paragraph id="H781C06CDD6E644279C38B177D9EDA1D9">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Implementation</header>
          <text>The President may exercise all authorities provided under <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="International Emergency Economic Powers Act/s:203">sections 203</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="International Emergency Economic Powers Act/s:205">205 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act</cato:entity-ref> (<cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/50/1702">50 U.S.C. 1702</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="uscode" value="usc/50/1704">1704</cato:entity-ref>) to carry out the purposes of this section.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8D07E62FA9224CB88DE624137567F73A">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Penalties</header>
          <text>The penalties provided for in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="International Emergency Economic Powers Act/s:206/ss:b">subsections (b)</cato:entity-ref> and <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="International Emergency Economic Powers Act/s:206/ss:c">(c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">
              <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</cato:entity-ref>
            </external-xref>)</cato:entity> shall apply to a person that violates, attempts to violate, or conspires to violate, or causes a violation of, subsection (a) or (b) of this section, or an order or regulation prescribed under either such subsection, to the same extent that such penalties apply to a person that commits an unlawful act described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="International Emergency Economic Powers Act/s:206/ss:a">section 206(a) of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HF661924F117B49F88ED7730B667211C2">
        <enum>(f)</enum>
        <header>Termination</header>
        <text>This section, and sanctions imposed under this section, shall terminate on the date on which the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> submits to the appropriate congressional committees the certification described in <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="act" value="Ukraine Freedom Support Act of 2014/s:4/ss:h" proposed="true">section 4(h)</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
<section id="HDE7283B0A2114D7D9883EEB04051F688">
      <enum>6.</enum>
      <header>Increased military assistance for the Government of Ukraine</header> 
<subsection id="HB2CC989A08184F54B34BC7B6B2069C24">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> is authorized to provide defense articles, defense services, and training to the Government of Ukraine for the purpose of countering offensive weapons and reestablishing the sovereignty and territorial integrity of Ukraine, including anti-tank and anti-armor weapons, crew weapons and ammunition, counter-artillery radars to identify and target artillery batteries, fire control, range finder, and optical and guidance and control equipment, tactical troop-operated surveillance drones, and secure command and communications equipment, pursuant to the provisions of the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Arms Export Control Act">Arms Export Control Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2751">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/2751/etseq">22 U.S.C. 2751 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity>, the <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961">Foreign Assistance Act of 1961</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2151">
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/2151/etseq">22 U.S.C. 2151 et seq.</cato:entity-ref>
          </external-xref>)</cato:entity>, and other relevant provisions of law.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HF15179767FEF4443AF52BAB3D948942C">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Report required</header>
        <text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall submit a report detailing the anticipated defense articles, defense services, and training to be provided pursuant to this section and a timeline for the provision of such defense articles, defense services, and training, to—</text> 
<paragraph id="HB106C39047834F60BE9DA2CA6D0FDB88">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="SSFR00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Foreign Relations</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSAP00">Committee on Appropriations</cato:entity-ref>, and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="SSAS00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Armed Services of the Senate</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H016B6DFB820A4CF993CB646E13E22338">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="HFA00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Foreign Affairs</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="HAP00">Committee on Appropriations</cato:entity-ref>, and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="HAS00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H3EEFDC3B500D48F297D6D2C1027A7846">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Authorization of appropriations</header> 
<paragraph id="H3350AE859CF342969C97F71F4BC0D4DC">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>
            <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">There are authorized to be appropriated to the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>
              <cato:funds-and-year amount="100000000" year="2015"> $100,000,000 for fiscal year 2015</cato:funds-and-year>, <cato:funds-and-year amount="125000000" year="2016">$125,000,000 for fiscal year 2016</cato:funds-and-year>, and <cato:funds-and-year amount="125000000" year="2017">$125,000,000 for fiscal year 2017</cato:funds-and-year> <cato:property name="purpose">to carry out activities under <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Ukraine Freedom Support Act of 2014/s:6" proposed="true">this section</cato:entity-ref>
              </cato:property>.</cato:entity>
          </text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H26B29ACA915B42CAA487CC388093F6C5">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Availability of amounts</header>
          <text>Amounts authorized to be appropriated pursuant to paragraph (1) shall remain available for obligation and expenditure through the end of fiscal year 2018.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HB6022435F7B5428991F71189E3894CA1">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Authority for the use of funds</header>
        <text>The funds made available pursuant to subsection (c) for provision of defense articles, defense services, and training may be used to procure such articles, services, and training from the United States Government or other appropriate sources.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H153D10507FA8444EA906A9FC5154DFF6">
        <enum>(e)</enum>
        <header>Protection of civilians</header>
        <text>It is the sense of <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> that the Government of Ukraine should take all appropriate steps to protect civilians.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
<section id="H30327ED0DEDD4A4EBFF27459FC0A62F8">
      <enum>7.</enum>
      <header>Expanded nonmilitary assistance for Ukraine</header> 
<subsection id="H153BFC58705744828B0BEC7A82293B87">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Assistance to internally displaced people in Ukraine</header> 
<paragraph id="H74F287C8EBFB4E8AA73FFE05751D22FB">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> shall submit a plan, including actions by the United States Government, other governments, and international organizations, to meet the need for protection of and assistance for internally displaced persons in Ukraine, to—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HAFB53C357A8D4FC480A3A188623E0208">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="SSFR00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Foreign Relations</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSAP00">Committee on Appropriations</cato:entity-ref>, and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="SSEG00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC585A11E328E4CBBA94CBE048B0A951A">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="HFA00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Foreign Affairs</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="HAP00">Committee on Appropriations</cato:entity-ref>, and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="HIF00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H226813740E224FD1BCBAA009A140CFEB">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Elements</header>
          <text>The plan required by paragraph (1) should include, as appropriate, activities in support of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3BE7677F697C4E3D88B9E2EA955999F3">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>helping to establish a functional and adequately resourced central registration system in Ukraine that can ensure coordination of efforts to provide assistance to internally displaced persons in different regions;</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3AB6623912274B25B67337152336D4BE">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>encouraging adoption of legislation in Ukraine that protects internally displaced persons from discrimination based on their status and provides simplified procedures for obtaining the new residency registration or other official documentation that is a prerequisite to receiving appropriate social payments under the laws of Ukraine, such as pensions and disability, child, and unemployment benefits; and</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE5CEDFF2FEFE4562ABD969CDFBDA351C">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>helping to ensure that information is available to internally displaced persons about—</text> 
<clause id="H10482A095A594E8CB6AA5F8D0C731E61">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>government agencies and independent groups that can provide assistance to such persons in various regions; and</text>
            </clause> 
<clause id="HD908A42D429F48A6BC29EBBA30F81C6A">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>evacuation assistance available to persons seeking to flee armed conflict areas.</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF6720A0FD33E4B4D9D1D2963F1D645D1">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Assistance through international organizations</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall instruct the United States permanent representative or executive director, as the case may be, to the relevant <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="19UN" entity-type="federal-body">United Nations</cato:entity-ref> voluntary agencies, including the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-parent-id="19UN" entity-type="federal-body" value="Office of the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees">United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs" entity-parent-id="19UN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</cato:entity-ref>, and other appropriate international organizations, to use the voice and vote of the United States to support appropriate assistance for internally displaced persons in Ukraine.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H475E757EEBED4793BF804C2557CE8DEF">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Assistance to the defense sector of Ukraine</header>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9700" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Defense</cato:entity-ref> should assist entities in the defense sector of Ukraine to reorient exports away from customers in the Russian Federation and to find appropriate alternative markets for those entities in the defense sector of Ukraine that have already significantly reduced exports to and cooperation with entities in the defense sector of the Russian Federation.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HE0C2B66516344FFB86BB529ACEC95FA3">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Assistance To address the energy crisis in Ukraine</header> 
<paragraph id="HEB007A1174D64A6C9909394E6F4149B3">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Emergency energy assistance</header> 
<subparagraph id="H58E522EA48D2435382F43C2787632107">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <header>Plan required</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="8900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Energy</cato:entity-ref>, in collaboration with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7200" entity-type="federal-body">Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7022" entity-type="federal-body">Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency</cato:entity-ref>, shall work with officials of the Government of Ukraine to develop a short-term emergency energy assistance plan designed to help Ukraine address the potentially severe short-term heating fuel and electricity shortages facing Ukraine in 2014 and 2015.</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE7FAA2DEF05F4B0D8F83910B55515CEC">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <header>Elements</header>
            <text>The plan required by subparagraph (A) should include strategies to address heating fuel and electricity shortages in Ukraine, including, as appropriate—</text> 
<clause id="H54183AFC07FE4517B82132C40BB805F1">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>the acquisition of short-term, emergency fuel supplies;</text>
            </clause> 
<clause id="HF8CED8C150D8476B9B476658E8745EEE">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>the repair or replacement of infrastructure that could impede the transmission of electricity or transportation of fuel;</text>
            </clause> 
<clause id="H538C7B837DF04C83B08C72F0366ED521">
              <enum>(iii)</enum>
              <text>the prioritization of the transportation of fuel supplies to the areas where such supplies are needed most;</text>
            </clause> 
<clause id="H234179371D46478CAA537919990C4F3E">
              <enum>(iv)</enum>
              <text>streamlining emergency communications throughout national, regional, and local governments to manage the potential energy crisis resulting from heating fuel and electricity shortages;</text>
            </clause> 
<clause id="HC51A5F79220C49499BF86161B5263BF7">
              <enum>(v)</enum>
              <text>forming a crisis management team within the Government of Ukraine to specifically address the potential crisis, including ensuring coordination of the team’s efforts with the efforts of outside governmental and nongovernmental entities providing assistance to address the potential crisis; and</text>
            </clause> 
<clause id="H16964FC2EC724716B4F0DB15A4073136">
              <enum>(vi)</enum>
              <text>developing a public outreach strategy to facilitate preparation by the population and communication with the population in the event of a crisis.</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H65202620322D4691BA06B4E10B5B9825">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <header>Assistance</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="8900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Energy</cato:entity-ref>, and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7200" entity-type="federal-body">Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development</cato:entity-ref> are authorized to provide assistance in support of, and to invest in short-term solutions for, enabling Ukraine to secure the energy safety of the people of Ukraine during 2014 and 2015, including through—</text> 
<clause id="HB734547C9CDB479F8D93A2516B7363E0">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>procurement and transport of emergency fuel supplies, including reverse pipeline flows from Europe;</text>
            </clause> 
<clause id="H04F5556A24764E13838C3E585BFBFB96">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>provision of technical assistance for crisis planning, crisis response, and public outreach;</text>
            </clause> 
<clause id="H35F83B81BE904347AF5B85B37590C8D6">
              <enum>(iii)</enum>
              <text>repair of infrastructure to enable the transport of fuel supplies;</text>
            </clause> 
<clause id="HFA7D86A081A746E98AF360F4C74EC583">
              <enum>(iv)</enum>
              <text>repair of power generating or power transmission equipment or facilities;</text>
            </clause> 
<clause id="H92682E7DE1CA4FE1977DB802A539C0AF">
              <enum>(v)</enum>
              <text>procurement and installation of compressors or other appropriate equipment to enhance short-term natural gas production;</text>
            </clause> 
<clause id="H222F0C9D6C244C7D8D5B45F05C7241B7">
              <enum>(vi)</enum>
              <text>procurement of mobile electricity generation units;</text>
            </clause> 
<clause id="HD07A8462F60B47E196C2BBF30BDDAA6B">
              <enum>(vii)</enum>
              <text>conversion of natural gas heating facilities to run on other fuels, including alternative energy sources; and</text>
            </clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H010C5BA368BF442BA7CEF6C1E6FC9AA4">
              <enum>(viii)</enum>
              <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provision of emergency weatherization and winterization materials and supplies.</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBD3871F3C6974849B0276FB1044984EB">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Reduction of Ukraine’s reliance on energy imports</header> 
<subparagraph id="H33874E55EB33496EBB46206E47C81E79">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <header>Plans required</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>, in collaboration with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="8900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Energy</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7200" entity-type="federal-body">Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development</cato:entity-ref>, shall work with officials of the Government of Ukraine to develop medium- and long-term plans to increase energy production and efficiency to increase energy security by helping Ukraine reduce its dependence on natural gas imported from the Russian Federation.</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2E7C691A5EFA4DB5828402DDBF94359E">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <header>Elements</header>
            <text>The medium- and long-term plans required by subparagraph (A) should include strategies, as appropriate, to—</text> 
<clause id="HEAFAE7F04E11466EBB270F0D8D034A6F">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <text>improve corporate governance and unbundling of state-owned oil and gas sector firms;</text>
            </clause> 
<clause id="H20D0EF71756B48A998D2653434E1127E">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <text>increase production from natural gas fields and from other sources, including renewable energy;</text>
            </clause> 
<clause id="HB5BA83248DF649ABB79E0D0FBED4BA4F">
              <enum>(iii)</enum>
              <text>license new oil and gas blocks transparently and competitively;</text>
            </clause> 
<clause id="H9EE5E10E5BDF41A49DCB4C3C83C79085">
              <enum>(iv)</enum>
              <text>modernize oil and gas upstream infrastructure; and</text>
            </clause> 
<clause id="H6E9B2D837F4649239AD7E048C9380121">
              <enum>(v)</enum>
              <text>improve energy efficiency.</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEDA3EC4012DB446CAB3A3FCEFA879677">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <header>Prioritization</header>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7200" entity-type="federal-body">Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development</cato:entity-ref>, and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="8900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of Energy</cato:entity-ref> should, during fiscal years 2015 through 2018, work with other donors, including multilateral agencies and nongovernmental organizations, to prioritize, to the extent practicable and as appropriate, the provision of assistance from such donors to help Ukraine to improve energy efficiency, increase energy supplies produced in Ukraine, and reduce reliance on energy imports from the Russian Federation, including natural gas.</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H176198574B864C02843F52261B3F0512">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
            <text>
              <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">There are authorized to be appropriated <cato:funds-and-year amount="50000000" year="2016..2018">$50,000,000 in the aggregate for fiscal years 2016 through 2018</cato:funds-and-year> <cato:property name="purpose">to carry out activities under <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Ukraine Freedom Support Act of 2014/s:7/ss:c/p:2" proposed="true">this paragraph</cato:entity-ref>
                </cato:property>.</cato:entity>
            </text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1E55ED9EFEC14F359B13D018EEB4884A">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Support from the overseas private investment corporation</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7100" entity-type="federal-body">Overseas Private Investment Corporation</cato:entity-ref> shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H95E69CAEAEAD49DEA9312C9AC7E7C215">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>prioritize, to the extent practicable, support for investments to help increase energy efficiency, develop domestic oil and natural gas reserves, improve and repair electricity infrastructure, and develop renewable and other sources of energy in Ukraine; and</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H47964B471FAB4760950BAD44B8B749D2">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>implement procedures for expedited review and, as appropriate, approval, of applications by eligible investors (as defined in <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="law-citation">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Foreign Assistance Act of 1961/s:238">section 238 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2198">
                <cato:entity-ref entity-type="uscode" value="usc/22/2198">22 U.S.C. 2198</cato:entity-ref>
              </external-xref>)</cato:entity>) for loans, loan guarantees, and insurance for such investments.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H71CDDF60B192429CB95CF4C23A1251FD">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <header>Support by the world bank group and the european bank for reconstruction and development</header>
          <text>The President shall, to the extent practicable and as appropriate, direct the United States Executive Directors of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="11DR" entity-type="federal-body">World Bank</cato:entity-ref> Group and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="11DK" entity-type="federal-body">European Bank for Reconstruction and Development</cato:entity-ref> to use the voice, vote, and influence of the United States to encourage the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="11DR" entity-type="federal-body">World Bank</cato:entity-ref> Group and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="11DK" entity-type="federal-body">European Bank for Reconstruction and Development</cato:entity-ref> and other international financial institutions—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HEF2548CB32E34DCA9FEB76CA8D15B735">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>to invest in, and increase their efforts to promote investment in, projects to improve energy efficiency, improve and repair electricity infrastructure, develop domestic oil and natural gas reserves, and develop renewable and other sources of energy in Ukraine; and</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE597950E86224220A3E37E1F3C5A4A8B">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>to stimulate private investment in such projects.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H0D945D9597F7436C80CBBE6B4F3902CE">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Assistance to civil society in ukraine</header> 
<paragraph id="HD2388EF84FAC420A88DADFE25720BB1E">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="7200" entity-type="federal-body">Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development</cato:entity-ref> shall, directly or through nongovernmental or international organizations, such as the Organization for Security and Co-operation in Europe, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1969" entity-type="federal-body">National Endowment for Democracy</cato:entity-ref>, and related organizations—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5B48E11A908747A092E9CE01F7D52F6E">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>strengthen the organizational and operational capacity of democratic civil society in Ukraine;</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H11C5F667B2BC44CEB29D1035606D61A5">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>support the efforts of independent media outlets to broadcast, distribute, and share information in all regions of Ukraine;</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEDE0921E4E0549D6A04022A6909188A9">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>counter corruption and improve transparency and accountability of institutions that are part of the Government of Ukraine; and</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7FE31A8EAFC64C41973DA2E2B0EF8804">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <text>provide support for democratic organizing and election monitoring in Ukraine.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0EFED286E9724299A5134C7083306D15">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Strategy required</header>
          <text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall submit a strategy to carry out the activities described in paragraph (1) to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H2BDCB4CC318E4F9F87BEC956B83C66FF">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="SSFR00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Foreign Relations</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="SSAP00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Appropriations of the Senate</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE809517898DC4835AD9F4C07B32FD0F5">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="HFA00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Foreign Affairs</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="HAP00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEEA527FF4AE047E696455DFFC9DEBE75">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
          <text>
            <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">There are authorized to be appropriated to the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>
              <cato:funds-and-year amount="20000000" year="20165"> $20,000,000 for fiscal year 2016</cato:funds-and-year>
              <cato:property name="purpose"> to carry out <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Ukraine Freedom Support Act of 2014/s:7/ss:d" proposed="true">this subsection</cato:entity-ref>
              </cato:property>.</cato:entity>
          </text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5DEED2800D24486EA77711EDF0F74C91">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <header>Transparency requirements</header>
          <text>Any assistance provided pursuant to this subsection shall be conducted in as transparent of a manner as possible, consistent with the nature and goals of this subsection. The President shall provide a briefing on the activities funded by this subsection at the request of the committees specified in paragraph (2).</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
<section id="HFDA48738063C4E9196BC972B202D2385">
      <enum>8.</enum>
      <header>Expanded broadcasting in countries of the former Soviet Union</header> 
<subsection id="HD9938F61E3014E04BE0D35FF11BE8479">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9568" entity-type="federal-body">Chairman of the Broadcasting Board of Governors</cato:entity-ref> shall submit to <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> a plan, including a cost estimate, for immediately and substantially increasing, and maintaining through fiscal year 2017, the quantity of Russian-language broadcasting into the countries of the former Soviet Union funded by the United States in order to counter Russian Federation propaganda.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H47AAA4B8BF6C4CA38341121B9171355C">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Prioritization of broadcasting into Ukraine, Georgia, and Moldova</header>
        <text>The plan required by subsection (a) shall prioritize broadcasting into Ukraine, Georgia, and Moldova by the Voice of America and Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HB6A81196423747FB8245AF17EE4D3D1E">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Additional priorities</header>
        <text>In developing the plan required by subsection (a), the Chairman shall consider—</text> 
<paragraph id="H9DA6F705EB124B19955CDE6EDF39BE16">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>near-term increases in Russian-language broadcasting for countries of the former Soviet Union (other than the countries specified in subsection (b)), including Latvia, Lithuania, and Estonia; and</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE906E328FA024380BA65E98738BF8DF2">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>increases in broadcasting in other critical languages, including Ukrainian and Romanian languages.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H41472C77A0804631A9C8ED1B345FF4B8">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Broadcasting defined</header>
        <text>In this section, the term <term>broadcasting</term> means the distribution of media content via radio broadcasting, television broadcasting, and Internet-based platforms, among other platforms.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H6CFACAF913354A7B8695FD6DEE207A74">
        <enum>(e)</enum>
        <header>Authorization of appropriations</header> 
<paragraph id="HCB83812A2FDE455CA66F45D77757F9F2">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>
            <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">There are authorized to be appropriated to the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="9568" entity-type="federal-body">Broadcasting Board of Governors</cato:entity-ref> <cato:funds-and-year amount="10000000" year="2016, 2017, 2018">$10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2016 through 2018</cato:funds-and-year> <cato:property name="purpose">to carry out activities under <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Ukraine Freedom Support Act of 2014/s:8" proposed="true">this section</cato:entity-ref>
              </cato:property>.</cato:entity>
          </text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0196A6049B5F4C28A4EFD516F129DB8C">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Supplement not supplant</header>
          <text>Amounts authorized to be appropriated pursuant to paragraph (1) shall supplement and not supplant other amounts made available for activities described in this section.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
<section id="HC8EF2FAD986442C1812A250CFA992407">
      <enum>9.</enum>
      <header>Support for Russian democracy and civil society organizations</header> 
<subsection id="H047C022360494A9387B6833DFFB38ED0">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> shall, directly or through nongovernmental or international organizations, such as the Organization for Security and Co-operation in Europe, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1969" entity-type="federal-body">National Endowment for Democracy</cato:entity-ref>, and related organizations—</text> 
<paragraph id="H129248F349CA4A1EA8F6A4279D859DF0">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>improve democratic governance, transparency, accountability, rule of law, and anti-corruption efforts in the Russian Federation;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA53E171244EA4859AE1F013B771B5107">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>strengthen democratic institutions and political and civil society organizations in the Russian Federation;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H531106CC32464080B637DE0C8F8C7DBC">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <text>expand uncensored Internet access in the Russian Federation; and</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5E4CD81991194D4BA97C0CD7C93ED855">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <text>expand free and unfettered access to independent media of all kinds in the Russian Federation, including through increasing United States Government-supported broadcasting activities, and assist with the protection of journalists and civil society activists who have been targeted for free speech activities.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H293D61AA86914CFB8D97EEAE2CA6A6A3">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
        <text>
          <cato:entity xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="auth-auth-approp">There are authorized to be appropriated to the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref> <cato:funds-and-year amount="20000000" year="2016, 2017, 2018">$20,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2016 through 2018</cato:funds-and-year> <cato:property name="purpose">to carry out the activities set forth in <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Ukraine Freedom Support Act of 2014/s:9/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>
            </cato:property>.</cato:entity>
        </text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HCAECCF96B62544F88E3CC2827CD93287">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Strategy requirement</header>
        <text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall submit a strategy to carry out the activities set forth in subsection (a) to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H4087E8C877E947E1994F21BDC8357278">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="SSFR00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Foreign Relations</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="SSAP00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Appropriations of the Senate</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H512156A801DC4D569B95551F8677781E">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="HFA00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Foreign Affairs</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="HAP00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HB84FBE90262C4559BCAA047FDAF2176D">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Transparency requirements</header>
        <text>Any assistance provided pursuant to this section shall be conducted in as transparent of a manner as possible, consistent with the nature and goals of this section. The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall provide a briefing on the activities funded by this section at the request of the committees specified in subsection (c).</text>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
<section id="H45973D246A864AD69E6260D6DCBE4E69">
      <enum>10.</enum>
      <header>Report on non-compliance by the Russian Federation of its obligations under the INF Treaty</header> 
<subsection id="HA6234F92172B4322A83A3C90556B4A35">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Findings</header>
        <text>Congress makes the following findings:</text> 
<paragraph id="H5BD75AEB92804254B10E159074457548">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>The Russian Federation is in violation of its obligations under the Treaty between the United States of America and the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics on the Elimination of Their Intermediate-Range and Shorter-Range Missiles, signed at Washington December 8, 1987, and entered into force June 1, 1988 (commonly referred to as the <quote>Intermediate-Range Nuclear Forces Treaty</quote> or <quote>INF Treaty</quote>).</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H058E218CFD78445985F5715D3E2F7758">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>This behavior poses a threat to the United States, its deployed forces, and its allies.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H6B8A728EEDF846B4A289BDE8013EFA43">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Sense of Congress</header>
        <text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text> 
<paragraph id="HB4BC55E98E814AD9BB1116347429E6F4">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> should hold the Russian Federation accountable for being in violation of its obligations under the INF Treaty; and</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H298366D5E39C459FB89B1EAC90BF86C4">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>the President should demand the Russian Federation completely and verifiably eliminate the military systems that constitute the violation of its obligations under the INF Treaty.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H50403AC8913D4EB9A2D42E1D5E7F3344">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Report</header> 
<paragraph id="HF758EAB9DED3435E95B1A05E251A9803">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
          <text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 90 days thereafter, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall submit to the committees specified in subsection (d) a report that includes the following elements:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H58609F04981D44CFB40A1CDA14EB4559">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <text>A description of the status of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1100" entity-type="federal-body">President's</cato:entity-ref> efforts, in cooperation with United States allies, to hold the Russian Federation accountable for being in violation of its obligations under the INF Treaty and obtain the complete and verifiable elimination of its military systems that constitute the violation of its obligations under the INF Treaty.</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFE78C9ABC9944F12BCA71AFB5AF2C288">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <text>The <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1100" entity-type="federal-body">President's</cato:entity-ref> assessment as to whether it remains in the national security interests of the United States to remain a party to the INF Treaty, and other related treaties and agreements, while the Russian Federation is in violation of its obligations under the INF Treaty.</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1309DE3CCB8F4FDDBE43558620ABCE56">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <text>Notification of any deployment by the Russian Federation of a ground launched ballistic or cruise missile system with a range of between 500 and 5,500 kilometers.</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H61BC98D34C2D4FE68E823442188A7D01">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <text>A plan developed by the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1900" entity-type="federal-body">Secretary of State</cato:entity-ref>, in consultation with the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="federal-body" value="Office of the Director of National Intelligence">Director of National Intelligence</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="9761" entity-type="federal-body">Defense Threat Reduction Agency</cato:entity-ref> (DTRA), to verify that the Russian Federation has fully and completely dismantled any ground launched cruise missiles or ballistic missiles with a range of between 500 and 5,500 kilometers, including details on facilities that inspectors need access to, people inspectors need to talk with, how often inspectors need the accesses for, and how much the verification regime would cost.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC9F7124ED7314D55AED612386D5B8DF7">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Form</header>
          <text>The report required under paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form but may contain a classified annex.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H02C0F9F16FD84FE5ADB6BC58B3DB98FE">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Committees specified</header>
        <text>The committees specified in this subsection are—</text> 
<paragraph id="HF57399CC2B77497195EA884CED41C9AA">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="SSFR00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Foreign Relations</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</cato:entity-ref>, and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="SLIN00" entity-type="committee">Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate</cato:entity-ref>; and</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6F4DEA41264B45A0ABF458F36959CBFE">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <text>the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="HFA00" entity-type="committee">Committee on Foreign Affairs</cato:entity-ref>, the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-type="committee" entity-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</cato:entity-ref>, and the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="HIG00" entity-type="committee">Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
<section id="H8AB1841C2EDA42AA90526F81BD735A64">
      <enum>11.</enum>
      <header>Rule of construction</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act or an amendment made by this Act shall be construed as an authorization for the use of military force.</text>
    </section> 
</legis-body> <attestation>
    <attestation-group>
      <role>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</role>
    </attestation-group>
    <attestation-group>
      <role>Vice President of the United States and President of the Senate.</role>
    </attestation-group>
  </attestation>
</bill>