<bill session="113" type="hr" number="567" updated="2015-09-01T10:18:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-08T18:30:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-05-08T18:30:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for the Establishment of the Select Committee on the Events Surrounding the 2012 Terrorist Attack in Benghazi.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400367"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-07T22:22:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Rules. H. Rept. 113-442.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-05-07T22:23:00-04:00" state="REPORTED" calendar="House" number="105">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 105.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-05-07T22:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 575 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H. Res. 567 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-08T16:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 575 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-08T16:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 575.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3971-3979" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-08T16:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H. Res. 567 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-08T16:14:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 567.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-08T17:21:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3979" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-08T17:21:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H. Res. 567, the Chair put the question on the resolution and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Slaughter demanded the yeas and nays, and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-08T18:04:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3985" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="209" datetime="2014-05-08T18:30:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 232 - 186 (Roll no. 209).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3971-3972" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-05-08T18:30:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-08T18:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Sessions asked unanimous consent to modify H. Res. 567 in the form he had placed at the desk. Without objection, the modification was agreed to.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3985" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="113" type="hr" number="575"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hr" number="604"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hr" number="722"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Libya"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Protection of officials"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h652"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>5/8/2014--Passed House without amendment.
Establishes in the House of Representatives the Select Committee on the Events Surrounding the 2012 Terrorist Attack in Benghazi to conduct a full and complete investigation and study and issue a final report of its findings to the House regarding:

 all policies, decisions, and activities that contributed to the attacks on U.S. facilities in Benghazi, Libya, on September 11, 2012, as well as those that affected the ability of the United States to prepare for them; all policies, decisions, and activities to respond to and repel such attacks, including efforts to rescue U.S. personnel; internal and public executive branch communications about these attacks; accountability for policies and decisions related to the security of facilities in Benghazi, Libya, and the response to the attacks, including individuals and entities responsible for those policies and decisions; executive branch authorities' efforts to identify and bring to justice the perpetrators of such attacks; executive branch activities and efforts to comply with congressional inquiries into them; recommendations for improving executive branch cooperation and compliance with congressional oversight and investigations; information related to lessons learned from the attacks and executive branch activities and efforts to protect U.S. facilities and personnel abroad; and any other relevant issues relating to such attacks, the response to them, or the investigation by the House into the attacks.</summary>
</bill>
