<bill session="113" type="h" number="4809" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-26">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-09-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reauthorize the Defense Production Act, to improve the Defense Production Act Committee, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412011"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-06-11" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-07-29T14:18:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Campbell moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-29T14:18:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7002-7004" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-29T14:18:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4809.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-29T14:36:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-29T17:42:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7024" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="464" datetime="2014-07-29T17:49:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 386 - 32 (Roll no. 464).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7002" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-07-29T17:49:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-30">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote2" datetime="2014-09-17" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5720" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2014-09-19">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2014-09-26" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="113-172" type="public" datetime="2014-09-26">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 113-172.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, Markup"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Industrial policy and productivity"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Military readiness"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/26/2014--Public Law.
(This measure has not been amended since it was passed by the House on July 29, 2014. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

(Sec. 1) Reauthorizes provisions of the Defense Production Act of 1950 (provides authority for the President and federal agencies to prepare for national defense, military conflicts, disasters, or acts of terrorism using the domestic industrial base to supply materials and services) through September 30, 2019.

Reinstates authorities under which the President may provide for loans to private business enterprises or authorize a guaranteeing agency to guarantee loans by private institutions to contractors, providers of critical infrastructure, or other persons for services, production, or deliveries essential to national defense. Makes such authorities effective for any fiscal year only to such extent or in such amounts as are provided in advance in appropriations Acts.

(Sec. 2) Revises requirements relating to the Defense Production Act Committee to: (1) direct the Committee to coordinate and plan (currently, advise the President) according to specified priorities and allocation authorities; (2) require the Chairperson to be the head of the agency to which the President has delegated primary responsibility for government-wide coordination of such activities; and (3) require the Chairperson to appoint a coordinator of Committee activities (currently, the President appoints an Executive Director).

Expands the Committee's annual report to Congress to include a description of contingency planning by federal agencies, legislative recommendations, and updated copies of federal agencies' rules to promote national defense under both emergency and nonemergency conditions.

(Sec. 3) Requires federal agencies delegated defense production authority to review such rules annually and make updates whenever appropriate.

(Sec. 4) Prohibits the President from: (1) delegating a determination to execute a contract for an industrial resource, material, or critical technology that is essential to national defense; (2) executing contracts for such capabilities unless the purchases are the most cost effective, expedient, and practical alternative method for meeting the need; and (3) taking action to correct an industrial resource shortfall without congressional authorization if such action would cause the aggregate outstanding amount of all such actions to exceed $50 million.

Prohibits the congressional authorization requirement for an aggregate amount exceeding $50 million from applying to projects undertaken pursuant to a determination made before the enactment of this Act.

(Sec. 5) Authorizes specified appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
