<bill session="113" type="h" number="3864" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-01-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-01-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-01-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Flexibility to Promote Reemployment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend certain provisions of the Social Security Act relating to demonstration projects designed to promote the reemployment of unemployed workers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412462"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412539" joined="2014-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412407" joined="2014-01-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412536" joined="2014-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412401" joined="2014-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412256" joined="2014-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412393" joined="2014-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400660" joined="2014-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400406" joined="2014-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412428" joined="2014-03-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-01-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2870"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/14/2014--Introduced.
Flexibility to Promote Reemployment Act - Amends title III (Grants to States for Unemployment Compensation Administration) of the Social Security Act, with respect to grants to states by the Secretary of Labor for reemployment demonstration projects, to allow grants to up to 10 states per year instead of a maximum of 10 states altogether.

Allows a designee of a state governor, instead of only the governor, to apply for such a grant.

Extends the allowable project period through December 31, 2017.

Allows direct disbursements under a project to employers who hire individuals receiving unemployment compensation to include disbursements promoting retention.

Requires the Secretary of Labor to approve completed grant applications in the order of receipt.

Revises requirements for termination of a project to require the Secretary to: (1) notify a state in writing with sufficient detail describing any violation of the substantive terms or conditions of a project justifying its termination, and (2) determine that the state has not taken action to correct the violation within 90 days after notification.

Directs the Secretary to evaluate the impact of each demonstration project, using existing data sources and methodology appropriate to determine project effects, including the effect on individual skill levels, earnings, and employment retention.</summary>
</bill>
