<bill session="113" type="s" number="2725" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Consequences for Russia's Arms Control Violations Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to address noncompliance by the Russian Federation of its obligations under the Intermediate-Range Nuclear Forces (INF) Treaty.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412491"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412322" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2014-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="5293"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Poland"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Romania"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2014--Introduced.
Consequences for Russia's Arms Control Violations Act of 2014 - Expresses the sense of Congress that:

 the Russian Federation is in material breach of its Intermediate-Range Nuclear Forces (INF) Treaty obligations through its prohibited flight testing of both ballistic intermediate-range and cruise missiles, and the President should take actions to deny the Russian Federation any militarily significant advantage resulting from its noncompliance. Prohibits the use of Department of State funds to carry out programs of the U.S.-Russia Bilateral Presidential Commission until the President certifies to Congress that the Russian Federation has or has not performed certain prohibited ballistic missile flight tests.

Directs:

 the President to establish a program to develop certain ground-launched cruise missile and ground-launched ballistic missile capabilities; and the Secretary of Defense (DOD) to ensure that the Aegis Ashore sites in Romania and Poland are deployed with an operational capability to defend against cruise missiles and short-, medium-, and intermediate-range ballistic missiles launched from the Russian Federation. Authorizes the President to waive the requirement to establish such missile development program if the Russian Federation is in compliance with its Treaty obligations and has eliminated any military system that was developed and deployed in violation of the Treaty.

States that, if the President does not certify to Congress that the Russian Federation is not developing or deploying any military system that violates or circumvents the Treaty, the President shall:

 suspend any cooperation with the Russian Federation related to any aspect of the U.S. program for national, theater, or regional missile defense; deny any license for the export of nuclear material, equipment, or technology to the Russian Federation; terminate the Agreement Between the Government of the United States of America and the Government of the Russian Federation for Cooperation in the Field of Peaceful Uses of Nuclear Energy; and not award any U.S. government contract to a private or public entity in the Russian Federation. Authorizes the President to waive such sanctions in specified circumstances.

Prohibits the President from entering into any agreement with the Russian Federation regarding the reduction of nuclear forces except with the advice and consent of the Senate.</summary>
</bill>
