<bill session="113" type="h" number="4444" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-04-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-04-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Long-Term SCORE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Long-Term Studies of Comprehensive Outcomes and Returns for the Economy Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to require that the Congressional Budget Office prepare long-term scoring estimates for reported bills and joint resolutions that could have significant economic and fiscal effects outside of the normal scoring periods.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412489"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2014-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412284" joined="2014-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412487" joined="2014-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412585" joined="2014-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412520" joined="2014-04-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Budget, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-09">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-09">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Congressional Budget Office (CBO)"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/9/2014--Introduced.
Long-Term Studies of Comprehensive Outcomes and Returns for the Economy Act or Long-Term SCORE Act - Amends the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 (CBA) to establish within the Congressional Budget Office (CBO) a long-term budget scoring division.

Requires the CBO Director, whenever a CBO cost analysis of a public bill or resolution reported by any congressional committee (except the congressional appropriations committees) is prepared, and upon the request of any Member of Congress, to prepare and submit to such committee the information requested, except that it shall be for, if practicable, at least each of the next four 10 fiscal-year periods (long-term cost analysis).</summary>
</bill>
