<bill session="113" type="s" number="2189" updated="2015-09-01T17:50:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-04-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-04-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Energy Efficiency Tax Incentives Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to improve and extend the deduction for new and existing energy-efficient commercial buildings, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2014-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412507" joined="2014-04-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-01">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1925"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1925-1933" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-07">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs Subcommittee on Economic Policy. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 113-466.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSFI" subcommittee="Economic Policy" name="Senate Finance"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Lighting and heating"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/1/2014--Introduced.
Energy Efficiency Tax Incentives Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) extend through 2016, and increase the maximum rate of, the tax deduction for energy-efficient commercial building expenditures; (2) allow a new tax deduction for the cost of retrofitting existing commercial and multifamily buildings; (3)&#160;allow a new tax credit, through 2016, for home energy efficiency improvements that increase energy efficiency by at least 20%; (4) extend&#160;through 2018&#160;the tax credit for combined heat and power system property expenditures and increase the capacity limitations and credit percentages for systems with a higher efficiency rating; (5) allow an energy tax credit&#160;for investment in biomass heating property and for waste heat to power property (i.e., a system which generates electricity through the recovery of a qualified waste heat resource and is placed in service before January 1, 2019); (6) allow a new business-related tax credit for efficient advanced motor systems with adjustable speed capability; (7)&#160;allow a new business-related tax credit for&#160;replacement of large water-cooled&#160;refrigerant chillers that use environmentally harmful refrigerants; and (8) allow a new tax credit for expenditures to increase water use efficiency&#160;in the manufacturing sector.</summary>
</bill>
