<bill session="113" type="h" number="5204" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-30">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Lands Recreation Enhancement Modernization Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Federal Lands Recreation Enhancement Modernization Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Lands Recreation Enhancement Act to improve recreation opportunities and increase consistency and accountability in the collection and expenditure of recreation fees collected on public lands and forests, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400029"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-25">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-25">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-30">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-07-30" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-08-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Energy, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-22T17:54:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 113-706, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-22T17:55:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee on Agriculture discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-12-22T17:55:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="537">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 537.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG15" subcommittee="Conservation, Energy, and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/25/2014--Introduced.
Federal Lands Recreation Enhancement Modernization Act of 2014 - Amends the Federal Lands Recreation Enhancement Act to extend the authority for the collection and expenditure of recreation fees on federal lands through 2020.

Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to:

 charge day use fees for lands and waters at a National Conservation Area, a National Volcanic Monument, a destination visitor or interpretive center, and sites of concentrated public use that meet specified criteria; charge transportation fees at National Park Service units; charge amenity fees for the use of facilities or services on federal lands; charge fees for special recreation permits issued to recreation service providers and for individual and group use of federal facilities, lands, and waters; and issue recreation concession permits to provide facilities and services on lands and waters managed by the Bureau of Land Management (BLM). Prohibits the Secretary from charging recreation fees for any site, area, or activity except as authorized by statute.

Requires the Secretary to determine a nationally consistent fee policy and rate structure for specified fees authorized by this Act.

Establishes a stewardship program for recreation service providers involving credit against permit fees in exchange for maintenance and resource protection work performed.

Requires congressional approval of certain new or increased fees.

Increases the portion of fee revenue available for expenditure at the collection site from 80% to 90%. Limits fee revenues that the Secretary may use for overhead, administrative, and collection costs.</summary>
</bill>
