<bill session="113" type="h" number="3667" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-12-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-12-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-12-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to increase by 10 percentage points the required State match for certain newly eligible individuals under the Medicaid program and to apply savings against sequestration reductions otherwise required, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412434"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400052" joined="2013-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412269" joined="2013-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412472" joined="2013-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412275" joined="2013-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412474" joined="2013-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400626" joined="2013-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412483" joined="2013-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400433" joined="2013-12-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-12-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-05">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-05">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/5/2013--Introduced.
Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to increase by 10% the required state matching funds for certain newly eligible individuals under the Medicaid program who, as of January 1, 2014, are under age 65, not pregnant, not entitled to or enrolled for benefits under SSA title XVIII (Medicare), and whose income does not exceed 133% of the poverty line for a family of the size involved.

Directs the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to increase the discretionary spending limit under the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 (Gramm-Rudman-Hollings Act) for the security category by $20 billion for FY2014 and then to increase the security and nonsecurity categories for that fiscal year each by half of the remaining estimated reduction in new budget authority resulting from enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
