<bill session="113" type="h" number="5374" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FAIR Assistance Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fairness and Accountability In Rental Assistance Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a maximum limitation on the amount of the payment standard that may be used with respect to housing choice vouchers provided under the Moving to Work program of the Department of Housing and Urban Development.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412314"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2014--Introduced.
Fairness and Accountability In Rental Assistance Act of 2014 or the FAIR Assistance Act of 2014 - Amends the Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development, and Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 1996 with respect to the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) Moving to Work demonstration program.

Limits the payment standard used in connection with a voucher for tenant-based rental assistance under the program, for FY2015 and thereafter, to 120% of the fair market value rental established under the United States Housing Act of 1937 for the applicable market area and size of dwelling unit.

Exempts from this limitation any family that:

 is elderly or disabled; or resides, at the time of a declared major disaster, and before the first adjustment to the fair market rental after the disaster declaration, in a principal residence located within the disaster area that meets other conditions and requirements as the HUD Secretary may provide.</summary>
</bill>
