<bill session="113" type="h" number="4831" updated="2015-09-01T17:49:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Twenty-First Century Manufacturing Skills and Jobs Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a Federal tax credit approximation matching program for State new manufacturing jobs training tax credits, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412546"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2014-07-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-10">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-10">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Training" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1795"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="State and local taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/10/2014--Introduced.
Twenty-First Century Manufacturing Skills and Jobs Act of 2014 - Directs the Secretary of the Treasury, on a quarterly basis, to make payments to an eligible community college in an amount equal to the aggregate new manufacturing job withholding matches for qualified training provided to job trainees who are U.S. citizens. Defines "qualified training" as education or training to provide an individual with the education or skills necessary to perform the job for which such individual will be employed or with licenses or certificates necessary for such employment. Requires that any job for which a trainee is hired be a new job.

Defines "eligible community college" as a public institution of higher education: (1)&#160;at which the majority of degrees awarded are two-year associate's degrees that are acceptable for full credit toward a baccalaureate degree, (2) that is located in a state that has a state new manufacturing jobs tax credit program in effect, and (3) that participates in such program by having in effect&#160;a contract that meets requirements of such program.</summary>
</bill>
