<bill session="113" type="s" number="1744" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-12-15">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-12-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-11-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Security Clearance Accountability, Reform, and Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Security Clearance Accountability, Reform, and Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Security Clearance Accountability, Reform, and Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to strengthen the accountability of individuals involved in misconduct affecting the integrity of background investigations, to update guidelines for security clearances, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by senate">A bill to strengthen the accountability of individuals involved in misconduct affecting the integrity of background investigations, to update guidelines for position designation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412244"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412493" joined="2014-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300005" joined="2013-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2013-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412496" joined="2013-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412243" joined="2013-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300078" joined="2013-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400325" joined="2013-11-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-11-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-05-21" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-11-20">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Carper with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-11-20" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="606">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 606.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-12-01">
      <text>By Senator Carper from Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs filed written report. Report No. 113-276.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="2014-12-15" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment and an amendment to the Title by Voice Vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6866-6867" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S6866" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-12-16">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-16T12:11:00-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-16T13:24:00-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Employee leave"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Office of Personnel Management (OPM)"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/20/2013--Introduced.
Security Clearance Accountability, Reform, and Enhancement Act - Requires the Director of the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) to: (1) terminate or place on administrative leave an OPM employee if the Director determines that such employee was intentionally involved in misconduct affecting the integrity of the background investigations of OPM, including falsification of a background investigation report, fraud relating to such report, or other serious misconduct that compromises the integrity of a background investigation report; and (2) debar or suspend an individual employed or contracted by a person under contract with OPM if the Director determines that such individual was intentionally involved in similar misconduct.

Directs the President to review and update guidance for agencies that shall be used to: (1) determine whether a position requires its&#160;occupant to have&#160;a security clearance; (2) implement such guidance, including quality controls; and (3) review (at least every five years) and, if necessary, revise the designation of a position as requiring its occupant to have access to classified information or secure government facilities.</summary>
</bill>
