<bill session="113" type="h" number="5487" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Real Estate Investment and Jobs Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to exempt certain stock of real estate investment trusts from the tax on foreign investments in United States real property interests, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400046"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400087" joined="2014-09-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2870"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1181"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Real estate business"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Taxation of foreign income"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/16/2014--Introduced.
Real Estate Investment and Jobs Act of 2014 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) increase from 5% to 10% the allowable ownership interest in real estate investment trust (REIT) stock for purposes of tax exemptions allowed by the Foreign Investment in Real Property Tax Act (FIRPTA) relating to foreign investment in U.S. real property interests; (2) require a U.S. real property holding corporation to make its status readily accessible and publicly available; (3) require brokers who sell an interest in a U.S. real property holding corporation to deduct and withhold 10% on the amount realized from the sale, with specified exceptions; (4) include regulated investment companies (RICs) and real estate investment companies (REITs) in the definition of U.S. real property interests; and (5) deny dividends derived from RICs and REITs a tax deduction for the U.S. source portion of dividends from certain foreign corporations.</summary>
</bill>
