<bill session="113" type="h" number="4858" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">San Gabriel National Recreation Area Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the San Gabriel National Recreation Area as a unit of the National Park System in the State of California, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412379"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412517" joined="2014-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2014-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2014-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2014-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2014-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412521" joined="2014-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400355" joined="2014-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400361" joined="2014-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="2014-09-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="Public Lands and Environmental Regulation" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Property rights"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/12/2014--Introduced.
San Gabriel National Recreation Area Act - Designates approximately 615,245 acres of federal lands and interests in California as the San Gabriel National Recreation Area.

Requires National Forest System lands within the Recreation Area to be administered by the Department of Agriculture (USDA), and park lands to be administered by the Department of the Interior as a unit of the National Park System. Transfers approximately 2,987 acres of land administered by the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) to the National Park Service. Requires Interior and USDA to manage the land in a manner that protects and enhances the land's natural resources and values. Directs Interior and USDA to consult with the Secretary of Defense (DOD) regarding opportunities to manage the Army Corps of Engineers lands within the Recreation Area. Establishes the San Gabriel National Recreation Area Public Advisory Council and the San Gabriel National Recreation Area Partnership. Requires Interior, USDA, and the San Gabriel National Recreation Area Public Advisory Council to create a comprehensive management plan for the Recreation Area. Withdraws the land from: (1) entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws; (2) location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and (3) disposition under all laws pertaining to mineral and geothermal leasing or mineral materials. Permits grazing on Forest System lands where it is already established. Requires Interior to develop an integrated visitor services plan for the Recreation Area. Authorizes USDA and Interior to construct visitor use facilities. Requires Interior to conduct a study on the Area's accessibility.</summary>
</bill>
