<bill session="113" type="h" number="4369" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-04-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-04-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Using our Energy to Build Better Communities Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Mineral Leasing Act to require payment to each county of a portion of mining royalties received for mining operations in such county, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412460"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Energy revenues and royalties"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/2/2014--Introduced.
Using Our Energy To Build Better Communities Act - Amends the Mineral Leasing Act, with respect to disposition of moneys received from oil, gas, and geothermal leases and prospecting permits on federal lands, to reduce from 40% to 20% the amount designated for the reclamation fund created under the Reclamation Act.

Requires that another 20% of such funds be used to pay directly to each county in which mining operations occurred an amount directly proportional to the portion of such money attributable to those operations.

Requires that moneys paid directly to such county be used by the county for its schools and roads.

Makes this Act inapplicable to Alaska and its counties.</summary>
</bill>
