<bill session="113" type="h" number="4799" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Clean Air Fairness Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Clean Air Act to give States adequate time to revise their State implementation plans to prevent emissions activity within such States from contributing significantly to nonattainment in, or interfering with maintenance by, any other State with respect to any national ambient air quality standard, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412302"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400052" joined="2014-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400655" joined="2014-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400116" joined="2014-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412445" joined="2014-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412487" joined="2014-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412431" joined="2014-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400367" joined="2014-06-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/2/2014--Introduced.
Clean Air Fairness Act of 2014 - Amends the Clean Air Act to revise provisions concerning implementation plans for national primary and secondary ambient air quality standards.

Prohibits the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) from promulgating a federal implementation plan for a state related to national ambient air quality standards until the EPA: (1) promulgates a final rule identifying the emission reductions necessary to meet interstate transport of air emissions requirements, and (2) provides states at least two years to revise their state implementation plans (SIPs). (A federal implementation plan is created due to the failure of an SIP to contain adequate provisions prohibiting emissions activity which will contribute significantly to nonattainment in, or interfere with maintenance by, another state with any national ambient air quality standard.) Prohibits a state from being subjected to penalties for an inadequate SIP until these conditions are met.

Prohibits the EPA from promulgating, implementing, or enforcing a federal implementation plan due to the failure of an SIP to comply with the Cross-State Air Pollution Rule unless the EPA: (1) takes into consideration the Supreme Court's decision in Environmental Protection Agency et al. v. EME Homer City Generation, L.P., et al., (2) publishes a final notice indicating the EPA's intent to enforce the rule, and (3) provides states with at least two years from the publication date to revise their SIPs. Prohibits a state from being subject to penalties for the failure of a SIP to comply with the rule until these conditions are met.</summary>
</bill>
