<bill session="113" type="s" number="2705" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Renewable Energy Environmental Research Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish, within the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, an integrated and comprehensive ocean, coastal, Great Lakes, and atmospheric research and environmental information sharing program to support renewable energy, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412326"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Biological and life sciences"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="Libraries and archives"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/2014--Introduced.
Renewable Energy Environmental Research Act of 2014 - Requires the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), within three years, to: (1) develop a plan for a comprehensive and integrated ocean, coastal, Great Lakes, and atmosphere science program to support renewable energy development and smart grid technology; and (2) establish the program that is based on the plan and designed to collect, synthesize, and distribute data in a manner that can be used by resource managers responsible for making decisions about renewable energy projects.

Requires the Army Corps of Engineers, Department of Commerce, Bureau of Ocean Energy Management, Minerals Management Service, Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC), and Department of Energy (DOE) to consider this information when making planning, siting, and permitting decisions about renewable energy.

Requires NOAA to establish within three years a renewable energy information library and data portal to function as a cross-agency repository of data pertinent to renewable energy development.

Gives NOAA the discretion to allow any offshore exploration and production facility to execute a memorandum of understanding authorizing the use of offshore platforms and infrastructure for the placement of meteorological and oceanographic observation sensors of a type to be designated by NOAA in support of the Integrated Ocean Observing System. Requires information collected by the sensors to be readily available for use in hazard response as well as available to the National Weather Service, other NOAA programs, and the general public.</summary>
</bill>
