<bill session="113" type="h" number="2749" updated="2015-09-01T10:19:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Education Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to make certain records available to educational institutions where veterans or persons receiving educational assistance under the laws administered by the Secretary are enrolled, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400232"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412505" joined="2013-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="2013-07-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR10" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/19/2013--Introduced.
Veterans Education Transparency Act - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) to provide to any veteran or person who receives educational assistance under the laws administered by the Secretary the option of making such person's relevant records maintained by the Secretary, including information about the amount of educational assistance to which the person is entitled, available through an Internet website to the educational institution that provides the course of education in which the person is enrolled.

Directs the Secretary to take steps to ensure that: (1) such educational institution agrees that such records will be made available only for the purpose of counseling the person in making decisions related to his or her education, and (2) no unauthorized person is given access to any such record.</summary>
</bill>
