<bill session="113" type="s" number="1580" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-10-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-10-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ensuring Safe Shelter for Homeless Veterans Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to require recipients of per diem payments from the Secretary of Veterans Affairs for the provision of services for homeless veterans to comply with codes relevant to operations and level of care provided, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412326"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-30">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 113-280.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1950"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1982"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Homelessness and emergency shelter"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/28/2013--Introduced.
Ensuring Safe Shelter for Homeless Veterans Act of 2013 - Prohibits a per diem payment from being made to providers of services for homeless veterans unless the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) certifies that: (1) the building where the entity provides housing or services is in compliance with codes relevant to the operations and level of care provided; and (2) such building and the housing or services provided are in compliance with licensing, fire and safety, and other requirements of the relevant jurisdiction regarding the condition of the building and the provision of such housing or services.

 Authorizes the Secretary to revoke any certification upon determining that it is no longer accurate. Requires the Secretary to: (1) inspect such facilities at least annually, and (2) notify Congress of any such revocation and termination of per diem payments.

Requires the Secretary's annual report on assistance to homeless veterans to include an evaluation of the safety and accessibility of such providers' facilities.

Directs the Secretary to assess the compliance of the building and housing and services provided by current per diem payment recipients. Prohibits additional payments to a recipient that is not, within two years after enactment of this Act, certified to be in compliance until the Secretary certifies that the building and housing and services provided are in compliance.</summary>
</bill>
