<bill session="113" type="s" number="2563" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improving Driver Safety Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 23, United States Code, to improve highway safety and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412242"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412494" joined="2014-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2014-07-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/26/2014--Introduced.
Improving Driver Safety Act of 2014 - Revises distracted driving incentive grant program eligibility requirements to require the Secretary of Transportation (DOT) to award such grants to states that include distracted driving issues as part of their driver's license examination.

Authorizes the Secretary to use up to 50% of amounts available for grants to states that: (1) in FY2015 have a basic text messaging statute for drivers of all ages, make violation of the statute a primary offense, and participate in the Secretary's annual distracted driving law enforcement mobilization; and (2) in FY2016 meet the aforementioned requirements, impose increased fines for repeat violations, and have a statute that prohibits a driver younger than 18 from using a personal wireless communications device while driving.

Authorizes states to use grant funds for: (1) enforcement of distracted driving laws, and (2) highway safety program projects.

Directs the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration (NHTSA) to report to Congress on any legal and technical barriers to capturing data on the prevalence of wireless communications devices while driving, including recommendations on how to address those barriers.</summary>
</bill>
