<bill session="113" type="s" number="2173" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-03-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-03-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-03-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CHOICE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Consumers Having Options in Choosing Enrollment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to provide a permanent path for the direct enrollment of individuals in qualified health plans.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300063"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2014-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412554" joined="2014-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412391" joined="2014-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412321" joined="2014-03-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-03-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/27/2014--Introduced.
Consumers Having Options in Choosing Enrollment Act or CHOICE Act - Amends the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (PPACA) to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to issue guidelines and necessary operational specifications to provide for the establishment of a permanent pathway to enable individuals to enroll in qualified health plans through: (1) a state-based Exchange, if there is one, or if appropriate, a health insurance issuer, a certified agent or broker, or a Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS)-certified Internet web-based broker or entity; or (2) the Federal Exchange (in a state with no state exchange), a health insurance issuer, an agent or broker certified by the Federal Exchange, or a CMS-certified Internet web-based broker or entity.

Makes guidelines and operational capabilities issued under this Act available to consumers and applicable health insurance issuers and entities for any enrollment period required by PPACA.</summary>
</bill>
