<bill session="113" type="h" number="4962" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Border and Homeland Security Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for enhanced border security, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400141"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412216" joined="2014-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400077" joined="2014-07-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400086" joined="2014-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412526" joined="2014-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412479" joined="2014-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412397" joined="2014-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400206" joined="2014-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412510" joined="2014-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400656" joined="2014-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412295" joined="2014-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400279" joined="2014-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400441" joined="2014-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412302" joined="2014-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400652" joined="2014-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412309" joined="2014-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400341" joined="2014-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412411" joined="2014-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412399" joined="2014-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="410396" joined="2014-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412574" joined="2014-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412578" joined="2014-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412525" joined="2014-06-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, Natural Resources, and Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-25">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-25">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-25">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-25">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border and Maritime Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Cybersecurity, Infrastructure Protection, and Security Technologies.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM11" subcommittee="Border and Maritime Security" name="House Homeland Security"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM08" subcommittee="Cybersecurity, Infrastructure Protection, and Security Technologies" name="House Homeland Security"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Border Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="Public Lands and Environmental Regulation" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Chemical and biological weapons"/>
    <term name="Customs enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="General public lands matters"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes and releases"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Smuggling and trafficking"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/25/2014--Introduced.
National Border and Homeland Security Act - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to give state criminal alien assistance program (SCAAP) funding priority to: (1) northern or southern border states, or (2) state political subdivisions having one of the four largest populations of unlawfully present aliens for the preceding fiscal year.

Amends the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 to direct the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) (Secretary) to complete the required 700 mile southwest border fencing and priority-area fencing by December 31, 2015.

Amends the Secure Fence Act of 2006 to direct the Secretary, in consultation with state and local officials along the U.S.-Mexico border, to achieve operational control over U.S. international land and maritime borders by December 31, 2015.

Directs the Secretary to:

 increase the number of full-time, active-duty Border Patrol agents through FY2018; increase the number of U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) officers at U.S. ports of entry through FY2018; and establish within 18 months the biometric entry and exit data system required by the Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2004. Prohibits the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) from impeding border security-related activities by the Secretary on U.S. public lands.

Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct the Domestic Nuclear Detection Office (of DHS), in protecting the United States from a nuclear, fissile material, or radiological attack, to consider potential smuggling routes in land border areas between ports of entry, railcars entering the United States from Canada or Mexico, and private aircraft or small vessels.

Directs the Secretary to procure within one year the number of next generation portable radiation detectors (PRDs) and radioactive isotope identification devices (RIIDs) required by the Border Patrol along the southern and northern U.S. borders.

Directs the Secretary to develop within one year, and implement within two years of development, a strategic plan to detect and interdict biological and chemical weapons entering the United States.</summary>
</bill>
