<bill session="113" type="sr" number="586" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-12-04">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-12-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-11-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution calling on the Government of Burma to develop a non-discriminatory and comprehensive solution that addresses Rakhine State's needs for peace, security, harmony, and development under equitable and just application of the rule of law, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400272"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412598" joined="2014-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2014-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2014-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412390" joined="2014-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2014-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400222" joined="2014-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2014-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412491" joined="2014-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2014-11-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-11-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6209-6210" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-12-04" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-12-04">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Menendez with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and with an amended preamble. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-12-04" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="615">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 615.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Burma"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/4/2014--Reported to Senate amended.
Calls on the government of Burma to:

 develop a non-discriminatory and comprehensive solution that addresses Rakhine State's needs for peace and development under equitable application of the rule of law; end all forms of persecution and discrimination of the Rohingya people, and ensure respect for internationally recognized human rights for all ethnic and religious minority groups within Burma; respect the Rohingya's right to self-identification, redraft the Citizenship Law of 1982 so that it conforms to internationally recognized legal standards, and include both Rakhine and Rohingya leaders and community members in the redrafting process; support an international and independent investigation into the violence that has occurred in Rakhine State and prosecute the perpetrators consistent with due process; and conform to international norms on the provision of unrestricted humanitarian access by international organizations. Welcomes Burma's announcement that Medecins Sans Frontieres has been invited back to work in Rakhine State.

Calls on the regional governments to protect the rights of Rohingya asylum seekers and refugees, as well as to respect the international legal principle of non-refoulement.

Calls on the U.S. government and the international community to call on the government of Burma to end the persecution of the Rohingya population and to protect the fundamental rights of all ethnic and religious minority groups in Burma.</summary>
</bill>
