<bill session="113" type="h" number="4408" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-04-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-04-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Lawrence J. Hackett Jr. Vietnam Veterans Agent Orange Fairness Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to establish a task force on Agent Orange exposure.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412297"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2014-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400316" joined="2014-07-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR09" subcommittee="Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Birth defects"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
    <term name="South Korea"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
    <term name="Vietnam"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/4/2014--Introduced.
Lawrence J. Hackett Jr. Vietnam Veterans Agent Orange Fairness Act - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) to establish a task force to assess and make recommendations about the care and compensation that should be provided to veterans who have been exposed to Agent Orange, their spouses, and multiple generations of their offspring.

Requires the task force to make recommendations: (1) to establish the Agent Orange Illness Compensation Program to provide an exposed veteran or eligible survivor a lump sum payment for the veteran's injury, illness, or death; (2) for the establishment of a national outreach and education campaign to communicate information about Agent Orange exposures and health conditions to veterans who are affected by incidents of toxic exposures and their families; (3) for compensation and health care for individuals with Spina Bifida, birth defects, or other illnesses who are the children or descendants of members of the Armed Forces who served in Vietnam or in or near the demilitarized zone in Korea during certain time periods determined by the task force; and (4) for the establishment of a unified policy to deal with the consequences of exposure to hazardous materials in the military.

Terminates the task force not later than two years after its establishment.</summary>
</bill>
