<bill session="113" type="h" number="5360" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Renaissance in Manufacturing Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To enhance the competitiveness of American manufacturers and exports in the global marketplace by providing tax relief, regulatory relief, liability relief, and ensuring access to abundant and affordable supplies of energy, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412474"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412541" joined="2014-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412395" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400071" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412604" joined="2014-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412400" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412526" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400116" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412479" joined="2014-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400175" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412550" joined="2014-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412437" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412422" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412226" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412510" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412191" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412295" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400626" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412310" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412399" joined="2014-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, the Budget, the Judiciary, Rules, Natural Resources, Transportation and Infrastructure, and Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Science, Space, and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-08-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-08-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-08-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-08-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="Public Lands and Environmental Regulation" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW07" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW14" subcommittee="Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY18" subcommittee="Environment" name="House Science, Space, and Technology"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="271"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="367"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="982"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1582"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1900"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2218"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2231"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2655"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2728"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2784"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2823"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2850"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3042"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3301"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3309"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3826"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4438"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4457"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4718"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4743"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="5304"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1288"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1342"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1720"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1905"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2319"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2823"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Atlantic Ocean"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Birds"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Charitable contributions"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Energy revenues and royalties"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC)"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Fruit and vegetables"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Horticulture and plants"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Income tax rates"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Insects"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Nebraska"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pacific Ocean"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="South Carolina"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="U.S. territories and protectorates"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2014--Introduced.
American Renaissance in Manufacturing Act - Title I: Creating a More Competitive Tax Code - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to reduce to 25% of taxable income the income tax rate for corporations (currently, the maximum rate is 35%). Makes permanent: (1) the reduction in the recognition period for the built-in gains of S corporations, (2) the basis adjustments to the stock of S corporations making charitable contributions of appreciated property, (3) the expensing allowance for depreciable business assets, (4) the research tax credit, and (5) the additional depreciation allowance (bonus depreciation) for business assets.

Title II: Reining In Job-Killing Washington Red Tape - States that the purpose of this title is to increase accountability for and transparency in the federal regulatory process by requiring Congress to approve all new major regulations.

Revises provisions relating to congressional review of agency rulemaking to require a federal agency promulgating a rule to include in its report to Congress and to the Comptroller General (GAO) a classification of the rule as a major or nonmajor rule. Sets forth a congressional approval procedure for major rules and a congressional disapproval procedure for nonmajor rules. Amends the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 to provide that any rule subject to such congressional approval procedure affecting budget authority, outlays, or receipts shall be assumed to be effective unless it is not approved in accordance with such procedure.

Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), before promulgating as final an energy-related rule that is estimated to cost more than $1 billion, to report to Congress on the effects of such rule on the economy and on employment. Prohibits the Administrator from: (1) using the social cost of carbon in any cost-benefit analysis relating to such energy-related rule; and (2) issuing, implementing, or enforcing any proposed or final rule under the Clean Air Act that establishes a performance standard for greenhouse gas emissions from any new source that is a fossil fuel-fired electric utility generating unit unless the rule meets specified requirements.

Nullifies the force and effect of specified proposed rules (or similar successor proposed or final rules) for Standards of Performance for Greenhouse Gas Emissions for New Stationary Sources: Electric Utility Generating Units.

Amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act to authorize states to adopt and implement coal combustion residuals permit programs.

Title III: Reducing Frivolous Legal Costs - Amends the sanctions provisions in Rule 11 of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure to require the court to impose an appropriate sanction on any attorney, law firm, or party that has violated, or is responsible for the violation of, the rule with regard to representations to the court. Requires any sanction to compensate parties injured by the conduct in question.

Repeals the provision that prohibits filing a motion for sanctions if the challenged paper, claim, defense, contention, or denial is withdrawn or appropriately corrected within 21 days after service or within another time the court sets.

Authorizes the court to impose additional sanctions, such as striking the pleadings, dismissing the suit, or other nonmonetary directives or ordering penalty payments if warranted for effective deterrence.

Amends federal bankruptcy law to require a quarterly report on asbestos claims.

Revises pleading and procedural requirements for patent infringement actions. Directs the U.S. Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) to notify the public on its website when a patent case is brought in federal court.

Codifies judicial doctrine relating to the consideration of prior art in cases of double patenting for the purpose of determining the nonobviousness of a second patent's claimed invention, thereby specifying that such doctrine continues to apply to the first-inventor-to-file patent system under the Leahy-Smith America Invents Act.

Amends the Federal Power Act to require the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) to ensure that any emergency order issued under such Act for the interconnection of facilities for the generation, transmission, and sale of electric energy that may result in a conflict with a requirement of any environmental law: (1) requires generation, delivery, interchange, or transmission of electric energy only during hours necessary to meet the emergency and serve the public interest; and (2) to the maximum extent practical, is consistent with any other applicable environmental law and minimizes any adverse environmental impacts.

Title IV: Preserving Access to Abundant and Affordable Sources of Energy - Expedites the permit approval process for the Keystone Pipeline by eliminating the requirement for a presidential permit and other requirements.

Amends the Natural Gas Act to direct the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) to approve or deny a certificate of public convenience and necessity within 12 months after providing public notice of the permit application for a natural gas pipeline project.

Prohibits any person from constructing, connecting, operating, or maintaining a cross-border segment of an oil or natural gas pipeline or electric transmission facility at the national boundary of the United States for the import or export of oil, natural gas, or electricity to or from Canada or Mexico without obtaining a certificate of crossing under this Act.

Amends the Mineral Leasing Act to prohibit the Department of the Interior from enforcing any federal regulation, guidance, or permit requirement regarding hydraulic fracturing (including any component of that process), relating to oil, gas, or geothermal production activities on or under any land in any state that has regulations, guidance, or permit requirements for that activity.

Amends the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act to direct the Secretary of the Interior to implement a leasing program that includes at least 50% of the available unleased acreage within each Outer Continental Shelf (OCS) planning area considered to have the largest undiscovered, technically recoverable oil and gas resources, with an emphasis on offering the most geologically prospective parts of the planning area.

Directs the Secretary of the Interior to conduct specified oil and gas lease sales on the Outer Continental Shelf off the coasts of Virginia and South Carolina and to offer for sale leases of tracts in the Southern California area.

Allocates 37.5% of the amount of new federal leasing revenues to coastal states that are: (1) impacted by the leases under which those revenues are received by the United States, and (2) within 200 miles of the leased tract.

Establishes in the Department of the Interior: (1) an Under Secretary for Energy, Lands, and Minerals; (2) an Assistant Secretary of Ocean Energy and Safety; (3) an Assistant Secretary of Land and Minerals Management; (4) a Bureau of Ocean Energy; (5) an Ocean Energy Safety Service; and (6) an Office of Natural Resources Revenue.

Directs the Secretary to establish: (1) a National Offshore Energy Safety Academy to train oil and gas inspectors and other Department of Interior personnel; and (2) an Outer Continental Shelf Energy Safety Advisory Board to provide advice on mineral and renewable energy exploration, development, and production activities.

Abolishes the Minerals Management Service.

Prohibits the Bureau of Ocean Energy and the Ocean Energy Safety Service from developing, proposing, finalizing, administering, or implementing any limitation on activities under their jurisdictions as a result of the coastal and marine spatial planning component of the National Ocean Policy developed under Executive Order No. 13547.

Redefines the OCS to include all submerged lands lying within the U.S. exclusive economic zone and the Continental Shelf adjacent to any U.S. territory.

Sets forth requirements for filing complaints for judicial review of federal actions relating to energy leases.</summary>
</bill>
