<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 S1769 IS: Standard of Care Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2013-11-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>113th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1769</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20131121">November 21, 2013</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S351">Mr. Toomey</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S277">Mr. Carper</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To limit the establishment of certain standards of care or duties of care owed by health care providers to patients in any medical malpractice or medical product liability action or claim.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the
		  <quote><short-title>Standard of Care Protection Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id2ff65607ebf24941bdc73055b8b74502"><enum>2.</enum><header>Rule of construction regarding health care provider standards of care</header><subsection id="id9f96e6e7d50b498a93684244ffdd9954"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The development, recognition, or implementation of any guideline or other standard under any Federal health care provision shall not be construed to establish the standard of care or duty of care owed by a health care provider to a patient in any medical malpractice or medical product liability action or claim.</text></subsection><subsection id="idff84a59480fc4800918c01fb75989417"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section:</text><paragraph id="id0b60793974824262a02bfe13ba51dc29"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal health care provision</header><text>The term <term>Federal health care provision</term> means any provision of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/148">Public Law 111–148</external-xref>), title I and subtitle B of title III of the Health Care and Education Reconciliation Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/152">Public Law 111–152</external-xref>), and titles XVIII and XIX of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395">42 U.S.C. 1395 et seq.</external-xref> and 1396 et seq.).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfa30e9f298c843b4931507e7eed6efc6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Health care provider</header><text>The term <term>health care provider</term> means any individual or entity—</text><subparagraph id="id81aed1b2989a477f92d4a7efc90f78f0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>licensed, registered, or certified under Federal or State laws or regulations to provide health care services; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7f1b9c5eb20545ea93d4b0a3d3930676"><enum>(B)</enum><text>required to be so licensed, registered, or certified but that is exempted by other law or regulation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idb15080c5c19545509f1c182a57651eb7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Medical malpractice or medical product liability action or claim</header><text>The term <term>medical malpractice or medical product liability action or claim</term> means a medical malpractice action or claim (as defined in section 431(7) of the Health Care Quality Improvement Act of 1986 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11151">42 U.S.C. 11151(7)</external-xref>)) and includes a liability action or claim relating to a health care provider's prescription or provision of a drug, device, or biological product (as such terms are defined in section 201 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/321">21 U.S.C. 321</external-xref>) or section 351 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/262">42 U.S.C. 262</external-xref>)).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id91cf5af87757418691569944930e3fc3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> includes the 50 States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, and any other commonwealth, possession, or territory of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idd37623b7cd2048d6949f44b539d1f132"><enum>(c)</enum><header>No preemption</header><text>No provision of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/148">Public Law 111–148</external-xref>), title I or subtitle B of title III of the Health Care and Education Reconciliation Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/152">Public Law 111–152</external-xref>), or title XVIII or XIX of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395">42 U.S.C. 1395 et seq.</external-xref> and 1396 et seq.) shall be construed to preempt any State or common law governing medical malpractice or medical product liability actions or claims.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


