<bill session="113" type="s" number="2313" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-05-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Do Your Job Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit Congressional recesses until Congress adopts a concurrent resolution on the budget that results in a balanced federal budget by fiscal year 2024 and to control Congressional travel budgets.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412602"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers and employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/8/2014--Introduced.
Do Your Job Act - Prohibits either chamber from recessing or standing adjourned, between enactment of this Act and enactment of a concurrent budget resolution setting a deficit level of $0 or a surplus by FY2024, for a period that exceeds 24 hours.

Requires each Member of Congress to submit a budget for the fiscal year for official travel by the Member and the Member's employees to: (1) the Secretary of the Senate for a Senator, and (2) the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representative for a Member of the House.

Rescinds, effective on October 1 of each fiscal year, any unobligated amounts made available for official travel by a Member of Congress or his or her employee during the previous fiscal year. Requires rescinded funds to be used for deficit reduction.</summary>
</bill>
