<bill session="113" type="sr" number="413" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-04-10">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-04-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution recognizing 20 years since the genocide in Rwanda, and affirming it is in the national interest of the United States to work in close coordination with international partners to help prevent and mitigate acts of genocide and mass atrocities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412390"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2014-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2014-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400134" joined="2014-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2014-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2014-04-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2200" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-04-10" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-04-11">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Menendez without amendment. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-04-11" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="363">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 363.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-12-09">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6463" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-09">
      <text>Resolution agreed to in Senate with an amendment and an amended preamble by Voice.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 12/10/14 S6579" label="text"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Central African Republic"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="Rwanda"/>
    <term name="South Sudan"/>
    <term name="Sudan"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="War crimes, genocide, crimes against humanity"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s3993"/>
    <amendment number="s3994"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>12/9/2014--Passed Senate amended.
Recognizes the designation by the United Nations (U.N.) of April 7th as the International Day of Reflection on the Genocide in Rwanda.

 Honors the memory of the more than 800,000 victims of the Rwandan genocide.

Affirms that it is in the U.S. national interest to work with international partners to prevent and mitigate acts of genocide and mass atrocities.

Condemns ongoing acts of violence and mass atrocities perpetrated in Syria, the Central African Republic, South Sudan, Sudan, and elsewhere.

Urges the President to: (1) confer with Congress on an ongoing basis regarding the priorities and objectives of the Atrocities Prevention Board, and (2) work with Congress to strengthen the U.S. government's ability to respond to genocide and mass atrocities.

Supports U.S. and international efforts to: (1) strengthen multilateral peacekeeping capacities; (2) improve civilian protection in areas of conflict; (3) ensure measures of accountability for perpetrators of mass atrocities and crimes against humanity; and (4) strengthen the work of U.S. and international institutions, such as the Holocaust Memorial Museum, to document and prevent mass atrocities and inspire citizens and leaders to confront hatred and prevent genocide.</summary>
</bill>
