<bill session="113" type="h" number="1900" updated="2015-09-01T10:19:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-11-21T12:14:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-11-21T12:14:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Natural Gas Pipeline Permitting Reform Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Natural Gas Pipeline Permitting Reform Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Natural Gas Pipeline Permitting Reform Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the timely consideration of all licenses, permits, and approvals required under Federal law with respect to the siting, construction, expansion, or operation of any natural gas pipeline projects.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412431"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412469" joined="2013-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400018" joined="2013-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400032" joined="2013-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412269" joined="2013-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412508" joined="2013-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412555" joined="2013-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412472" joined="2013-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412406" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400165" joined="2013-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412280" joined="2013-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412460" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400224" joined="2013-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412256" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412468" joined="2013-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400255" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412487" joined="2013-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400285" joined="2013-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412302" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412528" joined="2013-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400367" joined="2013-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400400" joined="2013-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400433" joined="2013-08-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-05-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-08">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-10">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-11">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-11">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-16">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-17">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-07-17" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 28 - 14.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-11-18T12:15:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 113-269.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-11-18T12:15:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="192">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 192.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-11-19T16:40:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 420 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1900 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-20T13:53:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 420 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-21T09:18:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 420.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7315-7332, H7334-7335" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-21T09:18:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1900 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-21T09:18:00-05:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 420 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-21T09:19:00-05:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Ted Poe to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-21T09:19:00-05:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 1900.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-21T10:10:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 420, the Committee of Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Tonko amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-21T10:16:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Tonko amendment No. 1, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Tonko demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-21T10:17:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 420, the Committee of Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Castor (FL) amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-21T10:27:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Castor (FL) amendment No. 2, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Castor demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-21T10:27:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 420, the Committee of Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Speier amendment No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-21T10:34:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Speier amendment No. 3, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Speier demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-21T10:34:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 420, the Committee of Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Jackson Lee (TX) amendment No. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-21T10:41:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Jackson Lee (TX) amendment No. 4, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Jackson Lee (TX) demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-21T10:42:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 420, the Committee of Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Dingell amendment No. 5.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-21T10:51:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Dingell amendment No. 5, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Dingell demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-21T10:52:00-05:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question on adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-21T11:44:00-05:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 1900.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-21T11:45:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7332" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-21T11:45:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Tierney moved to recommit with instructions to Energy and Commerce.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7332" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7332" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-21T11:46:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Tierney motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to report the same back to the House forthwith, with an amendment to prevent any provisions of the underlying bill from taking effect unless the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, in consultation with appropriate regulatory agencies, determines that the implementation of the bill will not: adversely impact natural gas pipeline safety; or inhibit the ability of communities to meaningfully engage in the siting of natural gas pipelines that affect them.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-21T11:50:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7332" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-21T11:56:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 180 - 233 (Roll no. 610).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7333-7334" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="611" datetime="2013-11-21T12:14:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 252 - 165 (Roll no. 611).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7322" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-11-21T12:14:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-09">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="113" type="hr" number="420"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="5360"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC)"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h512"/>
    <amendment number="h513"/>
    <amendment number="h514"/>
    <amendment number="h515"/>
    <amendment number="h516"/>
    <amendment number="h517"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>11/21/2013--Passed House amended.
Natural Gas Pipeline Permitting Reform Act - Amends the Natural Gas Act to direct the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) to approve or deny a certificate of public convenience and necessity for a prefiled project within 12 months after receiving a complete application that is ready to be processed.

Defines "prefiled project" as a project for the siting, construction, expansion, or operation of a natural gas pipeline with respect to which a prefiling docket number has been assigned by FERC pursuant to a prefiling process established by FERC for the purpose of facilitating the formal application process for obtaining a certificate of public convenience and necessity.

Requires the agency responsible for issuing any federal license, permit, or approval regarding the siting, construction, expansion, or operation of a project for which a certificate is sought to approve or deny issuance of the certificate within 90 days after FERC issues its final environmental document regarding the project.

Requires FERC to grant an agency request for a 30-day extension of the 90-day time period if the agency demonstrates that it cannot otherwise complete the process required to approve or deny the license, permit, or approval, and therefore will be compelled to deny it.

Authorizes FERC, in granting such an extension, to offer technical assistance to the agency in order to address conditions preventing completion of the application review.

Declares that, if the agency fails to approve or deny issuance of a permit, license, or approval within the prescribed time-frame, the license, permit, or approval shall take effect upon expiration of 30 days after the period's end.

Directs FERC to incorporate into the terms of a license, permit, or approval any conditions proffered by the agency that FERC does not find to be inconsistent with the final environmental document.</summary>
</bill>
