<bill session="113" type="s" number="2879" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sustainable Chemistry Research and Development Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the implementation of a Sustainable Chemistry Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412390"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2014-09-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Chemistry"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Scientific communication"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/18/2014--Introduced.
Sustainable Chemistry Research and Development Act of 2014 - Directs the President to establish an interagency Sustainable Chemistry Program to promote and coordinate federal sustainable chemistry research, development, demonstration, technology transfer, commercialization, education, and training activities.

Directs the President to establish an Interagency Working Group that includes representatives from specified federal agencies to oversee the planning, management, and coordination of the Program.

Requires the Interagency Working Group to establish an Advisory Council on Sustainable Chemistry to make recommendations to it and provide it with advice and assistance.

Requires participating agencies to report to the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) on Program activities and appropriations.

Requires the Interagency Working Group to submit a report to Congress, as well as to the Government Accountability Office (GAO).

Instructs the Interagency Working Group to lead agencies in awarding grants to institutions of higher education to establish partnerships with companies across the value chain in the chemical industry to: (1) create collaborative research, development, demonstration, technology transfer, and commercialization programs; and (2) train students and retrain professional scientists and engineers in the use of sustainable chemistry concepts and strategies.

Requires the Director of the National Science Foundation (NSF) to contract with the National Research Council to assess the current status of sustainable chemistry research in the United States.

Directs the Interagency Working Group to produce a national strategy for sustainable chemistry that provides a framework for advancing sustainable chemistry research.</summary>
</bill>
