<resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="H94BF529CC21D42A0B03002DC079B80BD" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HRES 725 IH: Commending the Departments of Defense and Veterans Affairs for their joint campaign to raise awareness during September, Suicide Prevention Month, to reduce suicide among members of the United States Armed Forces and veterans.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-09-15</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 725</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20140915">September 15, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="E000293">Ms. Esty</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Veterans’ Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Commending the Departments of Defense and Veterans Affairs for their joint campaign to raise
			 awareness during September, Suicide Prevention Month, to reduce suicide
			 among members of the United States Armed Forces and veterans.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas>
      <text>Whereas suicide is a leading noncombat cause of death among members of the United States Armed
			 Forces;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas on average, 22 veterans are lost to suicide in the United States each day;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas more than 38,000 people in the United States take their lives each year, 20 percent of whom
			 are veterans;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the <cato:entity entity-type="law-citation">
          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Joshua Omvig Suicide Prevention Act">Joshua Omvig Suicide Prevention Act</cato:entity-ref> (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/110">
          <cato:entity-ref entity-type="public-law" value="public-law/110/110">Public Law 110–110</cato:entity-ref>
        </external-xref>; <cato:entity-ref entity-type="statute-at-large" value="statute-at-large/121/1031">121 Stat. 1031</cato:entity-ref>)</cato:entity> was enacted in
			 2007 to establish a comprehensive program for suicide prevention among
			 veterans;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Veterans Crisis Line, which was established under the Joshua Omvig Suicide Prevention
			 Act, has received more than 890,000 telephone calls and facilitated more
			 than 30,000 life-saving rescues;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas many suicides are preventable, and 90 percent of individuals who die by suicide have a
			 diagnosable psychiatric disorder at the time of death;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas September is National Suicide Prevention Awareness Month; and</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas in September 2014, the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="9700" entity-type="federal-body">Department of Defense</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="3600" entity-type="federal-body">Department of Veterans Affairs</cato:entity-ref>
			 launched the joint public awareness campaign <quote>The Power of 1</quote> to draw attention to the mental health services and suicide prevention programs available to
			 members of the United States Armed Forces and veterans, focusing on
			 everyday actions that can save lives: Now, therefore, be it</text>
    </whereas>
  </preamble>
	<resolution-body id="H8E8FC4C82FA54AB8B63A10C807817C7C" style="traditional">
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HCFC3DE29F2894A6AA7ECDE45FA681E3D" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text>That the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="0050" entity-type="federal-body">House of Representatives</cato:entity-ref>—</text>
			<paragraph id="H70F82BBC8FA847999C5C38F7B27E0A5D">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">commends the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="9700" entity-type="federal-body">Department of Defense</cato:entity-ref> and the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="3600" entity-type="federal-body">Department of Veterans Affairs</cato:entity-ref> for raising awareness
			 during Suicide Prevention Month of the life-saving resources available to
			 those who have served, or are currently serving, in uniform; and</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HAD64580A369D47BDB9449EDFC6041552">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>supports the goals and ideals of National Suicide Prevention Awareness Month, <quote>The Power of 1</quote> campaign, and efforts to improve outreach to individuals at risk for suicide, especially those
			 addressed to veterans and members of the United States Armed Forces.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>