<bill session="113" type="h" number="5848" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-12-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-12-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-12-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Early Warning Reporting System Improvement Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To enhance the early warning reporting requirements for motor vehicle manufacturers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412571"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="408211" joined="2014-12-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-12-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="s" number="2151"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/11/2014--Introduced.
Early Warning Reporting System Improvement Act of 2014 - Revises early warning reporting requirements for manufacturers of motor vehicles regarding possible defects of motor vehicles and motor vehicle equipment.

Directs the Secretary of Transportation (DOT) to require a manufacturer in cases where the defect has caused a fatality to provide certain additional information as part of its report to the Secretary. Requires that information to be publicly disclosed and entered into the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration (NHTSA) early warning reporting database.

Directs the Secretary to: (1) take specified actions to improve public accessibility to information on NHTSA's public vehicle safety databases; and (2) give public notice via the internet of all inspections or investigations conducted by the Secretary to enforce a motor vehicle safety requirement or order, or that are related to a motor vehicle accident due to a possible defect.</summary>
</bill>
