<bill session="113" type="h" number="3423" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-10-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-10-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure the safety and well-being of adopted children.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400230"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412404" joined="2013-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412453" joined="2014-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412451" joined="2013-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412562" joined="2013-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2014-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2013-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412412" joined="2013-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412255" joined="2013-10-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-30">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-30">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1527"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/30/2013--Introduced.
Amends part B (Child and Family Services) of title IV of the Social Security Act to make it a purpose of the Stephanie Tubbs Jones Child Welfare Services Program to promote efforts to prevent children from entering the foster care system through the provision of pre- and post-adoptive support services.

Extends adoption promotion and support services to those designed to support adoptions from other countries as well as domestic adoptions. Specifies related pre- and post-adoptive support services.

Amends SSA title IV part E (Foster Care and Adoption Assistance) to revise requirements for state expenditures for adoption support services.

Amends the Public Health Service Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), acting through the Administrator of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration, to award grants or cooperative agreements to eligible entities to develop and implement statewide or tribal post-adoption mental health service programs for all adopted children.

Amends SSA title IV part D (Child Support and Establishment of Paternity) to direct the Secretary, as part of the child support and paternity data collection system, to promulgate final regulations requiring the states to collect and report information regarding children adopted within the United States or from other countries who enter into state custody as a result of the disruption of a placement for adoption or the dissolution of an adoption.

Directs the Comptroller General (GAO) to report to Congress on how children are advertised for adoption, prospective parents, and support for adopting families.</summary>
</bill>
