<bill session="113" type="h" number="5377" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Postal Facilities Preservation and Sales Reform Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for certain safeguards with respect to the sale of historic postal facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400366"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2014-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Art, artists, authorship"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
    <term name="U.S. Postal Service"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2014--Introduced.
Postal Facilities Preservation and Sales Reform Act - Revises requirements for making a determination as to the necessity for&#160;closing or consolidating any postal facility to require that the U.S. Postal Service (USPS): (1) hold at least three public meetings, located in the area affected by the closing or consolidation, at least 120 days prior to the determination; and (2) provide adequate notice of the closing or consolidation to persons served by such facility&#160;at least 180 days prior to the proposed date of such closing or consolidation.

Prohibits USPS from entering into any contract or agreement to sell or relocate a historic postal facility until the proposed decision to sell or relocate is reviewed in accordance with requirements of the National Historic Preservation Act.

Requires USPS to use the Historic Surplus Property Program to dispose of a historic postal facility that has been determined by the State Historic Preservation Officer or the Keeper of the National Register of Historic Places to be of national significance. Requires: (1) the Postmaster General to maintain a list of historic postal facilities and to publish such list on the USPS website, (2) the Postmaster General to maintain a separate preservation budget for such facilities, and (3) the USPS Federal Preservation Officer to notify the National Museum of American Art when New Deal art (art located at a postal facility that was commissioned by the federal government between 1933 and 1937)&#160;owned by USPS is loaned or relocated.

Requires the Postmaster General to develop a model covenant to be used and applied to any historic postal facility offered for sale that: (1) requires the purchaser of such a facility to allow public access to any historic artwork located within such facility, (2) requires USPS&#160;to contribute sufficient funds to the maintenance of such artwork, and (3) prohibits the purchaser of the historic postal facility from demolishing or altering&#160;it in any way that is incompatible with its historic character.

Nullifies the proposed rule published&#160;by USPS in&#160;the Federal Register on January 13, 2014, relating to a categorical exclusion under the National Environmental Policy Act for disposal of USPS facilities.</summary>
</bill>
