<bill session="113" type="h" number="5485" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ravi Thackurdeen Safe Students Study Abroad Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require additional reporting on crime and harm that occurs during student participation in programs of study abroad, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412562"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400364" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400415" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400623" joined="2014-11-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Training" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Area studies and international education"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/16/2014--Introduced.
Ravi Thackurdeen Safe Students Study Abroad Act - Amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require an institution of higher education (IHE), other than a foreign IHE, that is participating in the programs under title IV to distinguish, in its annual campus security report on crime statistics, crimes that occur while a student is participating in an approved study abroad program, without regard to whether the IHE owns or controls a building or property at the location where the crime occurred.

Requires such IHEs to develop and distribute, as part of their annual security report provided to students and employees, a statement that the IHE has adopted and implemented a program to protect students participating in an approved study abroad program from crime and harm.

Requires each student protection program to include:

 a biennial review by the IHE of its study abroad programs to determine their effectiveness in protecting students from crime and harm and the number of deaths and sexual assaults of program participants, accidents and illnesses occurring during program participation, and incidents resulting in police involvement during the preceding 10 years; and the crime statistics IHEs are required to include in their annual campus security report. Requires such IHEs to:

 provide each student who is interested in participating in an approved study abroad program with a pre-trip orientation session and information regarding the countries in which the programs are located and the incidents and crime statistics they are required to include in their protection program for students studying abroad; and provide each student who returns from such a study abroad program with a post-trip orientation session, including an exit interview that assists the IHE in carrying out its program to protect students studying abroad. Directs the Secretary to periodically review a representative sample of those student protection programs.</summary>
</bill>
