<bill session="113" type="s" number="2459" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Know Before You Owe Federal Student Loan Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to revise counseling requirements for certain borrowers of student loans and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300048"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3596-3597"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/10/2014--Introduced.
Know Before You Owe Federal Student Loan Act of 2014 - Amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require institutions of higher education (IHEs) to provide pre-loan counseling at or prior to the first disbursement of a new loan to a student borrower under the William D. Ford Federal Direct Loan program. (Currently, such counseling is limited to students who are first-time borrowers of such loans.)

Adds to the information to be provided to students as part of such counseling:

 an estimate of their projected loan debt-to-income ratio upon graduation and their estimated total student loan debt, calculated for their particular program of study; a statement that they should borrow the minimum amount necessary to cover expenses; information about the default risk of having a projected loan debt-to-income ratio greater than 12%; options for reducing borrowing through scholarships, reduced expenses, work-study, or other work opportunities; and an explanation of the importance of graduating on time and of how adding an additional year of study impacts total indebtedness. Requires each IHE, prior to certifying a Federal Direct Loan for disbursement to a student borrower, to ensure that the student manually enters, either in writing or through electronic means, the exact dollar amount of such loan that the student desires to borrow.</summary>
</bill>
