<bill session="113" type="h" number="4154" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-03-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-03-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Russia Visa Sanctions Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To deny visas and entry to the United States to officials and employees of the Government of the Russian Federation due to the Russian military intervention in Ukraine, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400652"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400147" joined="2014-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412569" joined="2014-03-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-03-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Border Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Ukraine"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/5/2014--Introduced.
Russia Visa Sanctions Act - Directs the Secretary of State, except to meet treaty obligations regarding United Nations (U.N.) headquarters, to deny a visa to, and the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to deny U.S. admission to, all government officials and employees of the Russian Federation until the Secretary of State certifies to Congress that: (1) Russian military intervention into Ukraine has ceased; and (2) the Russian Federation respects the sovereignty, independence, and territorial integrity of Ukraine in accordance with the 1994 Budapest Memorandum on Security Assurances.

States that this certification requirement shall not apply to military bases of the Russian Federation in Ukraine's Crimean peninsula operating in accordance with the 1997 agreement on the Status and Conditions of the Black Sea Fleet Stationing on the Territory of Ukraine.</summary>
</bill>
