<bill session="113" type="h" number="4685" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Central Coast Heritage Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To designate certain Federal lands in California as wilderness, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400062"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412516" joined="2014-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="2014-05-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="Public Lands and Environmental Regulation" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Property rights"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/20/2014--Introduced.
Central Coast Heritage Protection Act - Designates specified Bureau of Land Management (BLM) and National Forest System lands in California as wilderness areas and as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System.

Designates certain land in Los Padres National Forest in California, comprising approximately 2,174 acres, as the Machesna Mountain Potential Wilderness Area. Requires such Area to be incorporated into the Machesna Mountain Wilderness Area.

Designates specified segments of the Indian, Mono, Matilija, Sespe, and Piru Creeks and Sisquoc River in California as components of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System.

Designates certain land in the Los Padres National Forest in California, comprising approximately 41,617 acres, as the Fox Mountain Potential Wilderness Area. Requires such Area to be incorporated into the San Rafael Wilderness.

Designates specified land: (1) in Los Padres National Forest comprising approximately 18,666 acres, as the Condor Ridge Scenic Area; and (2) in Los Padres National Forest and in the Bakersfield Field Office of the BLM, comprising approximately 15,846 acres, as the Black Mountain Scenic Area.

Designates the Condor Trail in Monterey County, California, as the Condor National Recreation Trail.

Requires the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) to study: (1) connecting the northern and southern parts of the Los Padres National Forest using a trail corridor across parts of the Northern and Southern Santa Lucia Mountains of the Southern California Coastal Range; and (2) nonmotorized recreation trail opportunities (including mountain bicycling) on land not designated as wilderness by this Act within the Santa Barbara, Ojai, and Mt. Pinos ranger districts.

Ensures that Indian tribes have access to the wilderness areas, scenic areas, and potential wilderness areas designated by this Act for traditional cultural and religious purposes.</summary>
</bill>
