<bill session="113" type="h" number="5232" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">NOTICE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Notice of Observation Treatment and Implication for Care Eligibility Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to require hospitals to provide certain notifications to individuals classified by such hospitals under observation status rather than admitted as inpatients of such hospitals.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400111"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412538" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412428" joined="2014-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-29">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-29">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-08-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/29/2014--Introduced.
Notice of Observation Treatment and Implication for Care Eligibility Act or the NOTICE Act - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to require a hospital with an agreement with the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to give each individual entitled to benefits under Medicare part A (Hospital Insurance), whom the hospital classifies for more than 24 hours as an outpatient under observation status or any other similar status, an adequate oral and written notification within 36 hours of that classification which:

 explains the individual's status as an outpatient under observation (or any similar status) and not as an inpatient; explains the reason for that classification; explains the implications of that outpatient status on eligibility for Medicare coverage of items and services as well as cost-sharing requirements; includes the name and title of the hospital staff who gave an oral notification and its date and time; and is signed by individual, if the notification is written, to acknowledge its receipt.</summary>
</bill>
