<bill session="113" type="s" number="2638" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Natural Gas Export Certainty Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Natural Gas Act to provide certainty with respect to the timing of Department of Energy decisions to approve or deny applications to export natural gas.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412494"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2274"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2592"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC)"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/22/2014--Introduced.
Natural Gas Export Certainty Act of 2014 - Amends the Natural Gas Act to direct the Secretary of Energy (DOE) to make a public interest determination and issue an order for an application for the exportation of natural gas to a foreign country through a particular liquefied natural gas (LNG) terminal not later than 45 days after receipt of an application for either: (1) construction of an LNG terminal, or (2) conversion of an LNG terminal into an LNG import or export facility.

Restricts such an order solely to applications for exportation of natural gas to certain foreign countries that have been pending for a period of at least 180 calendar days.

Confers upon the Court of Appeals for the circuit in which such export facility will be located original and exclusive jurisdiction over civil actions for the review of: (1) an order issued by the Secretary about the application, or (2) the failure of the Secretary to issue a decision on it.

Requires the Court, if it finds that the Secretary has failed to issue a decision on an application, to order the Secretary to issue one within 30 days.

Requires the Court to set any civil action brought under this Act on the docket, for expedited consideration, as soon as practical after the filing date of the initial pleading.</summary>
</bill>
