<bill session="113" type="h" number="5091" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Drone Reform Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To consolidate within the Department of Defense all executive authority regarding the use of armed unmanned aerial vehicles, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412525"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412438" joined="2014-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412252" joined="2014-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2014-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2014-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2014-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412419" joined="2014-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2014-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412503" joined="2014-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412474" joined="2014-07-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select), for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-11">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-11">
      <text>Referred to House Intelligence</text>
      <reference ref="Permanent Select"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Military command and structure"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/11/2014--Introduced.
Drone Reform Act - Prohibits operations involving the use of an armed unmanned aerial vehicle from being carried out under the authority of federal agency other than the Department of Defense (DOD).

Defines "unmanned aerial vehicle" (UAV) as an aircraft operated without the possibility of direct human intervention from within or on the aircraft, including drones, unmanned aircraft or aerial systems, remotely piloted aircraft or vehicles, remotely operated aircraft, and unmanned aerial vehicle systems.

Authorizes only uniformed members of the Armed Forces to: (1) operate, or order the operation of, an armed UAV; or (2) operate or fire, or order the operation or firing of, any weapon or other munition carried on an armed UAV.

Subjects the operation and use of armed UAVs to the requirements of laws applicable to the Armed Forces.

Prohibits this Act from being construed to: (1) limit or expand the authority of a component of the federal government to provide intelligence to the DOD, or (2) create or expand any authority for the federal government to kill any person.</summary>
</bill>
