<bill session="113" type="h" number="5366" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Historic Vehicle Register Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a program to accurately document vehicles that were significant in the history of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412305"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412011" joined="2014-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-08-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="Public Lands and Environmental Regulation" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Photography and imaging"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2014--Introduced.
National Historic Vehicle Register Act of 2014 - Authorizes the Director of the National Park Service to expand and maintain a National Historic Vehicle Register composed of: (1) a narrative describing each historic vehicle and its significance, (2) a photographic record of the vehicle, and (3) line drawings or engineering drawings of the vehicle. Requires the Register to be archived in the Library of Congress.

Requires the Director to: (1) coordinate with the Historic Vehicle Association in order to invite owners of historic vehicles to participate in the Register, and (2) develop criteria for historic vehicles.

Requires the Director, when developing such criteria, to consider vehicles that are: (1) associated with important events or significant people in automotive or U.S. history; (2) distinctive based on design, engineering, craftsmanship, or aesthetic value; or (3) of a particular type that was the first or last produced or among the most well-preserved or authentically restored examples.</summary>
</bill>
