<bill session="113" type="s" number="2751" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rural and Tribal Voter Rights Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide payments to States for activities to expand early voting access, provide for an equitable distribution of early voting polling locations, including early voting polling locations on Indian tribal land, and to implement voter registration reforms for elections for Federal office, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412602"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="280"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="532"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Voting rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2014--Introduced.
Rural and Tribal Voter Rights Act - Directs the Election Assistance Commission to make a payment each fiscal year to each state which meets early voting location distribution plan development requirements for ensuring that eligible voters have adequate access to early voting locations.

Requires a state or local election official to provide at least one one early voting location on tribal land when requested by the tribal government.

Requires each state to, after reasonable notice and public hearings, adopt and submit to the Commission a plan which provides for the equitable distribution of early voting locations.

Requires each state to make early voting available to any eligible voter for at least 10 days before an election for federal office.

Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), the Commissioner of the Social Security Administration, the Postmaster General, the Secretary of Agriculture, and the Secretary of the Interior to permit a state to designate facilities of the respective agencies located in the state as voter registration agencies.

Requires each state to permit any eligible individual on the same day as a federal election and on any day when voting, including early voting, is permitted for a federal election to: (1) register to vote in the election, and (2) cast a vote in it.

Requires each state to provide a secure online interface available to the public on a public, government website that allows any eligible individual to register electronically to vote or to update their voter registration.

Authorizes the Attorney General to bring a civil action in an appropriate district court for declaratory or injunctive relief as necessary to carry out this Act. Allows any aggrieved person a private right of action, too.</summary>
</bill>
