<bill session="113" type="h" number="4315" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-29T17:42:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-07-29T17:42:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-03-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">21st Century Endangered Species Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">21st Century Endangered Species Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Endangered Species Transparency and Reasonableness Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Endangered Species Act of 1973 to require publication on the Internet of the basis for determinations that species are endangered species or threatened species, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400171"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412500" joined="2014-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400029" joined="2014-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412531" joined="2014-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412508" joined="2014-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412555" joined="2014-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400141" joined="2014-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412397" joined="2014-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412434" joined="2014-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412429" joined="2014-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412437" joined="2014-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2014-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412464" joined="2014-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400247" joined="2014-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412292" joined="2014-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412294" joined="2014-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412295" joined="2014-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400659" joined="2014-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400441" joined="2014-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412302" joined="2014-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400313" joined="2014-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412431" joined="2014-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412596" joined="2014-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412408" joined="2014-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412317" joined="2014-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400406" joined="2014-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412405" joined="2014-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412515" joined="2014-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400419" joined="2014-04-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-03-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-08">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-30">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-04-30" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 17 - 15.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-07-17T16:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 113-537.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-07-17T16:55:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="403">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 403.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-07-28T19:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 693 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4315 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-29T13:40:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 693 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-29T14:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 693.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7007-7024" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7015-7016" label="text of amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-29T14:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4315 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-29T14:58:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 693 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-29T14:58:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Rodney Davis to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-29T14:59:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 4315.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-29T16:10:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 693, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hastings (WA) amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-29T16:15:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 693, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the DeFazio amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-29T16:25:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the DeFazio amendment No. 2, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. DeFazio demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-29T16:26:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 693, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Holt amendment No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-29T16:37:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Holt amendment No. 3, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. Holt demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-29T16:38:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 693, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Duffy amendment No. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-29T16:46:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that, pursuant to clause 6 of Rule XVIII, the unfinished business was the question of adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-29T17:19:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 4315.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-29T17:19:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7022" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-29T17:19:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-29T17:21:00-04:00">
      <text>Mrs. Kirkpatrick moved to recommit with instructions to the Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7022-7023" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7022" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-29T17:21:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to require the Secretary of the Interior to consult with affected Indian tribes to ensure that the Federal trust responsibility with respect to Indian tribes is fulfilled when carrying out any provision of H.R. 4315.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-29T17:35:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 197 - 225 (Roll no. 462).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="463" datetime="2014-07-29T17:42:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 233 - 190 (Roll no. 463).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-07-30">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="113" type="hr" number="693"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2635"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h1127"/>
    <amendment number="h1128"/>
    <amendment number="h1129"/>
    <amendment number="h1130"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>7/29/2014--Passed House amended.
Endangered Species Transparency and Reasonableness Act - (Sec. 2) Amends the Endangered Species Act of 1973 to require the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Commerce, as appropriate, to make publicly available on the Internet the best scientific and commercial data available that are the basis for the determination of whether a species is an endangered species or a threatened species, including each proposed regulation for the listing of a species.

Prohibits the appropriate Secretary from making the information publicly available when: (1) the public disclosure of the information is prohibited by a state law requiring the protection of personal information, and (2) the state requests that the information be withheld.

 Requires the appropriate Secretary to execute an agreement with the Department of Defense (DOD) that prevents the disclosure of classified information pertaining to DOD personnel, facilities, lands, or waters.

(Sec. 3) Requires the appropriate Secretary to: (1) provide to affected states all data that is used as the basis of a determination on whether a species is an endangered species or a threatened species before making a determination; and (2) use data submitted by a state, tribal, or county government in making such a determination.

(Sec. 4) Requires the Secretary of the Interior to submit an annual report detailing federal expenditures for civil actions brought under the ESA containing claims that are based on the actions of the Department of the Interior, the Forest Service, the National Marine Fisheries Service, the Bonneville Power Administration, the Western Area Power Administration, the Southwestern Power Administration, or the Southeastern Power Administration. Requires Interior to make the information available online in a searchable database.

Requires the report to include the total funds expended to respond to ESA lawsuits, the number of full-time federal employees dedicated to ESA lawsuits, attorneys' fees awarded in the course of ESA lawsuits and settlements, and any federal funding used in bringing a claim under the ESA.

(Sec. 5) Replaces the current standard for awarding court costs, including attorney's fees, in citizen suits with the federal judicial code standard for awarding costs to a prevailing party.</summary>
</bill>
