<bill session="113" type="hr" number="520" updated="2015-09-01T10:18:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-04-30">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-04-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-03-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Calling for an end to attacks on Syrian civilians and expanded humanitarian access.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400348"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="2014-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2014-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412385" joined="2014-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="2014-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2014-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400356" joined="2014-12-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-03-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Middle East and North Africa.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-30">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-04-30" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA13" subcommittee="Middle East and North Africa" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Egypt"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Jordan"/>
    <term name="Lebanon"/>
    <term name="Marriage and family status"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Militias and paramilitary groups"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development programs"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Turkey"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="War crimes, genocide, crimes against humanity"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/14/2014--Introduced.
Condemns all parties' attacks on civilians in Syria.

Calls for the United Nations (U.N.)-monitored implementation of the provisions of U.N. Security Council Resolution 2139 to allow unhindered humanitarian access to people in need throughout Syria.

Urges the Administration and U.S. allies to formally withdraw their recognition of Bashar al-Assad's regime unless the Assad regime and its supporting militias discontinue their grave human rights abuses.

Calls upon the U.N. Security Council to suspend Syria's General Assembly membership until the Assad regime has ceased attacks upon civilians and granted access for deliveries of humanitarian assistance throughout Syria.

Commends regional governments and communities for continuing to host Syrian refuges.

Calls upon the Assad regime, the Syrian opposition, the Administration, and the U.N. to improve their support for the Syrian-American community as they work to aid the Syrian people.

Calls on the international community to implement steps to mitigate risks and prevent gender-based violence against refugee and displaced women and girls.

Urges international donors and aid agencies to integrate humanitarian relief and longer-term development programs through a comprehensive strategy to address the protracted Syrian crisis.

Calls on the President to submit a strategy to Congress for U.S. engagement in the Syria crisis, with a specific focus on humanitarian assistance and protecting human rights.</summary>
</bill>
