<bill session="113" type="h" number="2949" updated="2015-09-01T10:19:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-08-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-08-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To delay for one year certain amendments to the Medicaid program made by the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400659"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/1/2013--Introduced.
Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act, as amended by the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (PPACA), to delay from January 1, 2014 to January 1, 2015, the mandate to cover individuals with an income at or below 133% of the poverty line, as well as the state option to cover them.

Delays for a year certain reports on such coverage by the states to the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) and by the Secretary to Congress.

Revises the increased federal medical assistance percentage (FMAP) for newly eligible mandatory individuals to repeal the 100% FMAP for 2014, but keep it for 2015 and 2016.

Delays from the two-year period between January 1, 2014, and December 31, 2015, to the two-year period between January 1, 2015, and December 31, 2016, the increase in the FMAP by 2.2% for certain states for expenditures for individuals who are not newly eligible.

Delays until January 1, 2015, application of the special FMAP for a Medicaid expansion state with respect to certain nonpregnant childless adults whom the state may require to enroll in benchmark coverage.

Delays from January 1, 2014, to January 1, 2015, the effective date of the requirement that any benchmark benefit package or benchmark equivalent coverage provide certain minimum essential health benefits prescribed by PPACA.</summary>
</bill>
