<bill session="113" type="h" number="3091" updated="2015-09-01T10:19:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-09-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-09-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-09-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">MODDERN Cures Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Modernizing Our Drug &amp; Diagnostics Evaluation and Regulatory Network Cures Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To promote the development of meaningful treatments for patients.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412290"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412196" joined="2013-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2013-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412278" joined="2013-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2013-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400219" joined="2013-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412209" joined="2013-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412445" joined="2013-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412293" joined="2013-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400654" joined="2013-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412303" joined="2013-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2013-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412202" joined="2013-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412449" joined="2013-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400647" joined="2013-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400406" joined="2013-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400419" joined="2013-09-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-09-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-12">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-12">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-12">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, Intellectual Property, and the Internet.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts, Intellectual Property, and the Internet" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2085"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3116"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Drug therapy"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Food and Drug Administration (FDA)"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/12/2013--Introduced.
Modernizing Our Drug &amp; Diagnostics Evaluation and Regulatory Network Cures Act of 2013 or MODDERN Cures Act of 2013 - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to: (1) establish the Advanced Diagnostics Education Council to recommend standard terms and definitions related to innovative diagnostics for use by patients, physicians, health care providers, payers, and policy makers; and (2) publish a guide regarding such terms and definitions.

Sets forth additional factors for the Secretary to consider in determining the payment amount for new clinical diagnostic laboratory tests under gap filling procedures which are used when no comparable existing test is available.

Extends the exclusivity period for a medicine if the diagnostic test related to such drug has been determined by the Secretary to have been developed by, or with the participation of, the manufacturer or sponsor of the medicine, and use of the diagnostic tests provides for or improves: (1) the identification of a patient population for the medicine; or (2) the determination of the most appropriate treatment option for a patient population with the medicine.

Establishes a dormant therapy designation for medicine that addresses unmet medical needs. Gives such medicine 15 years of data exclusivity under which no drug can be approved by relying on the approval or licensure of the dormant therapy.

 Directs the Secretary to arrange with the Institute of Medicine (or, if it declines, another appropriate entity) to study intellectual property laws and their impact on therapy and diagnostic development in order to formulate recommendations on how to facilitate the clinical evaluation and development of therapies currently available on the market for new potential indications.</summary>
</bill>
