<bill session="113" type="h" number="3565" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-11-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-11-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-11-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Biennial Commission on Energy Policy Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Department of Energy Organization Act to establish a biennial commission to develop a comprehensive energy policy for the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412487"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400101" joined="2013-11-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-11-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="General energy matters"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/20/2013--Introduced.
Biennial Commission on Energy Policy Act of 2013 - Amends the Department of Energy Organization Act to establish the Biennial Commission on Energy Policy.

Directs the Commission to: (1) analyze the accessibility, affordability, reliability, resiliency, and sustainability of energy sources in the United States, including coal, oil, natural gas, wind, solar, nuclear, hydropower, geothermal, and biofuels; (2) assess policy options to increase domestic energy supplies and energy efficiency; (3) evaluate energy storage, transmission, and distribution requirements including intermittent energy sources; (4) analyze the prospective role of stakeholders in creating an integrated and comprehensive energy policy, including academia, industry representatives, the public, and federal laboratories and agencies; (5) assess the effectiveness of and need for energy programs, including tax incentives, funding mechanisms, and energy subsidies; and (6) make recommendations for changes to the organization of executive branch entities to facilitate the development and implementation of national energy objectives.</summary>
</bill>
