<bill session="113" type="h" number="5222" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rental Assistance Housing Preservation and Rehabilitation Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To increase the unit cap on the rental assistance demonstration of the Department of Housing and Urban Development, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412595"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1243"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Housing supply and affordability"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/28/2014--Introduced.
Rental Assistance Housing Preservation and Rehabilitation Act of 2014 - Modifies funding requirements for the Rental Assistance Demonstration, provided in the Department of Housing and Urban Development Appropriations Act, 2012, for voluntary conversion of properties assisted via public housing agencies from the Public Housing Capital and Operating Funds, or assisted under the moderate rehabilitation program to properties with assistance under a project-based subsidy contract or the voucher program.

Increases from 60,000 to 150,000 the maximum number of units currently receiving specified assistance required to be so converted.

Extends through FY2016 the eligibility for the conversion of assistance of owners of certain assisted properties for which an event after October 1, 2006 has caused or results in the termination of rental assistance or affordability restrictions and the issuance of tenant protection vouchers.</summary>
</bill>
