<bill session="113" type="s" number="2264" updated="2015-09-01T17:50:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">World War I Memorial Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to designate memorials to the service of members of the United States Armed Forces in World War I, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412243"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2014-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="2014-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-23">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 113-493.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="National Parks" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3979"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4435"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4489"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Art, artists, authorship"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Military history"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Missouri"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/28/2014--Introduced.
World War I Memorial Act of 2014 - Designates the Liberty Memorial of Kansas City at America's National World War I Museum in Kansas City, Missouri, as the National World War I Museum and Memorial.

Redesignates Pershing Park in the District of Columbia as the National World War I Memorial (Memorial).

Authorizes the World War I Centennial Commission (Commission) to plan, develop, and execute ceremonies to recognize the above designation and redesignation and to enhance the General Pershing Commemorative Work by constructing appropriate sculptural and other elements on the Memorial.

Amends the World War I Centennial Commission Act to: (1) allow for completion of construction at the Memorial after termination of the Commission, and (2) revise provisions concerning Commission members and pay rates. Prohibits any federal funds from being obligated or expended for the designation, establishment, or enhancement of a memorial or commemorative work by the Commission.</summary>
</bill>
