<bill session="113" type="sr" number="411" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-04-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-04-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate with respect to the territorial integrity and sovereignty of the Republic of Moldova.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300055"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2014-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2014-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412556" joined="2014-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412496" joined="2014-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400222" joined="2014-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="2014-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412491" joined="2014-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300088" joined="2014-04-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2166" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Moldova"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/3/2014--Introduced.
Affirms that it is U.S. policy to support the Republic of Moldova's sovereignty, independence, and territorial integrity.

 Calls upon the government of the Russian Federation to remove its military forces from the Republic of Moldova.

 Supports constructive engagement between the government of Moldova and the authorities in Transnistria in order to secure a peaceful resolution to the conflict.

Expresses the Senate's belief that a resolution to the Transnistria issue can only be accomplished by ensuring the freedom of the government and the people of Moldova to determine their own future without external pressure.

Urges the President to consider increasing security and intelligence cooperation with the government of Moldova.

 Affirms that stability in Europe is a U.S. priority that can only be achieved if the territorial integrity and sovereignty of all parties is respected.</summary>
</bill>
