<bill session="113" type="h" number="4587" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-28T16:25:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-05-28T16:25:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Venezuelan Human Rights and Democracy Protection Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Venezuelan Human Rights and Democracy Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To impose targeted sanctions on individuals responsible for carrying out or ordering human rights abuses against the citizens of Venezuela, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400344"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412250" joined="2014-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="2014-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412526" joined="2014-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412385" joined="2014-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400108" joined="2014-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412488" joined="2014-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412472" joined="2014-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412530" joined="2014-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412276" joined="2014-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412451" joined="2014-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2014-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400654" joined="2014-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412527" joined="2014-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400652" joined="2014-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400343" joined="2014-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400606" joined="2014-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412186" joined="2014-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="2014-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="410396" joined="2014-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400623" joined="2014-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412412" joined="2014-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412525" joined="2014-05-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-07">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-07">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-09">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-05-09" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-05-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4047"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-28T16:00:00-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Ros-Lehtinen moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-28T16:00:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4844-4850" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-28T16:00:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4587.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2014-05-28T16:25:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4844-4846" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-06-02">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-06-05" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="410">
      <text>Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 410.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-07-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Border Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign property"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="Organization of American States"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="Venezuela"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/28/2014--Passed House amended.
Venezuelan Human Rights and Democracy Protection Act - (Sec. 4) Directs the Secretary of State (Secretary) to require the U.S. Permanent Representative to the Organization of American States (OAS) to use U.S. influence at the OAS to protect the Inter-American Democratic Charter, and strengthen efforts by international and multilateral organizations to protect human rights throughout the Western Hemisphere, especially in Venezuela.

(Sec. 5) Directs the President to impose asset blocking sanctions and the Secretary or the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to impose U.S. exclusion sanctions against any person, including a current or former official of the government of Venezuela or a person acting on behalf of such government, who has: (1) perpetrated or is responsible for directing acts of violence or human rights abuses against individuals participating in protests in Venezuela that began on February 12, 2014; (2) directed or ordered the arrest or prosecution of a person primarily because of the person's exercise of freedom of expression or assembly in relation to such protests; (3) knowingly assisted, sponsored, or provided significant financial, material, or technological support for, or goods or services in support of, the commission of such acts; or (4) engaged in censorship against individuals or media outlets disseminating information in relation to such protests.

Sets forth related penalty requirements.

States that U.S. exclusion sanctions shall not apply if necessary to permit the United States to comply with the Agreement regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations or other applicable international obligations.

Authorizes the President to waive sanctions if: (1) in the U.S. national security interests, or (2) conditions in Venezuela have improved with regard to respect for peaceful protest and basic human rights.

(Sec. 6) Directs the President to transmit to Congress a list of, and impose sanctions against, persons who: (1) transfer or facilitate the transfer of goods or technologies that are likely to be used to commit serious rights abuses to Venezuela, to any person organized under the laws of Venezuela, or to any national of Venezuela, for use in Venezuela; or (2) provide services with respect to such goods or technologies after their transfer to Venezuela.

States that the President shall not be required to include a person on this list if: (1) that person is no longer engaging in or has taken significant steps toward stopping sanctioned activities, and (2) the President has received reliable assurances that such person will not knowingly engage in any new sanctioned activity.

Authorizes the President to waive sanctions if: (1) in the U.S. national security interests, or (2) conditions in Venezuela have improved with regard to respect for peaceful protest and basic human rights.

(Sec. 7) Directs the Secretary to submit a comprehensive strategy to Congress for promoting internet and information access freedom in Venezuela.

 (Sec. 8) Directs the Secretary to submit a comprehensive strategy to Congress outlining U.S. support for the citizens of Venezuela in seeking free elections, civil liberties and human rights, and the development of an independent civil society.

(Sec. 9) States that it shall be U.S. policy to: (1) support efforts to identify prisoners of conscience and cases of human rights abuses in Venezuela, and (2) offer refugee status or political asylum in the United States to political dissidents in Venezuela or assist in their relocation to other countries.

 (Sec. 10) Authorizes FY2015 appropriations to the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) for assistance to civil society in Venezuela.

(Sec. 11) Amends the Enhanced Partnership with Pakistan Act of 2009 to reduce specified funding for Pakistan through FY2014.

(Sec. 12) Sunsets this Act two years after its enactment.</summary>
</bill>
