<bill session="113" type="s" number="1990" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-02-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-02-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-02-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit aliens who are not lawfully present in the United States from being eligible for postsecondary education benefits that are not available to all citizens and nationals of the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400418"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-02-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/4/2014--Introduced.
Amends the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 to prohibit unlawful aliens from being eligible for any postsecondary education benefit unless every citizen and national of this country is eligible to receive that benefit in no less of an amount, duration, or scope. (This replaces a prohibition on states offering unlawful aliens postsecondary benefits on the basis of their residence in the state that are more generous than those offered citizens or naturals of this country without regard to their state residence.)

Allows any citizen or national who is enrolled at a postsecondary educational institution that is alleged to have violated that prohibition to bring a civil action against any state official overseeing the institution to obtain appropriate relief, attorneys' fees, and court costs.</summary>
</bill>
