<bill session="113" type="hr" number="754" updated="2015-09-01T10:18:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-11-19T16:20:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-11-19T16:20:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-11-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Condemning the Government of Iran for its gross human rights violations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400348"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="2014-11-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-11-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-19T15:49:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Royce moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-19T15:49:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8106-8110" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-19T15:49:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Res. 754.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2014-11-19T16:20:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8106-8107" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-11-19T16:20:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Foreign property"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="Political movements and philosophies"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/19/2014--Passed House without amendment.
Calls on the government of Iran to abide by its international and domestic obligations regarding human rights and civil liberties, including freedoms of assembly, speech, and press.

Deplores: (1) the dramatic rise in executions of Iranian citizens by authorities since the election of President Hassan Rouhani in June 2013, and (2) Iran's mistreatment of its religious minorities.

 Condemns: (1) the recent execution of Reyhaneh Jabbari, a woman convicted of killing a man she said she stabbed in self-defense during a sexual assault; (2) the relentless persecution of the Baha'i minority; and (3) the undemocratic elections process that denies Iranians the ability to freely choose their own government.

Calls on Iran to release all political prisoners and prisoners of conscience.

Notes that the Administration has designated only one Iranian person for the commission of serious human rights abuses under the Comprehensive Iran Sanctions, Accountability, and Divestment Act since May 30, 2013.

Urges the President to increase the utilization of all available authorities, including the Comprehensive Iran Sanctions, Accountability, and Divestment Act of 2010, to impose sanctions on Iranian officials and others responsible for serious human rights abuses, including by freezing assets and barring U.S. entry.

Urges the U.S. government to adopt and implement the following recommendations of the U.S. Commission on International Religious Freedom regarding Iran:

 to seek that violations of freedom of religion and related human rights are part of discussions with Iran, and to work with allies to apply pressure through advocacy, diplomacy, and targeted sanctions; to speak out at the highest levels about the severe religious freedom abuses in Iran, to work for the release of all prisoners of conscience, and to highlight the need for the international community to hold authorities accountable; and to call on Iran to cooperate fully with and allow the United Nations (U.N.) Special Rapporteur on the Human Rights Situation in Iran to visit Iran. Stands with the people of Iran who seek the opportunity to freely elect a government of their choosing.</summary>
</bill>
