<bill session="113" type="s" number="1520" updated="2015-09-01T17:50:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-09-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">York River Wild and Scenic River Study Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate segments of the York River and associated tributaries for study for potential inclusion in the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412545"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-09-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-23">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 113-493.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="National Parks" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2197"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hunting and fishing"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Maine"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Property rights"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/18/2013--Introduced.
York River Wild and Scenic River Study Act of 2013 - Amends the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate a specified segment of the York River in Maine and any of its associated tributaries for potential addition to the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System.

Requires the Secretary of the Interior to study the York River to: (1) determine the designation's effect on existing commercial and recreational activities, the construction and operation of energy production and transmission infrastructure, and the authority of state and local governments to manage those activities; and (2) identify any authorities that would authorize or require the Secretary to influence local land use decisions such as zoning, or to place restrictions on non-federal land if designated under this Act, any authorities that the Secretary may use to condemn property, and any private property located in the area studied pursuant to this Act.</summary>
</bill>
