<bill session="113" type="h" number="4909" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Permanent Families for All Children Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide States with assistance in finding a permanent home for every child.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400230"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412517" joined="2014-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412221" joined="2014-06-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-19">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-19">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Training" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/19/2014--Introduced.
Permanent Families for All Children Act - Amends part E (Foster Care and Adoption Assistance) of title IV of the Social Security Act to:

 limit to 36 the number of months for which foster care maintenance payments made on behalf of a child not in a legal guardianship or kinship guardian arrangement may be reimbursed; limit to 12 the number of months for which foster care maintenance payments made to child-care institutions on behalf of a child residing in the institution may be reimbursed; eliminate the Aid to Families with Dependent Children (AFDC) income eligibility requirement for foster care maintenance payments; replace the federal medical assistance percentage (FMAP, or federal matching rate) for foster care maintenance payments and related costs in a state with a foster care partnership rate for the quarter determined by the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS); and make children in residential treatment programs eligible for 50% of regular foster care maintenance payments. Directs the Secretary to increase the proportion of the amounts expended by a state for caseworker training on child-focused recruitment and retention.

Increases the amount of spending for child welfare programs by the unused savings resulting from this Act.

Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to authorize the cancellation of Federal Direct Student Loans for a social worker employed in a public child or family service agency after the social worker has made 60 monthly payments on the eligible loan after the enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
