<bill session="113" type="h" number="1423" updated="2015-09-01T10:19:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-02-25T15:54:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-02-25T15:54:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-04-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Taxpayers Right-To-Know Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Taxpayers Right-To-Know Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Taxpayers Right-To-Know Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide taxpayers with an annual report disclosing the cost and performance of Government programs and areas of duplication among them, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412464"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412541" joined="2014-01-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400032" joined="2014-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400081" joined="2013-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412526" joined="2014-01-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400255" joined="2013-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412409" joined="2014-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412383" joined="2013-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400351" joined="2014-01-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412408" joined="2014-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412213" joined="2014-02-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-04-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-24">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-07-24" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-02-21T11:30:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform. H. Rept. 113-355.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-02-21T11:30:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="263">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 263.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-02-25T15:43:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Lankford moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1902" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-25T15:43:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1902-1904" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-25T15:43:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1423.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2014-02-25T15:54:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1902-1903" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-02-26">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-27">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2113"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/25/2014--Passed House amended.
Taxpayers Right-To-Know Act - (Sec. 2) Sets forth additional information relating to a federal program that the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) is required to include on its website and update at least annually, including: (1) the total administrative cost of the program and the expenditures for services for the program for the previous fiscal year; (2) an estimate of the number of clients served by the program and beneficiaries who received assistance under the program for the previous fiscal year; (3) an estimate, for the previous fiscal year, of the number of full-time federal employees who administer the program and the number of full-time employees whose salary is paid in part or in full by the federal government through a grant or contract or other form of financial assistance; (4) an identification of the specific statute that authorizes the program and whether such authorization is expired; (5) any finding of duplication or overlap; and (6) any program performance reviews for such program.

Requires the OMB Director, not later than February 1 of each fiscal year, to publish on the OMB website the total amount of undisbursed grant funding remaining in grant accounts for which the period of availability to the grantee has expired.

(Sec. 3) Amends the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010 to require the Comptroller General (GAO) to maintain and provide regular annual updates to a publicly available website that tracks the status of agency responses to recommendations by the Comptroller General for identifying duplicative government programs.

(Sec. 4) Declares that nothing in this Act shall be construed to require the disclosure of classified information.

(Sec. 5) Requires the OMB Director to implement this Act not later than one year after its enactment. Prohibits the authorization of additional funds to carry out the requirements of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
