<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="Hd9802aed-d627-42a5-ac1b-ce79fd25ddb4" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Reported-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HRES 696 RH: Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 5230) making supplemental appropriations for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2014, and for other purposes; providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 5272) to prohibit certain actions with respect to deferred action for aliens not lawfully present in the United States, and for other purposes; providing for consideration of the Senate amendment to the bill (H.R. 5021) to provide an extension of Federal-aid highway, highway safety, motor carrier safety, transit, and other programs funded out of the Highway Trust Fund, and for other purposes; and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2014-07-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<calendar display="yes">House Calendar No. 132</calendar>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 696</legis-num>
		<associated-doc display="yes" role="report">[Report No. 113–567]</associated-doc>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20140730">July 30, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc><cosponsor name-id="C001053">Mr. Cole</cosponsor>, from the <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</committee-name>, reported the following resolution; which was referred to the House Calendar and ordered to be
			 printed</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 5230) making supplemental appropriations for the
			 fiscal year ending September 30, 2014, and for other purposes; providing
			 for consideration of the bill (H.R. 5272) to prohibit certain actions with
			 respect to deferred action for aliens not lawfully present in the United
			 States, and for other purposes; providing for consideration of the Senate
			 amendment to the bill (H.R. 5021) to provide an extension of Federal-aid
			 highway, highway safety, motor carrier safety, transit, and other programs
			 funded out of the Highway Trust Fund, and for other purposes; and for
			 other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<resolution-body id="H79f56c20-47b8-4b06-ba80-b255d7e19c17" style="traditional">
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="Ha2511e78-425d-479b-988b-5d122dbb92fd" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That upon adoption of this resolution it shall be in order to consider in the House the bill (H.R.
			 5230) making supplemental appropriations for the fiscal year ending
			 September 30, 2014, and for other purposes. All points of order against
			 consideration of the bill are waived. The bill shall be considered as
			 read. All points of order against provisions in the bill are waived. The
			 previous question shall be considered as ordered on the bill and on any
			 amendment thereto to final passage without intervening motion except: (1)
			 one hour of debate equally divided and controlled by the chair and ranking
			 minority member of the Committee on Appropriations; and (2) one motion to
			 recommit.</text>
		</section><section id="H299718667FF24718BD54FAF6DAEAD750"><enum>2.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After passage of H.R. 5230, and on the legislative day of July 31, 2014, the House shall consider
			 in the House the bill (H.R. 5272) to prohibit certain actions with respect
			 to deferred action for aliens not lawfully present in the United States,
			 and for other purposes. All points of order against consideration of the
			 bill are waived. The bill shall be considered as read. All points of order
			 against provisions in the bill are waived. The previous question shall be
			 considered as ordered on the bill and on any amendment thereto to final
			 passage without intervening motion except: (1) one hour of debate equally
			 divided and controlled by the chair and ranking minority member of the
			 Committee on the Judiciary; and (2) one motion to recommit.</text>
		</section><section id="HF0F64B9F99994CF4B8F924A25240FF4B"><enum>3.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon adoption of this resolution it shall be in order to take from the Speaker’s table the bill
			 (H.R. 5021) to provide an extension of Federal-aid highway, highway
			 safety, motor carrier safety, transit, and other programs funded out of
			 the Highway Trust Fund, and for other purposes, with the Senate amendment
			 thereto, and to consider in the House, without intervention of any point
			 of order, a motion offered by the chair of the Committee on Transportation
			 and Infrastructure or his designee that the House disagree to the Senate
			 amendment. The Senate amendment and the motion shall be considered as
			 read. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the motion
			 to its adoption without intervening motion except one hour of debate
			 equally divided and controlled by the chair and ranking minority member of
			 the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
		</section><section id="H7511FE2464D845BD907BF34BCF05CF68"><enum>4.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any motion pursuant to clause 4 of rule XXII relating to H.R. 5021 may be offered only by the
			 Majority Leader or his designee.</text>
		</section><section id="H07E59FC0DAF54DC29B5D224E445C983C"><enum>5.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It shall be in order at any time on the legislative day of July 31, 2014, for the Speaker to
			 entertain motions that the House suspend the rules as though under clause
			 1 of rule XV. The Speaker or his designee shall consult with the Minority
			 Leader or her designee on the designation of any matter for consideration
			 pursuant to this section.</text>
		</section><section id="HC10EC992C1464A40AB604ADAB8D7C488"><enum>6.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirement of clause 6(a) of rule XIII for a two-thirds vote to consider a report from the
			 Committee on Rules on the same day it is presented to the House is waived
			 with respect to any resolution reported through the legislative day of
			 July 31, 2014.</text>
		</section></resolution-body><endorsement><action-date>July 30, 2014</action-date><action-desc>Referred to the House Calendar and ordered to be
			 printed</action-desc></endorsement>
</resolution>


