<bill session="113" type="s" number="1417" updated="2015-09-01T17:50:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-01-29">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-01-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Newborn Screening Saves Lives Reauthorization Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Newborn Screening Saves Lives Reauthorization Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Newborn Screening Saves Lives Reauthorization Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to reauthorize programs under part A of title XI of such Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412324"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300002" joined="2014-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412330" joined="2013-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2014-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2013-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2013-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="2013-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2013-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412205" joined="2013-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2013-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2013-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2013-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="2013-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412194" joined="2013-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412507" joined="2013-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2013-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2014-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2013-12-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-12-18" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-12-19">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-12-19" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="282">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 282.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2014-01-29" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S605-607" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S605-607" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-01-30">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-31T15:02:00-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-31">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Genetics"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Hereditary and development disorders"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/29/2014--Passed Senate amended.
Newborn Screening Saves Lives Reauthorization Act of 2013 - (Sec. 2) Amends the Public Health Service Act to extend through FY2018 a grant program for newborn and child screening programs for heritable disorders. Includes the improvement of the timely collection, delivery, and receipts, and screening of specimens, and the timely diagnosis of heritable disorders in newborns as a permissible use of grant funds.

(Sec. 3) Extends through FY2018 a demonstration program to evaluate the effectiveness of screening, follow-up, counseling or health care services in reducing the morbidity and mortality caused by heritable disorders in newborn and children. Permits the program to also evaluate and assess: (1) methods to improve quality in the diagnosis, treatment, and disease management of heritable disorders based on gaps in services or care; and (2) methods or best practices by which states or political subdivisions of a state, territories, Indian health care facilities or programs, or any entity with appropriate expertise in newborn screening can achieve the timely collection, delivery, receipt, and screening of newborn screening specimens, and the timely diagnosis of heritable disorders in newborns.

(Sec. 4) Reauthorizes through FY2018 and extends for five years the operation of the Advisory Committee on Heritable Disorders in Newborns and Children. Expands the duties of the Advisory Committee to include providing technical assistance to individuals and organizations regarding the submission of nominations to the uniform screening panel. Requires the Advisory Committee to give recommendations, advice, or information to the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) on the timely collection, delivery, receipt, and screening of specimens to be tested for heritable disorders in newborns.

Revises the process for the Secretary to consider the Advisory Committee's recommendations.

Requires the Advisory Committee to meet at least four times per year.

(Sec. 5) Extends through FY2018 the Newborn Screening Clearinghouse of current education and family support and services information, materials, resources, research, and data on newborn screening.

(Sec. 6) Extends through FY2018 a quality assurance program requiring the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to provide for quality assurance of laboratories involved in screening for heritable disorders. Authorizes the Secretary, acting through the Director, to also provide for the coordination of surveillance activities.

(Sec. 7) Makes the Interagency Coordinating Committee on Newborn and Child Screening permanent. Includes the Commissioner of Food and Drugs (FDA) as a member of the Interagency Committee.

(Sec. 8) Requires the national contingency plan for newborn screening to be updated at least every five years.

(Sec. 9) Allows the expansion of the Hunter Kelly Newborn Screening Research Program to include: (1) providing research findings and data for newborn conditions under review by the Advisory Committee to be added to the recommended uniform screening panel, and (2) conducting pilot studies on conditions recommended by the Advisory Committee to ensure that the screenings are ready for nationwide implementation.

(Sec. 11) Requires the Comptroller General to report to the relevant congressional committees on the timeliness of screening for heritable disorders in newborns.

Requires the Secretary to report to the relevant congressional committees biennially on activities related to newborn screening and screening children who have or are at risk for heritable disorders.</summary>
</bill>
