<bill session="113" type="h" number="5598" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Travel and Resource Access Including Local Stakeholders Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Bureau of Land Management to incorporate the needs, uses, and input of affected communities, and to obtain the concurrence of affected communities, before taking any travel management action affecting access to public lands, including access to mining claims or access using motorized vehicles or nonmotorized means, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412397"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400141" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412489" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400606" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="410396" joined="2014-09-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-10-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="Public Lands and Environmental Regulation" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4272"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="General public lands matters"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/18/2014--Introduced.
Travel and Resource Access Including Local Stakeholders Act - Requires the Director of the Bureau of Land Management (BLM), as a condition on the preparation of an environmental impact statement or environmental assessment under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (NEPA) for a proposed access travel management action, to consult with affected counties for the purpose of incorporating their needs, uses, and input. Prohibits the Secretary from implementing such an action until the Secretary: (1) complies with such consultation requirement, and (2) obtains the concurrence of each affected county.

Defines an "access travel management action" as a BLM action that will alter public access to public lands, including any change in access to mining claims or access using motorized vehicles or nonmotorized means resulting from the decommissioning of a road or trail, a change in the status of a road as open or closed, or a change in road densities.</summary>
</bill>
