<bill session="113" type="h" number="4795" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-11-20T10:59:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-11-20T10:59:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Promoting New Manufacturing Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Promoting New Manufacturing Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Promoting New Manufacturing Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To promote new manufacturing in the United States by providing for greater transparency and timeliness in obtaining necessary permits, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412261"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400018" joined="2014-05-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412250" joined="2014-05-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412269" joined="2014-05-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412278" joined="2014-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400165" joined="2014-05-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412421" joined="2014-05-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412256" joined="2014-05-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412487" joined="2014-05-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412302" joined="2014-05-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400320" joined="2014-05-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412431" joined="2014-05-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400400" joined="2014-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400431" joined="2014-05-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-09">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-10">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-06-10" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 30 - 19.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-06-23T12:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 113-488.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-06-23T12:31:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="363">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 363.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-11-17T19:26:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 756 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1422, H.R. 4012 and H.R. 4795. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 1422, H.R. 4012, and H.R. 4795. General debate is limited to 1 hour for each bill. The resolution specifies certain amendments are in order for H.R. 1422, H.R. 4012, and H.R. 4795. One motion to recommit with instructions is permitted for each bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-18T13:31:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 756 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-20T09:15:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 756.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8137-8146" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H8140-8141" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-20T09:15:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1422, H.R. 4012 and H.R. 4795. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 1422, H.R. 4012, and H.R. 4795. General debate is limited to 1 hour for each bill. The resolution specifies certain amendments are in order for H.R. 1422, H.R. 4012, and H.R. 4795. One motion to recommit with instructions is permitted for each bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-20T09:15:00-05:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 756 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-20T09:15:00-05:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Randy Hultgren to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-20T09:15:00-05:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 4795.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-20T09:46:00-05:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 756, the House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Waxman Part C amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-20T09:53:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Waxman Part C amendment No. 1, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Waxman demanded a recorded vote and the chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-20T09:54:00-05:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 756, the House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Whitfield Part C amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-20T10:00:00-05:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question on adoption of an amendment which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-20T10:31:00-05:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 4795.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-20T10:32:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8143" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-20T10:32:00-05:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-20T10:34:00-05:00">
      <text>Ms. Kuster moved to recommit with instructions to the Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8143-8145" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H8144" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-20T10:34:00-05:00">
      <text>Floor summary: DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Kuster motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to report the same back to the House forthwith with an amendment to ensure that nothing in the underlying legislation would affect the authority of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to: (1) require compliance with a new ambient air quality standard in a preconstruction permit if doing so would protect children and seniors from dangerous air pollutants, including cancer-causing pollutants, located within 5 miles of a school, day care facility, hospital or nursing home or (2) require small businesses to comply with an outdated ambient air quality standard if doing so would result in higher costs or job losses for that small business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-20T10:42:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8144" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-20T10:51:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 189 - 223 (Roll no. 530).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8145" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="531" datetime="2014-11-20T10:59:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 238 - 172 (Roll no. 531).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-11-20T11:00:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-01">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="113" type="hr" number="756"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h1148"/>
    <amendment number="h1149"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>11/20/2014--Passed House amended.
Promoting New Manufacturing Act - (Sec. 2) Requires the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to publish on its website for FY2008 and each subsequent fiscal year:

 the total number of preconstruction permits issued annually under the Clean Air Act's New Source Review Program for the construction or modification of a major emitting facility or major stationary source (any stationary facility or source of air pollutants which directly emits, or has the potential to emit, 100 tons per year or more of any air pollutant); the percentage of permits issued within one year of the application; and the average length of time for the EPA's Environmental Appeals Board to decide appeals of decisions to grant or deny a permit. (Sec. 3) Requires the EPA to publish concurrently regulations and guidance for implementing any final rule establishing or revising a national ambient air quality standard (NAAQS). Prohibits a NAAQS from applying to the review and disposition of a permit application until the EPA has met this requirement.

Prohibits this Act from being construed to eliminate the obligation of a preconstruction permit applicant to install best available control technology and the lowest achievable emissions rate technology.

(Sec. 4) Requires the EPA to submit annually a report on actions to expedite the process for review of preconstruction permits.</summary>
</bill>
