<bill session="113" type="s" number="1971" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-11-13">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-11-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-01-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">NEWS Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nexus of Energy and Water for Sustainability Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">NEWS Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Nexus of Energy and Water for Sustainability Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish an interagency coordination committee or subcommittee with the leadership of the Department of Energy and the Department of the Interior, focused on the nexus between energy and water production, use, and efficiency, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300075"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400013" joined="2014-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2014-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412507" joined="2014-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2014-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2014-01-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-01-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S601-602"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S602" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-25">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 113-428.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-11-13" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-12-10">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Landrieu with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 113-296.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-12-10" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="636">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 636.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG07" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/29/2014--Introduced.
Nexus of Energy and Water for Sustainability Act of 2014 or NEWS Act of 2014 - Requires the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy to establish either Committee on Energy-Water Nexus for Sustainability or the Subcommittee on Energy-Water Nexus for Sustainability under the National Science and Technology Council (NSTC), co-chaired by the Secretary of Energy (DOE) and Secretary of the Interior.

Defines "energy-water nexus" as the link between: (1) energy efficiency and the quantity of water needed to produce fuels and energy; and (2) the quantity of energy needed to transport, reclaim, and treat water.

Requires the Committee or Subcommittee to: (1) serve as a forum for developing common federal goals and plans on energy-water nexus issues; (2) promote coordination of the related activities of all federal departments and agencies; (3) coordinate and develop capabilities for data collection, categorization, and dissemination of data from and to other federal departments and agencies; and (4) engage in information exchange between federal departments and agencies.

Requires the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB), by 30 days after the President submits the budget of the U.S. Government each year, to submit to specified congressional committees an interagency budget crosscut report that: (1) displays the budget proposed, including any interagency or intra-agency transfer, for each of the federal agencies that carry out energy-water nexus projects for the upcoming fiscal year; (2) identifies all federal and state expenditures since 2011 on energy-water nexus projects; and (3) lists all energy-water nexus projects to be undertaken in the upcoming fiscal year, with the federal portion of funds for those projects.</summary>
</bill>
