<bill session="113" type="h" number="2567" updated="2015-09-01T10:19:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Child Handgun Safety Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require that all handguns manufactured, sold in, or imported into, the United States incorporate technology that precludes the average five year old child from operating the handgun when it is ready to fire.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412259"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412571" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412470" joined="2013-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412221" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400074" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412529" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400308" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412219" joined="2013-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412520" joined="2014-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400407" joined="2013-06-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-27">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-27">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF17" subcommittee="Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Consumer Product Safety Commission"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/27/2013--Introduced.
Child Handgun Safety Act - Directs the Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC) to promulgate a consumer product safety standard for handguns that requires that: (1) any handgun manufactured in the United States must be child-resistant and include a mechanism that effectively precludes an average five-year old child from operating it when it is ready to fire (effective one year after this Act's enactment date); and (2) any handgun sold, offered for sale, traded, transferred, shipped, leased, or distributed in the United States must be child-resistant as manufactured or retrofitted to be child-resistant (effective two years after such date).

Includes as such a mechanism: (1) raising trigger resistance to at least a 10-pound pull, (2) altering the firing mechanism so that an average 5-year old child's hands are too small to operate the handgun, or (3) requiring a series of multiple motions in order to fire the handgun.

Exempts antique firearms and firearms owned by the Department of Defense (DOD).

Requires the cost of retrofitting a firearm to meet such requirement to be borne by the manufacturer if the manufacturer is operational at the time the retrofit is required, but permits the use of the Department of Justice Assets Forfeiture Fund for payments to reimburse handgun manufacturers for the costs of retrofitting required by this Act.</summary>
</bill>
