<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H64C481BEDDB743EEBB10AA84542544C5" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HR 3913 IH: To amend the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956 to require agencies to make considerations relating to the promotion of efficiency, competition, and capital formation before issuing or modifying certain regulations.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2014-01-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress>113th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>H. R. 3913</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20140116">January 16, 2014</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000614">Mr. Duffy</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956 to require agencies to make considerations relating to the promotion of efficiency, competition, and capital formation before issuing or modifying certain regulations.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H03E4972547C5463387EC86CDC2764A09" style="OLC"><section id="H387E256D40394D1CA7CD9E0D7C5C382A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Rulemaking considerations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 13 of the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1851">12 U.S.C. 1851</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H86DBFD054B7C4F4681264E92F7898F20" style="OLC"><subsection id="HAB333A66A52F4755AE238DBC787F11C9"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Consideration of Promotion of Efficiency, Competition, and Capital Formation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In issuing or modifying any regulation under this section, the appropriate Federal banking agencies, the Commodity Futures Trading Commission, and the Securities and Exchange Commission—</text><paragraph id="HDF949328D2C745449F0DBA08D2E943AE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall consider whether the regulation is necessary or appropriate in the public interest;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F910492AC934D3A8A6DD5F6B37B709D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall consider whether the regulation will promote efficiency, competition, and capital formation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA491493FAD0940758CEEB3811607FC2E"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall consider, among other matters, the impact the regulation would have on competition;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCDF22C3CEB4C4252A59904E11E25616D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>may not adopt the regulation if it would impose a burden on competition not necessary or appropriate in furtherance of the purposes of this section; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H19365E88FCCB49D2B62A1C464AC3321C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>shall include in the statement of basis and purpose incorporated in the regulation adopted under this section, the reasons for the determination under paragraph (4) that any burden on competition imposed by the regulation is necessary or appropriate in furtherance of the purposes of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>


