<bill session="113" type="h" number="5380" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medicare Telehealth Parity Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for a phased-in expansion of telehealth coverage under the Medicare program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400403"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400041" joined="2014-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2014-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412280" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2014-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2014-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="2014-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400276" joined="2014-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2014-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412239" joined="2014-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-08-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Allied health services"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Digestive and metabolic diseases"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Hearing, speech, and vision care"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2014--Introduced.
Medicare Telehealth Parity Act of 2014 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act with regard to payment for telehealth services to include in the term "originating site" additional sites, including any federally qualified health center and any rural health clinic, at which the eligible telehealth individual is located at the time the service is furnished via a telecommunications system.

Prohibits application of the originating site facility fee to the additional sites.

Authorizes additional telehealth providers, including a certified diabetes educator or licensed respiratory therapist, audiologist, occupational therapist, physical therapist, or speech language pathologist.

Extends Medicare coverage to remote patient management services for certain chronic health conditions.

Directs the Comptroller General (GAO) to study the effectiveness of remote patient monitoring on decreasing hospital readmissions for specified chronic conditions, and the savings to the Medicare program associated with use of such monitoring.

Authorizes home telehealth sites as additional originating sites.

Directs GAO to study the effectiveness of using described telehealth services between therapy providers and patients, any associated savings, and the potential for greater use of telehealth services for other forms of therapy

Authorizes the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to develop and implement payment methods to apply in the case of anyone who would be an eligible telehealth individual except that the telehealth services are furnished at a site other than an originating site.</summary>
</bill>
