<bill session="113" type="h" number="4908" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Alyce Spotted Bear and Walter Soboleff Commission on Native Children Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the Alyce Spotted Bear and Walter Soboleff Commission on Native Children, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400077"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Appropriations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-19">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-19">
      <text>Referred to House Appropriations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee Indian and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII24" subcommittee="Indian and Alaska Native Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/19/2014--Introduced.
Alyce Spotted Bear and Walter Soboleff Commission on Native Children Act - Establishes the Alyce Spotted Bear and Walter Soboleff Commission on Native Children in the Office of Tribal Justice of the Department of Justice (DOJ).

Requires the President and Congress to appoint to the Commission individuals who have significant experience and expertise in Indian affairs and the matters to be studied by the Commission.

Requires the Commission to conduct a comprehensive study of federal, state, local, and tribal programs that serve Native children, including an evaluation of:

 the impact of concurrent jurisdiction on child welfare systems, barriers Indian tribes and Native Hawaiians face related to grant resources, obstacles to nongovernmental financial support for programs benefitting Native children, issues relating to the validity and statistical significance of data on Native children, programs designed to assist high-risk Native children and their families, and barriers to interagency coordination on programs benefitting Native children. Directs the Commission to use the results of the study and analyses of existing federal data relating to Native children to:

 develop plans and goals for federal policy relating to Native children informed by accurate child well-being measures; recommend modifications and improvements to programs that serve Native children at the federal, state, and tribal level; recommend improvements to the collection of data regarding Native children and the programs that serve them; and identify models of successful federal, state, and tribal programs in the areas studied by the Commission. Requires the Commission to report to the President, Congress, and the White House Council on Native American Affairs on its findings, conclusions, and recommendations for appropriate legislative and administrative action.</summary>
</bill>
