<bill session="113" type="h" number="3517" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-11-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-11-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-11-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal and State Insurance Exchange Access Fairness and Penalty Delay Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to delay the individual health insurance mandate and any penalties for violating the individual mandate until after there is a certification that the healthcare.gov or other applicable State Exchange website is fully operational, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412315"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400630" joined="2013-11-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-11-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-15">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-15">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3425"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/15/2013--Introduced.
Federal and State Insurance Exchange Access Fairness and Penalty Delay Act of 2013 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to delay the effective date of the penalty for failure to maintain minimum essential health insurance coverage to months beginning no earlier than 30 days after the end of an enrollment period extension required by this Act (a period of at least 90 days after a certification to Congress by the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services [HHS] that the healthcare.gov website and a state exchange website are fully operational, or only the healthcare.gov website in the case of an individual residing in a state without a state exchange website).

Requires the Inspector General, in determining whether to make such certification, to consider monthly reports by the Comptroller General (GAO) on the progress of the websites in achieving such status.</summary>
</bill>
