<bill session="113" type="h" number="3381" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-11-25T19:37:00-05:00">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-11-25T19:37:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize appropriations for fiscal year 2014 for intelligence and intelligence-related activities of the United States Government, the Community Management Account, and the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement and Disability System, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400342"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-21T12:15:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Rogers (MI) announced that the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence has ordered the bill, H.R. 3381, the Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2014, reported favorably to the House with amendments and that if Members wish to review the classified information, they should contact the committee's director of security to arrange a time and date.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-25T19:37:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Intelligence. H. Rept. 113-277.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-11-25T19:37:00-05:00" state="REPORTED" calendar="Union" number="198">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 198.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4661"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4681"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1681"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2741"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Central Intelligence Agency (CIA)"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Director of National Intelligence"/>
    <term name="Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA)"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI)"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/25/2013--Reported to House amended.
Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2014 - Title I: Intelligence Activities - (Sec. 101) Authorizes appropriations for FY2014 for the conduct of intelligence and intelligence-related activities of the: (1) Office of the Director of National Intelligence; (2) Central Intelligence Agency (CIA); (3) Department of Defense (DOD); (4) Defense Intelligence Agency (DIA); (5) National Security Agency (NSA); (6) Departments of the Army, Navy, and Air Force; (7) Coast Guard; (8) Departments of State, the Treasury, Energy (DOE), and Justice (DOJ); (9) Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI); (10) Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA); (11) National Reconnaissance Office; (12) National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency; and (13) Department of Homeland Security (DHS).

(Sec. 102) Specifies that the amounts authorized and the authorized personnel ceilings as of September 30, 2014, for such activities are those specified in the classified Schedule of Authorizations, which shall be made available to the congressional appropriations committees and the President. Prohibits the President from publicly disclosing the classified Schedule of Authorizations or any portion of such Schedule, except: (1) as provided in the Implementing Recommendations of the 9/11 Commission Act of 2007, (2) to the extent necessary to implement the budget, or (3) as otherwise required by law.

(Sec. 103) Allows the Director of National Intelligence, with the approval of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB), to authorize employment of civilian personnel in excess of the number authorized for FY2014 when necessary for the performance of important intelligence functions. Requires written notification to the congressional intelligence committees on the use of such authority.

(Sec. 104) Authorizes appropriations for the Intelligence Community Management Account for FY2014, as well as for full-time personnel for elements within such Account. Authorizes funds identified for advanced research and development in the classified Schedule of Authorizations to remain available until September 30, 2015.

Title II: Central Intelligence Agency Retirement and Disability System - (Sec. 201) Authorizes appropriations for FY2014 for the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement and Disability Fund.

Title III: General Provisions - (Sec. 301) Permits appropriations authorized by this Act for salary, pay, retirement, and other benefits for federal employees to be increased by such additional or supplemental amounts as necessary for increases in such compensation or benefits authorized by law.

(Sec. 302) Prohibits the authorization of appropriations by this Act from being deemed to constitute authority to conduct any intelligence activity not otherwise authorized by the Constitution or laws of the United States.

(Sec. 303) Amends the National Security Act of 1947 to require the Director of National Intelligence to: (1) ensure that the background of each employee or officer and contractor of the intelligence community is monitored continuously to determine their eligibility for access to classified information; and (2) develop procedures to require sharing of potentially derogatory security information concerning an employee officer, contractor, or employee of a contractor of the intelligence community that may impact the eligibility of such individuals for a security clearance.

(Sec. 304) Requires the Director of National Intelligence and the CIA Director to: (1)&#160;ensure that any contractor to an element of the intelligence community with access to classified information develops and operates a security plan that is consistent with standards established by the Director of National Intelligence for intelligence community networks, (2) conduct periodic assessments of each such security plan, and (3) ensure that the insider threat detection capabilities and policies of the intelligence community apply to facilities of contractors with access to a classified network.

(Sec. 305) Repeals provisions of the National Security Act of 1947 requiring a report on the threat of attack using weapons of mass destruction.

Requires the Director of National Intelligence and the CIA Director to notify the congressional intelligence committees each time the Director creates an advisory committee and to include a description of such committee and its subject matter.

(Sec. 306) Amends the National Security Act of 1947 to: (1) exempt from Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) disclosure requirements the identities of employees submitting complaints to the Inspector General of the Intelligence Community, and (2)&#160; require the President to establish in writing a plan to respond to the unauthorized public disclosure of an activity within a covert action program.

(Sec. 308) Authorizes the DHS Secretary to use funds available through the National Intelligence Program for official representation items in support of the Coast Guard Attache Program.

(Sec. 309) Requires the Director of National Intelligence, within 120 days after the enactment of this Act, to: (1) complete a declassification review of documents collected in Abbottabad, Pakistan, during the mission that killed Osama bin Laden on May 1, 2011; (2) make publicly available any information that is declassified as a result of such review; and (3) report to Congress&#160;on as to why any such information must remain classified.

(Sec. 310) Requires the Director of National Intelligence to submit to the congressional intelligence committees: (1) a report on the extent to which the intelligence community has implemented recommendations of the Inspector General of the Intelligence Community on electronic waste, and (2)&#160;a plan to establish a national program to promote cybersecurity and computer literacy among students in high schools or institutions of higher education.

Title IV: Technical Amendments - Makes technical amendments to the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949, the National Security Act of 1947, and the Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2013.</summary>
</bill>
