<bill session="113" type="h" number="5394" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-08-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-08-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Education Elimination Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the elimination of the Department of Education, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412252"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-08-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Training" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/1/2014--Introduced.
Department of Education Elimination Act of 2014 - Abolishes the Department of Education (Department) and repeals any program for which it or the Secretary of Education has administrative responsibility.

Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to provide grants to states, for FY2015-FY2024, for any: (1) elementary and secondary education purpose permitted by state law, and (2) postsecondary education purpose permitted by state law. Sets the funding level for those grants at the amount of funding provided to states for federal elementary and secondary education programs and the amount provided for federal postsecondary education programs, respectively, for FY2012, minus the funding they were provided for education programs that this Act transfers to other federal agencies.

Requires states to contract for an annual audit of their expenditures or transfers of grant funds.

Requires the transfer of:

 each of the Department's job training programs to the Department of Labor; each special education grant program under the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act to the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS); each of the Department's Indian Education programs to the Department of the Interior; each Impact Aid program under the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to the Department of Defense (DOD); and the Federal Pell Grant program and the Federal Family Education Loan and William D. Ford Federal Direct Loan programs, under the Higher Education Act of 1965, to the Department of HHS. Sets a fiscal year cap on Federal Pell Grant funding.</summary>
</bill>
