<bill session="113" type="h" number="4455" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-04-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-04-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Learning Opportunities With Creation of Open Source Textbooks (LOW COST) Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require Federal agencies to collaborate in the development of freely available open source educational materials in college-level physics, chemistry, and math, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412257"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2014-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2014-04-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-10">
      <text>Referred to House Science, Space, and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-10">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Research and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY15" subcommittee="Research and Technology" name="House Science, Space, and Technology"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Training" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/10/2014--Introduced.
Learning Opportunities With Creation of Open Source Textbooks (LOW COST) Act of 2014 - Requires the Director of the National Science Foundation (NSF) to develop high quality, college freshman-level, open source materials that: (1) contain, at minimum, a comprehensive set of textbooks or other educational materials covering topics in physics, chemistry, and calculus; (2) are posted on the Federal Open Source Material Website (Website); and (3) are free of copyright violations.

Requires the Director to establish and maintain the Website.

Requires materials on the Website to be made available free of charge. Allows those materials to be downloaded, redistributed, or revised by the public.

Directs the head of each federal agency that spends more than a specified amount in a fiscal year on scientific education or research to use at least 2% of those funds to collaborate with the heads of other such agencies or any federally funded research and development center to develop and implement procedures for checking the veracity, accuracy, and educational effectiveness of open source materials that are posted on the Website.</summary>
</bill>
