<bill session="113" type="h" number="5506" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Home Improvement Loan Modernization Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title I of the National Housing Act to, for financing alterations, repairs, and improvements to, or conversion of, existing structures, modify premium charges and the dollar amount limitation on loans, including energy efficiency home improvements.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412511"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412584" joined="2014-09-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/17/2014--Introduced.
Home Improvement Loan Modernization Act of 2014 - Amends the National Housing Act to specify the premium charge paid by a financial institution to insure any loan, advance of credit, or purchase of obligations representing loans and advances of credit it makes to finance certain home improvements for both existing single-family and multifamily structures.

Sets the initial premium at 2.75% of the original insured principal obligation, with annual premium payments not to exceed 1.5% of the remaining balance.

Limits any premium charges to the minimum amounts necessary to maintain a negative credit subsidy for the insurance program.

Increases the maximum obligation that may be insured for improvements to: (1) an existing single-family dwelling from $25,000 to $42,000; and (2) an existing multi-family structure from $60,000 to $101,888, with an average amount of $20,378 (currently $12,000) per family unit.

Directs the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to develop a method of indexing to increase these dollar amount limitations annually, based on the Consumer Price Index for all urban consumers (CPI-U) computed by the Bureau of Labor Statistics (BLS).

Allows an increase in these dollar amount limitations also by up to 150% if at least half of the amount will be used for energy conserving improvements or the installation of solar energy systems.</summary>
</bill>
