<bill session="113" type="h" number="5402" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-10">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-09-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Standard Merger and Acquisition Reviews Through Equal Rules Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Standard Merger and Acquisition Reviews Through Equal Rules Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Clayton Act and the Federal Trade Commission Act to provide that the Federal Trade Commission shall exercise authority with respect to mergers only under the Clayton Act and only in the same procedural manner as Attorney General exercises such authority.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412482"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400154" joined="2014-09-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-09">
      <text>Subcommittee on Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-10">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-09-10" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-12-11T11:21:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 113-658.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-12-11T11:21:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="495">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 495.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSJU05" subcommittee="Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Competition and antitrust"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Federal district courts"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction and venue"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/11/2014--Reported to House without amendment.
Standard Merger and Acquisition Reviews Through Equal Rules Act of 2014 - Amends the Clayton Act with respect to actions brought by the Attorney General for violations of antitrust laws. Requires the Federal Trade Commission (FTC), but only under the Clayton Act, to exercise the same authority and procedures of the Attorney General specified in the Act with respect to the prohibition against acquisition by one corporation of the stock of another (merger) that may substantially lessen competition or tend to create a monopoly.

Amends the Federal Trade Commission Act (FTCA) to exclude proposed mergers, acquisitions, joint ventures, or similar transactions from FTC proceedings.

Grants jurisdiction to the U.S. district courts to issue writs of mandamus commanding compliance with the FTCA or any FTC order, if the FTC applies to such courts with respect to any activity related to consummation of a merger, acquisition, joint venture, or similar transaction that results in an unfair method of competition.</summary>
</bill>
