<bill session="113" type="h" number="4093" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-03-05">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-03-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-02-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Greater Opportunities for Small Business Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Greater Opportunities for Small Business Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Small Business Act to raise the prime and subcontract goals, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400158"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412454" joined="2014-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412527" joined="2014-03-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-02-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-05">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-03-05" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-04-09T14:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Small Business. H. Rept. 113-409.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-04-09T14:51:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="301">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 301.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/9/2014--Reported to House without amendment.
Greater Opportunities for Small Business Act of 2014 - Amends the Small Business Act to require subcontracting plans for certain contracts with federal agencies exceeding a specified amount to include a minimum percentage goal of at least 40% for the utilization of small businesses as subcontractors.

Increases from 23% to 25% the minimum government-wide percentage goal for participation by small businesses in the total value of all procurement contracts awarded as prime contracts for each fiscal year.

Repeals a requirement under which first tier subcontracts (contracts in which a subcontractor has a subcontract directly with the prime contractor) awarded to small businesses by management and operating contractors sponsored by the Department of Energy (DOE) are considered toward the annually established agency and government-wide goals for procurement contracts awarded.

Delays the effective date of the 40% goal until the Small Business Administration (SBA) has promulgated any regulations necessary, and the Federal Acquisition Regulation has been revised, to implement specified provisions of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2014 concerning the standards for determining whether a prime contractor has attained small business subcontracting percentage goals.</summary>
</bill>
