<bill session="113" type="h" number="5427" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SAVE for Small Businesses Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Savings Accounts for a Variable Economy for Small Businesses Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to establish small business savings accounts.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400195"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400031" joined="2014-09-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Financial crises and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/9/2014--Introduced.
SAVE for Small Businesses Act or the Savings Accounts for a Variable Economy for Small Businesses Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide for tax-exempt small business savings accounts. Allows tax deductible contributions to such accounts of not more than 10% of the gross profits of an eligible small business (persons employing an average of 50 or fewer full-time employees)&#160;for the preceding taxable year.

Excludes qualified distributions from such accounts from gross income for income tax purposes. Defines "qualified distribution" as: (1) any amount that is distributed from a small business savings account during a specified period of economic hardship, and (2) the distribution of which is certified as being part of a plan that provides for the reinvestment of such distribution for the funding of worker hiring or financial stabilization for the purposes of job retention or creation.

Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to: (1) establish minimum standards for small business savings accounts that seek to minimize fees and risk of loss of principal, and (2) ensure a range of investment risk options available to account beneficiaries.</summary>
</bill>
