<bill session="113" type="s" number="2334" updated="2015-09-01T17:50:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-05-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improving Opportunities for Service-Disabled Veteran-Owned Small Businesses Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Small Business Act and title 38, United States Code, to provide for a consolidated definition of a small business concern owned and controlled by veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412545"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2014-05-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2882"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4435"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/14/2014--Introduced.
Improving Opportunities for Service-Disabled Veteran-Owned Small Businesses Act of 2014 - Amends the Small Business Act to expand the definition of "small business concern owned and controlled by service-disabled veterans" for purposes of federal agencies awarding&#160;small business contracts pursuant to Small Business Administration (SBA) programs to&#160;include: (1) a small business concern not less than 51% of which is owned by one or more veterans with service-connected disabilities that are permanent and total who are unable to manage the daily business operations of such concern; or (2) in the case of a publicly owned business, a small business concern not less than 51% of the stock of which is owned by one or more such veterans. (Currently, such veterans with permanent and total disabilities are provided for in a separate small business program under veterans' benefits laws&#160;carried out by the&#160;Department of Veterans Affairs [VA].)

Revises the VA definition of "small business concern owned and controlled by veterans" to be the same as the SBA definition of such term, thereby making the eligibility requirements for participation in veteran-owned small business contracting programs consistent for both SBA programs and VA programs.

Provides that if the death of a service-disabled veteran causes a small business concern to be less than 51% owned by one or more such veterans, the surviving spouse of such veteran who acquires ownership rights in such small business concern shall be treated as if the surviving spouse were that veteran for the purpose of maintaining the business's eligibility for such contracting programs&#160;until the earliest of the following dates: (1) the date on which the surviving spouse either remarries or relinquishes the ownership interest, (2) 10 years after the veteran's death in the case of a surviving spouse of a veteran with a service-connected disability rated as 100% disabling or who dies as a result of a service-connected disability, or (3) 3 years after the veteran's death in the case of a surviving spouse of a veteran with a service-connected disability rated as less than 100% disabling who does not die as a result of a service-connected disability. (Currently, the SBA program does not provide such treatment&#160;for surviving spouses while the VA program provides such treatment only until remarriage, ownership relinquishment, or for 10 years&#160;with respect to&#160;surviving spouses of veterans with a 100% disabling service-connected disability or who die as a result of a service-connected disability.)

Requires&#160;a Comptroller General (GAO) report on the advisability of the SBA or the VA having government-wide responsibility for verifying businesses purporting to be small business concerns owned and controlled by service-disabled veterans.</summary>
</bill>
