<bill session="113" type="h" number="4150" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-03-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-03-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Employment and Training Service Longitudinal Study Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Labor to enter into a contract for the conduct of a longitudinal study of the job counseling, training, and placement services for veterans provided by the Secretary, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412513"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412271" joined="2014-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412318" joined="2014-03-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-03-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-05">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-05">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-25">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSVR10" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/5/2014--Introduced.
Veterans Employment and Training Service Longitudinal Study Act of 2014 - Directs the Secretary of Labor to enter into a contract with a non-governmental entity to conduct a longitudinal study of a statistically valid sample of each of the following groups of individuals over a period of at least five years: (1) veterans who have received intensive job counseling, training, and placement services; (2) veterans who did not receive intensive services but who otherwise received services; and (3) veterans who did not seek or receive services.

Requires the study to include the collection of specified information for each individual who participates in the study, including: (1) the average number of months served on active duty, (2) the distribution of disability ratings, (3) unemployment benefits received, (4) the average number of months employed and average individual and household annual income, (5) employment status, (6) whether the individual believes that any service received helped the individual to become employed, (7) use of educational assistance, (8) participation in a vocational rehabilitation program, (9) conditions of discharge or release from the Armed Forces, and (10) demographic information.

Directs the Secretary to submit annual reports on the outcomes of the study that include any information the Secretary determines is necessary to determine long-term outcomes of the individuals in such groups.

Amends the Social Security Act to grant the Secretary access to new hire information reported by employers.</summary>
</bill>
