<bill session="113" type="s" number="2126" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-03-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-03-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-03-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Regenerative Medicine Promotion Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to launch a national strategy to support regenerative medicine through the establishment of a Regenerative Medicine Coordinating Council, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300011"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400013" joined="2014-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412598" joined="2014-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2014-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400222" joined="2014-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2014-04-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-03-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Product development and innovation"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Surgery and anesthesia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/13/2014--Introduced.
Regenerative Medicine Promotion Act of 2014 - Requires the Comptroller General to submit to Congress a report identifying all ongoing federal programs and activities regarding regenerative medicine.

Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish a Regenerative Medicine Coordinating Council, which shall:

 prepare a national strategy to support research into regenerative medicine and enable the development of drugs, biological products, medical devices, and biomaterials for use in regenerative medicine; develop national goals for regenerative medicine research and product development; prepare a plan specifying priorities for research into regenerative medicine; identify sources of funding for research into regenerative medicine and areas where such funding is inadequate or duplicative; make recommendations regarding federal policies to support development and marketing of regenerative medicine products; develop consensus standards regarding scientific issues critical to regulator approval of regenerative medicine products; and determine the need for establishing centers of excellence or consortia to further advance regenerative medicine. Directs the Council to: (1) adopt procedures to ensure the receipt of public input; and (2) submit an annual report on its activities to Congress, the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH), and the Commissioner of Food and Drugs (FDA).</summary>
</bill>
