<bill session="113" type="s" number="2877" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Debt Management Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to appropriately manage the debt of the United States by limiting the use of extraordinary measures.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400418"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/18/2014--Introduced.
Federal Debt Management Act of 2014 - Limits the Department of the Treasury's authority to manage the debt of the United States by using extraordinary measures to prevent the public debt limit from being exceeded.

Limits the authority of the Secretary of the Treasury to suspend the investing of amounts or the issuance of obligations for the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund, the Thrift Savings Fund, the Exchange Stabilization Fund, or any other fund or account for the purposes of preventing the public debt of the United States from exceeding the public debt limit.

Requires the Secretary to submit to Congress additional information regarding the Daily Treasury Statement, including: (1) all cash flow and debt transaction information used in preparing the Daily Treasury Statement, and (2) forecasts for the cash flow and debt transactions of the federal government.</summary>
</bill>
