<bill session="113" type="s" number="1939" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-01-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-01-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-01-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">War Powers Consultation Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to repeal the War Powers Resolution and to provide for proper war powers consultation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412582"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412545" joined="2014-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="2014-01-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-01-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S442-443"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="5416"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/16/2014--Introduced.
War Powers Consultation Act of 2014 - States that: (1) the purpose of this Act is to establish a means by which the judgment of both the President and Congress can be brought to bear when deciding whether the United States should engage in a significant armed conflict; and (2) this Act is not meant to define, circumscribe, or enhance the constitutional war powers of either the executive or legislative branch of government.

Repeals the War Powers Resolution.

Establishes the Joint Congressional Consultation Committee.

Directs the President to: (1) consult regularly with the Committee regarding significant matters of foreign policy and national security; (2) before ordering the deployment of members of the Armed Forces into a significant armed conflict, consult with and report to the Committee regarding the circumstances necessitating the significant armed conflict, the objectives, and the conflict's estimated scope and duration; and (3) consult with the Committee at least every two months for the duration of any significant armed conflict.

States that, if the President determines that the need for secrecy or other emergency circumstances preclude carrying out such reporting before significant armed conflict is ordered or begins, the President shall carry out such reporting not later than three days after the beginning of the significant armed conflict.

	Declares that, within 30 days after the deployment of members of the Armed Forces into a significant armed conflict for which Congress has not enacted a formal declaration of war or otherwise enacted a specific authorization for the use of military force, the chair and vice chair of the Committee shall introduce a joint resolution of approval. Sets forth related congressional procedures, including the introduction of a joint resolution of disapproval if a vote against a resolution of approval's passage has taken place.

States that nothing in this Act shall be construed as modifying U.S. obligations under any treaty or international agreement.</summary>
</bill>
