<bill session="113" type="s" number="1863" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-12-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-12-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-12-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish in the Department of Veterans Affairs a continuing medical education program for licensed medical professionals to increase knowledge and recognition of medical conditions common to veterans and family members of veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400050"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-12-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/19/2013--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to establish a continuing medical education program for medical professionals with the goal of: (1) increasing knowledge and recognition of medical conditions common to veterans and family members of veterans, and (2) improving outreach to veterans and family members.

Requires the program to include education on: (1) dealing with patients who are veterans or family members; (2) identifying and treating common mental and physical conditions of veterans and family members; (3) programs and benefits available to veterans and family members through the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA), the Department of Labor, and such other federal agencies and non-federal organizations as the Secretary considers appropriate; and (4) the VA health care system.

Directs the Secretary to: (1) carry out such program for five years on a VA website at no cost to participating medical professionals, and (2) ensure that the program is accredited in as many states as practicable.</summary>
</bill>
