<bill session="113" type="h" number="2953" updated="2015-09-01T10:19:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-08-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-08-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medicare VA Reimbursement Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide Medicare payments to Department of Veterans Affairs medical facilities for items and services provided to Medicare-eligible veterans for non-service-connected conditions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400274"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, and Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR03" subcommittee="Health" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/1/2013--Introduced.
Medicare VA Reimbursement Act of 2013 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), in cooperation with the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA), to establish a Medicare VA reimbursement program under which the HHS Secretary shall reimburse the VA Secretary, from the Medicare trust funds, for any item or service: (1) furnished to a Medicare-eligible veteran by a VA medical facility for the treatment of a non-service-connected condition, and (2) covered by Medicare or determined to be medically necessary by the VA Secretary.

Requires the HHS Secretary to enter a memorandum of understanding with the VA Secretary concerning administration of the program. Specifies required conditions in the memorandum.

Directs the Comptroller General to report to Congress on the program every three years.

Declares the sense of Congress that the amount of funds appropriated to the VA for medical care in any fiscal year should not be reduced as a result of the implementation of the Medicare VA reimbursement program.</summary>
</bill>
