<bill session="113" type="hr" number="429" updated="2015-09-01T10:18:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-12-04T14:36:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-12-04T14:36:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-12-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3309) to amend title 35, United States Code, and the Leahy-Smith America Invents Act to make improvements and technical corrections, and for other purposes; and providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1105) to amend the Investment Advisers Act of 1940 to provide a registration exemption for private equity fund advisers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412409"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-12-03T18:54:00-05:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 113-283, by Mr. Nugent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-03T18:54:00-05:00">
      <text>For H.R. 3309, resolution provides one hour of general debate; bill is considered read; specified amendments are in order; and one motion to recommit, with or without instructions. For H.R. 1109, resolution provides that an amendment in the nature of a substitute consisting of the text of Rules Committee print 113-29 shall be considered as adopted; one hour of debate; makes in order an additional specified amendment; and one motion to recommit, with or without instructions.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-12-03T18:54:00-05:00" state="REPORTED" calendar="House" number="77">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 77.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-12-04T12:37:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7461-7469" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-04T12:41:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 429.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-04T13:31:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H.Res. 429, the Chair put the question on ordering the previous question on H.Res. 429 and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Polis demanded the yeas and nays on ordering the previous question on H.Res 429 and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-04T14:02:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7469-7470" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-04T14:29:00-05:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 220 - 194 (Roll no. 618).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7468-7469" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7468" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="619" datetime="2013-12-04T14:36:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 229 - 185 (Roll no. 619).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7461-7462" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-12-04T14:36:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="113" type="h" number="1105"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3309"/>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="113" type="h" number="3309"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/3/2013--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3309) to amend title 35, United States Code, and the Leahy-Smith America Invents Act to make improvements and technical corrections, and for other purposes; and providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1105) to amend the Investment Advisers Act of 1940 to provide a registration exemption for private equity fund advisers.</summary>
</bill>
