<bill session="113" type="hj" number="76" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-08-04">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-08-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Nuclear weapon security &amp; non-proliferation bill</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Nuclear Security Administration Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">National Nuclear Security Administration Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Emergency Supplemental Appropriations Resolution, 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Emergency Supplemental Appropriations Resolution, 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Making continuing appropriations for the National Nuclear Security Administration for fiscal year 2014, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by senate">A joint resolution making an emergency supplemental appropriation for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2014, to provide funding to Israel for the Iron Dome defense system to counter short-range rocket threats.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400142"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-11T09:12:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 371.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6497-6502" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-11T09:13:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 40 minutes of debate on H.J. Res. 76.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-11T09:57:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6502" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-11T09:57:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - The Chair announced that further proceedings on H.J. Res. 76 had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-11T10:26:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6502-6504" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-11T10:27:00-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Kelly (IL) moved to recommit with instructions to Appropriations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6502" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6502" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-11T10:27:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Kelly (IL) motion recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House forthwith with an amendment to replace the underlying bill with the Senate Amendment to H.J. Res. 59, Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2014, pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-11T10:30:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Frelinghuysen raised a point of order against the motion to recommit with instructions. Mr. Frelinghuysen stated that the amendment was not germane to the underlying bill. Sustained by the Chair.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-11T10:30:00-04:00">
      <text>Point of order sustained against the motion to recommit with instructions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-11T10:32:00-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Kelly (IL) appealed the ruling of the chair. The question was then put on sustaining the ruling of the chair.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6502" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-11T10:32:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Frelinghuysen moved to table the appeal of the ruling of the Chair.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-11T10:56:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to table the appeal of the ruling of the Chair Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 226 - 195 (Roll no. 541).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="542" datetime="2013-10-11T11:07:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 248 - 176 (Roll no. 542).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6497" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-10-11T11:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-12">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-10-13" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="220">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 220.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-08-01">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5318-5319" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote2" datetime="2014-08-01" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_BACK:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment and an amendment to the Title by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-08-01">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-08-01T17:38:00-04:00">
      <text>ORDER OF BUSINESS - Mr. Sessions asked unanimous consent that it be in order at any time to take from the Speaker's table H.J.Res. 76, with the Senate amendments thereto, and to consider in the House, without intervention of any point of order, a single motion offered by the Chair of the Committee on Appropriations or his designee that the House concur in the Senate amendments; the Senate amendments be considered as read; the previous question be considered as ordered on the motion to adoption without intervening motion or demand for division of the question; and the Chair may postpone the question of adoption of the motion as though under clause 8 of rule 20.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-08-01T17:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Rogers (KY) moved that the House agree to the Senate amendments.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7205, H7236" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-08-01T17:38:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7205" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-08-01T17:39:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Rogers (KY) motion to agree in the Senate amendments to H.J.Res. 76, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the Senate amendments and by voice vote, announced that the ayes prevailed. Mr. Rogers (KY) demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="pingpong" roll="480" datetime="2014-08-01T22:04:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On motion that the House agree to the Senate amendments Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 395 - 8 (Roll no. 480).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7205" label="text as House agreed to Senate Amendments"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-08-01T22:04:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2014-08-04">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2014-08-04" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="113-145" type="public" datetime="2014-08-04">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 113-145.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hr" number="371"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s3780"/>
    <amendment number="s3781"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>8/4/2014--Public Law.
(This measure has not been amended since it was passed by the Senate on August 1, 2014.&#160; The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Emergency Supplemental Appropriations Resolution, 2014 - Appropriates FY2014 supplemental funds to the Department of Defense (DOD) to assist the government of Israel with procurement of the Iron Dome defense system to counter short-range rocket threats.

Provides that the funds shall be transferred immediately only through an exchange of letters to address emergent operations in support of Operation Protective Edge, notwithstanding the U.S-Israel Iron Dome Procurement Agreement.

Designates funding provided in this joint resolution as an emergency requirement pursuant to the Balanced Budget And Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</summary>
</bill>
