<bill session="113" type="h" number="5431" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Isolating ISIS Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To impose sanctions on foreign financial institutions that engage in certain transactions with the Islamic State of Iraq and Syria, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400646"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412536" joined="2014-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412544" joined="2014-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2014-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412489" joined="2014-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412570" joined="2014-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412399" joined="2014-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412317" joined="2014-09-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Government Reform, and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-10">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-10">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-10">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Currency"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international banking"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/10/2014--Introduced.
Isolating ISIS Act - Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to prohibit, or impose strict conditions on, the opening or maintaining in the United States of a correspondent account or a payable-through account by a foreign financial institution that knowingly: facilitates a transaction for the Islamic State of Iraq and Syria (ISIS); facilitates a transaction of a person designated for acting on behalf of or at the direction of, or owned or controlled by, ISIS; engages in money laundering to carry out such an activity; facilitates a transaction or provides financial services to carry out such an activity; or facilitates such an activity, conspires to facilitate or participate in such an activity, or is owned or controlled by a foreign financial institution that knowingly engages in such an activity. Applies specified penalties under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act for violations of this Act.

Authorizes the Secretary to waive the application of a prohibition for up to 180 days (with renewable 180-day waivers) if in U.S. national security interests, and with congressional notification.

Directs the Secretary to identify to Congress every 180 days each foreign central bank that carries out a prohibited activity.

Directs the President to transmit to Congress a list of, and impose specified sanctions against, any person who knowingly engages in a transaction with a foreign person that transfers or receives, or facilitates the transfer or receipt of, any goods or services to or from ISIS.

States that the President shall not be required to include a person on this list if: (1) that person is no longer engaging in or has taken significant steps toward stopping sanctioned activities, and (2) the President has received reliable assurances that such person will not knowingly engage in any new sanctioned activity.

States that nothing in this Act shall apply to authorized U.S. intelligence activities.</summary>
</bill>
