<bill session="113" type="h" number="3501" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-11-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-11-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-11-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Generational Residences and Nurturing Dwellings Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">GRAND Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to provide assistance to eligible nonprofit organizations to provide specialized housing and supportive services for elderly persons who are the primary caregivers of children that are related to such persons.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400366"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400087" joined="2013-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2013-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="2013-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="2013-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412530" joined="2013-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412276" joined="2013-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400179" joined="2013-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2013-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400195" joined="2013-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412561" joined="2013-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2013-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412293" joined="2013-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400271" joined="2013-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400290" joined="2013-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400310" joined="2013-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412506" joined="2013-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400347" joined="2013-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412186" joined="2013-12-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-11-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Housing for the elderly and disabled"/>
    <term name="Housing supply and affordability"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/14/2013--Introduced.
Generational Residences and Nurturing Dwellings Act or GRAND Act - Establishes in the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) a program to provide need-based assistance for each fiscal year, made available on a competitive basis, to up to five eligible nonprofit organizations to expand the supply of specialized housing and social services for qualified elderly relatives, age 60 or older, who are raising a child of which they are not a parent either by blood or marriage.

Provides such assistance in the form of:

 financing for the construction, reconstruction, moderate or substantial rehabilitation, or acquisition of a structure or a portion of a structure to be used as specialized housing in accordance with the program; tenant-based rental (voucher) assistance under the United States Housing Act of 1937 for use only by qualified relatives who are raising a child and are eligible for such assistance for rental of a dwelling unit that qualifies as specialized housing; elderly housing project rental assistance under the Housing Act of 1959 in connection with dwelling units that qualify as specialized housing and are made available for occupancy only by qualified relatives who are raising a child and are eligible for occupancy in such housing; and help with ongoing operational expenses of any specialized housing, including costs of supportive services required for such housing.</summary>
</bill>
