<bill session="113" type="h" number="5626" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Property Low Hanging Fruit Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide uniform authority for executive departments to use funds from the disposal of Federal real property and to establish a pilot program in certain agencies for the use of public-private agreements to enhance the efficiency of Federal real property.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412558"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="General Services Administration"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Real estate business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/18/2014--Introduced.
Federal Property Low Hanging Fruit Act - Authorizes the head of each executive department to convey real and related property under the department's ownership and control and retain the net proceeds in an account within the Treasury. Makes such proceeds available to the department head to pay necessary and incidental costs for the department's property management activities, including acquisition, improvements, maintenance, reconstruction or construction needs.

Directs the head of each of the Departments of Defense (DOD), Agriculture, and&#160;Energy (DOE) and the General Services Administration (GSA) to develop and carry out a plan to enter into agreements with a nongovernmental person to: (1) lease at least 5, but not more than 10, federal real properties that are underutilized or excess; and (2) develop, rehabilitate, or renovate facilities on such leased properties. Requires such agreements to provide a lease option to the United States and indemnity for any actions, debts, or liability of the nongovernmental person.&#160;Directs the Comptroller General (GAO) to submit reports to Congress on the effectiveness of the plan.</summary>
</bill>
