<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="H3DA14D54A77F460F88F9DAD261525466" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-concurrent" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HCON 102 IH: Expressing support for designation of June 21 as National ASK (Asking Saves Kids) Day to promote children’s health and gun safety.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2014-06-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes"> IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. CON. RES. 102</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20140620">June 20, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000559">Mr. Langevin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000266">Mr. Tierney</cosponsor>) submitted the following concurrent resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>CONCURRENT RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Expressing support for designation of June 21 as National ASK (Asking Saves Kids) Day to promote
			 children’s health and gun safety.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas><text>Whereas on average in 2010, 1 child under the age of 15 died every 6 days due to the unintentional
			 discharge of a firearm;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas according to estimates from the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, in 2012,
			 approximately 667 children sustained nonfatal injuries from the
			 unintentional discharge of a firearm;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas in States that collect data through the National Violent Death Reporting System, on
			 average, 80 percent of unintentional firearm deaths of children under 15
			 occurred in a home;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the ASK Campaign encourages parents to add one more question to a conversation before their
			 child visits other homes, <quote>Is there an unlocked gun in your house?</quote>;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the ASK Campaign was first established by the American Academy of Pediatrics (AAP) and the
			 Center to Prevent Youth Violence along with other partners in 2000;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the President of the AAP has said <quote>keeping children and teens safe from preventable
			 injuries is one of the most important things we do as pediatricians</quote>;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas according to the National Rifle Association’s Parents Guide to Gun Safety, <quote>Parental
			 responsibility does not end, however, when the child leaves the home …
			 Even
			 if no one in your family owns a gun, chances are that someone you know
			 does. Your child could come in contact with a gun at a neighbor’s house,
			 when playing with friends, or under other circumstances outside your
			 home</quote>;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas asking this simple question about gun safety before sending your child to play at another
			 home could help save your child’s life;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas June 21, the first day of summer, the season in which kids typically spend more time at a
			 friend’s or family member’s home, has traditionally been designated as
			 National ASK Day; and</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas June 21, 2014, has been designated by national organizations as the 14th annual National
			 ASK Day: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body id="HCAC62ACDBBD64F4F831A2211337E1CAE" style="traditional">
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H310A42E61D5A4228A919470F85584302" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That Congress—</text>
			<paragraph id="H91D4F24F5DEF43769A63E2B743E2C63B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports designation of National ASK (Asking Saves Kids) Day to encourage parents to begin asking
			 this life-saving question; and</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HDA77ECD906C9405982514EC39CDDFA59"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports the goals and ideals of National ASK Day.</text>
			</paragraph></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


