<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="H6DDFD38C25F2420F825264DE6A607D98" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HRES 769 IH: Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the healthcare, energy, telecommunications, and other sectors of the United States economy should continue their sector-specific efforts to protect critical infrastructure, to prevent information security breaches, and to prevent cybersecurity breaches.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2014-12-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 769</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20141202">December 2, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000459">Mr. Terry</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the healthcare, energy,
			 telecommunications, and other sectors of the United States economy should
			 continue their sector-specific efforts to protect critical infrastructure,
			 to prevent information security breaches, and to prevent cybersecurity
			 breaches.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas><text>Whereas the United States economy is diverse, and has many different sectors;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas each sector faces different challenges related to critical infrastructure, information
			 security, and cybersecurity; and</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the healthcare, energy, telecommunications, and other industry sectors are taking
			 sector-specific steps to protect critical infrastructure, to prevent
			 information security breaches, and to prevent cybersecurity breaches: Now,
			 therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body id="HAB489935515B428792A4AAAC035FC04D" style="traditional">
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HD3B1C404F8C54A2CAB7EDC00473BBB12" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That it is the sense of the House of Representatives that—</text>
			<paragraph id="H2DDE95C2D6FE430C8BB6A65EA9B65205"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the healthcare sector should continue its sector-specific efforts to protect critical
			 infrastructure, to prevent information security breaches, and to prevent
			 cybersecurity breaches (other than for research and development purposes);</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H7E8F19D428FB4A8681EDB8844025D220"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the energy sector should continue its sector-specific efforts to protect critical infrastructure,
			 to prevent information security breaches, and to prevent cybersecurity
			 breaches (other than for research and development purposes);</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HA4E9C3A1BEE440019E332799A1FC4B4E"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the telecommunications sector should continue its sector-specific efforts to protect critical
			 infrastructure, to prevent information security breaches, and to prevent
			 cybersecurity breaches (other than for research and development purposes);
			 and</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H76B40D4303FC41BCB4F6993966FC274C"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other industry sectors should continue their sector-specific efforts to protect critical
			 infrastructure, to prevent information security breaches, and to prevent
			 cybersecurity breaches (other than for research and development purposes).</text>
			</paragraph></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


