<bill session="113" type="s" number="2297" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-05-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">NURSE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nurses for Under-Resourced Schools Everywhere Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to make demonstration grants to eligible local educational agencies or consortia of eligible local educational agencies for the purpose of reducing the student-to-school nurse ratio in public elementary schools and secondary schools.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412244"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2014-05-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1857"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Nursing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/7/2014--Introduced.
Nurses for Under-Resourced Schools Everywhere Act or the NURSE Act - Authorizes the Secretary of Education to make competitive matching demonstration grants to local educational agencies (LEAs) in which the student-to-school nurse ratio in each of their public elementary and secondary schools is 750 or more students to every school nurse to pay a specified federal share of the cost of reducing such ratio.

Gives grant priority to high-need LEAs that demonstrate: (1) the greatest need for new or additional nursing services for their students, or (2) that they do not have a school nurse in any of their schools.

Defines a "high-need LEA" as an LEA for which not fewer than 10,000 or not less than 20% of the children served are from families with incomes below the poverty line.</summary>
</bill>
