<bill session="113" type="s" number="2564" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">End Trafficking Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Child Trafficking Victims Protection Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">SAVE Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Stop Advertising Victims of Exploitation Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide justice for the victims of trafficking, to stop exploitation through trafficking, and to amend title 18, United States Code, by providing a penalty for knowingly selling advertising that offers certain commercial sex acts.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400432"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4294"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/7/2014--Introduced.
End Trafficking Act of 2014 - Stop Advertising Victims of Exploitation Act of 2014 or the SAVE Act of 2014 - Amends the federal criminal code to prohibit the advertising of commercial sex acts with children or with others who are coerced to engage in such acts.

Child Trafficking Victims Protection Act - Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to authorize the Attorney General to award grants to state and local governments for court-based programs that involve: (1) continuing judicial supervision over offenders who are younger than 18, have been trafficked, and are not violent offenders; and (2) integrated administration of other sanctions and services, including housing, education, health care, counseling, and job placement.

Directs the Comptroller General (GAO) to report on: (1) the effectiveness and impact of such grants, (2) any service gap between trafficking victims who are U.S. citizens or lawful permanent residents and foreign nationals residing in the United States and federal agency progress in addressing that gap, (3) efficiencies that could be achieved by consolidating federal grant programs for trafficking survivors, and (4) legislative and regulatory options to ensure adequate criminal justice policies to combat sex trafficking of minors.

Amends the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act to expand the definitions of: (1) "child abuse and neglect" to include any act or failure to act that results in commercial sexual exploitation, and (2) "sex abuse" to include the use of a child's engagement in sexually explicit conduct for commercial purposes.

Directs the Attorney General to: (1) report on deficiencies that exist in the services available to child victims of human trafficking in the United States, (2) make available a database on resources and services for trafficking survivors, and (3) give priority for Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance grants to states and local governments that have adopted demand reduction strategies designed to combat minor sex trafficking.

Prescribes increased penalties for fraud in foreign labor contracting if the offense results in sexual abuse or trafficking of a foreign national younger than age 21.

Extends the statute of limitations for civil actions against perpetrators of human trafficking offenses until ten years after the victim reaches age 18.</summary>
</bill>
