<bill session="113" type="h" number="5823" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-12-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-12-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-12-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Incentivizing Healthcare Quality Outcomes Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to create incentives for healthcare providers to promote quality healthcare outcomes, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400255"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-12-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-09">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-09">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/9/2014--Introduced.
Incentivizing Healthcare Quality Outcomes Act of 2014 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act. in order to incentivize healthcare quality outcomes, to prescribe specific adjustment factors for incentive payments to: (1) healthcare delivery organizations, and (2) healthcare professionals (who are not part of an applicable healthcare delivery organization) in a geographic region to coordinate care and reduce potentially preventable outcomes.

Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish geographic regions to which health professionals shall be assigned.

Requires the Secretary to select a methodology of identifying potentially preventable: (1) inpatient hospital complications, (2) admissions and readmissions, (3) emergency room visits, (4) outpatient procedures and tests, as well as (5) outcomes. Requires selection of a methodology also for risk adjusting the rate of each potentially preventable outcome.

Directs the Secretary to: (1) give confidential reports to healthcare delivery organizations with respect to potentially preventable outcomes, (2) make information available to the public regarding potentially preventable outcomes of each applicable healthcare delivery organization, (3) apply to state plans (or waivers) under SSA title XIX (Medicaid) regulations that will relate to payment adjustments for potentially preventable outcomes, and (4) award quality improvement grants to eligible healthcare delivery organizations with an organization-specific adjustment factor lower than the factor for 75% of all other such organizations.

Directs the Comptroller General (GAO) to study the impact of this Act on Medicare beneficiaries' care, Medicare expenditures, and Medicare providers.</summary>
</bill>
