<bill session="113" type="h" number="4206" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-03-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-03-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HAND UP Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Help Americans in Need Develop their Ultimate Potential Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize a State or a portion of a State to conduct a demonstration project designed to test methods of program integration and coordination of services with the goals of moving individuals and families towards self-sufficiency, reducing welfare dependence, and increasing work and earnings.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412393"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412401" joined="2014-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412465" joined="2014-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400660" joined="2014-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412408" joined="2014-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412428" joined="2014-03-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-03-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Agriculture, Financial Services, and Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-11">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-11">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-11">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-11">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, and Nutrition.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG22" subcommittee="Department Operations, Oversight, and Nutrition" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Training" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/11/2014--Introduced.
Help Americans in Need Develop Their Ultimate Potential Act or HAND UP Act - Establishes a framework for the head of a state entity or of a sub-state entity administering two or more qualified federal programs to participate in a demonstration project, approved by the administering Secretary, that supports individuals and families with the goal of moving them towards self-sufficiency, reducing welfare dependence, and increasing work and earnings. Authorizes the administering Secretary to waive program requirements for purposes of the demonstration.

Specifies as qualified federal programs: (1) the TANF program under part A (Temporary Assistance for Needy Families) (TANF) of title IV of the Social Security Act (SSA), (2) the Block Grants to States for Social Services under SSA title XX, (3) activities funded under the Workforce Investment Act of 1998, (4) activities funded under the United States Housing Act of 1937, and (5) the supplemental nutrition assistance program under the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008.

Amends the United States Housing Act of 1937 to require an annual public housing agency plan for a public housing agency to contain certain demonstration project application information.</summary>
</bill>
