<bill session="113" type="h" number="4533" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-04-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-04-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">NSA Internal Watchdog Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Inspector General Act of 1978 to provide for the Inspector General of the National Security Agency to be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400081"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412282" joined="2014-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400381" joined="2014-04-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, and Intelligence (Permanent Select), for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-30">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-30">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-30">
      <text>Referred to House Intelligence</text>
      <reference ref="Permanent Select"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU10" subcommittee="Constitution and Civil Justice" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2439"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="National Security Agency"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/30/2014--Introduced.
NSA Internal Watchdog Act - Amends the Inspector General Act of 1978 to require the President to appoint, with advice and consent of the Senate, the Inspector General of the National Security Agency (NSA). (Currently, the NSA Inspector General is appointed by the NSA Director.)

Directs the Inspector General to include in an annual report to Congress a review of the mechanisms for NSA employees or contractors to submit complaints.

Establishes a General Counsel to the NSA Inspector General, to be appointed by the Inspector General.

Requires the General Counsel to prescribe professional rules of ethics and responsibilities for NSA employees, officers, and contractors.

 Authorizes the Inspector General, after providing the Attorney General (DOJ) with seven days' advance notice, to subpoena the attendance and testimony of former NSA employees or NSA contractors, former contractors, or former detailees.

Requires the Inspector General to provide Congress with an evaluation of any notice or statement of reasons the Inspector General receives from the Secretary of Defense (DOD) regarding the Secretary's exercise of authority in the interest of national security to prohibit the Inspector General from initiating, carrying out, or completing any audit or investigation.

Directs the Inspector General, in carrying out any audit or investigation of a surveillance or data collection program, to assess the impact of such program on civil rights and liberties.

Requires the Inspector General's reports to Congress to be made available to all Members of Congress.

Directs the Inspector General to audit and report to Congress regarding the effectiveness and use (including improper or illegal use) of NSA surveillance and data collection programs, including programs under the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (FISA) that authorize: (1) the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) to submit applications to the FISA court for an order requiring the production of tangible things (commonly referred to as business records, including books, records, papers, documents, and other items); and (2) the Attorney General and the Director of National Intelligence (DNI), with the approval of the FISA court or under exigent circumstances, to authorize the targeting of persons located outside the United States.

Requires such audit to address: (1) the interactions between the NSA and the FISA court, and (2) the process for conducting background investigations of persons for NSA employment or for receiving access to classified information.</summary>
</bill>
