<bill session="113" type="h" number="3532" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-11-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-11-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-11-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Student Athletes From Concussions Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To promote State requirements for local educational agencies and public elementary and secondary schools relating to the prevention and treatment of concussions suffered by students.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400031"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2014-01-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="2014-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="2014-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="2013-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2014-01-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412585" joined="2014-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412308" joined="2014-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412219" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="2014-02-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-11-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="5324"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1546"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2718"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="School athletics"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/19/2013--Introduced.
Protecting Student Athletes from Concussions Act of 2013 - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA) to condition each state's receipt of ESEA funds, beginning in FY2015, on the state having in effect and enforcing a law or regulation that meets the minimum requirements for the prevention and treatment of concussions set forth in this Act.

Requires each local educational agency in the state to develop and implement a standard plan for concussion safety and management for its public schools that includes: (1) the education of students, parents, and school personnel about concussions through specified activities; (2) specified supports for each student recovering from a concussion; and (3) specified best practices designed to ensure the uniformity of safety standards, treatment, and management.

Requires each public school to post on school grounds and make publicly available on the school website specified information on concussions.

Provides that if any public school personnel suspects that a student has sustained a concussion during a school-sponsored activity: (1) the student is to be immediately removed from participation in that activity and prohibited from participating in school-sponsored athletic activities until the student submits a written release from a health care professional; and (2) that individual is to report all available information regarding the student's injury to a concussion management team that will then confirm and report to the student's parents the date, time, and type of the injury suffered by the student and any actions taken to treat the student.

Requires each concussion management team to include a health care professional, the student's parents, other relevant school personnel, and an individual assigned by the public school to oversee and manage the students' recovery.

Requires the school's concussion management team to consult with and make recommendations to relevant school personnel and the student to ensure that the student is receiving the appropriate academic supports, including: (1) periods of cognitive rest over the course of the school day, (2) modified academic assignments, (3) gradual reintroduction to cognitive demands, and (4) other appropriate academic accommodations or adjustments.</summary>
</bill>
