<bill session="113" type="h" number="4441" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-04-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-04-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Pipeline Jobs and Safety Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require pipelines regulated by the Secretary of Transportation to be made of steel that is produced in the United States and originates from iron ore and taconite mined and processed in the United States, for safety, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="408211"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-09">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-09">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW14" subcommittee="Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF17" subcommittee="Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Buy American requirements"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/9/2014--Introduced.
American Pipeline Jobs and Safety Act of 2014 - Directs the Secretary of Transportation (DOT) to prescribe minimum safety standards to require gas or hazardous liquid pipelines constructed or replaced after enactment of this Act to be made of steel that: (1) is produced in the United States, and (2) originates from (or in the case of recycled steel is combined with) iron ore and taconite mined and processed in the United States (Buy America requirements).

Authorizes the Secretary to waive such requirements if certain conditions are met.

Requires DOT inspection and testing of intrastate gas pipelines not covered by a state pipeline safety program certification or a state pipeline safety agreement to include direct, pre-installation testing of such pipelines for quality verification.</summary>
</bill>
