<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="H1F99433FBEC04E0A9EBCF0A5C411974E" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Received-in-Senate" resolution-type="house-concurrent" stage-count="1" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HCON 125 : Providing for the sine die adjournment of the second session of the One Hundred Thirteenth Congress.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. CON. RES. 125</legis-num>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action><action-date>December 12, 2014</action-date><action-desc>Received</action-desc></action><legis-type>CONCURRENT RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Providing for the sine die adjournment of the second session of the One Hundred Thirteenth
			 Congress.</official-title>
	</form>
	<resolution-body id="HFE847FC83687426BB455F8565A00161F" style="traditional">
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HC7C3AB9122724B52AEF2BE981CF94B40" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That when the House adjourns on any legislative day from Friday, December 12, 2014, through
			 Wednesday, December 31, 2014, on a motion offered pursuant to this
			 concurrent resolution by its Majority Leader or his designee, it stand
			 adjourned until 1 p.m. on Friday, January 2, 2015, or until the time of
			 any reassembly pursuant to section 2 of this concurrent resolution,
			 whichever occurs first; and that when the House adjourns on the
			 legislative day of Friday, January 2, 2015, on a motion offered pursuant
			 to this concurrent resolution by its Majority Leader or his designee, it
			 stand adjourned sine die, or until the time of any reassembly pursuant to
			 section 2 of this concurrent resolution, whichever occurs first; and that
			 when the Senate recesses or adjourns on any day from Friday, December 12,
			 2014, through Friday, January 2, 2015, on a motion offered pursuant to
			 this concurrent resolution by its Majority Leader or his designee, it
			 stand adjourned sine die, or until the time of any reassembly pursuant to
			 section 3 of this concurrent resolution, whichever occurs first.</text>
		</section><section id="H77D755CF2F72438984D0D55B623B670A"><enum>2.</enum>
			<subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H49A95CA120F545DD934F0C6A072F8AD3"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Speaker or his designee, after consultation with the Minority Leader of the House, shall notify
			 Members of the House to reassemble at such place and time as he may
			 designate if, in his opinion, the public interest shall warrant it.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H0343D6C794394CBB8A83F8F6C4630797"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After reassembling pursuant to subsection (a), when the House adjourns on a motion offered pursuant
			 to this subsection by its Majority Leader or his designee, the House shall
			 again stand adjourned pursuant to the first section of this concurrent
			 resolution.</text>
			</subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5B4CA4A99DF7407FBE478E6B744C8FC8"><enum>3.</enum>
			<subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H88B1BE2976AF4854885EA708C3B96B20"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Majority Leader of the Senate or his designee, after concurrence with the Minority Leader of
			 the Senate, shall notify the Members of the Senate to reassemble at such
			 place and time as he may designate if, in his opinion, the public interest
			 shall warrant it.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HECDC4C597B074A2997EF9BF515DAFE39"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After reassembling pursuant to subsection (a), when the Senate adjourns on a motion offered
			 pursuant to this subsection by its Majority Leader or his designee, the
			 Senate shall again stand adjourned pursuant to the first section of this
			 concurrent resolution.</text>
			</subsection></section></resolution-body>
	<attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date chamber="House" date="20141212">Passed the House of Representatives December 12, 2014.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation>
</resolution>


