<bill session="113" type="h" number="4498" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Legitimate Use of Medicinal Marijuana Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">LUMMA</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the legitimate use of medicinal marijuana in accordance with the laws of the various States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412485"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2014-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2014-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412521" joined="2014-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2014-05-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Alternative treatments"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/28/2014--Introduced.
Legitimate Use of Medical Marijuana Act or the LUMMA -&#160;Transfers marijuana from schedule I to schedule II of the Controlled Substances Act (CSA).

Provides that in a state in which marijuana may be prescribed for medical use under state law, no provision of the CSA or of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act shall prohibit or otherwise restrict: (1) the prescription of marijuana for medical use; (2) an authorized patient from obtaining, possessing, transporting, or using marijuana for that individual's medical use; (3) an individual from obtaining, possessing, transporting, or manufacturing marijuana pursuant to an authorization under state law; (4) a pharmacy or other entity authorized under state law to distribute medical marijuana to an authorized patient for medical use from obtaining, possessing, or distributing marijuana for that purpose; or (5) an entity authorized by such state from producing, processing, or distributing marijuana for&#160; prescribed medical use.</summary>
</bill>
