<bill session="113" type="sj" number="47" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-12-13">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-12-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-12-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Authorization for the Use of Military Force against the Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">An original joint resolution to authorize the limited use of the United States Armed Forces against the Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400272"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-12-13">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Menendez with a preamble. With written report No. 113-323. Minority views filed.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-12-13" state="REPORTED" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="653">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 653.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="sj" number="42"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/13/2014--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Authorization for the Use of Military Force against the Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant - Authorizes the President to use the U.S. Armed Forces against the Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant (ISIL) or associated persons or forces.

Declares that this resolution is intended to constitute specific statutory authorization pursuant to section 5(b) of the War Powers Resolution.

States that the authority granted by this resolution does not authorize use of the U.S. Armed Forces for ground combat operations except as necessary:

 for the protection or rescue of U.S. Armed Forces members or U.S. citizens from imminent danger posed by ISIL; or to conduct missions not intended to result in ground combat operations by U.S. forces, such as intelligence collection and sharing, enabling kinetic strikes, operational planning, or other forms of advice and assistance to forces fighting ISIL in Iraq or Syria. Terminates such military use authorization in three years.</summary>
</bill>
