<bill session="113" type="h" number="5249" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rosoboronexport Embargo Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To re-impose sanctions on Russian arms exporter Rosoboronexport, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400283"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412258" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400077" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="2014-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412524" joined="2014-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412282" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="2014-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412435" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412421" joined="2014-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400233" joined="2014-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Government Reform, and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-29">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-29">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-29">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="Ukraine"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/29/2014--Introduced.
Rosoboronexport Embargo Act of 2014 - Prohibits the head of an executive agency from entering into a contract, memorandum of understanding, or cooperative agreement with, or make a grant to, or provide a loan or loan agreement to Rosoboronexport (the state intermediary agency for Russia's exports/imports of defense-related and dual use products, technologies, and services).

Authorizes the President to: (1) waive such prohibition under specified circumstances, and (2) reprogram funds for a country that enters into any such arrangement with Rosoboronexport.

Prohibits any U.S. person (individual or corporation) from assisting Rosoboronexport through the provision of financing. Imposes a ban on dealing in government finance and restrictions on U.S. business operations on a person that engages in such activity.

Authorizes: (1) the President to waive the application of sanctions under specified circumstances, and (2) the Attorney General (DOJ) to bring an action in U.S. district court for injunctive and other relief with respect to such activities.

Imposes procurement and export sanctions on any U.S. person that transfers goods or technology, enters into contracts, or engages in trade with Rosoboronexport.

Directs the Secretary of Defense (DOD) to report to Congress regarding: (1) transfers of lethal military equipment by Rosoboronexport to separatist groups in Ukraine and to the government of Syria; and (2) contracts, memorandums of understanding, cooperative agreements, grants, and loans and loan guarantees between DOD and Rosoboronexport.</summary>
</bill>
