<bill session="113" type="sr" number="500" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-23">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-07-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate with respect to enhanced relations with the Republic of Moldova and support for the Republic of Moldova's territorial integrity.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412323"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2014-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2014-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="2014-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2014-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412194" joined="2014-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412491" joined="2014-07-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4417-4418" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-07-16" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-07-16">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Menendez without amendment and with a preamble. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-07-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="470">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 470.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="2014-07-23" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>Resolution agreed to in Senate without amendment and with a preamble by Voice Vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4845" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hr" number="562"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="sr" number="478"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="European Union"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="International exchange and broadcasting"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Moldova"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
    <term name="Ukraine"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/23/2014--Passed Senate without amendment.
Reaffirms that it is U.S. policy to support the Republic of Moldova's sovereignty, independence, and territorial integrity.

 Supports the Strategic Dialogue as a means to strengthen relations between the Republic of Moldova and the United States and enhance the democratic, economic, rule of law, and security reforms being implemented by the Republic of Moldova.

 Encourages: (1) the President and the Department of State to enhance U.S. cooperation with the government of Moldova and civil society organizations, and (2) the President to expedite implementation of the Act relating to "United States International Programming to Ukraine and Neighboring Regions."

Urges the President to consider increasing security and intelligence cooperation with Moldova.

Supports increased U.S.-Moldova educational exchanges.

Affirms the Republic of Moldova's sovereign right to determine its own partnerships free of external coercion and affirms Moldova's right to associate with the European Union (EU) or any regional organization.

Urges the EU to continue to work for greater political, economic, and social integration with the Republic of Moldova.

Calls upon the government of Russia to: (1) withdraw its military forces from within the internationally recognized territory of the Republic of Moldova, (2) refrain from economic coercion, and (3) cease actions that support separatist movements in Moldova.

Supports confidence-building measures between the government of Moldova and the authorities in the Transnistria region in order to secure a peaceful resolution to the conflict.

 Affirms that lasting stability and security in Europe is a key U.S. priority that can only be achieved if the territorial integrity and sovereignty of all European countries are respected.</summary>
</bill>
