<bill session="113" type="s" number="1888" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-12-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-12-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-12-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Inyo National Forest Land Exchange Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to facilitate a land exchange involving certain National Forest System land in the Inyo National Forest, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300043"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-12-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9106-9107"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9107" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-30">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on Public Lands, Forests, and Mining. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 113-433.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG03" subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1241"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/20/2013--Introduced.
Inyo National Forest Land Exchange Act - Authorizes the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA), in any land exchange involving the conveyance of certain National Forest System (NFS) land within the boundaries of Inyo National Forest in California, to accept the conveyance of certain non-federal land in California outside the Forest boundaries in exchange for the conveyance of the federal land, if acquiring the non-federal land is desirable for NSF purposes.

Authorizes the Secretary to accept a cash equalization payment exceeding 25% of the value of the federal land. Requires the deposit of any such payment into the fund established under the Sisk Act and made available for the acquisition of lands or interests for addition to the NFS.</summary>
</bill>
