<bill session="113" type="h" number="5781" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-12-09T13:53:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-12-09T13:53:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-12-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">California Emergency Drought Relief Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">California Emergency Drought Relief Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide short-term water supplies to drought-stricken California.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412515"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="2014-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412513" joined="2014-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400618" joined="2014-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412510" joined="2014-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412190" joined="2014-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412295" joined="2014-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400297" joined="2014-12-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-12-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-08T14:08:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 770.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8826-8840" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-08T14:08:00-05:00">
      <text>Resolution provides for consideration of the Senate amendment to H.R. 3979; consideration of the bill H.R. 5759; and consideration of the bill H.R. 5781.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-08T14:08:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 770, the House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 5781.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-08T15:12:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8840" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-08T15:13:00-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - The Chair announced that, pursuant to clause 1(c), rule XIX, further proceedings on H.R. 5781 would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-09T13:07:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8886-8889" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-09T13:07:00-05:00">
      <text>Pursuant to clause 1(c) of rule 19, further proceedings on H.R. 5781 were resumed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-09T13:07:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Miller, George moved to recommit with instructions to the Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8886-8888" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H8886" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-09T13:07:00-05:00">
      <text>Floor summary: DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the George Miller (CA) motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to ensure that nothing in the underlying legislation would: (1) adversely affect the commercial or sport fishing industries of California, Oregon, or Washington state or any population of west coast salmon; (2) create any legal precedent for any state other than California on water rights; or (3) undermine Native American tribal sovereignty, or reduce the quantity or quality of the water available by affected Indian tribes.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-09T13:16:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8887-8888" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-09T13:45:00-05:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 182 - 228 (Roll no. 552).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="553" datetime="2014-12-09T13:53:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 230 - 182 (Roll no. 553).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 12/08/2014 H8826-8829" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-12-09T13:53:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-10">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hr" number="770"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h1154"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>12/2/2014--Introduced.
California Emergency Drought Relief Act of 2014 - Title I: California Emergency Drought Relief - Grants the Secretaries of Commerce and the Interior (Secretaries) emergency authority, subject to existing water rights, to direct the operations of the Central Valley Project (CVP) and allow the State Water Project (SWP) operated by the California Department of Water Resources to provide the maximum quantity of water supplies possible to CVP agricultural, municipal and industrial, and refuge service repayment contractors and SWP contractors, by allowing, consistent with applicable laws, any projects or operations to: (1) provide additional water supplies; and (2) as quickly as possible, based on available information, address the emergency drought conditions.

Grants the applicable Secretary authority to take certain actions to increase the water supply, subject to specified environmental protections, including:

 ensuring that the Delta Cross Channel Gates remain open to the maximum extent practicable; implementing turbidity control strategies to increase water deliveries and minimize water supply reductions for the CVP and the SWP; adopting a 1:1 inflow to export ratio for the increment of increased flow of the San Joaquin River; issuing all necessary permit decisions within 30 days of receiving a completed application by the state of California to place and use temporary barriers or operable gates in Delta channels to improve water quantity and quality; completing all requirements under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (NEPA) necessary to make final permit decisions on water transfer requests within 30 days of receiving such requests; allowing any North of Delta agricultural water service contractor with unused CVP water to take delivery of unused water through April 15 following the contract year in which such water was allocated; and implementing instream and offsite projects in the Delta and upstream in the Sacramento River and San Joaquin basins that offset the effects on threatened species under the Endangered Species Act of 1973 due to actions taken under this Act. Directs federal agency heads to use the expedited procedures of this Act to make final decisions relating to a federal project or operation to provide additional water supplies or to address emergency drought conditions.

Directs the Secretaries to authorize the CVP and the SWP, combined, to operate at levels that result in negative Old and Middle River flows for a cumulative period of 28 days during certain high-flow conditions on the Sacramento River.

Title II: Protection Of Third-Party Water Rights - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to confer with the California Department of Fish and Wildlife on potential impacts to any consistency determination for operations of the SWP resulting from the implementation of this Act.

Requires the Secretary, in the operation of the CVP, to: (1) adhere to California laws governing water rights priorities and honor water rights senior to those held by the United States for operation of the CVP, regardless of the source of priority; and (2) allocate water provided for irrigation purposes to existing CVP agricultural water service contractors within the Sacramento River Watershed (i.e., water service contractors within the Shasta, Trinity, and Sacramento River Diversions of the CVP) in compliance with specified requirements.

Requires the Secretary to ensure that actions taken to comply with environmental laws do not: (1) result in the involuntary reduction of water supply or fiscal impacts to recipients of water from either the SWP or the United States, or (2) cause redirected adverse water supply or fiscal impacts to those within the Sacramento River or San Joaquin River watersheds or the SWP service area.

Requires the Secretary to direct the Bureau of Reclamation to develop and implement a program to enable existing CVP agricultural water service contractors within the Sacramento River Watershed to reschedule water from one year to the next.

Title III: Miscellaneous Provisions - Declares that nothing in this Act preempts or modifies any existing obligation of the United States under federal reclamation law to operate the CVP in conformity with state law, including established water rights priorities. Terminates this Act on the later of September 30, 2016, or the date on which the governor of California suspends the state of drought emergency declaration.</summary>
</bill>
