<bill session="113" type="h" number="3715" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-12-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-12-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-12-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Personal Drug Importation Fairness Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reduce prescription drug costs by allowing the importation and reimportation of certain drugs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412215"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400343" joined="2013-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2013-12-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-12-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/12/2013--Introduced.
Personal Drug Importation Fairness Act of 2013 - Allows a drug to be imported into the United States, and re-imported into the United States by a person other than the drug's manufacturer, if the drug: (1) has the same active ingredients, route of administration, and strength as a prescription drug approved under provisions of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (FFDCA) regarding adulterated drugs; (2) may be lawfully marketed in, and is imported or reimported from, a qualified country; (3) is dispensed by a licensed pharmacist; (4) is shipped directly to, or is imported by, the ultimate consumer from the qualified country; (5) is shipped or imported in quantities that do not exceed a 90-day supply; and (6) is accompanied by a copy of a valid prescription.

Defines: (1) "drug" for purposes of this Act as excluding any controlled substance; and (2) "qualified country" to mean any of specified countries (Australia, Canada, Israel, Japan, New Zealand, Switzerland, South Africa, a member-state of the European Union, or a country in the European Economic Area) that is determined by the Commissioner of Food and Drugs (FDA) to have standards for ensuring drug safety and effectiveness that are at least as protective as U.S. standards.</summary>
</bill>
