<bill session="113" type="s" number="2903" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SPOT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strengthening Privacy, Oversight, and Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reform the Privacy and Civil Liberties Oversight Board, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300100"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400413" joined="2014-09-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="5595"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Privacy and Civil Liberties Oversight Board"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Specialized courts"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/18/2014--Introduced.
Strengthening Privacy, Oversight, and Transparency Act or the SPOT Act - Amends the Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2004 to expand the functions of the Privacy and Civil Liberties Oversight Board to include reviews of legislation, regulations, policies, and executive branch actions relating to foreign intelligence.

Allows intelligence community employees, contractors, or detailees to submit to the Board a whistleblower complaint or information believed to be related to a privacy or civil liberties concern. Permits the Board to: (1) investigate such complaints, or (2) transmit such complaints to any other executive agency or the congressional intelligence committees.

Authorizes the Board to subpoena persons (other than agencies and elements of the executive branch) to produce documentary or testimonial evidence. (Currently, the Board submits a request for the Attorney General to issue a subpoena.)

Permits the Board, at the direction of the majority of its members, to exercise the authority of the Board chairman to appoint and fix compensation of Board staff when the position of chairman is vacant.

Provides for members of the Board to serve in a full-time capacity. Removes exceptions to the requirement that members continue to serve after the expiration of their term of office until a successor has been appointed and qualified. Revises the compensation of the Board chairman, members, and staff.

Directs the Attorney General to fully inform the Board about government activities under the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (FISA), including by providing to the Board copies of: (1) FISA reports submitted to Congress; and (2) FISA court decisions, orders, and opinions that include significant construction or interpretation of FISA.</summary>
</bill>
