<bill session="113" type="s" number="2711" updated="2015-09-01T17:51:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">United States Commission on International Religious Freedom Reform and Reauthorization Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reauthorize the United States Commission on International Religious Freedom, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300038"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-30">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5143-5144"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5144-5145" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4653"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="U.S. Commission on International Religious Freedom"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/2014--Introduced.
United States Commission on International Religious Freedom Reform and Reauthorization Act of 2014 - Amends the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998 to reauthorize the U.S. Commission on International Religious Freedom through September 30, 2016.

Directs the Commission, during an initial election, to elect: (1) as Chair a Commissioner appointed by an elected official of the political party that is not the political party of the President, and (2) as Vice Chair a Commissioner appointed by an elected official of the political party of the President. Sets forth a process for future elections in which the positions of Chair and Vice Chair rotate annually between Commissioners appointed by elected officials of each political party.

Requires the Ambassador at Large to be notified in advance of all Commission meetings. Allows the Ambassador to attend all meetings as a nonvoting member.

Removes authority under which a Commission member may serve after the expiration of that member's term until a successor has taken office.

Requires approval by at least six of the nine members of the Commission before: (1) issuance of a statement on behalf of the Commission, or (2) submittal of policy recommendation reports to the President, the Secretary of State, and Congress. Permits each member to include individual or dissenting views.

Authorizes elected officials to appoint majority and minority staff directors for the Commission, as well as professional staff for the political parties. (Currently, the Commission appoints a single executive director and is served by nonpartisan staff.)</summary>
</bill>
