<bill session="113" type="sr" number="355" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-02-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-02-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-02-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution calling on the Government of the Islamic Republic of Afghanistan to cease the extra-judicial release of Afghan detainees, carry out its commitments pursuant to the Memorandum of Understanding governing the transfer of Afghan detainees from the United States custody to Afghan control and to uphold the Afghan Rule of Law with respect to the referral and disposition of detainees.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300047"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412493" joined="2014-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2014-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2014-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="2014-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412573" joined="2014-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412205" joined="2014-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2014-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="2014-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412391" joined="2014-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="2014-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="2014-03-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-02-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S957" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/12/2014--Introduced.
Insists that President of Afghanistan Hamid Karzai honor the March 2013 Memorandum of Understanding governing the transfer of Afghan detainees from U.S. custody to Afghan control.

Insists that, if the Afghan Review Board (ARB) will not follow the conditions of the Memorandum, the ARB shall be dismantled and the National Directorate for Security and Afghan prosecutors shall determine how to handle the remaining detainees.

Urges Afghanistan to cease the extra-judicial release of detainees.

 Calls on the Secretary of State to consider Afghanistan's adherence to existing detainee memoranda of understanding in implementing certification requirements for certain assistance for Afghanistan.</summary>
</bill>
