<bill session="113" type="h" number="4879" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Research for All Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to provide for expedited review of drugs and biological products to provide safer or more effective treatment for males or females, to amend the Public Health Service Act to enhance the consideration of sex differences in basic and clinical research, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400081"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2014-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412535" joined="2014-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2014-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2014-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2014-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="2014-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412294" joined="2014-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2014-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2014-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412489" joined="2014-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2014-07-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="2014-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400422" joined="2014-12-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Food and Drug Administration (FDA)"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="National Institutes of Health (NIH)"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/17/2014--Introduced.
Research for All Act of 2014 - Directs the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) to review and develop policies to ensure that the design and size of clinical trials for products granted expedited approval to treat a serious or life-threatening disease or condition are sufficient to determine the safety and effectiveness of the products for men and women using subgroup analysis.

Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to require FDA, at the request of the sponsor of a new drug, to facilitate the development and expedite its review if the drug is:

 intended to avoid serious adverse events or to treat a serious or life-threatening disease or condition, intended for safer or more effective treatment for either men or women than a currently available product approved to treat the general population or the other sex, and supported by results of clinical trials that include and separately examine outcomes for men and women. Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to determine when it is appropriate for projects of basic research involving cells, tissues, or animals to include both male and female cells, tissues, or animals. Requires, in such cases, disaggregation of results according to sex. Provides guidelines for ensuring that sex differences are examined and analyzed.

Authorizes the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to support the continued operation and expansion of Special Centers of Research on Sex Differences.

Requires the Comptroller General (GAO) to provide to Congress updated versions of the reports entitled &#8220;Women's Health: NIH Has Increased Its Efforts To Include Women in Research&#8221; and &#8220;Women's Health: Women Sufficiently Represented in New Drug Testing, But FDA Oversight Needs Improvement,&#8221; including in the reports examination of:

 the inclusion of women, female animals, and female-derived cells and tissues in federally funded research over the past decade; federal reporting and analysis of subgroup information and the translation of differences to the medical community and patients; the effect of inclusion rates in research on the quality of women&#8217;s health care; and current efforts within government agencies to encourage the sharing of research data on sex differences and mechanisms to improve such sharing.</summary>
</bill>
