<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 S2448 IS: Servicemember Higher Education Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2014-06-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 2448</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20140605">June 5, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S320">Mrs. Hagan</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To protect servicemembers in higher education, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body><section id="id25012B5D4A674A14AD55949B6DCCC5FD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Servicemember Higher Education Protection Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="id0BAD0ECC704D48D29F495058F7956683">
			<enum>2.</enum>
			<header>References</header>
			<text display-inline="no-display-inline">Except as otherwise expressly provided, wherever in this Act an amendment or repeal is expressed in
			 terms of an amendment to, or repeal of, a section or other provision, the
			 reference shall be considered to be made to a section or other provision
			 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
		</section><section id="id5FF6D6D69BA14BBCA2CC8002AD222476">
			<enum>3.</enum>
			<header>Benefits for borrowers who are members of the Armed Forces</header>
			<text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 131(f) is amended to read as
			 follows:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0861D39BB7A94CBDA26C4646802FB6BA" style="OLC">
				<subsection id="id120B1E5654E54472BD90CC9EA65A5FDA">
					<enum>(f)</enum>
					<header>Benefits for members of the Armed Forces</header>
					<paragraph id="id2732FCDB5B894501BED7037653510AE0">
						<enum>(1)</enum>
						<header>Website</header>
						<subparagraph id="id379626C191AB4AAF94231C1BD99DCE8F">
							<enum>(A)</enum>
							<header>In General</header>
							<text>The Secretary, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs,
			 shall create a revised and updated searchable Internet website that—</text>
							<clause id="id4B12A4E5716B4498BD9E756E4E7A7C7A">
								<enum>(i)</enum>
								<text>contains information, in simple and understandable terms, about all Federal and State student
			 financial assistance, readmission requirements under section 484C, and
			 other student services, for which members of the Armed Forces (including
			 members of the National Guard and Reserves), veterans, and the dependents
			 of such members or veterans may be eligible; and</text>
							</clause><clause id="id7BCE120D0C6A400B8649F4F647F9DB3E">
								<enum>(ii)</enum>
								<text>is easily accessible through the Internet website described in subsection (e)(3).</text>
							</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0E9EBF6BF49B4B1ABFA12677BB6AB6CF">
							<enum>(B)</enum>
							<header>Implementation</header>
							<text>Not later than 365 days after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Servicemember Higher Education Protection Act</short-title>, the Secretary shall make publicly available the revised and updated Internet
			 website described in
			 subparagraph (A).</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA896766D8CE14A1A9C0067C24FD58B60">
							<enum>(C)</enum>
							<header>Dissemination</header>
							<text>The Secretary, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs,
			 shall make the availability of the Internet website
			 described in subparagraph (A) widely known to members of the Armed Forces
			 (including members of the National Guard and Reserves), veterans, the
			 dependents of such members or veterans, States, institutions of higher
			 education, and the general public.</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6D47D327F686438E910A0CD058ADFE32">
							<enum>(D)</enum>
							<header>Definition</header>
							<text>In this paragraph, the term <term>Federal and State student financial assistance</term> means any grant, loan, work assistance, tuition assistance, scholarship, fellowship, or other form
			 of financial aid for pursuing a postsecondary education that is—</text>
							<clause id="ID6505E0A527B54DB591E73AEAC742FD10">
								<enum>(i)</enum>
								<text>administered, sponsored, or supported by the Department of Education, the Department of Defense,
			 the Department of Veterans Affairs, or a State; and</text>
							</clause><clause id="IDE0FE8D5327BF4327AF5F55C85BEC35F8">
								<enum>(ii)</enum>
								<text>available to members of the Armed Forces (including members of the National Guard and Reserves),
			 veterans, or the dependents of such members or veterans.</text>
							</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id688F470F2CD64D17AB71B4C21B434C45">
						<enum>(2)</enum>
						<header>Enrollment Form</header>
						<subparagraph id="idA69A1EC28D5D4745982CFA3A6AD2B4D8">
							<enum>(A)</enum>
							<header>In General</header>
							<text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection
			 and the heads of any other relevant Federal agencies, shall create a
			 simplified disclosure and enrollment form for borrowers who are performing
			 eligible military service (as defined in section 481(d)).</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="id405279C2D0D24E9889A1404D22577B5E">
							<enum>(B)</enum>
							<header>Contents</header>
							<text>The disclosure and enrollment form described in subparagraph (A) shall include—</text>
							<clause id="id1DAEFFC0B8B742589A03366391C9FAB2">
								<enum>(i)</enum>
								<text>information about the benefits and protections under title IV and under the Servicemembers Civil
			 Relief Act (50 U.S.C. App. 501 et seq.) that are available to such
			 borrowers because of their status as borrowers who are performing eligible
			 military service (as defined in section 481(d)); and</text></clause><clause id="idA820451B971F46989EC2F0E39E0DD09A">
								<enum>(ii)</enum>
								<text>an opportunity for the borrower, by completing the enrollment form, to invoke certain protections,
			 activate certain benefits, and enroll in certain programs that may be
			 available to that borrower, which shall include the opportunity—</text>
								<subclause id="idEA7F612EA1A14E459E5ED9D28C765FD2">
									<enum>(I)</enum>
									<text>to invoke applicable  protections that are available under the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act
			 (50 U.S.C.
			 App. 501 et seq.), as such protections relate to Federal student loans
			 under title IV; and</text>
								</subclause><subclause id="idC1F17A27AF0B42289CC9DC14A63AB454">
									<enum>(II)</enum>
									<text>to activate or enroll in any other applicable benefits that are available to such borrower under
			 this Act due to the borrower's status as a borrower who is performing
			 eligible military service (as defined in section 481(d)), such as
			 eligibility for a deferment or
			 eligibility for a period during which interest shall not accrue.</text>
								</subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id618E6403A8634D5DB1732082D56D932C">
							<enum>(C)</enum>
							<header>Implementation</header>
							<text>Not later than 365 days after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Servicemember Higher Education Protection Act</short-title>, the Secretary shall make available to eligible institutions, eligible lenders, and personnel at
			 the Department of Defense and other Federal agencies that provide services
			 to borrowers who are members of the Armed Forces or the
			 dependents of such members or individuals performing eligible military
			 service, the disclosure and  enrollment form
			 described in subparagraph (A).</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="id34300522B42D4DE29F4C3043E81C48F5">
							<enum>(D)</enum>
							<header>Notice Requirements</header>
							<clause id="id97E3A6F7454D4ED7AF291626FA67277F">
								<enum>(i)</enum>
								<header>SCRA interest rate limitation</header>
								<text>The completion of the disclosure and enrollment form created pursuant to subparagraph (A) by the
			 borrower of a loan made, insured, or guaranteed under part B or part D of 
			 title IV who is otherwise subject to the interest rate limitation in
			 subsection (a) of section 207 of the
			 Servicemembers Civil Relief Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc-appendix" parsable-cite="usc-appendix/50/527">50 U.S.C. App. 527(a)</external-xref>) and submittal of
			 such form to the Secretary shall be considered, for purposes of such
			 section, provision to the creditor of written notice as described in
			 subsection (b)(1) of such section.</text>
							</clause><clause id="idE0BF6E2FA8EA4B03BDB045631A0FE368">
								<enum>(ii)</enum>
								<header>FFEL Lenders</header>
								<text>The Secretary shall provide each such disclosure and  enrollment form completed and submitted by a
			 borrower of a loan made, insured, or guaranteed under part B of title IV
			 who is otherwise subject to the interest rate limitation in subsection (a)
			 of section 207 of the
			 Servicemembers Civil Relief Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc-appendix" parsable-cite="usc-appendix/50/527">50 U.S.C. App. 527(a)</external-xref>) to any applicable
			 eligible lender under part B of title IV so as to satisfy the provision to
			 the lender of written notice as described in subsection (b)(1) of such
			 section.</text>
							</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="idAA34685ED0024B629CB50F61A4BA683D">
			<enum>4.</enum>
			<header>POC in the FSA Ombudsman for members of the Armed Forces and veterans</header>
			<text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 141(f) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1018">20 U.S.C. 1018(f)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
			<paragraph id="id878BCE8515724D2EBCB6AA25A6B7DB3F">
				<enum>(1)</enum>
				<text>by redesignating paragraph (4) as paragraph (5);  and</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="id12160AAEA8AF4823A1FCED63CA1BB6F9">
				<enum>(2)</enum>
				<text>by inserting after paragraph (3) the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id303BB8ECD1A046DD92E0A37E0009D13E" style="OLC">
					<paragraph id="idf536dd71bc1d442cb3c7f06f57597979">
						<enum>(4)</enum>
						<header>Military and Veteran Point of Contact</header>
						<subparagraph id="idc3f45b277275432b86f4efcd28163ff9">
							<enum>(A)</enum>
							<header>In general</header>
							<text>The Chief Operating Officer, in consultation with the Secretary, shall appoint a designated
			 military and veteran point of contact within the office of the Student
			 Loan Ombudsman.</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7C729AB48E584F09A5E47BC407B1BC3C">
							<enum>(B)</enum>
							<header>Functions</header>
							<text>The designated military and veteran point of contact described in subparagraph (A)  shall—</text>
							<clause id="id9f0c6696aec04d7bbec7e061e9850ced">
								<enum>(i)</enum>
								<text>monitor the complaints received from the Ombudsman under paragraph (3)(A)  from, and provide timely
			 assistance to, members of
			 the Armed Forces (including members of the National Guard and Reserves),
			 veterans, and their dependents;</text>
							</clause><clause id="id1166e3be744647c59b6629c3d61676bd">
								<enum>(ii)</enum>
								<text>coordinate with other agencies, including the Department of Defense, the Department of Veterans
			 Affairs, and the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, to ensure that
			 members of the Armed Forces, veterans,  and the dependents of members of
			 the Armed Forces and
			 veterans, who are students, borrowers, or potential borrowers, are aware
			 of the availability and functions of the Ombudsman;  and</text>
							</clause><clause id="idb3cfa84548f149b8bb76c2c9fa272f8c">
								<enum>(iii)</enum>
								<text>issue to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate,  the Committee on
			 Education and the Workforce of the House of Representatives, the Committee
			 on Veterans' Affairs of the Senate, the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of
			 the House of Representatives, the Committee on Armed Services of the
			 Senate, and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of
			 Representatives an annual report on the challenges that such members of
			 the Armed Forces, veterans, and dependents are facing
			 as students, borrowers, and potential borrowers.</text>
							</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section><section id="idBB6A190970234534AEB9144296FB317F">
			<enum>5.</enum>
			<header>Disability determinations</header>
			<subsection id="idE9DA2BBA2AD740A8B82A583DF921E975">
				<enum>(a)</enum>
				<header>Amendment to the Higher Education Act of 1965</header>
				<text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 437(a)(2) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087">20 U.S.C. 1087(a)(2)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD1027FF55C934C64B91218F053A3EB78" style="OLC">
					<paragraph id="id133AF38D111B408BA814AA296C8B0F6D">
						<enum>(2)</enum>
						<header>Disability determinations</header>
						<subparagraph id="idB4F1D81B2EC746E4A20BF2826ECB35E7">
							<enum>(A)</enum>
							<header>In General</header>
							<text>A borrower who has been assigned a disability rating of 100 percent (or a combination of ratings
			 equaling 100 percent or more) by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs or the
			 Secretary of Defense for a service-connected disability (as defined in
			 <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/101">section 101</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code)  and who
			 provides documentation of such rating to the Secretary of
			 Education, shall be considered permanently and totally disabled for the
			 purpose of discharging such borrower's loans under this subsection, and
			 such borrower shall not be required to present any additional
			 documentation for purposes of this subsection.</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6834949C15164EB2AC94DD1112F0FAB7">
							<enum>(B)</enum>
							<header>Rating of disability</header>
							<text>A disability rating described in subparagraph
			 (A), or similar determination of unemployability by the Secretary of
			 Veterans
			 Affairs or the Department of Defense, transmitted in accordance with
			 subparagraph (C) shall be considered sufficient documentation for purposes
			 of this subsection.</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3A6A6C63A78846AE88B57A59803223C8">
							<enum>(C)</enum>
							<header>Transfer of information</header>
							<text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Servicemember Higher Education Protection Act</short-title>, the Secretary, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans
			 Affairs, shall create a system through which the applicable disability
			 ratings (or alternative means of  transmitting a determination of
			 unemployability) shall be automatically transmitted from the Department of
			 Defense or the Department of Veterans Affairs, as the case may be, to the
			 Department of Education and shall satisfy the documentation requirement
			 described in this paragraph.  The Secretary shall have the authority to
			 enter into any agreements necessary to implement the requirements of this
			 paragraph.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="id6EEC0282F33246CBBDFB2191925988DA">
				<enum>(b)</enum>
				<header>Reports</header>
				<paragraph id="id19EFCC915E8742A3A9E46AFE127600C4">
					<enum>(1)</enum>
					<header>Plan</header>
					<text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Education
			 shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report that
			 includes a plan to carry out the activities described under  section
			 437(a)(2)(C) of the Higher Education Act
			 of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087">20 U.S.C. 1087(a)(2)</external-xref>), as amended by this section.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="id9997C913D5E34F85917B70E189DD356F">
					<enum>(2)</enum>
					<header>Follow-up Report</header>
					<text>If the Secretary of Education has not carried out the activities described under section
			 437(a)(2)(C)
			 of the Higher Education Act
			 of 1965, as amended by this section, by the date that is 1 year after the
			 date of
			 enactment of
			 this Act, the Secretary of Education shall submit, by such date, a report
			 that includes an explanation of why those activities have not been
			 implemented and a description of any legislative changes that are
			 necessary to allow for the  implementation of such activities.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id935848ED8B2A43048A31359BA3962F67">
			<enum>6.</enum>
			<header>Loan deferment for borrowers performing military service and certain spouses of members of the
			 Armed Forces</header>
			<subsection id="id4621FFA987FD400091E346C1BFFC5962">
				<enum>(a)</enum>
				<header>FFEL Loans</header>
				<text>Section 428(b)(1)(M) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1078">20 U.S.C. 1078(b)(1)(M)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
				<paragraph id="idEDF80D5EBB3846CDAF5C22065EC41151">
					<enum>(1)</enum>
					<text>by redesignating clause (iv) as clause (v);</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="idBD06777E3D6440648BC498515DE25ACC">
					<enum>(2)</enum>
					<text>in clause (iii), by striking <quote>the borrower—</quote> and all that follows through <quote>described in subclause (I) or (II); or</quote> and inserting <quote>the borrower is performing eligible military service,
			  and for the 180-day period following the demobilization date for such
			 eligible military service;</quote>; and</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="id8D9E4FF148A44BD8A79B8328680D65DC">
					<enum>(3)</enum>
					<text>by inserting after clause (iii) the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id889CA215567349F0BB71113C0D2D32B1" style="OLC">
						<clause id="id44C595DC0D874F12AC1AC44D029BDD01">
							<enum>(iv)</enum>
							<text>not in excess of 180 days after the effective movement date listed on the military orders of a
			 borrower's spouse if that spouse is a member of the Armed Forces who has
			 received military orders for a
			 permanent change of station; or</text>
						</clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7B06A9C7A2A44BB4AB7B8433772BD2A4">
				<enum>(b)</enum>
				<header>Direct Loans</header>
				<text>Section 455(f)(2) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087e">20 U.S.C. 1087e(f)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
				<paragraph id="id854F24ED81DF4B7B8AA20106DDC479DB">
					<enum>(1)</enum>
					<text>by redesignating subparagraph (D) as subparagraph (E);</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="id4FB76EC80C774BBD91D2E2C57A2EDB3E">
					<enum>(2)</enum>
					<text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>the borrower—</quote> and all that follows through <quote>described in clause (i) or (ii); or</quote> and inserting <quote>the borrower is performing eligible military service,	and for the
			 180-day
			 period following the demobilization date for such eligible military
			 service;</quote> and</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="idED98C85A3AF54C3A942F52DAAD5B8305">
					<enum>(3)</enum>
					<text>by inserting after subparagraph (C) the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id409D1492788A4280A8A605490C6DC535" style="OLC">
						<subparagraph id="id4B05CC503C1948FE91C7390B0E03B501">
							<enum>(D)</enum>
							<text>any period not in excess of 180 days after the effective movement date listed on the military
			 orders of a
			 borrower's spouse if that spouse is a member of the Armed Forces who has
			 received military orders for a
			 permanent change of station; or</text>
						</subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idC15EA0959E10421AA741565431433685">
				<enum>(c)</enum>
				<header>Federal Perkins Loans</header>
				<paragraph id="idFF138CC2AF21401E94BCA3676363638E">
					<enum>(1)</enum>
					<text>Section 464(c)(2)(A) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087dd">20 U.S.C. 1087dd(c)(2)(A)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
					<subparagraph id="idCD77985B21D946E3AF4A3B8C7421EA8F">
						<enum>(A)</enum>
						<text>by redesignating clauses (iv) and (v) as clauses (v) and (vi), respectively;</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE803F16282B247D5999A5B38A6EB46F4">
						<enum>(B)</enum>
						<text>in clause (iii), by striking <quote>the borrower—</quote> and all that follows through <quote>described in subclause (I) or (II);</quote> and inserting <quote>during which the borrower is performing eligible military service,
			  and for the 180-day period following the demobilization date for such
			 eligible military service;</quote>; and</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="id85CF1A47615F46DDA26F775651561EB1">
						<enum>(C)</enum>
						<text>by inserting after clause (iii) the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id10EC93934E9A4188AAB6646320AF57F1" style="OLC">
							<clause id="id64F28B8A46C149A9BB5C6AC1CA2A2369" indent="up1">
								<enum>(iv)</enum>
								<text>not in excess of 180 days after the effective movement date listed on the military orders of a
			 borrower's spouse if that spouse is a member of the Armed Forces who has
			 received military orders for a
			 permanent change of station; or</text>
							</clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idDEC6A21343DC4915B5EF003967F86508">
					<enum>(2)</enum>
					<text>Section 465(a)(2)(D) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087ee">20 U.S.C. 1087ee(a)(2)(D)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>qualifies for special pay under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/37/310">section 310</external-xref> of title 37, United States Code, as an area of
			 hostilities</quote> and inserting <quote>is eligible military service</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2ACC9AC9CBCE43D8B62D3D48CA97C903">
				<enum>(d)</enum>
				<header>Definition</header>
				<text>Section 481(d) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1088">20 U.S.C. 1088(d)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="id301A81390DB048D59778E663F0DDC414"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (2) through (5) as paragraphs (3) through (6), respectively; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idB1BE9BD40131473094AC6E52DFF11AA5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (1) the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7BAD0323B30E4B85BBACD98D5181E0AC" style="OLC">
						<paragraph commented="no" id="idDD7CAB99EB644B39B045C76DAFA2F0C8">
							<enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible military service</header><text>The term <term>eligible military service</term>—</text><subparagraph id="idA3FFF9B5EF1142F3983A879FC92E5547"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of a member of a regular component of the Armed Forces, means full-time duty in the
			 Armed Forces, other than active duty for training (as defined in section
			 101 of title 38, United States Code);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id23F3A8466A8C41D0846F3D6132940BC3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of a member of the reserve components of the Armed Forces, means service on active duty
			 under a call or order to active duty under section 688, 12301(a),
			 12301(d), 12301(g), 12302, or 12304 of title 10, United States Code, or
			 <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/14/712">section 712</external-xref> of title 14, United States Code;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4FBCB6C791914AC5835E9950717BB546"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in the case of a member of the Army National Guard of the United States or Air National Guard of
			 the United States, means, in addition to service described in subparagraph
			 (B), full-time service—</text><clause id="id81CE7D5B98FF4132B7721697CAACD0C9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the National Guard of a State for the purpose of organizing, administering, recruiting,
			 instructing, or training the National Guard; or</text></clause><clause id="idE3C22F5AB52548409981B5E940E68D4B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the National Guard under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/32/502">section 502(f)</external-xref> of title 32, United States Code, when authorized by the
			 President or the
			 Secretary of Defense for the purpose of responding to a national emergency
			 declared by the President and supported by Federal funds;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA5D2A1747D8D4867A762045AD482B256"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in the case of a servicemember who is a commissioned officer of the Public Health Service or the
			 National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, active service; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1996DE81D4CD4B34BDFC9C5EF8A8A0AF"><enum>(E)</enum><text>does not include any period during which an individual—</text><clause id="id7456A527D8AD45D1AFF0AE83D6793271"><enum>(i)</enum><text>was assigned full-time by the Armed Forces to a civilian institution for a course of education that
			 was substantially the same as established courses offered to civilians;</text></clause><clause id="id6D519618491F4E26A859FD2F5B51427B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>serves as a cadet or midshipman at one of the military service academies of the United States; or</text></clause><clause id="idB1577C0DF8134AD6A6FCA8B12808B35C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>serves under the provisions of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/12103">section 12103(d)</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, pursuant to an
			 enlistment in the Army National Guard or the Air National Guard, or as a
			 Reserve for service in the Army Reserve, Navy Reserve, Air Force Reserve,
			 Marine Corps Reserve, or Coast Guard Reserve.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idB877FD0B7B8D4FB297002377B2138779">
			<enum>7.</enum>
			<header>Public service loan forgiveness</header>
			<text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 455(m) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087e">20 U.S.C. 1087e(m)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
			<paragraph id="id0C6B36C018534980A58DCE7B0A956B33">
				<enum>(1)</enum>
				<text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating paragraphs (3) and (4) as paragraphs (4) and (5), respectively; and</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="id54B6EB1CB1E04254A6AEABD204E49254">
				<enum>(2)</enum>
				<text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting after paragraph (2) the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7849112D385C438AAA77A18027AAD22B" style="OLC">
					<paragraph id="id947391D2FEFA49238783B6D745518FF2">
						<enum>(3)</enum>
						<header>Lump sum payment</header>
						<text>For purposes of this subsection, if a borrower has enrolled in a repayment plan described in
			 paragraph (1)(A) and  makes a lump sum payment through a student loan
			 repayment program under section 2171 of
			 title 10, United States Code, or a similarly structured eligible repayment
			 program (as determined by the Secretary),  the Secretary will treat the
			 borrower as having made a number of qualifying payments equal to the
			 lesser
			 of—</text>
						<subparagraph id="id6E141074901B45789D329B88344B007B">
							<enum>(A)</enum>
							<text>the number, rounded to the nearest whole number, equal to the quotient of—</text>
							<clause id="idB12D34B07D344D1EABE595AC75703379">
								<enum>(i)</enum>
								<text>such lump sum payment; divided by</text>
							</clause><clause id="idE22B07C5FE9B43F3A6DAAAAA4C6AE5A0">
								<enum>(ii)</enum>
								<text>the monthly payment amount that the borrower would have otherwise made under the  repayment plan
			 described in paragraph (1)(A) selected by the borrower; or</text>
							</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE6D08D4DC8114C10889D45A653780DD1">
							<enum>(B)</enum>
							<text>12 payments.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section><section id="idCD0B039314A845ACAF679907E59E9FAC">
			<enum>8.</enum>
			<header>Accrual of interest for members of the Armed Forces subject to hostile fire or imminent danger</header>
			<text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 455(o) is amended—</text>
			<paragraph id="id200BDB803861496EA8C248AACEBE7686">
				<enum>(1)</enum>
				<text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking paragraph (1) and inserting the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD2ADFE2294C14C9DA8F9D8F52490EDBF" style="OLC">
					<paragraph id="idC2B7FDB34C554851A297C052828EBB99">
						<enum>(1)</enum>
						<header>In General</header>
						<text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this part and in accordance with paragraphs (2) and (4), the
			 Secretary shall not charge interest on a loan made to a borrower under
			 this part for which the first disbursement is made on or after October 1,
			 2008, during the period in which a borrower who is performing eligible
			 military service (as defined in section 481(d)) is  serving in an area of
			 hostilities in which service qualifies for special pay
			 under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/37/310">section 310</external-xref> of title 37, United States Code.</text>
					</paragraph><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="idA601801950AF4E9CBC9454C1295651A3">
				<enum>(2)</enum>
				<text>by striking paragraph (3) and inserting the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id019F6C6FC3F5475789DACE2593B898BD" style="OLC">
					<paragraph id="id6DBE420D173C4544A7DC4D71DFD246AA">
						<enum>(3)</enum>
						<header>Implementation of accrual of interest provision for members of the Armed Forces</header>
						<subparagraph id="idD6D6564D474A4E509119A0DC91AFFB99">
							<enum>(A)</enum>
							<header>In General</header>
							<text>The Secretary shall enter into any necessary  agreements, including agreements	with
			 the Commissioner of Revenue and the Secretary of Defense—</text>
							<clause id="id5242F91D4D024A689482CC5CB1E5372F">
								<enum>(i)</enum>
								<text>to ensure that interest does not accrue for borrowers described in paragraph (1), in accordance
			 with this
			 subsection; and</text>
							</clause><clause id="idC3AA8F0427214C839787FEED86EC3925">
								<enum>(ii)</enum>
								<text>to obtain or provide any information necessary to implement clause (i) without requiring a request
			 from the borrower.</text>
							</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA71E2DA58B1A46E5944FA0D57CC2235B">
							<enum>(B)</enum>
							<header>Reports</header>
							<clause id="id0BEDCD69C6154141933DC0B44518836C">
								<enum>(i)</enum>
								<header>Plan</header>
								<text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Servicemember Higher Education Protection Act</short-title>, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report that
			 includes a plan to implement the accrual of  interest provision described
			 in subparagraph (A).</text>
							</clause><clause id="id82699F34891043329C179730CEB43D8B">
								<enum>(ii)</enum>
								<header>Follow-up Report</header>
								<text>If the Secretary has not implemented the accrual of interest provision described in
			 subparagraph (A) by the date that is  1
			 year after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Servicemember Higher Education Protection Act</short-title>, the Secretary shall submit, by such date, a report that includes an explanation of why
			 such provision has not been implemented and a description of any
			 legislative changes that are necessary to allow for the  implementation of
			 such provision.</text>
							</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="id4AAFBD80446741A9BA6DFD2262CD9034">
				<enum>(3)</enum>
				<text>in paragraph (4), by striking <quote>who qualifies as an eligible military borrower under this subsection</quote> and inserting <quote>described in paragraph (1)</quote>.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="id8218C2CEF3BC47C1AB79CC810D300177">
			<enum>9.</enum>
			<header>National Student Loan Data System</header>
			<subsection id="idC584F2A6E7A74AD296402C453CC1511B">
				<enum>(a)</enum>
				<header>Amendment to the Higher Education Act of 1965</header>
				<text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (h) of section 485B (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1092b">20 U.S.C. 1092b(h)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF40AE9DB9D2349A18C101EC3187E14A1" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="id5E979E6BCE764A4995D6DEF0AC4268CF">
						<enum>(h)</enum>
						<header>Integration of databases</header>
						<paragraph id="idF572F75491B04FBEACDA721B41B0F9EB">
							<enum>(1)</enum>
							<header>In General</header>
							<text>The Secretary shall integrate the National Student Loan Data System with the Federal Pell Grant
			 applicant
			 and recipient databases as of January 1, 1994, and any other databases
			 containing information on participation in programs under this title.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="idB9C9594CBA644EDDAB9E2AEBE8315170">
							<enum>(2)</enum>
							<header>Department of Defense Information</header>
							<subparagraph id="id68A08E4791054068B2443D1799D2992B">
								<enum>(A)</enum>
								<header>In General</header>
								<text>In order to incorporate the military and veteran status of borrowers into the National Student Loan
			 Data System, the Secretary shall integrate the National Student Loan Data
			 System with information from—</text>
								<clause id="id2AD625B5801F4C68BEB358131B9BE757">
									<enum>(i)</enum>
									<text>the Department of Defense, including the Defense Manpower Data Center; and</text>
								</clause><clause id="idCAE6CF8B17274C869030F53A4A6755E3">
									<enum>(ii)</enum>
									<text>the Department of Veterans Affairs, including data about  veterans who are eligible for educational
			 assistance under laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs.</text>
								</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE3E3B3B6F4ED47A68CC62CC329A8CF0C">
								<enum>(B)</enum>
								<header>Memoranda of understanding</header>
								<text>The Secretary shall enter into any memoranda of understanding or other agreements that are
			 necessary to carry out this paragraph.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="id15DA4F50F35243EE99390B8BA9AB42FA">
				<enum>(b)</enum>
				<header>Reports</header>
				<paragraph id="idB00635566C4D45F18E9EDD072B79555D">
					<enum>(1)</enum>
					<header>Plan</header>
					<text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Education
			 shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report that
			 includes a plan to implement the Department of Defense data integration
			 provision described under section 485B(h)(2) of the Higher Education Act
			 of 1965, as amended by this section.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="id521910FD35E64FCEBCB8C541DA430A9C">
					<enum>(2)</enum>
					<header>Follow-up Report</header>
					<text>If the Secretary of Education has not implemented the Department of Defense data integration
			 provision described under section 485B(h)(2) of the Higher Education Act
			 of 1965, as amended by this section, by the date that is 1 year after the
			 date of
			 enactment of
			 this Act, the Secretary of Education shall submit, by such date, a report
			 that includes an explanation of why such provision has not been
			 implemented and a description of any legislative changes that are
			 necessary to allow for the  implementation of such provision.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id44DCD4263CC04F87824CFEC1015BBFE5">
			<enum>10.</enum>
			<header>Program participation agreements</header>
			<text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 487(a) is amended by adding at the
			 end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idCC3358142A9946969CCD8896F7C2EDD2" style="OLC">
				<paragraph id="id1DCEC04DCD574F61B29C5D0A531A623D">
					<enum>(30)</enum>
					<text>In the case of an institution that enrolls during an academic year more than 100 students who are
			 veterans, the institution shall
			 certify that the institution has developed and implemented a plan to
			 ensure the success of veterans at that institution.   To the extent
			 practicable, the institution shall make the plan, and associated
			 policies, public and accessible to students who are veterans.	Such plan
			 shall include the following:</text>
					<subparagraph id="id7DE56AD35F144BF7979472EF7ECDEE2F">
						<enum>(A)</enum>
						<text>The designation of certain faculty or staff at the institution who will serve as a point of contact
			 for veterans—</text>
						<clause id="idA10999240BB2481AA4E58146981D578E">
							<enum>(i)</enum>
							<text>within campus offices, including the admissions office; and</text>
						</clause><clause id="idE84B09724CAB48E89CE22E78E0EFB102">
							<enum>(ii)</enum>
							<text>during any orientation process for newly enrolled students.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id852F5FD52489467E8C01D2EC95D55DE1">
						<enum>(B)</enum>
						<text>The establishment of a working group that will be responsible for veterans' issues.</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="idBCED85C7C9AB4A3CB278D2714BCB76F3">
						<enum>(C)</enum>
						<text>A description of disability services that are available to meet the needs of disabled students who
			 are veterans.</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="id008F02335E0246FF96014136B2F41F46">
						<enum>(D)</enum>
						<text>A plan for how the institution will identify students who are veterans through the application
			 process, or through other processes, to provide better assistance in the
			 receipt of educational
			 assistance under laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs or
			 the Secretary of Defense.</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6E1281E1C339427BAB6DF4D40780F70F">
						<enum>(E)</enum>
						<text>A description of how the institution will evaluate and maximize the number of credits students can
			 receive from military training and service.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section commented="no" id="idA66B30E9C92B42A3997AC908CBACAA86">
			<enum>11.</enum>
			<header>Extending the protections for student loans for active duty borrowers</header>
			<text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 493D (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1098f">20 U.S.C. 1098f</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
			<paragraph commented="no" id="id9D3C7CCE7A744314B879D013AA347DBC">
				<enum>(1)</enum>
				<text>in the section heading, by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">and protections for active duty borrowers</header-in-text></quote> before the period at the end;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id6B02DD90ADFC40678BCB033458E4EAF8">
				<enum>(2)</enum>
				<text>by redesignating subsection (b) as subsection (c); and</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id4E668EA98D67476690EA1A2EC6BAE9B9">
				<enum>(3)</enum>
				<text>by inserting after subsection (a) the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8574312AB20545728254B93FAB81EE28" style="OLC">
					<subsection commented="no" id="id278E83A19B23484D8D5B73F4690AD811">
						<enum>(b)</enum>
						<header>Use of information</header>
						<paragraph commented="no" id="id110B78A3D5764F02BB1ADD4BD091C8EF">
							<enum>(1)</enum>
							<header>In general</header>
							<text>The Secretary shall utilize information the Secretary  receives regarding the active duty
			 status of borrowers from the
			 Secretary of Defense for any purpose under this title	to ensure that the
			 interest rate charged on any  loan made under part D of
			 title IV for borrowers who are subject to  section
			 207(a)(1) of the Servicemembers
			 Civil
			 Relief Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc-appendix" parsable-cite="usc-appendix/50/527">50 U.S.C. App. 527(a)(1)</external-xref>) does not exceed the maximum interest
			 rate set forth in such section.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="idB8BEAA2A1887438AABEB2EA0CFACDEA4">
							<enum>(2)</enum>
							<header>SCRA interest rate limitation notice requirements</header>
							<text>The submittal by the Secretary of Defense to the Secretary of Education of information that informs
			 the Secretary of Education that an individual with a
			 student loan under part D of title IV has been or is being
			 called to military service (as defined in section 101 of the
			 Servicemembers Civil Relief Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/511">50 U.S.C. 511</external-xref>)) shall be considered, for
			 purposes of subjecting such student loan to the provisions of section 207
			 of the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc-appendix" parsable-cite="usc-appendix/50/527">50 U.S.C. App. 527</external-xref>), provision by
			 the borrower to the creditor of written notice and a copy of military
			 orders as described in subsection (b)(1) of such section.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idCC141F77745F4522B3B595E485C0D145">
							<enum>(3)</enum>
							<header>Procedures</header>
							<text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Servicemember Higher Education Protection Act</short-title>, the Secretary, in consultation with the Department
			 of Defense, shall establish a procedure to implement
			 this subsection.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section><section id="id4FB5938457C840ECAD79B1B80F6AB858" section-type="subsequent-section">
			<enum>12.</enum>
			<header>Modification of limitation on rate of interest on student loans during and immediately after period
			 of military service</header>
			<subsection id="idDD2D26106D144EF3A471750D2EBBF550">
				<enum>(a)</enum>
				<header>Extension of period of applicability of limitation on rate of interest on student loans incurred
			 before service</header>
				<text>Section 207(a)(1) of the Servicemembers Civil
			 Relief Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc-appendix" parsable-cite="usc-appendix/50/527">50 U.S.C. App. 527(a)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
				<paragraph id="idAEF66C00A8814C879AB4AC2C2409E800">
					<enum>(1)</enum>
					<text>in subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>or a student loan</quote> after <quote>nature of a mortgage</quote>; and</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE8AACDDE8E02454EBFBADDD74A1116D7">
					<enum>(2)</enum>
					<text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the paragraph heading,
			 by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">on debt
			 incurred before service</header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">Limitation to 6
			 percent</header-in-text></quote>.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idE6B40DBAF5D443388CAF6806D35C12FE">
				<enum>(b)</enum>
				<header>Debt entered into during military service To consolidate or refinance
			 student
			 loans incurred before military service</header>
				<text>Subsection (a) of section 207 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc-appendix" parsable-cite="usc-appendix/50/527">50 U.S.C. App. 527</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
				<paragraph id="idB7D04152412D45F3945CF37F01A79862">
					<enum>(1)</enum>
					<text>by redesignating
			 paragraphs (2) and (3) as paragraphs (3) and (4), respectively;</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="id7962673B89734DAAAF8DAB73F8110666">
					<enum>(2)</enum>
					<text>by inserting
			 after paragraph (1) the following new paragraph (2):</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5A7725BE03F747CFA327B93DCAE0363B" style="OLC">
						<paragraph id="idD2FFB8ACE3514FDD9D3913BB8B6ABD82">
							<enum>(2)</enum>
							<header>Limitation to 6
				percent on debt incurred during service to consolidate or refinance
			 student
				loans incurred before service</header>
							<text>An obligation or liability bearing
				interest at a rate in excess of 6 percent per year that is incurred
			 by a
				servicemember, or the servicemember and the servicemember's spouse
			 jointly,
				during military service to consolidate or refinance one or more
			 student loans
				incurred by the servicemember before such military service shall
			 not bear an
				interest at a rate in excess of 6 percent during the period of
			 military
				service and one year thereafter.</text>
						</paragraph><after-quoted-block>;
				</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="id300D217F16874B10B48199BA8FB8FF3B">
					<enum>(3)</enum>
					<text>in paragraph (3),
			 as redesignated by paragraph (1) of this subsection, by inserting <quote>or
			 (2)</quote> after <quote>paragraph (1)</quote>; and</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="id93BDE702041349898E1DFC0BF86C2786">
					<enum>(4)</enum>
					<text>in paragraph (4),
			 as so redesignated, by striking <quote>paragraph (2)</quote> and inserting
			 <quote>paragraph (3)</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id397C33D09D454A268E58E5FAE7975668">
				<enum>(c)</enum>
				<header>Implementation
			 of limitation</header>
				<text>Subsection (b) of such section is amended—</text>
				<paragraph id="id693A720A11FD49F48396ED6A25E2088A">
					<enum>(1)</enum>
					<text>in paragraph (1),
			 by striking <quote>the interest rate limitation in subsection (a)</quote> and
			 inserting <quote>an interest rate limitation in paragraph (1) or (2) of
			 subsection (a)</quote>; and</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="idF49FA4BBB80F4F859A5CA7B81D2B22AB">
					<enum>(2)</enum>
					<text>in paragraph
			 (2)—</text>
					<subparagraph id="id5365D2B1C20942FB94395C1F9F035D8E">
						<enum>(A)</enum>
						<text>in the paragraph
			 heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">as of
			 date of order to active duty</header-in-text></quote>; and</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1D19E077ECA24389A12283FFA6F12147">
						<enum>(B)</enum>
						<text>by inserting
			 before the period at the end the following: <quote>in the case of an obligation
			 or liability covered by subsection (a)(1), or as of the date the
			 servicemember
			 (or servicemember and spouse jointly) incurs the obligation or liability
			 concerned under subsection (a)(2)</quote>.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idC711FB22EACA45D590ED138395F7A3BA">
				<enum>(d)</enum>
				<header>Student loan
			 defined</header>
				<text>Subsection (d) of such section is amended by adding at
			 the end the following new paragraph:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id85ED31F1E9784606B8BD0395ED1F1EB6" style="OLC">
					<paragraph id="id45CE21FBAE024A8D902976BACE7E42B0">
						<enum>(3)</enum>
						<header>Student
				loan</header>
						<text>The term <term>student loan</term> means the
				following:</text>
						<subparagraph id="id267F5BEDA26841CF95BEDD7363E00B6E">
							<enum>(A)</enum>
							<text>A Federal student
				loan made, insured, or guaranteed under title IV of the Higher
			 Education Act of
				1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070">20 U.S.C. 1070 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD28D09768A584362ACFA970728A6FAB3">
							<enum>(B)</enum>
							<text>A private student
				loan as that term is defined in section 140(a) of the Truth in
			 Lending Act (15
				U.S.C.
				1650(a)).</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="id034B035DC3404286BB63EDCBCDD91107">
			<enum>13.</enum>
			<header>Working group on improvement of resources available to members of the Armed Forces and their
			 spouses in using tuition assistance programs of the Department of Defense</header>
			<subsection id="idCF3BB30DE5CB4F34B1C1A54C07E6E5FE">
				<enum>(a)</enum>
				<header>Working group required</header>
				<text>The Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Education, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, and the
			 Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection shall jointly, and
			 in consultation with the heads of such other departments and agencies of
			 the Federal Government as such officials consider appropriate, establish
			 and maintain a working group to assess and improve the resources available
			 to education service officers and other personnel of the Federal
			 Government who provide assistance to members of the Armed Forces and their
			 spouses in using or seeking to use the tuition assistance programs of the
			 Department of Defense.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="id717284AB06D644F9AD4EE3589A3127FA">
				<enum>(b)</enum>
				<header>Resources</header>
				<text>In improving resources as described in subsection (a), the working group shall provide for the
			 inclusion of the following in such resources:</text>
				<paragraph id="id71CF84C6D1FE44F5A769155BCA9E9782">
					<enum>(1)</enum>
					<text>Information on the benefits and protections for members of the Armed Forces and their dependents
			 provided in this Act and the amendments made by this Act.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="id8BF86246603F4AD58F02ECE4E4763DAA">
					<enum>(2)</enum>
					<text>Consumer information, resources, and tools created and maintained by the working group	pursuant to
			 this section.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="id190DCA04631B4D4088EC330D2DF70813">
					<enum>(3)</enum>
					<text>Information on the availability of consumer protection measures, including the complaint system
			 established pursuant to Executive Order 13607 (77 Fed. Reg. 25861;
			 relating to establishing principles of excellence for educational
			 institutions serving servicemembers, veterans, spouses, and other family
			 members).</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="id4AD1F79F5C9C47B29ED3BEF2EA16F6C4">
					<enum>(4)</enum>
					<text>Such other information or resources as the working group considers appropriate.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idDC0A9C78734D4828A63F7557436F8366"><enum>14.</enum><header>Exception for Servicemembers Civil Relief Act</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 428(d) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1078">20 U.S.C. 1078(d)</external-xref>) is amended by striking “section 207 of the Servicemembers Civil
			 Relief Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc-appendix" parsable-cite="usc-appendix/50/527">50 U.S.C. App. 527</external-xref>)” and inserting “the Servicemembers Civil
			 Relief Act (50 U.S.C. App. 501 et seq.)”.</text></section></legis-body>
</bill>


