<bill session="113" type="h" number="4975" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SALTS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Synthetic Abuse and Labeling of Toxic Substances Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Controlled Substances Act relating to controlled substance analogues.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400404"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400381" joined="2014-06-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-25">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-25">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1322"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/25/2014--Introduced.
Synthetic Abuse and Labeling of Toxic Substances Act of 2014 or the SALTS Act - Amends the Controlled Substances Act to provide that, in determining whether a controlled substance analogue was intended for human consumption, the following factors may be considered: (1) the marketing, advertising, and labeling of the substance; (2) the known efficacy or usefulness of the substance for the marketed, advertised, or labeled purpose; (3) the difference between the price at which the substance is sold and the price at which the substance it is purported to be or advertised as is normally sold; (4) the diversion of the substance from legitimate channels and the clandestine importation, manufacture, or distribution of the substance; and (5) whether the defendant knew or should have known that the substance was intended to be consumed by injection, inhalation, ingestion, or any other immediate means.

Declares that evidence that a substance was not marketed, advertised, or labeled for human consumption shall not by itself be sufficient to establish that the substance was not intended for human consumption.</summary>
</bill>
