<bill session="113" type="h" number="4515" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-04-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-04-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Getting into Researching, Learning, &amp; Studying of STEM Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">GIRLS-STEM Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to provide grants to eligible local educational agencies to encourage female students to pursue studies and careers in science, mathematics, engineering, and technology.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412189"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412571" joined="2014-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412600" joined="2014-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2014-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412535" joined="2014-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="2014-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2014-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2014-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2014-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400230" joined="2014-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2014-05-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="2014-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412521" joined="2014-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400663" joined="2014-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412518" joined="2014-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="408211" joined="2014-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412523" joined="2014-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412219" joined="2014-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412520" joined="2014-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412522" joined="2014-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412412" joined="2014-06-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
    <term name="Women's education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/29/2014--Introduced.
Getting into Researching, Learning, &amp; Studying of STEM Act of 2014 or the GIRLS-STEM Act of 2014 - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to authorize the Secretary of Education to award grants to local educational agencies that serve underrepresented or low-income students to enable their elementary and secondary schools to establish and implement programs that:

 encourage the ongoing interest of female students in careers requiring science, technology, engineering, or mathematics (STEM) skills at all levels of the career pathway; and prepare female students to pursue the industry-recognized credentials needed to pursue a STEM career. Requires the grants to be awarded in four-school-year increments.

Requires the grants to be used to:

 acquaint female students with, and prepare them to pursue, STEM careers; educate the parents of such students about the opportunities and advantages of STEM careers; provide female students with STEM tutoring, mentoring, after-school activities, and summer programs; expose female students to STEM role models, events, academic programs, or career and technical education programs; purchase education materials, equipment, or software that facilitate STEM instruction; assist female students in selecting secondary school courses that provide them with preparation for postsecondary education and experiential learning opportunities in STEM; facilitate STEM internships for such students; and provide teachers with training that enables them to more effectively teach STEM and overcome gender biases that discourage female students' advancement in those fields.</summary>
</bill>
