<bill session="113" type="s" number="1824" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-12-15">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-12-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-12-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Drinking Water Supply Assistance Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Safe Drinking Water Act to exempt certain lead pipes, fittings, fixtures, solder, and flux that contain brass.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300041"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412251" joined="2013-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2013-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400040" joined="2013-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300030" joined="2013-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="2013-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400284" joined="2013-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412322" joined="2013-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="2013-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2013-12-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-12-13">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate, read the first time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-12-15" state="REPORTED" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="261">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 261.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3588"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1779"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/13/2013--Introduced.
Drinking Water Supply Assistance Act of 2013 - Amends the Safe Drinking Water Act to exempt any pipe, pipe or plumbing fitting or fixture, solder, or flux that contains brass from certain prohibitions against the use of lead pipes, solder, and flux under the following conditions:

 a supplier of water owns the brass before enactment of this Act; the brass is used to prevent or mitigate a municipal budget deficit or an interruption in service of a public water system; and the supplier of water is otherwise in compliance with all laws and regulations, except monitoring requirements regarding lead in water. Makes the exemption inapplicable to a municipality if the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) determines it would result in an unreasonable risk to public health.

Directs the Administrator to: (1) consult with and seek the advice of the National Drinking Water Advisory Council on potential changes to federal regulations pertaining to lead; and (2) request the Council to consider sources of lead throughout drinking water distribution systems, including through components used to reroute drinking water during distribution system repairs.</summary>
</bill>
