<bill session="113" type="s" number="2294" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-05-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require a survey of the preferences of members of the Armed Forces regarding military pay and benefits.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412582"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2014-05-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2721"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1960"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4435"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/6/2014--Introduced.
Directs the Military Compensation and Retirement Modernization Commission to carry out an anonymous survey of random members of the Armed Forces regarding their preferences in military pay and benefits, with respect to: (1) the relative value that they place on specified forms of compensation (including basic pay, allowances for housing and subsistence, bonuses, various healthcare benefits, and retirement pay); (2) how they value different levels of pay or benefits, including the impact of copayments or deductibles; and (3) how information collected varies by age, grade, dependent status, and other factors.

Directs the Commission to submit to the Secretary of Defense (DOD) and Congress and make available to the public a report on the analysis and raw data of the survey.

Amends the National Defense Authorization Act for FY2013 to require the Commission to make its recommendations for changes to the military compensation and retirement systems only after examining the analysis and raw data collected pursuant to such survey.</summary>
</bill>
