<bill session="113" type="h" number="3317" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-10-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-10-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Holding Individuals Accountable and Deterring Money Laundering Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To strengthen the Federal statutes designed to deter money laundering and terrorism financing, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400422"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400063" joined="2013-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400074" joined="2013-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400653" joined="2013-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400249" joined="2013-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2013-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400271" joined="2013-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400661" joined="2013-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2014-06-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-23">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-23">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Commodity Futures Trading Commission"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC)"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international banking"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/23/2013--Introduced.
Holding Individuals Accountable and Deterring Money Laundering Act - Amends provisions of federal law known as the Bank Secrecy Act of 1970&#160;relating to money laundering violations to: (1) increase civil penalties for willful violations of anti-money laundering laws; (2) increase the civil penalty for negligent violations of such laws and impose a penalty on partners, directors, officers, or employees of a financial institution for such violations; and (3) impose a 20-year maximum prison term for&#160;individuals who facilitate evasion of an anti-money laundering program or control. Directs the Comptroller General (GAO) to study contrasting mandatory minimum sentencing laws and guidelines for narcotics-related offenses and Department of Justice (DOJ) prosecutorial discretion in determining penalties for violations of anti-money laundering laws.&#160;

Authorizes a court, in granting an injunction directed at money laundering activities, to issue a conditional or permanent ban on any individual who has violated money laundering laws from acting as an officer or director of a financial institution.

Grants independent legal authority to the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network (FinCEN) of the Department of the Treasury to bring legal action to enforce anti-money laundering laws.

Requires the issuance of regulations by appropriate federal banking agencies, the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC), the Commodities Futures Trading Commission (CFTC), and FinCEN prohibiting financial institutions that are subject to an anti-money laundering program requirement from providing executive compensation based on any criteria that could undermine compliance by any individual with anti-money laundering requirements.&#160;Imposes personal liability on&#160;officers, directors, employees, or affiliated parties of a financial institution for fines relating to money laundering violations.

Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to issue regulations requiring each financial institution that is subject to an anti-money laundering program to establish written policies, procedures, and risk management standards for ensuring compliance with anti-money laundering requirements. Imposes civil liability on&#160;officers or&#160;employees of a financial institutions who knew or should have known about money laundering violations but who failed to take meaningful steps to stop such violations.&#160;

Requires each&#160; appropriate federal banking agency, the SEC, and the CFTC to report to FinCEN on each enforcement or supervisory action taken relating to an anti-money laundering violation.

Expands: (1) criteria for granting safe harbor protections to financial institutions&#160;that voluntarily disclose money laundering violations,&#160;and (2) the types of crimes that can be a predicate offense to money laundering to include all felony offenses.

Expands anti-discrimination protections and legal remedies for&#160;individuals who provide information about money laundering violations (whistle blowers).&#160; Provides enhanced monetary incentives for such whistle blowers.

Directs the Secretary to work with foreign counterparts and financial organizations&#160;to promote stronger anti-money laundering frameworks and enforcement of anti-money laundering laws. &#160;

Expresses the sense of Congress that DOJ should vigorously pursue criminal penalties against individuals who willfully violate anti-money laundering laws. Sets forth considerations for the Department of&#160; the Treasury when identifying countries or jurisdictions as primary money laundering concerns under the USA Patriot Act.</summary>
</bill>
