<bill session="113" type="h" number="3393" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-24T17:32:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-07-24T17:32:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Student and Family Tax Simplification Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Student and Family Tax Simplification Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Child Tax Credit Improvement Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Student and Family Tax Simplification Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to consolidate certain tax benefits for educational expenses, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by house">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to consolidate certain tax benefits for educational expenses, to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to make improvements to the child tax credit, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412478"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="2013-10-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-25">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-06-25" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 22 - 13.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-07-17T11:43:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Ways and Means. H. Rept. 113-526.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-07-17T11:44:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="392">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 392.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-07-23T17:40:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 680 Reported to House. The rule provides for the consideration of H.R. 3393 and H.R. 4935 under a closed rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-24T15:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 680.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6779-6791" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6779-6780" label="text of amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-24T15:54:00-04:00">
      <text>The rule provides for the consideration of H.R. 3393 and H.R. 4935 under a closed rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-24T15:55:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 3393.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-24T16:50:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6789" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-24T16:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Sinema moved to recommit with instructions to the Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6789-6790" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6789" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-24T16:51:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Sinema motion to recommit with instructions, pending reservation of a point of order. Subsequently, the point of order was withdrawn. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to require the Secretary of the Treasury to provide a table for student loan borrowers in any publication related to the underlying bill. That table shall illustrate their current monthly payments for higher education loans and the amount that they would pay for that same loan had they been able to benefit from the lower interest rates that would go into effect if H.R. 4582, Bank on Students Emergency Loan Refinancing Act, were passed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-24T16:58:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6790" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-24T17:26:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 195 - 219 (Roll no. 448).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="449" datetime="2014-07-24T17:32:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 227 - 187 (Roll no. 449).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-07-24T17:32:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-28">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-07-29" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="493">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 493.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hr" number="680"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="113" type="hr" number="680"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1738"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2253"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3437"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3476"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4935"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="835"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1090"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Tax treatment of families"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h1123"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>7/24/2014--Passed House amended.
Title I: Student and Family Tax Simplification Act - Student and Family Tax Simplification Act - (Sec. 102) Amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide for an American Opportunity Tax Credit, in lieu of the current Hope Scholarship and Lifetime Learning tax credits and the tax deduction for qualified tuition and related expenses, that provides for each eligible student (i.e., a student who meets certain requirements of the Higher Education Act of 1965 and who is carrying at least 1/2 the normal full-time course load) a credit of 100% of up to $2,000 of qualified tuition and related expenses (i.e., tuition, fees, and course materials, excluding expenses for courses involving sports, games, or hobbies or for expenses unrelated to academic instruction), plus 25% of so much of such expenses as exceeds $2,000, but not more than $4,000. Makes up to $1,500 of such credit refundable. Modifies the phaseout of such credit based on taxpayer modified adjusted gross income by increasing the income level for such phaseout. Allows an inflation adjustment to credit and phaseout amounts for taxable years beginning after 2018.

Eliminates the disallowance of the credit for students who have been convicted of a felony drug offense.

Requires a taxpayer claiming such credit to include on the his or her tax return the employer identification number of the educational institution to which qualified tuition and related expenses were paid.

(Sec. 103) Excludes from gross income, for income tax purposes, amounts received as a Federal Pell Grant in taxable years beginning after 2014.

(Sec. 104) Prohibits the entry of the budgetary effects of this Act on any PAYGO (pay-as-you-go) scorecard.

Title II: Child Tax Credit Improvement Act - Child Tax Credit Improvement Act of 2014 - (Sec. 202) Amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to the child tax credit, to: (1) increase from $110,00 to $150,000 ($75,000 for individual taxpayers and married taxpayers filing separately) the threshold amount applicable to married couples filing joint tax returns above which such tax credit is reduced, and (2) allow an inflation adjustment to the threshold amounts and the $1,000 credit amount beginning after 2014.

(Sec. 203) Requires taxpayers to include their social security numbers on their tax returns to claim the refundable portion of the child tax credit.

(Sec. 204) Prohibits the entry of the budgetary effects of this Act on any PAYGO (pay-as-you-go) scorecard.</summary>
</bill>
