<bill session="113" type="h" number="3008" updated="2015-09-01T10:19:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-01-27T19:05:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-01-27T19:05:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the conveyance of a small parcel of National Forest System land in Los Padres National Forest in California, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400062"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-08-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-14">
      <text>Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-14">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-11-14" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-12-16T11:28:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 113-295.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-12-16T11:28:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="213">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 213.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-01-27T17:53:00-05:00">
      <text>Mrs. Lummis moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-27T17:53:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1258-1259" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-27T17:53:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3008.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-27T18:00:00-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-27T18:56:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1260-1261" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="25" datetime="2014-01-27T19:05:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 367 - 27 (Roll no. 25).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1258" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-01-28">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-30">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands, Forests, and Mining. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSII10" subcommittee="Public Lands and Environmental Regulation" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG03" subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/27/2014--Passed House amended.
Authorizes the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA), if the White Lotus Foundation in Santa Barbara, California, offers to convey to the Secretary a parcel of non-federal land that is acceptable to the Secretary and the Secretary accepts the offer, to convey approximately five acres of certain identified National Forest System land in Santa Barbara County to the Foundation.

Subjects the land exchange to provisions under the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 related to exchanges of public lands and interests therein within the National Forest System.

Expresses the intent of Congress that the land exchange be completed within two years of enactment of this Act. Allows the Secretary to offer to sell to the White Lotus Foundation the federal land for fair market value if such exchange is not completed by such time.

Makes the land exchange and any such sale subject to specified additional terms and conditions, including to valid existing rights and the White Lotus Foundation paying the reasonable costs of surveys, appraisals, and other administrative costs associated with the exchange or sale.

Requires land conveyed by exchange or sale under this Act to be appraised by an independent appraiser selected by the Secretary and such an appraisal to be conducted in accordance with nationally recognized appraisal standards.</summary>
</bill>
