<bill session="113" type="s" number="1999" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-02-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-02-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-02-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SCRA Rights Protection Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act to require the consent of parties to contracts for the use of arbitration to resolve controversies arising under the contracts and subject to provisions of such Act and to preserve the rights of servicemembers to bring class actions under such Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300047"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2014-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2014-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2014-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2014-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300081" joined="2014-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412542" joined="2014-07-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-02-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="4068"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Alternative dispute resolution, mediation, arbitration"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/6/2014--Introduced.
SCRA Rights Protection Act of 2014 - Amends the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act to allow the use of arbitration to resolve a controversy that arises under a contract with a servicemember (or with a servicemember and spouse jointly) that provides for arbitration, only if all parties to the controversy consent in writing to arbitration after the controversy arises.

Allows a servicemember's waiver of any of such Act's rights and protections to be effective only if it is made after a specific dispute has arisen and the dispute is identified in the waiver.

Allows a representative of members of an aggrieved class, or a member of such class, to bring a private civil action for a violation of any rights or protections under such Act.</summary>
</bill>
