<bill session="113" type="h" number="4842" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Business Supply Chain Transparency on Trafficking and Slavery Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to require certain companies to disclose information describing any measures the company has taken to identify and address conditions of forced labor, slavery, human trafficking, and the worst forms of child labor within the company's supply chains.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400251"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="2014-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="2014-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="2014-06-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E960"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-11">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED10" subcommittee="Workforce Protections" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Business ethics"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Youth employment and child labor"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/11/2014--Introduced.
Business Supply Chain Transparency on Trafficking and Slavery Act of 2014 - Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) legislation is necessary to provide consumers information on products that are free of child labor, forced labor, slavery, and human trafficking; and (2) businesses and consumers, by means of publicly available disclosures, can avoid inadvertently promoting or sanctioning these crimes through production and purchase of goods and products that have been tainted in the supply chains.

Amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to direct the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC), within one year after enactment of the Global Supply Chain Transparency for Trafficking, Forced Labor, and Child Labor Eradication Act, to promulgate regulations requiring that mandatory annual reports include a disclosure whether the covered issuer has taken any measures during the year to identify and address conditions of forced labor, slavery, human trafficking, and the worst forms of child labor within the issuer's supply chains.

Requires any business entity filing such disclosures to make them available on its Internet website.

Directs the Secretary of Labor to develop and publish annually on the Internet website of the Department of Labor a list of top 100 companies adhering to supply chain labor standards, as established under federal and international guidelines.</summary>
</bill>
