<bill session="113" type="h" number="5611" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Public School Emergency Relief Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for temporary emergency impact aid for local educational agencies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400195"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400031" joined="2014-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2014-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400219" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400257" joined="2014-12-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Foreign language and bilingual programs"/>
    <term name="Immigrant health and welfare"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/18/2014--Introduced.
Public School Emergency Relief Act - Directs the Secretary of Education to provide emergency impact aid payments to states and, through them, to local educational agencies and Indian schools for each quarter of the 2014-2015 school year for any increase in the enrollment of immigrant children from the corresponding quarter of the 2012-2013 school year.

Requires the payments to be used to provide services and assistance to schools that enroll immigrant students.

Authorizes the funds to be used for:

 compensating school personnel, identifying and acquiring curricular material and mobile educational units and leasing sites or spaces, basic instructional services for immigrant students, reasonable transportation costs, health and counseling services, education and support services, and other uses allowed under title III (Language Instruction for Limited English Proficient and Immigrant Students) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965. Requires any payment made on behalf of a disabled immigrant student to be used for special education and related services.

Prohibits the use of the emergency impact aid for any expenses that are not incurred during the 2014-2015 school year.</summary>
</bill>
