<bill session="113" type="h" number="4595" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-05-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">School Bus Safety Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Grants for Motion-Activated Detection System on School Buses Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Kadyn's Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To encourage school bus safety.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412208"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412209" joined="2014-09-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-07">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-07">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW12" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Motor carriers"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/7/2014--Introduced.
School Bus Safety Act - Kadyn's Act - Directs the Secretary of Transportation (DOT) to withhold 10% of a state's apportionment of certain federal-aid highway funds if the state has not enacted and is not enforcing a law that imposes specified first offense and second offense civil and criminal penalties for motorists found guilty of illegally passing a stopped school bus.

Grants for Motion-Activated Detection System on School Buses Act - Authorizes the Secretary to provide grants to states to equip school buses with motion-activated detection systems.

Directs the Secretary to withhold 10% of a state's apportionment of certain federal-aid highway funds if the state has not enacted a law that requires the employer to conduct background checks before hiring school bus drivers.

Authorizes the Secretary to award grants to states to develop a school bus seat belt demonstration program to purchase type 1 school buses (weighing more than 10,000 pounds) equipped with lap/shoulder seat belts or equip such existing buses with such belts.

Directs the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration to study the effects of illegal passing of school buses, including a pilot program demonstrating the effectiveness of additional technologies and equipment on the buses.</summary>
</bill>
