<bill session="113" type="h" number="5884" updated="2015-09-01T17:50:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-12-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-12-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-12-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Don't Track Me Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit the replacement of the gasoline excise tax with a GPS, location or distance-based tax and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410396"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-12-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-11">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-11">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-11">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW12" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Photography and imaging"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/11/2014--Introduced.
Don't Track Me Act - Declares that it is contrary to U.S. public policy to require the placement or use of any global positioning satellite (GPS), location, or distance tracking system to collect identities of vehicle owners by remote means.

Prohibits the federal gasoline excise tax from being replaced or supplemented with any tax, fee, or fine based upon vehicle location or distance traveled that is determined by GPS, license plate reading cameras, or other methods of determining vehicle location, travel distance, or registration and identity data.

Prohibits motor vehicles from being required to have certain devices that track or transmit location, distance, or driver identity information.

Bars public funds from being used to study, implement, or require the use of any method of tracking or reporting vehicle movement or location for the purpose of taxes, user fees, traffic fines, accident investigation, or communication with other vehicles or infrastructure.

Prohibits vehicle-to-vehicle or vehicle-to-infrastructure communication systems for the purposes of recording or transmitting or storing for later retrieval location, registration, identity, or speed data. Allows such transmissions to be used only for momentary accident avoidance or anonymized traffic reporting.

Bars federal agencies from requiring motor vehicles to have a "black box" accident data recorder that records vehicle data for longer than the last five minutes of vehicle operation. Prohibits such devices from: (1) recording audio, images, or video from inside the vehicle; or (2) broadcasting or transmitting any data except by a direct cable connection to a computer.</summary>
</bill>
