<bill session="113" type="h" number="3756" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-12-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-12-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-12-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the public disclosure of information regarding surveillance activities under the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412569"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-12-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select), for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-12">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-12">
      <text>Referred to House Intelligence</text>
      <reference ref="Permanent Select"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Specialized courts"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/12/2013--Introduced.
Requires the Attorney General to publicly disclose, in a&#160;manner consistent with national security,&#160;any decision of a court established by the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (FISA) that surveillance activities conducted by the U.S. government have violated a particular U.S. law or constitutional provision.

Requires the Director of National Intelligence (DNI) to provide information on surveillance activities to Congress, including information regarding: (1) whether the National Security Agency (NSA) or any other element of the intelligence community has ever collected, or made plans to collect, the cell-site location information of a large number of U.S. persons with no known connection to suspicious activity; (2) the type and amount of evidence the DNI believes is required to permit the collection&#160;of cell-site information for intelligence purposes; (3) whether NSA or any other element of the intelligence community has ever conducted a warrantless search of a collection of communications in an effort to find the communications of a particular U.S. person (other than a corporation) and, if so, the number of such searches or an estimate of such number; (4) when the U.S. government first began relying on authorities under FISA to justify the collection of records with no known connection to suspicious activity; (5) whether representations made to the U.S. Supreme Court by the Department of Justice (DOJ) in the case of Clapper v. Amnesty International USA accurately described the use of authorities under FISA by the government, which of such representations, if any, were inaccurate, and how such representations have been corrected; and (6) FISA court opinions that identified violations of the law, the Constitution, or FISA court orders relating to the collection of information under FISA.

Directs the Comptroller General (GAO), in consultation with the U.S. International Trade Commission, to conduct an assessment of the economic impact, including the impact on the ability of U.S. communication service providers to compete in foreign markets, of bulk collection and surveillance programs conducted under FISA, and to report to Congress on such assessment.</summary>
</bill>
