<bill session="113" type="h" number="3414" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-10-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-10-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FISH Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fundamentally Improving Salmon Habitat Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Water Resources Development Act of 2000 with respect to ecosystem restoration in the lower Columbia River and Tillamook Bay estuaries.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412486"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2013-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412501" joined="2013-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412315" joined="2013-10-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-30">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-30">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII22" subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/30/2013--Introduced.
Fundamentally Improving Salmon Habitat Act or the FISH Act - Amends the Water Resources Development Act of 2000 to revise requirements for studies and ecosystem restoration projects for the lower Columbia River and Tillamook Bay estuaries, Oregon and Washington. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to: (1) conduct studies and ecosystem restoration projects with total costs of $2 million or greater per project (designated as "large projects"); and (2) provide grants to the Lower Columbia Estuary Partnership, the Lower Columbia Fish Recovery Board, and the Tillamook Estuaries Partnership to conduct projects with total costs of less than $2 million per project ("small projects"). Revises and adds requirements relating to administration of such projects, including the provision of technical assistance to entities carrying out small projects, the determination of priority for large and small projects, and the allocation of funding for small projects.</summary>
</bill>
