<bill session="113" type="h" number="5469" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Propane Supply and Security Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prevent future propane shortages, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412256"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412214" joined="2014-11-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-15">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-15">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on General Farm Commodities and Risk Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG16" subcommittee="General Farm Commodities and Risk Management" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2762"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices, subsidies, credit"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Energy assistance for the poor and aged"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Lighting and heating"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/15/2014--Introduced.
Propane Supply and Security Act of 2014 - Directs the Administrator of the Energy Information Administration (EIA) to publish weekly inventory data on propane storage and propane markets, including pricing data for residential customers in states that voluntarily choose to participate in the State Heating Oil and Propane Program (SHOPP) of the EIA.

Directs the Administrator to publish data on storage at: (1) major market centers, and (2) the regions reported in specified weekly and monthly inventory data.

Directs the Secretary of Energy (DOE) to lead and coordinate federal and state emergency response efforts regarding propane supply emergencies in any state or region characterized by either sudden increases in consumer prices for propane, or propane supply shortages that threaten public safety or livestock safety.

Amends the Propane Education and Research Act of 1996 to direct the Propane Education and Research Council to develop for propane distributors and consumers training programs on strategies to mitigate negative effects of future propane price spikes.

Directs the Secretary to study the effectiveness and feasibility of establishing propane storage facilities operated separately from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve.

Authorizes the Secretary to submit to Congress and the President a plan describing such regional propane reserve.

Amends the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008 to direct the Secretary of Agriculture to include within the storage facility loan program funding for propane storage and handling facilities used for drying and heating.

Directs the Comptroller General (GAO) to study facilities appurtenant to propane pipelines that are not subject to the jurisdiction of the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) to determine: (1) whether the nonjurisdictional nature of the facilities had an impact on the propane price spike during the winter of 2013-2014, or (2) whether such finding demonstrates it would be in the public interest to place such facilities under FERC jurisdiction.</summary>
</bill>
