<bill session="113" type="s" number="1843" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-12-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-12-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-12-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Information Technology Savings, Accountability, and Transparency Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to eliminate duplication and waste in Federal information technology acquisition and management.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400413"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412320" joined="2013-12-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400284" joined="2013-12-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-12-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1232"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/17/2013--Introduced.
Federal Information Technology Savings, Accountability, and Transparency Act of 2013 - Modifies provisions relating to the position of Chief Information Officer (CIO)&#160;in federal agencies to require the appointment of not more than one&#160;CIO in the Departments of Agriculture, Commerce, Education, Energy (DOE), Health and Human Services (HHS), Interior, Justice (DOJ), Labor, State, Transportation (DOT), Treasury, and Veterans Affairs (VA), the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), and the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA).

Requires CIOs to: (1)&#160;be appointed or designated by the President, in consultation with&#160;relevant agency heads; (2)&#160;be chosen from among individuals who have demonstrated knowledge of information technology management practices and ability to manage such practices in large entities; and (3) be given enhanced authority in the budget planning process of an agency and the hiring of personnel who will have information technology responsibilities.

Expands the responsibilities of the Chief Information Officers&#160;Council to require the Council to: (1) develop cross-agency portfolio management practices and issue guidelines and practices for expansion of the federal enterprise architecture process, and (2) report&#160;to specified congressional committees&#160;on its activities.&#160;Requires the Comptroller General (GAO) to examine and report on the effectiveness of the Council.

Requires the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB)&#160;to make available to the public the cost, schedule, and performance data for at least 80% of all information technology investments in each federal agency to which this Act applies, unless the Director or the agency CIO determines that a waiver or limitation of such disclosure requirement is in the interests of national security.</summary>
</bill>
