<bill session="113" type="h" number="3106" updated="2015-09-01T10:19:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-09-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-09-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-09-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Alicia Dawn Koehl Respect for National Cemeteries Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of Veterans Affairs and the Secretary of the Army to reconsider decisions to inter or honor the memory of a person in a national cemetery, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412539"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412427" joined="2013-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412258" joined="2013-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412540" joined="2013-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412426" joined="2013-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412392" joined="2013-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400417" joined="2013-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412538" joined="2013-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412428" joined="2013-09-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-09-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-17">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-17">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="s" number="1471"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Michigan"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/17/2013--Introduced.
Alicia Dawn Koehl Respect for National Cemeteries Act - Authorizes the appropriate federal official (either the Secretary of Veterans Affairs or the Secretary of the Army) to reconsider a decision to inter or honor the memory of a person in the National Cemetery Administration or in Arlington National Cemetery upon receiving information that such person may have committed a federal or state capital crime but was not convicted by reason of unavailability for trial due to death or flight to avoid prosecution.

Requires the appropriate federal official, upon finding, after an opportunity for a hearing, that the person committed but was not convicted of such crime, to provide notice to the individual's next of kin or other authorized person. Allows such next of kin or other person 60 days to file a notice of disagreement, which shall be decided in accordance with such regulations as the Secretary of Defense shall prescribe. Authorizes the appropriate federal official, when a decision becomes final, to disinter the remains or remove the memorial headstone.

Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs: (1) to disinter the remains of Michael LaShawn Anderson from Fort Custer National Cemetery (Michigan); (2) to notify his next of kin of the impending disinterment; and (3) upon disinterment, to relinquish the remains to the next of kin or, if the next of kin of record in unavailable, arrange for the appropriate disposition of the remains.</summary>
</bill>
