<bill session="113" type="h" number="3312" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-10-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-10-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Homeowners Flood Insurance Relief Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to allow for monthly installment payments for flood insurance under the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968, to cap the annual cost of flood insurance under that Act, to provide for a ten-year phase-in of premium increases resulting from the enactment of the Biggert-Waters Flood Insurance Reform Act of 2012, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412250"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412195" joined="2013-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400266" joined="2013-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412311" joined="2013-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2013-10-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-23">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1554-1555"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/23/2013--Introduced.
Homeowners Flood Insurance Relief Act of 2013 - Amends the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 to direct the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to provide certain policy holders the option of paying their premiums monthly (or annually or in more frequent installments, as under current law).

Declares the maximum annual chargeable premium rate for a property to be the total appraised value of all structures located on it at the time of its purchase by the current owner of the property divided by 30.

Sets forth a ten-year phase-in period for risk premium rate increases resulting from enactment of the Biggert-Waters Flood Insurance Reform Act of 2012, at the rate of 10% for each year following the effective date of such Act.

Directs FEMA to refund or provide credit to insureds for any flood insurance premiums collected in excess of the mandatory phase-in of rates prescribed by this Act.</summary>
</bill>
