<bill session="113" type="h" number="5122" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Railroad Hours of Service Employees Technical Corrections Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 to clarify the eligibility requirements with respect to railroad Hours of Service employees.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400031"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2014-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="2014-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412209" joined="2014-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED10" subcommittee="Workforce Protections" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Employee leave"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/16/2014--Introduced.
Railroad Hours of Service Employees Technical Corrections Act - Amends the Family and Medical Leave Act (FMLA) of 1993 to consider that a railroad employee, subject to hours of service under federal law, meets the hours of service eligibility requirement under FMLA if: (1) the employee has worked for or been paid for at least 60% of the applicable total guarantee, or the equivalent, for the previous 12-month period, by the employer with respect to whom FMLA leave is requested; and (2) the employee has worked for or been paid by that employer for at least 504 hours (not counting personal commute time or time spent on vacation leave or medical or sick leave) during such period.

Defines "applicable guarantee" for an employee, as established in the applicable collective bargaining agreement or, if none exists, in the employer's policies as: (1) the minimum number of hours for which an employer has agreed to schedule a nonreserve status employee for any given period; and (2) the number of hours for which an employer has agreed to pay a reserve status employee for any given period.</summary>
</bill>
