<bill session="113" type="h" number="4959" updated="2015-09-01T17:49:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">EEOC Transparency and Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission to maintain up-to-date information on its website regarding charges and actions brought by the Commission, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412550"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400171" joined="2014-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400224" joined="2014-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412426" joined="2014-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412213" joined="2014-06-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-17">
      <text>Hearings Held by the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections Prior to Referral.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="HSED10" subcommittee="Workforce Protections" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Age discrimination"/>
    <term name="Alternative dispute resolution, mediation, arbitration"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/25/2014--Introduced.
EEOC Transparency and Accountability Act - Directs the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (EEOC) to provide information on its public website regarding each case brought in court by the EEOC after a judgment is made with respect to any cause of action.

Requires such information to include: (1) instances in which the EEOC was ordered to pay fees and costs; (2) cases in which a sanction was imposed on the EEOC; (3) the total number of charges of an alleged unlawful employment practice filed under specified provisions of the Civil Rights Act of 1964, the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990, the Age Discrimination in Employment Act of 1967, and the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938; and (4) cases of systemic discrimination, including pattern or practice discrimination.

Amends the Civil Rights Act of 1964 to prohibit the EEOC from bringing a suit unless it exhausts its obligation to engage in an informal conciliation and certifies that conciliation is at impasse.

Makes the determination as to whether the EEOC has engaged in a bona fide conciliation subject to judicial review.

Directs the EEOC Inspector General to notify Congress of any sanctions, fees, or costs imposed on the EEOC by a court. Requires the Inspector General to investigate such cases and the EEOC to report to Congress regarding the steps being taken to reduce such instances.</summary>
</bill>
