<bill session="113" type="s" number="1649" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-11-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-11-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-11-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Vietnam Human Rights Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to promote freedom and democracy in Vietnam.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400040"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2014-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2013-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="2013-12-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-11-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1897"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Area studies and international education"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Cultural exchanges and relations"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign language and bilingual programs"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="International exchange and broadcasting"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="Political movements and philosophies"/>
    <term name="Property rights"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="Vietnam"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/5/2013--Introduced.
Vietnam Human Rights Act of 2013 - Prohibits U.S. nonhumanitarian assistance to the government of Vietnam in excess of FY2012 amounts unless the President certifies to Congress that the government of Vietnam has made substantial progress respecting political, media, and religious freedoms, minority rights, access to U.S. refugee programs, return of confiscated religious estates and property, and actions to end trafficking in persons and to release political prisoners.

Authorizes the President to waive such requirements if increased U.S. nonhumanitarian assistance would promote the purposes of this Act or is otherwise in the U.S. national interest. Allows the President to waive such authority with respect to: (1) all U.S. nonhumanitarian assistance to Vietnam; or (2) one or more programs, projects, or activities of such assistance.

Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1)	the United States should take measures to overcome the jamming of Radio Free Asia by Vietnam and that the Broadcasting Board of Governors should not cut staffing, funding, or broadcast hours for the Vietnamese language services of the Voice of America and Radio Free Asia; (2) U.S.-Vietnam educational and cultural exchange programs should promote freedom and democracy in Vietnam; (3) the Secretary of State should oppose Vietnam's candidacy for membership on the United Nations Human Rights Council (UNHRC); (4) Vietnam should be designated as a country of particular concern for religious freedom; and (5) Vietnam does not fully comply with the minimum standards for the elimination of trafficking and is not making significant efforts to bring itself into compliance.</summary>
</bill>
