<bill session="113" type="s" number="2538" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Viral Hepatitis Testing Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to revise and extend the program for viral hepatitis surveillance, education, and testing in order to prevent deaths from chronic liver disease and liver cancer, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400222"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2014-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412200" joined="2014-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2014-09-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3723"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Digestive and metabolic diseases"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/26/2014--Introduced.
Viral Hepatitis Testing Act of 2014 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to carry out surveillance, education, and testing programs with respect to hepatitis B (HBV) and hepatitis C (HCV) virus infections.

Requires the Secretary to establish a national system with respect to HBV and HCV to: (1) determine the prevalence of such infections; (2) carry out testing programs to increase the number of individuals who are aware of their infection; (3) disseminate public information and education programs for the detection and control of such infections; (4) improve the training of health professionals in the detection, control, and treatment of such infections; and (5) provide referrals for counseling and medical treatment and ensure the provision of follow-up services. Directs the Secretary to determine the populations that are considered at high risk.

Directs the Secretary to establish and support public-private partnerships that facilitate such HBV and HCV surveillance, education, screening, testing, and linkage to care programs.

Requires the Director of the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ) to convene the Preventive Services Task Force every three years to review its recommendation for HBV and HCV screening.</summary>
</bill>
