<bill session="113" type="h" number="5189" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Energy and Water Research Integration Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure consideration of water intensity in the Department of Energy's energy research, development, and demonstration programs to help guarantee efficient, reliable, and sustainable delivery of energy and clean water resources.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400204"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400165" joined="2014-07-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Hydrology and hydrography"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/24/2014--Introduced.
Energy and Water Research Integration Act of 2014 - Requires the Department of Energy (DOE) to integrate water considerations into its energy research, development, and demonstration programs and projects by: (1) advancing energy and energy efficiency technologies and practices that meet the objectives of minimizing freshwater withdrawal and consumption, increasing water use efficiency, and utilizing nontraditional water sources with efforts to improve the quality of the water from those sources; (2) considering the effects climate variability may have on water supplies and quality for energy generation and fuel production; and (3) improving the understanding of the energy required to provide reliable water supplies and the water required to provide reliable energy supplies.

Directs DOE to develop and update every five years a strategic plan to carry out the integration.

Requires DOE to establish an Energy-Water Subcommittee of the Energy Advisory Board to promote and enable improved energy and water resource data collection, reporting, and technological innovation.

Prohibits this Act from being construed to require state, tribal, or local governments to take any action that may result in an increased financial burden by restricting their water use.</summary>
</bill>
