<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 S2947 IS: To amend the Federal Power Act to clarify the authority of the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission to prescribe just, reasonable, and not unduly discriminatory or preferential terms, conditions, and compensation applicable to wholesale demand response resource participation in organized wholesale energy, capacity, and ancillary service markets.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2014-11-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 2947</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20141120">November 20, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S359">Mr. Heinrich</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Federal Power Act to clarify the authority of the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission
			 to prescribe just, reasonable, and not unduly discriminatory or
			 preferential terms, conditions, and compensation applicable to wholesale
			 demand response resource participation in organized wholesale energy,
			 capacity, and ancillary service markets.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Treatment of wholesale demand response resources</header>
			<text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 206(a) of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/824e">16 U.S.C. 824e(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
			<paragraph id="id001220D969704DD295F2E1A5D7B319B3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by designating the first through third sentences as paragraphs (1) through (3), respectively; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idF70E15D59C0242979E53A272F9D2C0EB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idDDDFFEF0F11E4FA786896CBFF02A9153" style="OLC"><paragraph id="idF54F335293124D399DE95A97BD398843"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Treatment of wholesale demand response resources</header><subparagraph id="id895BB2B718814671B5891C42CBCBE89E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this paragraph:</text><clause id="id797094bec30e4a40a2ff9256b6e15562"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Demand response</header><text>The term <term>demand response</term> means a reduction in the consumption of electric energy by customers from their expected
			 consumption in response to an increase in the price of electric energy or
			 to incentive payments designed to induce lower consumption of electric
			 energy.</text></clause><clause id="idd0587f4c497f46ef9a1a6e15c7589088"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Demand response resource</header><text>The term <term>demand response resource</term> means a resource capable of providing demand response.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC6E83836B9214B33AE5D477ADE046BDE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>The Commission may prescribe just, reasonable, and not unduly discriminatory or preferential terms,
			 conditions, and compensation applicable to wholesale demand response
			 resource participation in organized wholesale energy, capacity, and
			 ancillary service markets.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body>
</bill>


