<bill session="113" type="s" number="2593" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FLAME Act Amendments Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the FLAME Act of 2009 to provide for additional wildfire suppression activities, to provide for the conduct of certain forest treatment projects, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300071"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412251" joined="2014-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2014-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400134" joined="2014-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412218" joined="2014-08-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1966"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Alternative dispute resolution, mediation, arbitration"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/10/2014--Introduced.
FLAME Act Amendments Act of 2014 - Amends the FLAME Act of 2009 to revise how the FLAME Funds for the Department of the Interior and the Department of Agriculture (USDA) are funded.

Makes amounts appropriated to a FLAME Fund available to USDA or Interior for wildfire suppression operations if the department concerned notifies the relevant congressional committees that a wildfire suppression event is eligible for funding from the FLAME Fund.

Amends the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 to require certain adjustments to discretionary spending limits to accommodate appropriations for wildfire suppression operations in the Wildland Fire Management accounts at USDA or Interior.

Requires adjustments for fire suppression to be made if all amounts in the FLAME Fund established under the FLAME Act of 2009 have been expended and other specified conditions are met.

Amends existing disaster funding adjustments to discretionary spending limits to add provisions related to fire suppression adjustments. National Forest Jobs and Management Act of 2014 - Authorizes USDA to conduct projects that involve the management or sale of national forest material within certain National Forest System (NFS) lands.

Amends the Healthy Forests Restoration Act of 2003 to authorize the Forest Service and the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) to obligate funds to cover any potential cancellation or termination for an agreement or contract under such Act in stages that are economically and programmatically viable.

Requires the Forest Service and BLM to notify Congress before entering into a multiyear agreement or contract that includes a cancellation ceiling in excess of $25 million, but does not include proposed funding for the costs of cancelling up to the ceiling.</summary>
</bill>
