<bill session="113" type="s" number="2512" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Emergency Interstate Bridge Safety Fund Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish an emergency transportation safety fund for the reconstruction of bridges along the Interstate Highway System, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300072"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412492" joined="2014-06-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-23">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3899"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3899" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Labor standards"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/23/2014--Introduced.
Emergency Interstate Bridge Safety Fund Act - Repeals the Davis-Bacon Act (which requires that the locally prevailing wage rate be paid to various classes of laborers and mechanics working under federally-financed or federally-assisted contracts for construction, alteration, and repair of public buildings or public works).

Establishes in the Treasury an Emergency Interstate Bridge Safety Fund.

Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to transfer to the Fund regularly amounts equal to the savings achieved through this repeal from the capital budgets of each affected federal agency.

Directs the Secretary of Transportation (DOT) to compile a prioritized list of emergency interstate bridge projects on the federal-aid highway system meeting specified criteria (e.g., the bridge is deemed functionally obsolete). Authorizes the obligation of Fund amounts for such projects.</summary>
</bill>
