<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H73723C5335F142EDA5B4E313CCDD6C80" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HR 5809 IH: Medicare DMEPOS Competitive Bidding Improvement Act of 2014</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2014-12-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 5809</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20141208">December 8, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000462">Mr. Tiberi</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to require State licensure and bid surety bonds for
			 entities submitting bids under the Medicare durable medical equipment,
			 prosthetics, orthotics, and supplies (DMEPOS) competitive acquisition
			 program, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H534438E19D6642AC81A001D79EEA3E18" style="OLC">
		<section id="H3B05F4A98BD345F2BB5B757BB8DF9B95" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the ‘‘<short-title>Medicare DMEPOS Competitive Bidding Improvement Act of 2014</short-title>’’.</text>
		</section><section id="H18BE80E4B50E4F97A0BF1C4DC8FE2943"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requiring state licensure and bid surety bonds for entities submitting bids under the Medicare
			 DMEPOS competitive acquisition program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1847(a)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-3">42 U.S.C. 1395w–3(a)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the
			 end the following new subparagraphs:</text>
			<quoted-block id="H5417F42DDA7F48AE9FBB1805883EFA83" style="OLC">
				<subparagraph id="H9AC4B7137EDD49E09E3E3868062C8664"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Requiring state licensure and bid bonds for bidding entities</header><text>With respect to rounds of competitions beginning under this subsection on or after the date of
			 enactment of this subparagraph, the Secretary may not accept a bid from an
			 entity for an area unless, as of the deadline for bid submission—</text>
					<clause id="HF12DCC30E1DC45D281074C7678452A27"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the entity meets applicable State licensure requirements for such area for all items in such bid
			 for a product category; and</text>
					</clause><clause id="H3202147CBC8049D4A3E0FB6E67D4B6AB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the entity has obtained (and provided the Secretary with proof of having obtained) a bid surety
			 bond (in this paragraph referred to as a <quote>bid bond</quote>) in a form specified by the Secretary consistent with subparagraph (H) and in an amount that is
			 not less than $50,000 and not more than $100,000 for each such area.</text>
					</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B02182F9E014EFA83B8F0CA58FC23F7"><enum>(H)</enum><header>Treatment of bid bonds submitted</header>
					<clause id="H1D1B2CB2C04046D7A7E4D1465DD7F63C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>For successful bidders that do not accept the contract</header><text>In the case of a bidding entity that is offered a contract for an area for a product category, if
			 the entity’s composite bid—</text>
						<subclause id="HDC2DAFD39830453DB2B0E9A4B28E8C99"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is at or below the product category’s median composite bid rate for the area and the entity does
			 not accept the contract offered for the product and area, the bid bond
			 submitted shall be forfeited by the bidding entity and the Secretary shall
			 collect on it; or</text>
						</subclause><subclause id="HF158BA0C622944E882C7BE4874AF5997"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is above such median composite bid rate and the entity chooses not to accept a contract for the
			 product category, the bid bond submitted shall be returned within 90 days
			 of the date of notice of nonacceptance.</text>
						</subclause></clause><clause id="H9DFE6D0C2477495997149D3A0D506597"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>For losing bidders</header><text>If a bidding entity submits a bid that is not accepted for an area, the bid bond submitted for the
			 entity for such area shall be returned within 90 days of the date of
			 notice of nonacceptance.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


