<bill session="113" type="h" number="5421" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-12-01T16:23:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-12-01T16:23:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Financial Institution Bankruptcy Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Financial Institution Bankruptcy Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 11 of the United States Code in order to facilitate the resolution of an insolvent financial institution in bankruptcy.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400010"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2014-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400154" joined="2014-09-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-10">
      <text>Subcommittee on Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-10">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-09-10" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-12-01T16:00:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 113-630.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-12-01T16:00:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="470">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 470.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-12-01T16:01:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Goodlatte moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-01T16:01:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8174-8181" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-01T16:01:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5421.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2014-12-01T16:23:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8174-8177" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-12-01T16:23:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-02">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSJU05" subcommittee="Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1861"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/1/2014--Passed House amended.
Financial Institution Bankruptcy Act of 2014 - (Sec. 2) Amends federal bankruptcy law with respect to a "covered financial corporation" incorporated or organized under any federal or state law (other than a stockbroker, a commodity broker, or a domestic or foreign insurance company or financial institution meeting certain criteria) that is: (1) a bank holding company; or (2) a corporation that exists for the primary purpose of owning, controlling, and financing its subsidiaries, has total consolidated assets of $50 billion or greater, and whose annual gross revenues or consolidated assets meet specified tests.

Allows a case under subchapter V (established by this Act) to be converted to chapter 7 (Liquidation) if certain conditions are met, including: (1) a court-ordered appointment of a special trustee, and 2) the court finds that conversion is in the best interest of creditors and the estate.

(Sec. 3) Adds "Subchapter V - Liquidation, Reorganization, or Recapitalization of a Covered Financial Corporation," setting forth requirements and prohibitions regarding: (1) commencement of a case concerning a covered financial corporation; (2) a special trustee and bridge company; (3) special transfer of the property of the estate in bankruptcy; (4) treatment of qualified financial contracts and affiliate contracts; (5) licenses, permits, and registrations; (6) exemption from securities laws; and (7) inapplicability of certain avoiding powers.

Authorizes the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve, the Securities Exchange Commission (SEC), the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency of the Department of the Treasury, and the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC) to raise and be heard on any issue in any case or proceeding under Subchapter V.

(Sec. 4) Amends the federal judicial code to require the Chief Justice of the United States to designate: (1) at least three appellate judges in at least four circuits to serve on an appellate panel available to hear appeals in a bankruptcy case concerning a covered financial corporation, and (2) a panel of at least 10 bankruptcy judges to be available to hear a case under subchapter V.

Prescribes requirements for the assignment of bankruptcy judges to subchapter V cases.</summary>
</bill>
