<bill session="113" type="h" number="3607" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-11-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-11-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-11-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">State Health Care Choice Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To enable States to opt out of certain provisions of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412474"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412472" joined="2014-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412473" joined="2013-11-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-11-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-21">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-21">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="s" number="1711"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/21/2013--Introduced.
State Health Care Choice Act - Authorizes a state to limit the application of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (PPACA) with respect to health insurance coverage within that state by enacting a law that: (1) expresses the intent of the state to opt out of one or more of the provisions of PPACA, (2) contains a list of the provisions that will not apply to the state, and (3) either expresses the state's intent to continue to administer health coverage-related laws as in effect in the state on March 23, 2010, or provides for the implementation of related state laws enacted after such date.

Sets forth provisions that may be made inapplicable within a state, including provisions related to health coverage, essential health benefits, health insurance exchanges, alternative health plans established by states, individual and employer health coverage requirements,&#160;interoperable protocols for enrollment in federal and state health and human service programs, and expansion of Medicaid coverage.</summary>
</bill>
