<bill session="113" type="s" number="1959" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-01-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-01-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-01-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Quell Unnecessary, Intentional, and Encroaching Telephone Calls Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">QUIET Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to criminalize the knowing use of commercial robocalls without the prior express written consent of the recipient, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300087"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-01-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/27/2014--Introduced.
Quell Unnecessary, Intentional, and Encroaching Telephone Calls Act of 2014 or the QUIET Act - Amends the federal criminal code to prohibit a a person within the United States, or a person outside the United States if the recipient is within the United States, from knowingly initiating a commercial robocall without the prior express written consent of the recipient. Defines "commercial robocall" to mean a telephone call made for the purpose of soliciting or encouraging the purchase or rental of, or investment or enrollment in, property, goods, or services, using an automatic telephone dialing system or an artificial or prerecorded voice.

Exempts telephone calls that: (1) are made for emergency purposes; (2) are by or on behalf of a tax-exempt nonprofit organization; (3) are made by a provider of commercial mobile radio service to subscribers of the service, for which the subscribers are not charged; or (4) deliver a message relating to health care made by, or on behalf of, a covered entity or a business associate of a covered entity.

Subjects any person who violates this Act to a fine of not more than $20,000 per violation, imprisonment for not more than 10 years, or both.</summary>
</bill>
