<bill session="113" type="s" number="1993" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-02-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-02-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-02-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Care Financial Protection Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to protect individuals who are eligible for increased pension under laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs on the basis of need of regular aid and attendance from dishonest, predatory, or otherwise unlawful practices, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412542"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412491" joined="2014-02-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-02-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="5046"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="5708"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/4/2014--Introduced.
Veterans Care Financial Protection Act of 2014 - Requires the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) to: (1) work with federal agencies, states, and such experts as the Secretary considers appropriate to develop and implement federal and state standards that protect individuals who are eligible for increased pension for a non-service-connected disability or death or for service on the basis of need for regular aid and attendance from dishonest, predatory, or otherwise unlawful practices; and (2) submit such standards to specified congressional committees not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.

Requires the Comptroller General: (1) within one year after enactment of this Act, to report standards that would be effective in protecting such individuals if the Secretary fails to submit such standards within such 180 days; and (2) not later than 540 days after enactment of this Act, to complete a study on standards implemented under this Act and report the findings to such committees.</summary>
</bill>
