<bill session="113" type="h" number="4699" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Indian Country Economic Revitalization Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Native American Business Development, Trade Promotion, and Tourism Act of 2000 to require the Secretary of Commerce to prepare and submit to Congress a report and recommendations to promote the sustained economic development of Indian tribes and Indian lands.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412505"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412517" joined="2014-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="2014-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2014-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412584" joined="2014-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412286" joined="2014-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412293" joined="2014-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400259" joined="2014-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400661" joined="2014-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412585" joined="2014-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400660" joined="2014-05-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee Indian and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII24" subcommittee="Indian and Alaska Native Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/21/2014--Introduced.
Indian Country Economic Revitalization Act of 2014 - Amends the Native American Business Development, Trade Promotion, and Tourism Act of 2000 to direct the Secretary of Commerce, within one year of this Act's enactment and every three years thereafter, to submit a report and recommendations for promoting the sustained growth of the economies of Indian tribes and lands.

Requires each report to include:

 data on Indian business development and employment during the preceding 3-year period, except for the first report which is to include data from the preceding 10 years; an assessment of existing structural advantages and barriers to the economic development of Indian tribes and lands; an analysis of Indian access to adequate infrastructure, affordable energy, educational opportunities, and investment capital; and recommendations on legislation to strengthen the economies of Indian tribes and lands in areas that include regulatory, tax, and trust reform. Directs the Secretary to consider appropriate information contained in previous studies and reports in conducting this Act's studies.</summary>
</bill>
