<bill session="113" type="h" number="5414" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Elkhorn Ranch and White River National Forest Patent Correction Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require a patent correction involving the Elkhorn Ranch and the White River National Forest in the State of Colorado to protect bona fide private property rights in the Elkhorn Ranch adversely impacted by a 1949 resurvey of the southern boundary of Section 18 of Township 7 South, Range 93 West, Sixth Principle Meridian, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412405"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412308" joined="2014-09-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="Public Lands and Environmental Regulation" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/8/2014--Introduced.
Elkhorn Ranch and White River National Forest Patent Correction Act of 2014 - Requires: (1) the 148-acre parcel of land depicted on the map entitled "Elkhorn Ranch Land-White River National Forest," dated June 2014, to be patented into the ownership of the Gordman-Leverich Partnership (GLP), a Colorado Limited Liability Limited Partnership; and (2) the patent to include all U.S. rights in and to the parcel, subject to the valid existing rights of the lessee of federal oil and gas lease COC-75070 and any other valid existing rights.

Requires: (1) the Secretary of the Interior to prepare and issue the patent required by this Act, and (2) GLP to bear costs incurred by the Secretary relating to any survey, lotting, legal description, or other activities undertaken in issuing the patent.</summary>
</bill>
