<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="H11c78206-0b06-4955-958b-cffe543567c1" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Reported-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HRES 727 RH: Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2) to remove Federal Government obstacles to the production of more domestic energy; to ensure transport of that energy reliably to businesses, consumers, and other end users; to lower the cost of energy to consumers; to enable manufacturers and other businesses to access domestically produced energy affordably and reliably in order to create and sustain more secure and well-paying American jobs; and for other purposes; providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 4) to make revisions to Federal law to improve the conditions necessary for economic growth and job creation, and for other purposes; and providing for proceedings during the period from September 22, 2014, through November 11, 2014.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2014-09-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<calendar display="yes">House Calendar No. 141</calendar>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 727</legis-num>
		<associated-doc display="yes" role="report">[Report No. 113–601]</associated-doc>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20140916">September 16, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc><cosponsor name-id="S000250">Mr. Sessions</cosponsor>, from the <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</committee-name>, reported the following resolution; which was referred to the House Calendar and ordered to be
			 printed</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2) to remove Federal Government obstacles to the
			 production of more domestic energy; to ensure transport of that energy
			 reliably to businesses, consumers, and other end users; to lower the cost
			 of energy to consumers; to enable manufacturers and other businesses to
			 access domestically produced energy affordably and reliably in order to
			 create and sustain more secure and well-paying American jobs; and for
			 other purposes; providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 4) to make
			 revisions to Federal law to improve the conditions necessary for economic
			 growth and job creation, and for other purposes; and providing for
			 proceedings during the period from September 22, 2014, through November
			 11, 2014.</official-title>
	</form>
	<resolution-body id="H9b51825c-326d-4f02-9152-43e4fd53d8e9" style="traditional">
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H97f9b8e8-5f62-4146-8db4-cb7dc1c454f9" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That upon adoption of this resolution it shall be in order to consider in the House the bill (H.R.
			 2) to remove Federal Government obstacles to the production of more
			 domestic energy; to ensure transport of that energy reliably to
			 businesses, consumers, and other end users; to lower the cost of energy to
			 consumers; to enable manufacturers and other businesses to access
			 domestically produced energy affordably and reliably in order to create
			 and sustain more secure and well-paying American jobs; and for other
			 purposes. All points of order against consideration of the bill are
			 waived. The bill shall be considered as read. All points of order against
			 provisions in the bill are waived. The previous question shall be
			 considered as ordered on the bill and on any amendment thereto to final
			 passage without intervening motion except: (1) two hours of debate equally
			 divided and controlled by the chair and ranking minority member of the
			 Committee on Natural Resources or their respective designees; and (2) one
			 motion to recommit.</text>
		</section><section id="HC34A34070217485384608D5F236E6929"><enum>2.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon adoption of this resolution it shall be in order to consider in the House the bill (H.R. 4) to
			 make revisions to Federal law to improve the conditions necessary for
			 economic growth and job creation, and for other purposes. All points of
			 order against consideration of the bill are waived. The bill shall be
			 considered as read. All points of order against provisions in the bill are
			 waived. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the bill
			 and on any amendment thereto to final passage without intervening motion
			 except: (1) two hours of debate equally divided and controlled by the
			 chair and ranking minority member of the Committee on Ways and Means or
			 their respective designees; and (2) one motion to recommit.</text>
		</section><section id="H048E5242BC2D4E00975BD094A97A8F8F"><enum>3.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On any legislative day during the period from September 22, 2014, through November 11, 2014,—</text>
			<subsection id="HF03B5265E60C4B66B5995B02D9A50805"><enum>(a)</enum><text>the Journal of the proceedings of the previous day shall be considered as approved; and</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H8955955C39B14043B658803387D2385E"><enum>(b)</enum><text>the Chair may at any time declare the House adjourned to meet at a date and time, within the limits
			 of clause 4, section 5, article I of the Constitution, to be announced by
			 the Chair in declaring the adjournment.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H680A0EA9F0574D809B14B1BDF5624B97"><enum>4.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Speaker may appoint Members to perform the duties of the Chair for the duration of the period
			 addressed by section 3 of this resolution as though under clause 8(a) of
			 rule I.</text>
		</section><section id="H33B3EECE156D4A8B9D1D34AFD79E3E03"><enum>5.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each day during the period addressed by section 3 of this resolution shall not constitute a
			 calendar day for purposes of section 7 of the War Powers Resolution (50
			 U.S.C. 1546).</text>
		</section><section id="H749E6DBC56DE409BBD0706D2A94EB1E6"><enum>6.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each day during the period addressed by section 3 of this resolution shall not constitute a
			 legislative day for purposes of clause 7 of rule XIII.</text>
		</section></resolution-body>
	<endorsement><action-date>September 16, 2014</action-date><action-desc>Referred to the House Calendar and ordered to be
			 printed</action-desc></endorsement></resolution>


