<bill session="113" type="h" number="4782" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-05-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">BUILD Career and Technical Education Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Building Understanding, Investment, Learning, and Direction Career and Technical Education Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a pilot grant program to support career and technical education exploration programs in middle schools and high schools.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412315"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412258" joined="2014-05-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2014-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412584" joined="2014-05-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400230" joined="2014-05-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412209" joined="2014-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400271" joined="2014-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412523" joined="2014-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412308" joined="2014-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412579" joined="2014-05-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1293"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/30/2014--Introduced.
Building Understanding, Investment, Learning, and Direction Career and Technical Education Act of 2014 or the BUILD Career and Technical Education Act of 2014 - Directs the Secretary of Education to award competitive two-year grants to local educational agencies to support career and technical education exploration programs that provide middle and high school students with experiential learning opportunities that are connected to their education and career pathways.

Requires grant funds to be used for: (1) leasing, purchasing, upgrading, or adapting equipment related to program activities; (2) staff expenses in coordinating or implementing program activities; (3) consultation services that are directly aligned to program goals; (4) professional development programs that are aligned to program goals; (5) minor remodeling to accommodate program equipment; and/or (6) program evaluation.

Requires each grantee to develop a plan to evaluate grant activities that includes an evaluation of specified outcomes.</summary>
</bill>
