<bill session="113" type="h" number="5649" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">United Nations Human Rights Council Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To promote transparency, accountability, and reform within the United Nations Human Rights Council, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400344"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412526" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412569" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412525" joined="2014-09-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3155"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/18/2014--Introduced.
United Nations Human Rights Council Accountability Act - Provides that until the Secretary of State makes a specified certification to Congress: (1) the Secretary shall withhold from a U.S. contribution to a regular budget of the United Nations (U.N.) an amount equal to the amount that would be allocated for the United Nations Human Rights Council (UNHRC), (2) the Secretary shall not make a voluntary contribution to UNHRC, and (3) the United States shall not run for a UNHRC seat.

Directs the Secretary to withhold from a U.S. contribution to a regular budget of the U.N. an amount equal to the amount that would be allocated for: (1) the U.N. Special Rapporteur on the situation of human rights in Palestinian territories occupied since 1967; and (2) any other U.N. Special Procedures used to display bias against the United States or Israel or to provide support for any member state which is subject to U.N. Security Council sanctions, under a Security Council-mandated human rights investigation, has repeatedly supported acts of international terrorism, or is a country of particular concern for religious freedom.</summary>
</bill>
