<bill session="113" type="hr" number="655" updated="2015-09-01T10:18:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Relating to the application of Article II, section 3, clause 5, of the Constitution of the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400196"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Rules, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-07">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-07">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU10" subcommittee="Constitution and Civil Justice" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hr" number="654"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hr" number="656"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
    <term name="Congressional-executive branch relations"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/7/2014--Introduced.
Declares that the Secretary of the Treasury has failed to meet the specified requirement of the U.S. Constitution to take care that a law be faithfully executed, with respect to the departmental policy provided under the Department of the Treasury Notice 2013-45, as announced by the Department on July 2, 2013, pertaining to the one-year delay in the application of the Internal Revenue Code with respect to reporting requirements by providers of health insurance coverage, certain employers required to report on health insurance coverage, and related requirements under the Code concerning shared responsibility for employers regarding health coverage.

Requires the House of Representatives to bring a civil action in the U.S. District Court for the District of Columbia for declaratory or injunctive relief to challenge the Secretary.</summary>
</bill>
