<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HD3605A5048F94235824212B74040FB25" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HR 5836 IH: Rare Cats and Canids Act of 2014</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2014-12-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 5836</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20141210">December 10, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="J000255">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To assist in the conservation of rare felids and rare canids by supporting and providing financial
			 resources for the conservation programs of nations within the range of
			 rare felid and rare canid populations and projects of persons with
			 demonstrated expertise in the conservation of rare felid and rare canid
			 populations.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HB66771C182094BEF9C42BB0C2065E0F5" style="OLC">
		<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA5B2AF95313A409782528D764AA16C2F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Rare Cats and Canids Act of 2014</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="H394906E1C6A14BF696E52C178E1595F1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purposes of this Act are to provide financial resources and to foster international
			 cooperation—</text>
			<paragraph id="HC39EA97783B049F2BC939F4435F5D895"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to restore and perpetuate healthy populations of rare felids and rare canids in the wild; and</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HB62B5EC9096842AFB7A82673D2E95148"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to assist in the conservation of rare felid and rare canid populations worldwide.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HF387C8C980B34A46A82055BF8C7ECC9C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
			<paragraph id="H829896EB173C4B8B9BC8164225E8EF46"><enum>(1)</enum><header>CITES</header><text>The term <quote>CITES</quote> means the Convention on International Trade in Endangered Species of Wild Fauna and Flora, done at
			 Washington March 3, 1973 (27 UST 1087; TIAS 8249), including its
			 appendices.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HB4970BD17D8A42F3B6465C722C05096D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conservation</header><text>The term <quote>conservation</quote>—</text>
				<subparagraph id="HF456B1EA91A1436489B233EE634500E3"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means the methods and procedures necessary to bring a population, subspecies, species, or taxon of
			 rare felid or rare canid to the point at which there are sufficient
			 populations in the wild to ensure its long-term viability; and</text>
				</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD60950B8CDE849D485050BEFCB4B7180"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes all activities associated with protection and management of a population, subspecies,
			 species, or taxon of rare felid or rare canid, including—</text>
					<clause id="H9BDE679695CC4F6A98025BB3341D2273"><enum>(i)</enum><text>maintenance, management, protection, and restoration of rare felid or rare canid habitat;</text>
					</clause><clause id="H14BCF66A829A48EAAAA8CD31C2581B7B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>research and monitoring;</text>
					</clause><clause id="HBA8249B7279D468F9D3C2DF8FE45CF76"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>law enforcement;</text>
					</clause><clause id="H5B5185AFFD224BE99F0EB426B79744A6"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>community outreach and education;</text>
					</clause><clause id="HFA2044707BD24715BB980FE806242734"><enum>(v)</enum><text>conflict resolution initiatives; and</text>
					</clause><clause id="H45C7A2125A3541FFB6C699246CAE6205"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>strengthening the capacity of local communities, governmental agencies, nongovernmental
			 organizations and other institutions to implement conservation programs.</text>
					</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H11CD82E49FFD4AC997FDF97455438305"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Fund</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Fund</quote> means the Rare Cats and Canids Conservation Fund established by section 5.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H7C99C5DDD76145F9BAE3417433EB0A9D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>IUCN Red List</header><text>The term <quote>IUCN Red List</quote> means the Red List of Threatened Species Maintained by the World Conservation Union.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H035623507F11410CBE1E2D092E5C4F0B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Rare canid</header>
				<subparagraph id="HEC28081335814DF2898CFFD7F5DE7CB1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the term <quote>rare canid</quote> means any population, subspecies, species, or taxon in the family Canidae that is listed in the
			 IUCN Red List as near threatened, vulnerable, endangered, or critically
			 endangered.</text>
				</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2E83389CAC36468195BBAD247F192368"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>The term <quote>rare canid</quote> does not include any subspecies or population that is native to the area comprised of the United
			 States and Canada.</text>
				</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB5F764B3DA494081935A57759B5940F2"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Rare Felid</header>
				<subparagraph id="H97F6D30E54724F43B4BB30A153A42807"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the term <quote>rare felid</quote> means any population, subspecies, species, or taxon in the family Felidae that is listed in the
			 IUCN Red List as near threatened, vulnerable, endangered, or critically
			 endangered.</text>
				</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCFE919EDB7DB4BBF91B873908E50751F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>The term <quote>rare felid</quote> does not include—</text>
					<clause id="H1D75668E8C0C4362B9460B1FD198C0C6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any subspecies or population that is native to the area comprised of the United States and Canada;
			 and</text>
					</clause><clause id="HC95A01130E7B4DF1A1497720E2908B84"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any tiger (Panthera tigris).</text>
					</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF2F3E598AF1043C182946A3BF9FBA159"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HCFAB4973A886417090A3F32D24B715AF"><enum>4.</enum><header>Financial assistance</header>
			<subsection id="HC0ED0B766A504846B98C4EAF70697ECC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text>Subject to the availability of funds and in consultation with other appropriate Federal officials,
			 the Secretary shall use amounts in the Fund to provide financial
			 assistance for projects for the conservation of rare felid and rare canids
			 for which project proposals are approved by the Secretary in accordance
			 with this section.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H36CCE924649446B28770027ACF6645BD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Project Proposals</header>
				<paragraph id="H871250F3C5ED44DDB530BF3FAD7A0B61"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible applicants</header><text>A proposal for a project for the conservation of rare felid and canids may be submitted to the
			 Secretary by—</text>
					<subparagraph id="HBB371CD27E3C40B09E118526BF17FEA2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any wildlife management authority of a country that has within its boundaries any part of the range
			 of a rare felid or rare canid, respectively; and</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD830776B006949F3917A83A063A6C396"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any person or group with the demonstrated expertise required for the conservation in the wild of
			 rare felids or rare canids, respectively.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H43BD20704CCB4F61AE56CA500A9BA440"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Project proposals</header><text>To be considered for financial assistance for a project under this Act, an applicant shall submit a
			 project proposal that includes—</text>
					<subparagraph id="HD8AD160594F9452490593075547C89E2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a concise statement of the purposes of the project;</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF5DCF7E6140746A0999E39BCCF6BBEDF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the name of the individual responsible for conducting the project;</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D97A4A64C554AB29CE74C99A9409366"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of the qualifications of the individuals who will conduct the project;</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE207210E840A4E37A36C41FD8D2E5D4A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a concise description of—</text>
						<clause id="HFD0BC86590E0471C86FB22281D6AF31B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>methods for project implementation and outcome assessment;</text>
						</clause><clause id="H6DB49BCD3BED47B1A85513804937F587"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>staffing for the project;</text>
						</clause><clause id="H518C951941AD455D87669A60313918C1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the logistics of the project; and</text>
						</clause><clause id="H0DCA1BC0ABAC458A83990CC1A9219F40"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>community involvement in the project;</text>
						</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFD7649BB4BC648AAB4E5D7563BB1401A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>an estimate of funds and time required to complete the project;</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF1746880C98E4488B9B61D0B2450BEA3"><enum>(F)</enum><text>evidence of support for the project by appropriate governmental entities of the countries in which
			 the project will be conducted, if the Secretary determines that such
			 support is required for the success of the project;</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H103F304AFEA84FD2B3302E621EA1A53E"><enum>(G)</enum><text>information regarding the source and amount of matching funding available for the project; and</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB07B5DDF18104BF991071D3367B70DAB"><enum>(H)</enum><text>any other information that the Secretary considers to be necessary for evaluating the eligibility
			 of the project for funding under this Act.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H895D03240C1D4EA9B19A375C8369DDE4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Project Review and Approval</header>
				<paragraph id="H58ECB5084C284BD3962A1A82D32A2E45"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text>
					<subparagraph id="H3A63E4176B6349DF9A504E1951402405"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not later than 30 days after receiving a project proposal, provide a copy of the proposal to the
			 appropriate Federal officials; and</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3CFB413A1D664265862346978C56AF9A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>review each project proposal in a timely manner to determine if the proposal meets the criteria
			 specified in subsection (d).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H492E643B1FD9403D9930D2D3680AE815"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation; approval or disapproval</header><text>Not later than 180 days after receiving a project proposal, and subject to the availability of
			 funds, the Secretary, after consulting with other appropriate Federal
			 officials, shall—</text>
					<subparagraph id="HCFAD0569799A4BF89DC63088506EBD90"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensure the proposal contains assurances that the project will be implemented in consultation with
			 relevant wildlife management authorities and other appropriate government
			 officials with jurisdiction over the resources addressed by the project;</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC522A5F870DC47D085C6F7D08AF63505"><enum>(B)</enum><text>approve or disapprove the proposal; and</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBED879AA6FCE4D398CB55D7E5CDFC89A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provide written notification of the approval or disapproval to the person who submitted the
			 proposal, other appropriate Federal officials, and each country within
			 whose borders the project will take place.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC251D00EE84F460F817EABAF4EB2EFCD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Criteria for Approval</header><text>The Secretary may approve a project proposal under this section if the project will contribute to
			 conservation of rare felids or rare canids in the wild by assisting
			 efforts to—</text>
				<paragraph id="H1AE2EAE682CF4A1EB440A3E25716D0C9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>implement conservation programs;</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H0BC353C6AAC34EEDACAB941F12F99ACE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>address the conflicts between humans and rare felids or rare canids, respectively, that arise from
			 competition for the same habitat or resources;</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H57C5EA6286FD4AB392A6E002966A82EB"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enhance compliance with CITES, the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.</external-xref>), and
			 other applicable laws that prohibit or regulate the taking or trade of
			 rare felids and rare canids or regulate the use and management of rare
			 felid and rare canid habitat;</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H0EDF00D5CB0143009FD0CDAA6AED8DD2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>develop sound scientific information on, or methods for monitoring—</text>
					<subparagraph id="HB5EBAEED3CE140B4892D679272CC6C55"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the condition and health of rare felid or rare canid habitat;</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H49BA0DED6CD84287A44881BDEBD35FBF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>rare felid or rare canid population numbers and trends; and</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFF60EB4B56B24BA49D51045D574489AA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the ecological characteristics and requirements of populations of rare felids or rare canids for
			 which there are little or no data;</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7A2160FD8BE549AEA0B09D5138C35B67"><enum>(5)</enum><text>promote cooperative projects among government entities, affected local communities, nongovernmental
			 organizations, and other persons in the private sector; or</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H23EA82837DE647D39E1A654BFC999F47"><enum>(6)</enum><text>funds will not be appropriated for the purchase or lease of lands to be used as suitable habitat
			 for felids or canids.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD71AC5F75B89416185246E72F57FCA8A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Project Sustainability</header><text>In approving project proposals under this section, the Secretary shall give preference to
			 conservation projects that are designed to ensure effective, long-term
			 conservation of rare felids and rare canids and their habitats.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H267A7C364D7E4A0B9CF2AB62DDE4AFB1"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Matching Funds</header><text>In determining whether to approve project proposals under this section, the Secretary shall give
			 preference to projects for which there exists some measure of matching
			 funds.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H5D8E5284412148A6A2317D0020B4ADD3"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Project Reporting</header>
				<paragraph id="HFDE4A63C4AAD43D38C75A89272DC5185"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each person that receives assistance under this section for a project shall submit to the Secretary
			 periodic reports (at such intervals as the Secretary considers necessary)
			 that include all information that the Secretary, after consultation with
			 other appropriate government officials, determines is necessary to
			 evaluate the progress and success of the project for the purposes of
			 ensuring positive results, assessing problems, and fostering improvements.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H67C8C344A762463DB7BACF8A97794147"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Availability to the public</header><text>Reports under paragraph (1), and any other documents relating to projects for which financial
			 assistance is provided under this Act, shall be made available to the
			 public.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H56689089B8E34EA78BC864E8223E6BE7"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Limitations on Use for Captive Breeding or Display</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts provided as a grant under this Act may not be used for captive breeding unless as part of
			 an accredited reintroduction or restoration program.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HB68765F052994982A7C8D93038B52580"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Advisory Group</header>
				<paragraph id="H8ECD2ACC37574A339C553AA2430932F1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To assist in carrying out this Act, the Secretary may convene an advisory group consisting of
			 individuals representing public and private organizations actively
			 involved in the conservation of felids and canids.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H50DDDE3C619F4C0CB96FFE3EC2B8030D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public participation</header>
					<subparagraph id="H27DD3C6F8731474A983BA19C8B007C00"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>The advisory group shall—</text>
						<clause id="H9976E37BF2AF4E0DB635B8D2E9872097"><enum>(i)</enum><text>ensure that each meeting of the advisory group is open to the public; and</text>
						</clause><clause id="HDF59E3F6489B47AC938CBCE280393673"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provide, at each meeting, an opportunity for interested persons to present oral or written
			 statements concerning items on the agenda.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0FEC64422B3F4B5D96EEB37F59ACC046"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>The Secretary shall provide to the public timely notice of each meeting of the advisory group,
			 including the meeting agenda.</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H03B67B145F974726A13642AD07811D42"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Minutes</header><text>Minutes of each meeting of the advisory group shall be kept by the Secretary and shall be made
			 available to the public.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3AD62243D5774312854E335CF7EF6A7F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exemption from Federal Advisory Committee Act</header><text>The Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.) shall not apply to the advisory group.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HEC0E3D0476124BA296DA67040F47FB11"><enum>5.</enum><header>Rare Cats and Canids Conservation Fund</header>
			<subsection id="HC8DAD0071E734BBBA9D5B01879C7DE6A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established, in the Multinational Species Conservation Fund established in title I of the
			 Department of the Interior and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1999
			 under the heading <quote>MULTINATIONAL SPECIES CONSERVATION FUND</quote>, a separate account to be known as the <quote>Rare Cats and Canids Conservation Fund</quote>, consisting of—</text>
				<paragraph id="H138889C08EC442B684BAEE656EAEBFAE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>amounts transferred to the Secretary of the Treasury for deposit into such account under subsection
			 (c); and</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H29378F69FE824323835A8CA5CF2CB237"><enum>(2)</enum><text>amounts appropriated to such account under section 6.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3B5C3CCC69014FD2867F70688E4D40E5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Expenditures From Fund</header>
				<paragraph id="HA0310D50961E4F1487D4E3522514F036"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), upon request by the Secretary, the Secretary of the Treasury shall
			 transfer from the Fund to the Secretary, without further appropriation,
			 such amounts as the Secretary determines are necessary to provide
			 assistance under section 4.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H37B080AD47B84EB79C6B12A23A6D8087"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administrative expenses</header><text>Of the amounts in the Fund available for each fiscal year, the Secretary may expend not more than
			 three percent, or up to $100,000, whichever is greater, to pay the
			 administrative expenses necessary to carry out this Act.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5BEA5AA91F2B4A4D938979A8E48C086B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Acceptance and Use of Donations</header><text>The Secretary may accept and use donations to provide assistance under section 4, and may make
			 public on the Internet Web site and in publications of the Department of
			 the Interior that the Secretary is authorized to accept and use such
			 donations. Amounts received by the Secretary in the form of such donations
			 shall be transferred to the Secretary of the Treasury for deposit into the
			 Fund.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H8BF3FD55099E4D89B57097DBCCE2046A"><enum>6.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Fund, $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2015
			 through 2019 to carry out this Act.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


