<bill session="113" type="s" number="1418" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-08-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-08-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Witness Security and Protection Grant Program Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Attorney General to make competitive grants to State, tribal, and local governments to establish and maintain witness protection and assistance programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400064"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="2884"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Organized crime"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/1/2013--Introduced.
Witness Security and Protection Grant Program Act of 2013 - Directs the Attorney General to: (1) make competitive grants to state, tribal, and local governments to establish or maintain programs that provide protection or assistance to witnesses in court proceedings involving a homicide, a serious violent felony, a serious drug offense,&#160;gangs, or organized crime; (2) evaluate grant applicants based on specified criteria, including the prevalence of witness intimidation and the number of such crimes per capita in the applicant's jurisdiction; (3) provide technical assistance to applicants for establishing or maintaining such programs; and (4) develop and disseminate best practice models to assist such governments in addressing witness safety, short-term and permanent witness relocation, financial and housing assistance, and other necessary witness protection or assistance services. Urges such governments to use such models to evaluate, improve, and develop witness protection or witness assistance programs.</summary>
</bill>
