<bill session="113" type="h" number="5154" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Open Government Technology Work to More Businesses Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Administrator of the Small Business Administration and the Administrator of General Services to make rules to streamline and simplify the registration system used by small business concerns, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412523"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412522" joined="2014-09-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="General Services Administration"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/17/2014--Introduced.
Open Government Technology Work to More Businesses Act - Directs the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) and the Administrator of General Services (GSA) to jointly make rules to: (1) streamline and simplify the registration system used by small businesses to be considered for an award of any federal contract, (2) establish procedures by which a small business may self-certify its eligibility for a federal contract under the Small Business Act, and (3) establish procedures by which a majority of small businesses may complete the registration process within four weeks after beginning it.

Requires both Administrators to make the registration system available in a unified electronic format accessible through the Internet.</summary>
</bill>
