<bill session="113" type="h" number="3512" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-11-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-11-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-11-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Seniors' Health Care Choice Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to facilitate the transition to Medicare for individuals enrolled in group health plans, to establish a 3-month open enrollment period under Medicare Advantage, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412446"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400640" joined="2014-11-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-11-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-15">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-15">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/15/2013--Introduced.
Seniors' Health Care Choice Act of 2013 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to establish: (1) a special enrollment period under Medicare part B (Supplementary Medical Insurance) for an individual enrolled in COBRA (health insurance continuation benefits) continuation coverage who elected not to enroll under part B during the individual's initial enrollment period, and (2) a three-month open enrollment period starting with 2014 and recurring in the first three months of each subsequent year in which a Medicare Advantage (MA)-eligible individual under Medicare part C (Medicare+Choice) may change his or her Medicare enrollment election.</summary>
</bill>
