<bill session="113" type="h" number="3703" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-12-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-12-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-12-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Approve the Pipeline Now Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the expedited approval of the construction, operation, and maintenance of the Keystone XL pipeline, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400221"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-12-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Foreign Affairs, Energy and Commerce, and Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-11">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-11">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-11">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-11">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW14" subcommittee="Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="Public Lands and Environmental Regulation" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/11/2013--Introduced.
Approve the Pipeline Now Act - Directs the Secretary of State to: (1) issue a Presidential permit approving the pipeline described in a specified application filed by TransCanada Keystone Pipeline, L.P. to the Department of State for the Keystone XL pipeline, as supplemented to include the Nebraska reroute evaluated in a certain Final Evaluation Report issued by the Nebraska Department of Environmental Quality; and (2) issue a final environmental impact statement for such pipeline.

Deems such final environmental impact statement, coupled with the Final Evaluation Report, to satisfy all requirements of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969, the National Historic Preservation Act, and the Endangered Species Act of 1973.

Prohibits the expenditure of federal funds to pay more than 75% of the salary of any senior official in the Department of State if either the Presidential permit or the final environmental impact statement remains unissued 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act.

Directs the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of the Army to issue all permits associated with the pipeline project that were applied for before enactment of this Act.

Prohibits the expenditure of federal funds, if the relevant permit remains unissued 30 days after enactment of this Act, to pay more than 75% of the salary of: (1) any senior official in the Department of the Interior, or (2) the Secretary of the Army and the Assistant Secretary of the Army for Civil Works.</summary>
</bill>
