<bill session="113" type="s" number="2674" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Columbia River Basin Restoration Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to establish within the Environmental Protection Agency a Columbia River Basin Restoration Program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412325"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2014-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412602" joined="2014-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2014-07-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="5216"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Pacific Ocean"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/28/2014--Introduced.
Columbia River Basin Restoration Act of 2014 - Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act) to require the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to establish a Columbia River Basin Restoration Program to reduce toxic contamination and clean up contaminated sites. Requires the program to be collaborative and stakeholder-based.

Requires the EPA to: (1) assess trends in water quality and toxic contamination or toxics reduction; (2) collect, characterize and assess data on toxics and water quality to identify possible causes of environmental problems; (3) update the Columbia River Basin Toxics Reduction Plan (Action Plan) and the Estuary Partnership Comprehensive Conservation and Management Plan (Estuary Plan) and ensure that the plans form a coherent toxic contamination reduction strategy; and (4) provide technical assistance in implementing and updating the Action Plan.

Directs the EPA to establish a Columbia River Basin Toxics Reduction Working Group to: (1) participate in developing updates to the Action Plan, (2) recommend and prioritize projects and actions for the Action Plan, and (3) review progress made.

Requires the Lower Columbia River Estuary Partnership to perform those duties and fulfill those responsibilities of the Working Group relating to the Lower Columbia River Estuary.

Requires the EPA to establish a Columbia River Basin toxics grant program to provide funding to develop or implement projects to implement the Action Plan and the Estuary Plan.</summary>
</bill>
