<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="HF7227ED765284DBD9B0DC326BC2DB3E0" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HRES 698 IH: Condemning the attack that occurred at the Oak Creek Sikh Gurdwara on August 5, 2012, and honoring the memory of those who died in the attack.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2014-07-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 698</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20140730">July 30, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000129">Mr. Valadao</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001181">Mr. Meehan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000295">Mr. Joyce</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000570">Mr. Ryan of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000587">Mr. Ribble</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001034">Mr. Honda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000595">Mr. Peters of Michigan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001032">Mr. Holt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000128">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000188">Mr. Kind</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000181">Mr. Nunes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000215">Ms. Eshoo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001245">Ms. Bordallo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson of Indiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001038">Mr. Crowley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell of California</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Condemning the attack that occurred at the Oak Creek Sikh Gurdwara on August 5, 2012, and honoring
			 the memory of those who died in the attack.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas><text>Whereas, on Sunday, August 5, 2012, a mass shooting took place, fueled by intolerance, killing 6
			 worshipers at the Sikh Temple of Wisconsin, a Gurdwara, in Oak Creek,
			 Wisconsin;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the attack occurred as members of the congregation prepared langar, a free community meal
			 served to all visitors to Gurdwaras, regardless of their race, religion,
			 sex, or social background;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 4 individuals were injured including a responding officer, Lieutenant Brian Murphy, who was
			 shot 15 times at close range;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Lieutenant Brian Murphy and all the first responders to the Oak Creek Gurdwara demonstrated
			 great courage in their quick response to the shooting, ultimately saving
			 lives;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas in the United States, Sikhs have endured high levels of stereotyping, bullying, and
			 violence, all of which rose dramatically in the wake of the attacks of
			 September 11, 2001;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Associated Press reported that more than 700 such incidents of intolerance targeting
			 Sikhs took place over the last decade;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Oak Creek shooting was one of the most lethal attacks on a place of worship in the
			 United States since the 1963 bombing of the 16th Street Baptist Church and
			 another sad example of violence and intolerance against Sikhs;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Sikh community responded to the shooting in Oak Creek with compassion and stayed true
			 to the Sikh principle of Chardi Kala, remaining in high spirits;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas although the effects of this shooting will be felt for years to come, the Oak Creek
			 community will continue to overcome the tragedy and become stronger than
			 before with a renewed sense of oneness, understanding, and cooperation;
			 and</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the August 5, 2012, shooting was not just a Sikh tragedy, but an American tragedy: Now,
			 therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body id="HBF702D19F5074F868D762CE14CE61A04" style="traditional">
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H220596E7B29043C78B1934D941459FA2" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the House of Representatives—</text>
			<paragraph id="HCAAD6214E11E428687A5D202B6FF5AB1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">condemns in the strongest possible terms the horrific attack that occurred at the Sikh Temple of
			 Wisconsin on August 5, 2012;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H9199A20AC110472F9E479CBC7920AD55"><enum>(2)</enum><text>honors the memory of Suveg Singh Khattra, Satwant Singh Kaleka, Ranjit Singh, Sita Singh, Paramjit
			 Kaur, and Prakash Singh, who died in the attack;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H98D8BE20EA154E32B9136E8A31F72D6A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>offers its heartfelt condolences to the families, friends, and loved ones of those who died in the
			 attack;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HFF5F8C6EACF34CC4B42411E250D347F9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>applauds the bravery of Lieutenant Brian Murphy and other first responders who prevented the gunman
			 from potentially taking more lives and quickly treated wounded
			 individuals; and</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HB66EE5BB5B6E4C16AB90AC951695C882"><enum>(5)</enum><text>condemns intolerance, including religious and racial discrimination, and calls for continued
			 vigilance against violence.</text>
			</paragraph></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


