<bill session="113" type="s" number="1252" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-11-21">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-11-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Upper Missisquoi and Trout Wild and Scenic Rivers Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Upper Missisquoi and Trout Wild and Scenic Rivers Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate segments of the Missisquoi River and the Trout River in the State of Vermont, as components of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400357"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2013-06-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-31">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 113-93.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-11-21" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-05-22">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Landrieu without amendment. With written report No. 113-170.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-05-22" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="396">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 396.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="National Parks" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="2569"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2569"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Vermont"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/22/2014--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Upper Missisquoi and Trout Wild and Scenic Rivers Act - Amends the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate two segments of the Missisquoi River and one segment of the Trout River in Vermont as components of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System to be administered by the Secretary of the Interior as a recreational river.

Requires the river segments designated by this Act to be managed in accordance with the Upper Missisquoi and Trout Rivers Management Plan.

Requires the Secretary to coordinate the management responsibilities with the Upper Missisquoi and Trout Rivers Wild and Scenic Committee.

Authorizes the Secretary to enter into cooperative agreements for the protection, preservation, and enhancement of the river segments with: (1) the state of Vermont; (2) specific municipalities; and (3) local, regional, statewide, or multistate planning, environmental, or recreational organizations.

 States that the designation of the river segments does not: (1) preclude the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) from licensing, relicensing, or otherwise authorizing the operation of specified hydroelectric projects; or (2) limit the modernization, upgrades, or other changes to the projects. Prohibits resource protection, mitigation, or enhancement measures required by FERC hydropower proceedings from being considered project works under this Act. Permits such measures within the segments.

Considers zoning ordinances adopted by specific towns as satisfying provisions in the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act that prohibit the Secretary from acquiring lands by condemnation within a designated Wild and Scenic River boundary when certain local zoning ordinances are in place.

 Limits the authority of the Secretary to acquire lands under this Act to acquisition by donation or with the owner's consent.

Bars the Missisquoi and Trout Rivers from being administered as part of the National Park System.

Directs the Secretary, upon determining that there is adequate local support for the designation of an additional segment in Vermont, to publish a notice of the designation in the Federal Register, designate the additional segment, and administer the additional segment as a recreational river.</summary>
</bill>
