<bill session="113" type="h" number="5316" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safely Exacting Cautious Useful Rules for Immigration This Year (SECURITY) Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To secure the border between the United States and Mexico.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410396"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Homeland Security, Ways and Means, Armed Services, and Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border and Maritime Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Border Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM11" subcommittee="Border and Maritime Security" name="House Homeland Security"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2778"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crimes against property"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Military civil functions"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Military readiness"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Normal trade relations, most-favored-nation treatment"/>
    <term name="Organized crime"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Smuggling and trafficking"/>
    <term name="Tax treatment of families"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2014--Introduced.
Safely Exacting Cautious Useful Rules for Immigration This Year (SECURITY) Act - Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) (Secretary) to submit to Congress a plan to achieve operational control of the international land and maritime borders of the United States.

 Directs the Secretary to submit to Congress a plan to construct and finish within 10 years double-layered reinforced fencing on the southern border.

Directs the Secretary of Defense (DOD) to: (1) deploy at least an additional 10,000 members of the National Guard for border control activities along the U.S.-Mexico border until the Secretary certifies that the federal government has achieved operational control of the southern border, and (2) provide funds to the governor of a state who submits a qualifying state border control activities plan.

Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to expand the grounds for extending an alien's removal (and detention) period beyond 90 days.

Directs the Secretary to establish an administrative review process (for aliens who are not subject to mandatory detention) to determine whether and how to release aliens who have received, and attempted to comply with, a final order of removal but have been unable to be returned by the United States to their country of origin.

 Establishes visa, trade, and foreign assistance sanctions against a country that refuses or unreasonably delays U.S. repatriation of an alien who is a citizen, national, subject, or resident of that country.

Authorizes the Secretary to designate groups as criminal street gangs. Requires detention for anyone found inadmissible or deportable for criminal street gang membership. Bars individuals found inadmissible or deportable for such membership from withholding of removal, asylum, or temporary protected status.

 Requires annual reports to Congress regarding: (1) the number, if any, of additional immigration judges needed to process the backlog of removal cases; and (2) the number, if any, of additional detention beds and detention space needed to hold criminal aliens and aliens without lawful presence or lawful status.

Amends the Internal Revenue Code to expand the identification requirements for the child tax credit to require taxpayers to provide valid identification numbers on their tax returns in addition to the names and identification numbers of each qualifying child.

States that any alien who is an illegal entrant or who is in possession of invalid entry documents and who gains lawful status pursuant to an Act of Congress, or lawful status or lawful presence pursuant to an executive order or policy directive shall not be qualified for public benefits.

Taxes at a 10% rate monetary remittances sent from U.S. senders to recipients in any of the top ten remittance recipient nations.

Prohibits a federal agency or instrumentality from using federal funding or resources to: (1) adjudicate any new or previously denied application of any alien requesting consideration of deferred action for childhood arrivals, as authorized by executive memorandum on August 15, 2012; or (2) authorize any alien to work in the United States who was not lawfully admitted into the United States and who is not in lawful U.S. status on the date of enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
