<bill session="113" type="h" number="3778" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-12-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-12-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-12-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">EARLY Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Expanded Access to Real Learning for our Young Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Education to award grants to States to pay the Federal share of carrying out full-day prekindergarten programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400097"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400030" joined="2014-01-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400218" joined="2014-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412319" joined="2014-01-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-12-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/16/2013--Introduced.
Expanded Access to Real Learning for our Young Act or the EARLY Act - Authorizes the Secretary of Education to award competitive grants to states to carry out full-day prekindergarten programs.

Requires those programs to:

 be located at public schools, if practicable, or otherwise carried out by private or other community providers; permit parents, regardless of income, to voluntary enroll their four-year old children in the programs and do so at no cost if their combined income does not exceed 400% of the poverty line; be full-day programs that run the length of the regular school year; maintain a maximum class size of 20 children, with at least 1 prekindergarten teacher per classroom; ensure that the ratio of children to prekindergarten teachers and teacher aides does not exceed 10 to 1; be taught by teachers who are paid a salary comparable to kindergarten through grade 12 teachers at the state's public schools; and meet a minimum level of parental engagement set by the state. Requires the Secretary to give grant priority to states that carry out such programs at public schools.

Prohibits the federal share of a grant from exceeding 75% of the prekindergarten program's costs.</summary>
</bill>
