<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="H5F786080222A4EC5808F3CE0F4FC1C4C" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HRES 562 IH: Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives with respect to enhanced relations with the Republic of Moldova and support for Moldova’s territorial integrity.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2014-05-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 562</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20140501">May 1, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000373">Mr. Pitts</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="E000179">Mr. Engel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000523">Mr. Price of North Carolina</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives with respect to enhanced relations with the
			 Republic of Moldova and support for Moldova’s territorial integrity.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas><text>Whereas the United States has enjoyed good relations since the Republic of Moldova’s independence
			 in 1991;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas since the Republic of Moldova’s independence, the United States has provided financial
			 assistance to support the people of Moldova’s efforts to build a
			 prosperous European democracy;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States and the Republic of Moldova further strengthened their partnership
			 through the launching of a Strategic Dialogue on March 3, 2014;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Republic of Moldova is due to sign an Association Agreement containing comprehensive
			 free trade provisions with the European Union in June or July of 2014;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States Government supports the democratic aspirations of the people of the
			 Republic of Moldova and their expressed desire to deepen their association
			 with the European Union;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States supports the sovereignty and territorial integrity of the Republic of
			 Moldova and on that basis participates as an observer in the <quote>5+2</quote> negotiations to find a comprehensive settlement that will provide a special status for the
			 separatist region of Transnistria within Moldova;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the leaders of the Transnistrian region of the Republic of Moldova requested to postpone
			 the <quote>5+2</quote> round of talks scheduled to take place in April 2014;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Government of the Russian Federation banned the import of Moldovan wine in 2013 and has
			 threatened to ban Moldovan agricultural products, curtail the supply of
			 energy resources to Moldova, and impose stricter labor migration policies
			 on the people of Moldova;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Government of the Russian Federation maintains a contingent of Russian troops and a
			 stockpile of Russian military equipment and ammunition within the Moldovan
			 region of Transnistria;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Government of Russia has been actively issuing Russian passports to the residents of
			 the Transnistria region;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Council of Europe, the Organization for Security and Cooperation in Europe, and the
			 Government of Moldova have called upon the Government of the Russian
			 Federation to remove its troops from the territory of the Republic of
			 Moldova;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas authorities in the Republic of Moldova’s Transnistria region have restricted access to the
			 region by OSCE Mission to Moldova monitors, preventing the Mission from
			 providing impartial reporting on the security situation in the region;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the House of Representatives and the Senate both passed by an overwhelming majority, and
			 the President signed into law, S. 2183, providing for a United States
			 international broadcasting programming surge to counter misinformation
			 from Russian-supported news outlets and ensuring that Russian-speaking
			 populations in Ukraine and Moldova have access to independent news and
			 information; and</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Moldova has been a valued and reliable partner in promoting global security by
			 participating in U.N. peacekeeping missions in Liberia, Cote d’Ivoire,
			 Sudan, and Georgia: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body id="HC46C693A7E5B421397ADBDBA25BF58F0" style="traditional">
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H6506182216764EE4B557C855514AD8AA" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the House of Representatives—</text>
			<paragraph id="H574666C852C5423FB2AB1416AD17AE15"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reaffirms that it is the policy of the United States to support the sovereignty, independence, and
			 territorial integrity of the Republic of Moldova and the inviolability of
			 its borders;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H92DDD9DB4D904B5AA20BE6560BC93083"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports the Strategic Dialogue as a means to strengthen relations between the Republic of Moldova
			 and the United States and enhance the democratic, economic, rule of law,
			 and security reforms already being implemented by the Republic of Moldova;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HA79DB6F968EF405781DFBBB96EDE631D"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">encourages the President and the Department of State to enhance United States cooperation with the
			 Government of Moldova and civil society organizations and focus assistance
			 on justice sector reform, anti-corruption efforts, strengthening
			 democratic institutions, domestic energy development, diversification of
			 energy supplies and energy efficiency, as well as promoting trade and
			 investment opportunities;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H0CEA9856C05E4F5EB98B29F180A8849C"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">encourages the President to expedite the implementation of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/96">Public Law 113–96</external-xref>, especially for
			 populations in Ukraine and Moldova;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H9E2A5E6400A047D99B573ADDCE3D5D02"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">affirms the Republic of Moldova’s sovereign right to determine its own partnerships free of
			 external coercion and pressure, and affirms Moldova’s right to associate
			 with the European Union or any regional organization as well as its right
			 to develop political, trade, social, and cultural and security links with
			 the European Union;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H8FD05DDDCF774ECAAA7EACBE811846D9"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">calls upon the Government of Russia to fulfill its commitments made at the OSCE’s Istanbul summit
			 in 1999 and to withdraw its military forces and munitions from within the
			 internationally recognized territory of the Republic of Moldova;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HA28BE3E1843A4E31B62E9E1568F73E0D"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">calls upon the Government of Russia to refrain from economic threats and pressure against
			 Moldova and to cease any and all actions that support separatist movements
			 on the territory of Moldova;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H17427159717444409FE9B901228A29C7"><enum>(8)</enum><text>supports constructive engagement and confidence-building measures between the Government of Moldova
			 and the authorities in the Transnistria region in order to secure a
			 peaceful resolution to the conflict;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H5C60B1D8ACC244799FA2E238FA3ABDB3"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">finds that the only lasting resolution to the Transnistria issue is through a comprehensive
			 settlement that affirms Moldova’s sovereignty and territorial integrity,
			 while providing a special status for the Transnistrian region within
			 Moldova;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H5F458FD758F3470F8F262939E92426E3"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">urges officials in the Transnistrian region to allow OSCE Mission to Moldova monitors unrestricted
			 access to the region;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HC7E4E1ECA9CC4FBDADAEF9D478CC49EF"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">urges all parties to refrain from unilateral actions that may undermine efforts to achieve a
			 peaceful resolution, as well as the agreements already reached, and
			 encourages leaders of the Transnistrian region to resume negotiations
			 toward a political settlement; and</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H471EA44D6C4E404BBF15ECE6A3A894D9"><enum>(12)</enum><text>affirms that lasting stability and security in Europe is a key priority for the United States and
			 that these can only be achieved if the territorial integrity and
			 sovereignty of all European countries is respected.</text>
			</paragraph></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


