<bill session="113" type="s" number="2758" updated="2015-09-01T17:51:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Air Force to modernize C-130 aircraft using alternative communication, navigation, surveillance, and air traffic management program kits and to ensure that such aircraft meet applicable regulations of the Federal Aviation Administration.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412244"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2014-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300019" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="300041" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="300080" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412602" joined="2014-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="5119"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2014--Introduced.
Authorizes the Secretary of the Air Force, for purposes of modernizing the C-130 aircraft fleet, to install alternative communication, navigation, surveillance, and air traffic management program kits in lieu of C-130 aircraft avionics modernization program kits if the Secretary determines, on a case-by-case basis, that such alternative program is appropriate and notifies Congress of such determination.

Requires the Secretary to ensure that all C-130 aircraft are capable of meeting applicable regulations of the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) by January 1, 2020.

Authorizes the Secretary to use amounts made available for FY2013 or FY2014 for the Air Force for the C-130 aircraft avionics modernization program that remain available for obligation to carry out this Act.</summary>
</bill>
