<bill session="113" type="s" number="2247" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-04-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-04-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Contracting and Tax Accountability Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit the awarding of a contract or grant in excess of the simplified acquisition threshold unless the prospective contractor or grantee certifies in writing to the agency awarding the contract or grant that the contractor or grantee has no seriously delinquent tax debts, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412243"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="882"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Debt collection"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/10/2014--Introduced.
Contracting and Tax Accountability Act of 2014 - Requires the head of any executive agency that issues an invitation for bids or a request for proposals for a contract, or that offers a grant, in an amount greater than the simplified acquisition threshold, to require each person submitting a bid or proposal or grant application to submit a form: (1) certifying whether the person has a seriously delinquent tax debt, and (2) authorizing the Secretary of the Treasury to disclose information limited to describing whether such person has such a debt.

Subjects a person who submits a certification that he or she has a seriously delinquent tax debt, or whose certification that he or she does not have such a debt is demonstrated to be false, to a negative responsibility determination when applying for a federal contract or grant. Provides for: (1) the suspension from the federal procurement process of a person who certifies that he or she has such a debt, and (2) debarment of a person whose certification that he or she does not have such a debt is demonstrated to be false.

Defines "seriously delinquent tax debt" as an outstanding tax debt for which a notice of lien has been filed in public records. Exempts from such definition: (1) tax debts that are being paid in a timely manner under an approved installment agreement, and (2) debts for which a collection due process hearing has been requested or is pending.</summary>
</bill>
