<bill session="113" type="s" number="1447" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-12-04">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-12-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">New Mexico Native American Water Settlements Technical Corrections Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Navajo Water Settlement Technical Corrections Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">New Mexico Navajo Water Settlement Technical Corrections Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to make technical corrections to certain Native American water rights settlements in the State of New Mexico, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by senate">A bill to make technical corrections to the Navajo water rights settlement in the State of New Mexico, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400413"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412281" joined="2013-08-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-10">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 113-143.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-06-11" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-08-26">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Reported by Senator Tester under authority of the order of the Senate of 08/05/2014 with an amendment and an amendment to the title. With written report No. 113-246.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-08-26" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="536">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 536.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2014-12-04" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment and an amendment to the Title by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6355" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S6355" label="text of measure as reported in Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S6355" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-12-08">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-08T12:32:00-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="3564"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/26/2014--Reported to Senate amended.
Navajo Water Settlement Technical Corrections Act - (Sec. 2) Amends the Omnibus Public Land Management Act of 2009 to expand the current authorization for the construction or rehabilitation and operation and maintenance of conjunctive use wells in the San Juan River Basin, Little Colorado River Basin, and Rio Grande Basin in New Mexico to include the planning and design of those wells.

Revises the percentages of funds authorized for the Navajo-Gallup Water Supply Project, conjunctive use wells, and San Juan River Irrigation Projects that may be made available for specified purposes by:

 increasing from 2% to 4% the portion of funds that may be used for the survey, recovery, protection, preservation, and display of archaeological resources in the area of a Project facility or conjunctive use well; and decreasing from 4% to 2% the portion of funds that may be used for purchasing land and constructing and maintaining facilities to mitigate the loss of, and improve conditions for the propagation of, fish and wildlife. Makes technical corrections.</summary>
</bill>
