<bill session="113" type="h" number="4253" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-04-09">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-04-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-03-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bureau of Land Management Withdrawn Military Lands Efficiency and Savings Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Bureau of Land Management Withdrawn Military Lands Efficiency and Savings Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To permanently withdraw, reserve, and transfer Bureau of Land Management lands used for military purposes in Alaska, Nevada, and New Mexico to the appropriate Secretary of the military department concerned.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400029"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412500" joined="2014-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400313" joined="2014-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="2014-03-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-03-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-14">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-14">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-25">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-09">
      <text>Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-09">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-04-09" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 21 - 10.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-07-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Readiness.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-12T16:02:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 113-671, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-12T16:02:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee on Armed Services discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-12-12T16:02:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="503">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 503.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSII10" subcommittee="Public Lands and Environmental Regulation" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS03" subcommittee="Readiness" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/14/2014--Introduced.
Bureau of Land Management Withdrawn Military Lands Efficiency and Savings Act - Amends the Military Lands Withdrawal Act of 1999 to declare that the withdrawal and reservation of certain lands and interests concerning the Naval Air Station Fallon Ranges and the Nellis Air Force Range in Nevada, the Fort Greely East and West Training Ranges and the Yukon Training Range of Fort Wainright in Alaska, and the McGregor Range of Fort Bliss in New Mexico shall not terminate except by an election and a determination of the Secretary of the military department concerned or until the Secretary of the Interior can permanently transfer administrative jurisdiction of the withdrawn and reserved lands to that Secretary.

(Currently the withdrawal and reservation of such lands must terminate, except in certain circumstances, 25 years after November 6, 2001.)</summary>
</bill>
