<bill session="113" type="s" number="2174" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-03-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-03-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-03-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Commonsense Competition and Access to Health Insurance Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to provide greater flexibility in offering health insurance coverage across State lines.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412321"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2014-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2014-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412554" joined="2014-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2014-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2014-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412391" joined="2014-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2014-09-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-03-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Insurance industry and regulation"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/27/2014--Introduced.
Commonsense Competition and Access to Health Insurance Act - Amends the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (PPACA) to permit two or more states to enter into an agreement under which one or more qualified health plans could be offered in small group markets, as well as in the individual markets (as under current law), in all such states.

Directs the Secretary, by December 31, 2014, to request the National Association of Insurance Commissioners (NAIC) to report on health plans provided for under PPACA.

Allows the Secretary also to request NAIC to gather concepts for inclusion in the report from organizations and entities that have experience in offering qualified health plans in states in which those plans were not originally issued.

Requires the Secretary, by December 31, 2014, to report to Congress about: (1) how the Secretary may utilize the flexibility provided under PPACA (relating to allowing a regional or interstate exchange) to allow health insurance issuers offering qualified health plans in an Exchange operated by the federal government to offer plans in a state other than the state in which that plan was originally written or issued; and (2) how such an Exchange can be a conduit to forming interstate insurance state compacts.</summary>
</bill>
