<bill session="113" type="sr" number="378" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-03-11">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-03-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution condemning illegal Russian aggression in Ukraine.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300038"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412493" joined="2014-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412251" joined="2014-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400040" joined="2014-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2014-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2014-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2014-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="402675" joined="2014-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2014-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412390" joined="2014-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412248" joined="2014-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2014-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412573" joined="2014-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2014-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2014-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2014-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412320" joined="2014-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412496" joined="2014-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412582" joined="2014-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400222" joined="2014-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2014-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2014-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="2014-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2014-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412194" joined="2014-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400325" joined="2014-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412322" joined="2014-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="2014-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412491" joined="2014-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2014-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2014-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412321" joined="2014-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="2014-03-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2014-03-11" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1527" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S1520-1521" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="European Union"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans and debt"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Lithuania"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Moldova"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development programs"/>
    <term name="Professional sports"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Ukraine"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/11/2014--Passed Senate without amendment.
Condemns the Russian military seizure of the Ukrainian Crimea and demands the immediate withdrawal of Russian forces except as allowed for by treaty.

 Demands the release of besieged Ukrainian security forces in Crimea, and warns that failure to do so or any additional military action against other areas of Ukraine will lead to significant consequences in the Russian Federation's relations with the United States and those nations who share our views.

Urges the President to use all appropriate economic elements of U.S. national power in coordination with U.S. allies to protect Ukraine's independence, sovereignty, and economic integrity.

Urges the President to use economic and diplomatic measures, including calibrated sanctions, against those responsible for the seizure of Crimea.

Urges the President to propose to G-8 nations to suspend the Russian Federation, and to propose to our North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) allies to suspend operation of the NATO-Russia Council and suspend the Russian Federation's military and diplomatic representation at NATO.

Condemns the economic coercion pursued by the Russian Federation against Ukraine, Moldova, Lithuania, and other countries in the region in order to obstruct closer ties between the European Union (EU) and the countries of the Eastern Partnership.

Supports assisting Ukraine and U.S. allies in the region in gaining energy security.

Encourages governments in Europe to take similar and coordinated actions to make it clear to the government of the Russian Federation that violating the territorial integrity of sovereign nations will have significant consequences.

Calls for the acceptance of a credible international observer mission in Crimea and other parts of Ukraine.

Calls on the Russian Federation to engage in a political dialogue with Ukraine on a political and diplomatic path that respects Ukrainian sovereignty and the Crimea's historic and ethnic makeup.

Supports efforts by the government of Ukraine to: (1) bring to justice those responsible for the acts of violence related to the anti-government protests that began on November 2013, and (2) recover Ukrainian state funds stolen by former President Yanukovych and others.

Calls upon the leadership of the Federation Internationale de Football Association (FIFA) to reconsider its decision to place World Cup 2018 matches in Russia.</summary>
</bill>
