<bill session="113" type="sr" number="311" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-11-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-11-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-11-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution calling on the International Olympic Committee (IOC) to strongly oppose Russia's discriminatory law against the freedom of expression for lesbian, gay, bisexual, and transgender (LGBT) persons and to obtain written assurance that host countries of the Olympic Games will uphold all international human rights and civil rights obligations for all persons observing or participating in the Games regardless of race, sex, sexual orientation, or gender identity, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412325"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2013-11-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2013-11-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412194" joined="2013-11-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-11-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8465-8466" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Athletes"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Olympic games"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/21/2013--Introduced.
Calls on the International Olympic Committee (IOC) to: (1) strongly oppose Russia's discriminatory law against the freedom of expression for lesbian, gay, bisexual, and transgender (LGBT) persons as inconsistent with Russia's international obligations and with the value of the Olympic movement; (2) insist, as a condition of holding the planned Olympic Games in Sochi, that the Government of the Russian Federation provide unconditional assurance that no one involved or affiliated with the Olympic Games will have their human rights, including their right to free expression, violated due to their actual or perceived sexual orientation or gender identity or expression of support for LGBT human rights; (3) insist that venders and contractors have LGBT nondiscrimination policies in place for the 2014 Winter Olympics in Sochi and for all future Olympic Games or other Olympic events; (4) call on the Russian Federation to allow a Pride House that has the mission of celebrating diversity and inclusiveness through sport and raising awareness of LGBT discrimination and criminalization; and (5) amend its charter to state that discrimination based on sexual orientation and gender identity is not compatible with the Olympic Games.

Urges the United States Olympic Committee to intervene and assist the IOC in establishing such objectives.</summary>
</bill>
