<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 S2961 IS: Office of Planning for Future Intercity Transportation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2014-11-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 2961</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20141120">November 20, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S319">Mr. Begich</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEV00">Committee on Environment and Public Works</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To establish the Office of Planning for Future Intercity Transportation within the Office of the
			 Secretary of Transportation.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
			<text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the
		  <quote><short-title>Office of Planning for Future Intercity Transportation Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id10e3856d44044264b6f072bd7610c272"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="idd51dfc1ea2344a3c97e7cc492a3ccfa1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>High-speed passenger rail technology, while not new in Europe and Asia, is a new transportation
			 technology in the United States.  Its design, development, construction,
			 financing, funding, and operation require specific skills and expertise
			 that are not abundant in the United States, and will require years to
			 develop.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idede0c8df02d64d3eaf81e3f81ae0f40b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Unlike highways, mass transit, and aviation, high-speed rail requires unique and separated rights
			 of way to operate and must be fully integrated with
			 other passenger transportation system elements to be successful.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id60b7dd1edf674c288220822be5c1f712"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In order to ensure the proper development of high-speed intercity passenger rail service in the
			 United States, it is critical that a dedicated office be established
			 at the highest levels of the Federal Government to coordinate and
			 facilitate the intricate relationships between—</text><subparagraph id="id5FBD8A1C5F69409ABC4D2D0AAD710905"><enum>(A)</enum><text>various levels of
			 government; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC34E33AC077C4FA5B8E692380F49CACF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the wide range of industrial interests that will be
			 required to work together to make high-speed rail successful.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0690b65954374450a481cc052c5b8c0d"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Resources for transportation infrastructure are in high demand. Many people contend that there are
			 not
			 enough resources to maintain the transportation system the Nation has
			 built, let alone to build new modes of
			 transportation such as high-speed intercity passenger rail.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id23d85bdeff9e43d98a463577803817df"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The capacity of the current transportation system threatens the present and future competitiveness
			 of the
			 United States. Unless investments are made in new, faster, and more
			 efficient transportation capacity, such as intercity high-speed passenger
			 rail, it will be very difficult for the United
			 States—</text><subparagraph id="idDC5E95E2212B4F9F80DF043BBF90464C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to rise out of
			 its current economic condition; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6CA7461C873C49B48BFF89207890F053"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to regain its leadership role
			 domestically  and internationally.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida9f5ffe4cf80461ebf719d74c6a015d2"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Placing the development of a national system
			 of intercity high-speed rail corridors that are highly integrated with
			 other modes of transportation under the direct supervision of the
			 Secretary of
			 Transportation and delegating the day-to-day administration of such system
			 to an Assistant Secretary will ensure an effective
			 launch  and the efficient operation of a new national transportation
			 modality.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd092045e258f4bb281665f06884ff365"><enum>(7)</enum><text>It is in the interest of the United States to expeditiously develop and deploy intercity high-speed
			 passenger rail under the singularly focused direction of the Secretary of
			 Transportation.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id02cfbeebb681491196499ffa2d50db74"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="id15433ccb306e4b0082e0edfcb104d9a0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Assistant secretary</header><text>The term <term>Assistant Secretary</term> means the head of the Office of Planning for Future Intercity Transportation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7e7ed3fd9aa9416baf672f7cf04d675a"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible participant</header><text>The term <term>eligible participant</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id6e6ebbb688d648c1ad4db8d2a9d9c7bb"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a State that has participated in the process to develop and implement a 	cost allocation
			 methodology under section 209(a) of the Passenger Rail  Investment and
			 Improvement Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/24101">49 U.S.C. 24101</external-xref> note);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id923e599d0a034217832f28e3d22866a7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a group consisting solely of States described in subparagraph (A);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf4307daa409c4b03aa662e5e9ec47db7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an Interstate Compact consisting solely of States described in	subparagraph (A);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5c36ff1876e74662b2dd46c46d3a809d"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a public agency established by 1 or more of the States described in	subparagraph (A) that is
			 responsible for providing intercity	  passenger rail service; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2c3de3de2faa414a8e0bc9e73c583fec"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any entity that seeks to perform services under a contract awarded	pursuant to this Act by
			 providing—</text><clause id="id88762BC7F544476BB603CCEADC92F647"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a description of how the entity intends to perform the covered services; and</text></clause><clause id="id08A3B11446AB4A92A318DEA0FAFCD819"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>materials demonstrating the entity’s capability to perform the proposed services in accordance with
			 the
			 requirements under this Act.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idc458909510ee4e28b4a45ec4e88110fa"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Office</header><text>The term <term>Office</term> means the Office of Planning for Future Intercity Transportation established
			 within the Office of the Secretary of Transportation pursuant to section
			 4.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3015A23E2E634E2499451C39C53AF12E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Program participant</header><text>The term <term>program participant</term> means an	eligible participant that has entered into an authorized procurement process under 
			     this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id42e5e4f8e3f44010b633f24a1da4fe35"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Rail carrier</header><text>The term <term>rail carrier</term> has the meaning given such term	in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/10102">section 10102(5)</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb8f30125b88e45b7b3fc821c0a63b342"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Transportation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3deb87177c5444fd8641b1727372be9d"><enum>(7)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means each of the several States and the District of Columbia.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id2756d602dbe04fa8a145785a18a336af"><enum>4.</enum><header>Office of Planning for Future Intercity Transportation</header><subsection id="id035522c64ca946b88d29ad0d85238acf"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 6 months after the date of      the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall
			 establish
			 the Office of Planning for Future Intercity Transportation within the
			 Office of the Secretary of Transportation. The Office shall be
			 composed of the Office of High-Speed Rail Policy, the Office of 
			 High-Speed Planning,
			 and the Office of High-Speed Rail Operations and Safety.</text></subsection><subsection id="idAD77DEBC581A4C9F945EE42832F5B04C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Assistant Secretary</header><paragraph id="id9F3A3092481240AD90E206FF4B85FD36"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appointment</header><text>The head of the Office shall be the Assistant Secretary for Intercity Transportation Planning, who
			 shall be appointed by the
			 President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id775D430E1CAC43A79532C383A4F02DC2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Assistant Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph id="id9FFAF0560E694AD19F45DAD2D9490FB7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>serve as the principal policy advisor to the
			 Secretary and the Deputy Secretary on High-Speed Rail; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idFF6A3944947A4DF7B8E1075C85EF5416"><enum>(B)</enum><text>assume responsibility for all activities of the Federal Government
			 associated with high-speed rail that were previously delegated to the
			 Administrator
			 of the Federal Railroad Administration or otherwise authorized by
			 Congress.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id6d61f59b77d74a3989bdb47644cdde9a"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Functions</header><text>Under the direction of the Assistant Secretary, the Office shall oversee the planning,
			 development, construction, financing, funding, and operation of high-speed
			 rail in selected corridors throughout the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="id28a665533f2f49468c65ae6f7d28dbee"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Feasibility study</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date on which the Office is established under this section, the
			 Secretary shall submit to Congress the results of a feasibility study that
			 identifies and prioritizes corridors that offer the best opportunity to
			 provide point-to-point transportation service based on—</text><paragraph id="id07EB7A680CA540A9AF8040C2C1C4E38B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>travel demand;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id01EC1187BA464AD790E942847A21CE1B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the total cost of construction and operation; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id179C094AC9944B3D97A2D3F0F6FBF19D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>expected passenger and other business revenue generated from the operation of transportation
			 service.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idc52e4692b96d45b69e977f86b609480e"><enum>5.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><subsection id="id33df48484b7649a7bacf03ad4876d8c9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated out of the Highway Trust Fund, for each of the fiscal years
			 2015, 2016, and 2017—</text><paragraph id="id2594863CC83F4079B3AC36D81525D90F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$20,000,000 to carry out the feasibility study required under section 4(d); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idA98226A30444478B94C4A0FD15DE4AEE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$5,000,000 for administrative expenses incurred by the Office.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide737d331b7d54bc49918d60c5c849f0f"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contract authority</header><paragraph id="id6E566F99571B4004933E90AE45C91C39"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Feasibility study</header><text>Amounts appropriated pursuant to subsection (a)(1) shall be	available for the procurement of
			 contract services to carry out such studies as the Secretary determines
			 necessary to carry out section 4(d).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idE7C7E7B898194DB7AA2033CDEC057C4D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other requirements</header><text>Amounts appropriated pursuant to subsection (a)(2) shall be	available for the procurement of
			 contract services to carry out any other requirement under this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


