<bill session="113" type="s" number="1290" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-07-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Domestic Violence and Stalking Victims Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to protect victims of stalking from gun violence.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412242"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412200" joined="2013-07-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-30">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/11/2013--Introduced.
Protecting Domestic Violence and Stalking Victims Act of 2013 - Amends the Brady Handgun Violence Prevention Act to revise the definition of: (1) "intimate partner" to include a dating partner and any other person similarly situated to a spouse who is protected by the domestic or family violence laws of the state or tribal jurisdiction in which the injury occurred or where the victim resides; and (2) "misdemeanor crime of domestic violence&#8221; to include the use or attempted use of physical force or a deadly weapon by a current or former intimate partner.

Prohibits: (1) the sale or other disposition of a firearm or ammunition to any person knowing or having reasonable cause to believe that such person has been convicted of a misdemeanor crime of stalking; and (2) the shipment or possession of a firearm or ammunition in interstate or foreign commerce, or the receipt of a firearm or ammunition that has been transported in interstate or foreign commerce, by an individual who has been convicted of a misdemeanor crime of stalking.</summary>
</bill>
