<bill session="113" type="hr" number="558" updated="2015-09-01T10:18:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-04-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-04-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Prohibiting the use of the Members' Representational Allowance for the payment of the costs of first-class airline accommodations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412533"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412535" joined="2014-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412557" joined="2014-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412527" joined="2014-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412509" joined="2014-07-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/29/2014--Introduced.
Requires the House Committee on House Administration to promulgate revisions to the regulations governing the use of the Members' Representational Allowance to ensure that it is not used to pay the costs of first-class airline accommodations for domestic travel.

 Authorizes a Member to use his or her Allowance for such a payment if he or she certifies in writing to the Committee that any of the following applies:

 the use is necessary to accommodate a medical disability or other special need, as demonstrated by such documentation as the Committee may require; no accommodations other than first-class are reasonably available given the timing of the travel, but only if the travel is urgent and its purpose may not be carried out on alternative dates; the use is necessary because of exceptional security circumstances or other exceptional circumstances; it will result in an overall cost savings by avoiding additional subsistence costs, overtime, or lost productive time while awaiting coach-class accommodations; or the length of the flight is five hours or greater.</summary>
</bill>
