<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="H0E32410016844B20901D4BFC9733DAAC" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Engrossed-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HRES 383 EH: Expressing the condolences of the House on the death of the Honorable Thomas S. Foley, former Member of the House for 15 terms and Speaker of the House of Representatives for the One Hundred First, One Hundred Second and One Hundred Third Congresses.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2013-10-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">IV</distribution-code> 
<congress display="no">113th CONGRESS</congress> 
<session display="no">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. RES. 383</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="yes">In the House of Representatives, U. S.,</current-chamber>
<action>
<action-date date="20131022">October 22, 2013</action-date>
</action> 
<legis-type display="yes">RESOLUTION</legis-type> 
<official-title display="no">Expressing the condolences of the House on the death of the Honorable Thomas S. Foley, former Member of the House for 15 terms and Speaker of the House of Representatives for the One Hundred First, One Hundred Second and One Hundred Third Congresses.</official-title> 
</form> 
<resolution-body style="multiple-resolved-clause" id="HDD0636AB9786485785E535F92ED54578"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HDEAB5CDD2C214ABBA73F04C623B08F5E"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House has learned with profound sorrow of the death of the Honorable Thomas S. Foley, former Member of the House for 15 terms and Speaker of the House of Representatives for the One Hundred First, One Hundred Second and One Hundred Third Congresses.</text></section> 
<section id="H5DD46E8313D14A5FBB36774D716ACCC0" section-type="resolved"><text>That in the death of the Honorable Thomas S. Foley the United States and the State of Washington have lost a valued and eminent public servant and citizen.</text></section> 
<section id="H0A6B83CFEDED4F32B7E0D58833CFA8D2" section-type="resolved"><text>That the Clerk communicate these resolutions to the Senate and transmit a copy thereof to the family of the deceased.</text></section> 
<section id="HB40809A319FE4958BBC9F36707240AF6" section-type="resolved"><text>That when the House adjourns today, it adjourn as a further mark of respect to the memory of the deceased.</text></section> 
</resolution-body> 
<attestation><attestation-group><attestor display="no">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation>
</resolution> 


