<bill session="113" type="h" number="3920" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-01-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-01-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-01-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Privacy Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 to limit the acquisition of certain business records under that Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412409"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412547" joined="2014-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412482" joined="2014-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412317" joined="2014-01-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-01-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select), for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-16">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-16">
      <text>Referred to House Intelligence</text>
      <reference ref="Permanent Select"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="First Amendment rights"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/16/2014--Introduced.
American Privacy Protection Act - Amends the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (FISA), with respect to the authority of the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) to make an application to a FISA court for an order requiring the production of tangible things (commonly referred to as "business records"), to limit the items that the FBI may seek to tangible things not pertaining to a U.S. person for an investigation to obtain foreign intelligence information not concerning a U.S. person (thus removes the FBI's authority to make such applications for an investigation regarding a U.S. person or to protect against international terrorism or clandestine intelligence activities).</summary>
</bill>
