<bill session="113" type="s" number="3014" updated="2015-09-01T17:51:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-12-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-12-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-12-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Traumatic Brain Injury Care Improvement Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to extend and modify a pilot program on assisted living services for veterans with traumatic brain injury, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412493"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2014-12-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-12-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4276"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Housing for the elderly and disabled"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/12/2014--Introduced.
Veterans Traumatic Brain Injury Care Improvement Act of 2014 - Amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2008 to alter the reporting requirements under the pilot program to assess the effectiveness of providing assistance to eligible veterans with traumatic brain injury to enhance their rehabilitation, quality of life, and community integration.

Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) to submit reports to the congressional veterans committees on the pilot program for each quarter occurring between January 1, 2015, and September 30, 2017. Requires each quarterly report to include for the preceding quarter:

 the number of individuals who participated in the pilot program, the number of individuals who successfully completed the program, the degree to which pilot program participants and their family members were satisfied with the program, and the interim findings and conclusions of the Secretary regarding the success of the program and recommendations for improving it. Requires the Secretary to include in the report the Secretary submits to the congressional veterans committees after the completion of the pilot program:

 an evaluation of the pilot program in light of the VA's independent living programs, including an assessment of whether&#160; the pilot program should be incorporated into such independent living programs; and recommendations for improving the pilot program. Replaces references to "assisted living" with the term "community-based brain injury residential rehabilitative care," including rehabilitation services within the meaning of such care.

Requires this Act and its amendments to be carried out using funds already available for such purposes.</summary>
</bill>
