<bill session="113" type="s" number="2084" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-03-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-03-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Community Protection Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Endangered Species Act of 1973 to require the Secretary of the Interior to publish and make available for public comment a draft economic analysis at the time a proposed rule to designate critical habitat is published.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300080"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412218" joined="2014-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300063" joined="2014-03-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-03-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4319"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/5/2014--Introduced.
Community Protection Act of 2014 - Amends the Endangered Species Act of 1973, with respect to critical habitat designations, to exclude an area from critical habitat upon a determination that the benefits of exclusion outweigh the benefits of including the area, unless the failure to designate such area as critical habitat will result in the extinction of the species concerned. (Under current law, such exclusion is permitted, not required.)

Requires the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Commerce, at the time a proposed rule to designate critical habitat is published, to publish and make available for public comment a draft quantitative analysis that examines the economic effects of the proposed designation, including any effects on possible uses of land and property values, employment, and state and local revenues.</summary>
</bill>
