<bill session="113" type="s" number="2029" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-02-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-02-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-02-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">All Year School Study Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to use amounts provided for the Fund for the Improvement of Education to establish a pilot program that supports year-round public elementary schools and secondary schools.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400222"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412598" joined="2014-02-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-02-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/12/2014--Introduced.
All Year School Study Act - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to direct the Secretary of Education to carry out a multi-year pilot program awarding four grants to states, local educational agencies, or other public entities to establish or expand year-round education programs at public elementary or secondary schools that focus on raising student achievement.

Allows grantees to increase the salaries of teachers participating in the year-round education programs, but by no more than 100%.

Requires the Secretary to give priority to grant applicants that: (1) propose to carry out year-round education activities that emphasize science, technology, engineering, and mathematics; and (2) target high-poverty areas that have low-performing schools.

Directs the Secretary to enter into a contract for an independent evaluation of the pilot program's effectiveness.</summary>
</bill>
