<bill session="113" type="h" number="5303" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">21st Century Classroom Innovation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To promote the use of blended learning in classrooms across America.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400659"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2014--Introduced.
21st Century Classroom Innovation Act - Amends part A (Teacher and Principal Training and Recruiting Fund) of title II of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to allow states to use that portion of their part A grant funds reserved for state activities to award competitive grants to local educational agencies (LEAs), charter schools, or consortia of such entities to carry out blended learning projects.

Defines a "blended learning project" as a formal education program that: (1) includes an element of online learning and instructional time in a supervised location away from home; (2) includes an element of student control over time, place, path, or pace; and (3) connects the modalities along each student's learning path within a course or subject to provide an integrated learning experience.

Requires the competitive grant funds to be used for: (1) planning activities, the purchase of digital instructional resources, initial professional development activities, and one-time information technology purchases; or (2) ongoing professional development for teachers, school leaders, or other personnel involved in the project.

Requires each state making such a grant to contribute non-federal funds equal to at least 10% of the grant.

Reduces, from 2.5% to 1.5%, that portion of part A grant funds that states must reserve for subgrants to local partnerships between institutions of higher education and high-need LEAs. (This increases the amount reserved for state activities.)</summary>
</bill>
