<bill session="113" type="s" number="2780" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a special resource study to evaluate the significance of the Mill Springs Battlefield located in Pulaski and Wayne Counties, Kentucky, and the feasibility of its inclusion in the National Park System, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300072"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5435-5436" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="298"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Kentucky"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Military history"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="U.S. history"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/9/2014--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a special resource study to evaluate the significance of the Mill Springs Battlefield in Kentucky (relating to the Battle of Mill Springs fought on January 19, 1862, in Pulaski and Wayne Counties during the Civil War) and the feasibility of its inclusion in the National Park System (NPS).

Requires such study, among other things, to analyze: (1) the effect of the Battlefield's designation as a unit of the NPS on existing commercial and recreational activities, energy production and transmission infrastructure, and the authority of state and local governments to manage those activities; and (2) the identification of any authorities, including condemnation, that will compel or permit the Secretary to influence or participate in local land use decisions (such as zoning) or place restrictions on non-federal lands if the Battlefield is designated as an NPS unit.

Requires owners of private property adjacent to the Battlefield to be notified of the commencement and scope of this study.</summary>
</bill>
