<bill session="113" type="h" number="3988" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-02-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-02-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-02-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fixing Operations of Reservoirs to Encompass Climatic and Atmospheric Science Trends Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FORECAST Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To supplement the Secretary of the Army's existing authorities to review the operations of reservoirs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412511"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412512" joined="2014-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412571" joined="2014-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412382" joined="2014-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="2014-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412521" joined="2014-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400663" joined="2014-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412189" joined="2014-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="2014-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400290" joined="2014-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412523" joined="2014-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412259" joined="2014-05-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400403" joined="2014-02-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-02-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hydrology and hydrography"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/4/2014--Introduced.
Fixing Operations of Reservoirs to Encompass Climatic and Atmospheric Science Trends Act or the FORECAST Act - Requires the Secretary of the Army, not later than one year after a request of a non-federal sponsor of a reservoir, to review operation of such reservoir, including the water control manual and rule curves, using improved weather forecasts and run-off forecasting methods, including the Advanced Hydrologic Prediction System of the National Weather Service and the Hydrometeorology Testbed program of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA).

Requires the Secretary to determine if a change in operations will improve core functions of the Army Corps of Engineers, including: (1) reducing risks to human life, public safety, property; (2) reducing the need for future disaster relief; (3) improving local water storage capability and reliability in coordination with the non-federal sponsor and other water users; (4) restoring, protecting, or mitigating the impacts of a water resources development project on the environment; or (5) improving fish species habitat or population within the boundaries and downstream of a water resources project.

Requires that if the Secretary determines from results of the review that using improved weather and run-off forecasting methods improves one or more core functions of the Corps at a reservoir, the Secretary shall incorporate such changes in its operation and update the water control manual.</summary>
</bill>
