<bill session="113" type="h" number="5076" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-23T17:32:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-07-23T17:32:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Enhancing Services for Runaway and Homeless Victims of Youth Trafficking Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Enhancing Services for Runaway and Homeless Victims of Youth Trafficking Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Runaway and Homeless Youth Act to increase knowledge concerning, and improve services for, runaway and homeless youth who are victims of trafficking.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412446"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412427" joined="2014-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400646" joined="2014-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412278" joined="2014-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412486" joined="2014-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412465" joined="2014-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400224" joined="2014-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412557" joined="2014-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412466" joined="2014-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412426" joined="2014-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400364" joined="2014-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412317" joined="2014-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412213" joined="2014-07-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-23T17:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Heck (NV) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-23T17:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6703-6704" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-23T17:24:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5076.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2014-07-23T17:32:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6703" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-07-23T17:32:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-24">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Homelessness and emergency shelter"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/23/2014--Passed House without amendment.
Enhancing Services for Runaway and Homeless Victims of Youth Trafficking Act of 2014 - Amends the Runaway and Homeless Youth Act with respect to grants to states, localities, and private entities to carry out research, evaluation, demonstration, and service projects regarding activities designed to increase knowledge concerning, and to improve services for, runaway youth and homeless youth.

Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to give priority to proposed projects relating to staff training in: (1) the behavioral and emotional effects of severe forms of trafficking in persons and sex trafficking, (2) responding to youth who are showing effects of severe forms of trafficking in persons and sex trafficking, and (3) agency-wide strategies for working with runaway and homeless youth who are victims of trafficking.

Extends the Secretary's authority to make grants to nonprofit private agencies for the purpose of providing street-based services to runaway and homeless, and street youth, who have been subjected to, or are at risk of being subjected to, sexual abuse, prostitution, or sexual exploitation. Extends the scope of such grants also to street-based services to runaway and homeless, and street youth, who have been subjected to, or are at risk of being subjected to, severe forms of trafficking in persons and sex trafficking.</summary>
</bill>
