<resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-joint" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 SJ 43 IS: Authorization for Use of Force Against the Organization Called the Islamic State</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-09-08</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IIA</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. J. RES. 43</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20140908">September 8, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="S236">Mr. Inhofe</sponsor> introduced the following joint resolution; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>JOINT RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To authorize the use of force against the organization called the Islamic State in order to defend
			 the American people and assist the Iraqi Government in expelling the
			 Islamic State from their territory.  </official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas>
      <text>Whereas the organization called the Islamic State or <quote>IS</quote>, formerly known as the Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant, has murdered United States citizens;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas IS has threatened to kill United States citizens and the current leader of IS has stated
			 that <quote>[t]he war with you has just begun</quote>;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="1101" entity-type="federal-body">President of the United States</cato:entity-ref> and the Prime Minister of United Kingdom have jointly
			 confirmed the threat posed by IS fighters returning to allied nations and
			 American shores by stating that <quote>[w]hether it is regional aggression going unchecked or the prospect that foreign fighters could
			 return from Iraq and Syria to pose a threat in our countries, the problems
			 we face today threaten the security of the British and American people,
			 and the wider world</quote>;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Secretary of Defense Chuck Hagel has stated IS is <quote>as sophisticated and well-funded as any group that we have seen. …</quote> and <quote>… an imminent threat to every interest we have, whether it’s in Iraq or anywhere else. …</quote>;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas acts, such as the murder of United States citizens, and threats of other terrorist acts
			 render it both necessary and appropriate that the United States exercise
			 its rights to self-defense and to protect United States citizens both home
			 and abroad;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas acts, such as the murder of United States citizens, and threats of other terrorist acts
			 continue to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national
			 security and foreign policy of the United States;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas United Nations Security Council Resolution (<quote>UNSCR</quote>) 2169 notes the Islamic State’s advancement is a major threat to Iraq’s future, condemns the
			 attacks by the Islamic State,	reiterates the international community
			 support for Iraq’s security and territorial integrity, and emphasizes <quote>the need to continue efforts to promote international and regional cooperation aimed at supporting
			 Iraq to prevent terrorist groups … in particular ISIL [IS], from using the
			 territories of Iraq and neighboring States to carry out violence or other
			 illicit acts to destabilize Iraq and the region …</quote>;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas UNSCR 2169 further notes IS’s actions have resulted in <quote>heavy human causalities including children, the displacement of more than one million Iraqi
			 civilians and the threats against all religious and ethnic groups …</quote>; and</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Iraqi Government has requested the assistance of the United States: Now, therefore, be
			 it</text>
		</whereas>
  </preamble>
	<resolution-body>
		<section id="id698EFFE6D23743ABAA8A8C89C203ACB8" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
      <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This joint resolution may be cited as the <quote>
          <short-title>
            <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Authorization for Use of Force Against the Organization Called the Islamic State" proposed="true">Authorization for Use of Force Against the Organization Called the Islamic State</cato:entity-ref>
          </short-title>
        </quote>.</text>
    </section>
    <section id="id35f0c7999a374f3bb0cbe28d8cb74749">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Authorization for use of United States Armed Forces</header>
      <subsection id="id25EB123BB6964C5EBCAF48C7A2081056">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
        <text>That the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> is authorized to use all necessary and appropriate force in order to
			 defend the national security of the United States against the threat posed
			 by the organization called the Islamic State (or <quote>IS</quote>), formally known as the Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant, as well as any successor
			 organization.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id6EE7EB8C7C524B4AA148A0687D19486D">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>War Powers Resolution requirements</header>
        <paragraph id="id75E0EB217FBA4CA883714694FEA1BD77">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Specific statutory authorization</header>
          <text>Consistent with <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="War Powers Resolution/s:8/ss:a/p:1">section 8(a)(1) of the War Powers Resolution</cato:entity-ref>, the Congress declares that this
			 section is intended to constitute specific statutory authorization within
			 the meaning of <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="War Powers Resolution/s:5/ss:b">section 5(b) of the War Powers Resolution</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA1406B599B1B49FAA71C045F9765495B">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Applicability of other requirements</header>
          <text>Nothing in this joint resolution supercedes any requirement of the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="War Powers Resolution">War Powers Resolution</cato:entity-ref>.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD42490B7776843C5AEE7C1AF5EB9C54A" section-type="subsequent-section">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Reports to Congress</header>
      <subsection id="ida5b2281fc79f4424bbfa991e7f3eeaeb">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Strategy</header>
        <text>Not later than 15 days after the date of the enactment of this joint resolution, the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref>
			 shall submit to <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> a written report setting forth a comprehensive
			 strategy of the United States to defeat the organization called the
			 Islamic State, as well as any successor organization, by using all
			 appropriate military, economic, and political capabilities of the United
			 States.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id7fbffaf7dd11481aafe597bc998480b5">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Implementation of strategy</header>
        <text>Not later than 90 days after the submittal of the report required by <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Authorization for Use of Force Against the Organization Called the Islamic State/s:3/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref> and every 90
			 days thereafter, the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> shall submit to <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> a written report
			 setting forth a current comprehensive description and assessment of the
			 implementation of the strategy set forth in the report required by
			 <cato:entity-ref entity-type="act" value="Authorization for Use of Force Against the Organization Called the Islamic State/s:3/ss:a" proposed="true">subsection (a)</cato:entity-ref>.  If the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> makes a substantive change to the
			 comprehensive strategy, the <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="1100">President</cato:entity-ref> will immediately submit a written
			 report to <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> which articulates the change, the reason for the change
			 and the change’s effect on the rest of the comprehensive strategy.</text>
			</subsection>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>