<bill session="113" type="h" number="5722" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-11-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-11-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-11-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">POWER Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Providing Opportunities to Work for Energy Reliability Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Power Act to require the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission to review the decisions of the North American Electric Reliability Corporation affecting cost allocation under system support resources agreements.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412436"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412305" joined="2014-11-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-11-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="s" number="2929"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Contracts and agency"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC)"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/17/2014--Introduced.
Providing Opportunities to Work for Energy Reliability Act or the POWER Act - Amends the Federal Power Act to direct the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) to review any decision by the North American Electric Reliability Corporation (NAERC) to approve a new balancing authority that would alter cost allocations under an existing system support resources agreement.

Precludes such new balancing authority from taking effect until approved by FERC.

Requires FERC to publish a cost-benefit analysis of the proposed NAERC decision, including its likely financial impact upon ratepayers, before issuing a decision to approve, disapprove, or modify the NAERC decision.</summary>
</bill>
