<bill session="113" type="s" number="2606" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the termination of any employee of the Department of Veterans Affairs who is found to have retaliated against a whistleblower.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412243"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/15/2014--Introduced.
Requires the termination of any employee of the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) who is found to have:

 retaliated or threatened to retaliate against any employee or applicant for employment for disclosing what the employee or applicant reasonably believes to be a violation of any law, rule, or regulation, mismanagement, a gross waste of funds, an abuse of authority, or a substantial and specific danger to public health or safety (provided the disclosure is not specifically prohibited by law); retaliated or threatened to retaliate against any employee or applicant for exercising, or assisting another individual in exercising, any appeal, complaint, or grievance right granted by any law, rule, or regulation; or implemented or enforced certain nondisclosure policies, forms, or agreements that conflict with whistleblower protections and employee rights.</summary>
</bill>
