<bill session="113" type="s" number="2133" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-03-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-03-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-03-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fair Employment Protection Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 and other statutes to clarify appropriate liability standards for Federal antidiscrimination claims.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400013"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2014-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2014-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412390" joined="2014-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2014-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2014-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2014-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412200" joined="2014-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2014-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2014-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="2014-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2014-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2014-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412507" joined="2014-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2014-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2014-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412542" joined="2014-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2014-03-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-03-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="4227"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Age discrimination"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers and employees"/>
    <term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Genetics"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers"/>
    <term name="Smithsonian Institution"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/13/2014--Introduced.
Fair Employment Protection Act of 2014 - Sets forth employer liability standards to be applied in employee harassment claims under specified provisions of the Civil Rights Act of 1964, the Age Discrimination in Employment Act of 1967, the Americans with Disabilities Act, the Rehabilitation Act of 1973, the Revised Statutes, the Genetic Information Nondiscrimination Act of 2008, the Government Employee Rights Act of 1991, employment discrimination laws relating to certain executive branch employees, and the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995.

Declares employers under such Acts liable for the acts of any individual whose harassment of an employee has created or continued an unlawful hostile work environment if, at the time of the harassment: (1) such individual was authorized by that employer to undertake or recommend tangible employment actions affecting the employee or to direct the employee's daily work activities, or (2) the negligence of the employer led to the creation or continuation of that hostile work environment (thus modifies the liability standards provided by the Supreme Court in Vance v. Ball State University, which limited the category of supervisors for whom an employer may be held vicariously liable to those individuals who have authority to take tangible employment actions).</summary>
</bill>
