<bill session="113" type="h" number="4722" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-05-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">EEZ Clarification Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To clarify that for purposes of all Federal laws governing marine fisheries management, the landward boundary of the exclusive economic zone between areas south of Montauk, New York, and Point Judith, Rhode Island, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400031"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII22" subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Rhode Island"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/22/2014--Introduced.
EEZ Clarification Act - Declares that the landward boundary of the exclusive economic zone (EEZ) between the area south of Montauk, New York, and the area south of Point Judith, Rhode Island, for purposes of all federal laws governing marine fisheries management, shall be considered to be a continuous line running: (1) from a point three miles south of the southernmost point of Montauk to a point three miles south of the southernmost point of Block Island, Rhode Island, and (2) from such point three miles south of the southernmost point of Block Island, Rhode Island, to a point three miles south of the southern most point of Point Judith.

Vests the authority to manage fisheries landward of such line in states and interstate marine fisheries management commissions that otherwise have jurisdiction over such waters.

Requires the Secretary of Commerce to report to Congress within three years on the impact of such boundary points and management authority.</summary>
</bill>
