<bill session="113" type="h" number="4110" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-02-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-02-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-02-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Helping to Encourage Real Opportunity for Veterans Transitioning from Battlespace to Workplace Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HERO Transition from Battlespace to Workplace Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide a tax credit to encourage private employers to hire veterans, to amend title 38, United States Code, to clarify the reasonable efforts an employer may make under the Uniformed Services Employment and Reemployment Rights Act with respect to hiring veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400199"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400030" joined="2014-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400616" joined="2014-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412571" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400639" joined="2014-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400075" joined="2014-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412530" joined="2014-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400653" joined="2014-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2014-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2014-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412579" joined="2014-02-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-02-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-27">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-27">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E331"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR10" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/27/2014--Introduced.
Helping to Encourage Real Opportunity for Veterans Transitioning from Battlespace to Workplace Act of 2014 or the HERO Transition from Battlespace to Workplace Act of 2014 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow employers a business-related tax credit for $1,000 times the number of veterans (not more than 25 in a taxable year) who begin work resulting from the efforts of a military relations manager.

Deems as a reasonable effort of an employer to employ veterans, for purposes of veteran employment and reemployment programs, the designation of an employee as a military relations manager and the use of the military skills translator database (database for assisting veterans in relating military skills, experience, and training to civilian skills, experience, and training). Defines "military relations manager" as an expert in the process of transitioning from being a member of the Armed Forces to being a civilian and in translating the skills, experience, and training gained in the Armed Forces to skills, experience, and training needed in the private sector.

Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) to ensure that the military skills translator database may be used by civilian employers and conduct outreach to inform civilian employers of such database.</summary>
</bill>
