<bill session="113" type="hr" number="565" updated="2015-09-01T10:18:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-07T19:11:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-05-07T19:11:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Calling on Attorney General Eric H. Holder, Jr., to appoint a special counsel to investigate the targeting of conservative nonprofit groups by the Internal Revenue Service.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412226"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412547" joined="2014-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400636" joined="2014-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400058" joined="2014-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412270" joined="2014-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412531" joined="2014-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412526" joined="2014-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412477" joined="2014-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400137" joined="2014-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400154" joined="2014-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412397" joined="2014-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412473" joined="2014-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400196" joined="2014-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412465" joined="2014-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412464" joined="2014-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412294" joined="2014-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412552" joined="2014-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400365" joined="2014-05-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-06T22:32:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 568 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H. Res. 565 with 40 minutes of general debate. H. Res. 568 also provides for consideration of House Report 113-415 and an accompanying resolution under a closed rule. If such a resolution is considered, the rule provides for 50 minutes of debate on said resolution followed by one motion to refer, if offered by Representative Cummings or his designee and is debatable for 10 minutes.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-07T15:49:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 568 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-07T17:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 568.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3909-3919" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-07T17:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H. Res. 565 with 40 minutes of general debate. H. Res. 568 also provides for consideration of House Report 113-415 and an accompanying resolution under a closed rule. If such a resolution is considered, the rule provides for 50 minutes of debate on said resolution followed by one motion to refer, if offered by Representative Cummings or his designee and is debatable for 10 minutes.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-07T17:28:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Res. 565.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-07T18:16:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3919" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-07T18:16:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H.Res. 565, the Chair put the question on adoption of the resolution and by voice vote, announced that the ayes prevailed. Ms. Jackson Lee (TX) demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the resolution until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-07T19:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3922-3923" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="204" datetime="2014-05-07T19:11:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 250 - 168 (Roll no. 204).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3909-3910" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-05-07T19:11:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="113" type="hr" number="568"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="sr" number="487"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="First Amendment rights"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Internal Revenue Service (IRS)"/>
    <term name="Political movements and philosophies"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/7/2014--Passed House without amendment.
Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives, with respect to the targeting by the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) of conservative nonprofit advocacy groups, that: (1) the statements and actions of the IRS, the Department of Justice (DOJ), and the Obama Administration have served to undermine DOJ's investigation of this matter; (2) the Administration's efforts to undermine the investigation, and the appointment of a person who has donated almost $7,000 to President Obama and the Democratic National Committee in a lead investigative role, have created a conflict of interest for DOJ that warrants removal of the investigation from its normal processes; (3) further investigation of the matter is warranted due to the apparent criminal activity by Lois G. Lerner, former IRS Director, Exempt Organizations, and the ongoing disclosure of internal communications showing potentially unlawful conduct by executive branch personnel; (4) given DOJ's conflict of interest, as well as the strong public interest in ensuring that public officials who inappropriately targeted American citizens for exercising their right to free expression are held accountable, appointment of a special counsel would be in the public interest; and (5) Attorney General Eric H. Holder, Jr., should appoint a special counsel, without further delay, to investigate the targeting of conservative nonprofit advocacy groups by the IRS.</summary>
</bill>
