<bill session="113" type="h" number="4169" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-03-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-03-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-03-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">S.O.S. Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Overdose Stat Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prevent deaths occurring from drug overdoses.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412263"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412404" joined="2014-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412565" joined="2014-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2014-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400063" joined="2014-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412407" joined="2014-05-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412258" joined="2014-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412571" joined="2014-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412600" joined="2014-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2014-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="2014-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2014-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412257" joined="2014-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412435" joined="2014-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412557" joined="2014-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2014-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="2014-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412209" joined="2014-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400246" joined="2014-05-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412293" joined="2014-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400249" joined="2014-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412562" joined="2014-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2014-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400274" joined="2014-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400661" joined="2014-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2014-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412575" joined="2014-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412307" joined="2014-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2014-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400347" joined="2014-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412519" joined="2014-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="2014-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400352" joined="2014-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400647" joined="2014-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400366" joined="2014-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412219" joined="2014-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400407" joined="2014-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412319" joined="2014-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412239" joined="2014-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412412" joined="2014-03-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-03-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/6/2014--Introduced.
Stop Overdose Stat Act or the S.O.S. Act - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to: (1) award grants or enter into cooperative agreements to enable eligible entities to reduce deaths occurring from drug overdoses, and (2) give priority to eligible public health agencies or community-based organizations that have expertise in preventing deaths occurring from overdoses in high risk populations.

Conditions receipt of a grant or agreement on an entity agreeing to: (1) use it for purchasing and distributing the drug naloxone, (2) report to the Secretary and the coordinating center (established under this Act) on the results of the activities supported, and (3) make available non-federal contributions of at least 50% of the federal funds provided. Requires a recipient to use such grant or agreement for: (1) educating prescribers and pharmacists about overdose prevention and naloxone prescription; (2) training first responders, other individuals in a position to respond to an overdose, and law enforcement and corrections officials on the effective response to individuals who have overdosed on drugs; (3) implementing and enhancing programs to provide overdose prevention, recognition, treatment, and response; and/or (4) expanding such activities.

Requires the Director to establish and provide for the operation of a coordinating center responsible for: (1) collecting, compiling, disseminating, and evaluating data on such activities; (2) developing best practices for preventing deaths occurring from drug overdoses; and (3) making such best practices specific to the type of community involved.

Requires the Director to award grants or cooperative agreements to improve drug overdose surveillance and reporting capabilities.

Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary to develop and submit to Congress a plan to reduce the number of deaths occurring from overdoses, to include implementation of a campaign to educate prescribers and the public about overdose prevention and naloxone prescription.

Requires the Director of the National Institute on Drug Abuse to: (1) prioritize and conduct or support research on drug overdose and overdose prevention, and (2) support research on the development of formulations of naloxone and dosage delivery devices specifically intended to be used for the prehospital treatment of unintentional drug overdose.</summary>
</bill>
