<bill session="113" type="h" number="5314" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PREPARE Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preparedness and Risk Management for Extreme Weather Patterns Assuring Resilience Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 31, United States Code, to enhance the Federal Government's planning and preparation for extreme weather, and the Federal Government's dissemination of best practices to respond to extreme weather, thereby increasing resiliency, improving regional coordination, and mitigating the financial risk to the Federal Government from such extreme weather.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412571"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400063" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400077" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400648" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400111" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400646" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412451" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412511" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412209" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2014-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412523" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412307" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="2014-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-08-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW13" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Office of Management and Budget (OMB)"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2014--Introduced.
Preparedness and Risk Management for Extreme Weather Patterns Assuring Resilience Act of 2014 or the PREPARE Act of 2014 - Directs the President to establish the Interagency Council on Extreme Weather Resiliency, Preparedness, and Risk Management (Council), co-chaired by an employee of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB).

 Directs the Council on Environmental Quality to provide administrative support and additional resources to the Council.

Requires the Council to establish government-wide goals and priorities for extreme weather preparedness and risk management.

Requires each agency to submit biannually to OMB and to the Council a comprehensive plan that integrates extreme weather into its operations and overall objectives.

Requires the United States Global Change Research Program to designate a participating agency to maintain an Internet website providing extreme weather preparedness information.

Directs the Council to publish biannually an inventory of all regional agency offices, centers, and programs that assist with extreme weather preparedness and risk management at the municipal level.

Requires annual agency performance plans to include the most recent agency extreme weather plan.</summary>
</bill>
