<bill session="113" type="h" number="3431" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-10-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-10-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Families United Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to promote family unity, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412575"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400618" joined="2013-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400111" joined="2014-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2014-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2013-11-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412518" joined="2014-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412303" joined="2014-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400313" joined="2013-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412523" joined="2014-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412514" joined="2014-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412520" joined="2014-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412515" joined="2014-02-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Border Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="15"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="744"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Temporary and part-time employment"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/30/2013--Introduced.
American Families United Act - States that nothing in this Act shall be construed to enable the Attorney General (DOJ) or the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to expand his or her discretionary authority beyond a case-by-case basis, or to provide legalization or nationalization of persons covered under this Act.

	Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act (INA) to revise waiver of inadmissibility requirements, among other things waiving inadmissibility for: (1) certain persons who entered the United States before age 16 who have earned a degree from a U.S. institution of higher education, (2) false claims of U.S. citizenship by persons under age 18 or lacking mental competence to knowingly misrepresent a claim, and (3) false claims of U.S. citizenship if inadmissibility would create family separation hardship for the alien (including a self-petitioner under the Violence Against Women Act) or for a U.S. citizen or lawful permanent resident family member.

Authorizes parents of U.S. citizens or lawful permanent residents to apply for a waiver of inadmissibility for unlawful presence. Places a three-year limit on immigration-related misrepresentations rendering aliens inadmissible. Revises the definition "conviction" for INA purposes.

Authorizes an immigration judge in specified circumstances, including family separation hardship, but with certain exceptions, to decline to order an alien removed, deported, or excluded and terminate related proceedings or grant permission to reapply for admission or for relief from removal.</summary>
</bill>
