<bill session="113" type="h" number="3506" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-11-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-11-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-11-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Honor Our Fallen Heroes With Dignity Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of the Army to permit visitors to leave appropriate items on gravesites and markers located in section 60 of Arlington National Cemetery, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400262"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-11-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1677"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-15">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-15">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR09" subcommittee="Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/15/2013--Introduced.
Honor Our Fallen Heroes With Dignity Act of 2013 - Directs the Secretary of the Army to permit visitors to leave on any gravesite or government-furnished marker located in section 60 of Arlington National Cemetery any item that: (1) does not present a safety or health concern, (2) is not permanently affixed to such marker, and (3) does not interfere with the normal operations and maintenance procedures of the Cemetery.

Requires the History Office of Arlington National Cemetery: (1) to collect, catalog, and store any other items left on a gravesite, headstone, or marker in section 60; and (2) at the end of each calendar month, to collect, catalog, and store all items left on gravesites, headstones, and government-furnished markers.</summary>
</bill>
