<bill session="113" type="s" number="131" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-07-24">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-07-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Women Veterans and Other Health Care Improvements Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Women Veterans and Other Health Care Improvements Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the reproductive assistance provided by the Department of Veterans Affairs to severely wounded, ill, or injured veterans and their spouses, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300076"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2013-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2013-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2013-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2013-01-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S286-287"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-01-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-09">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 113-203.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-07-24" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-09-17">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Reported by Senator Sanders with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 113-106. Minority views filed.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-09-17" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="185">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 185.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="958"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Sex and reproductive health"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/17/2013--Reported to Senate amended.
Women Veterans and Other Health Care Improvements Act of 2013 - (Sec. 2) Includes fertility counseling and treatment within authorized Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) medical services.

(Sec. 3) Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (Secretary) to furnish such counseling and treatment, including the use of assisted reproductive technology, to a spouse or surrogate of a severely wounded, ill, or injured veteran who has an infertility condition incurred or aggravated in the line of duty and who is enrolled in the VA health care system, as long as the spouse and veteran apply jointly for such counseling and treatment.

(Sec. 4) Authorizes the Secretary to pay to any such veteran an amount to assist in the adoption of one or more children. Provides cost limits.

(Sec. 5) Directs the Secretary to prescribe regulations on the furnishing of such counseling, treatment, and adoption assistance.

(Sec. 6) Requires the Secretary and the Secretary of Defense (DOD) to share best practices and facilitate referrals on the furnishing of such counseling and treatment.

(Sec. 7) Directs the Secretary to facilitate research conducted collaboratively by the Secretaries of Defense and Health and Human Services (HHS) in order to improve VA's ability to meet the long-term reproductive health care needs of veterans who have a service-connected genitourinary disability or a condition that was incurred or aggravated in the line of duty, such as a spinal cord injury, that affects the veterans' ability to reproduce. Requires the Secretary to report to Congress on such research.

(Sec. 8) Directs the Secretary to report annually to the congressional veterans committees on the counseling and treatment provided under this Act.

(Sec. 9) Directs the Secretary to carry out a program of providing assistance to veterans to obtain child care during the period they are receiving mental health services. Requires the program to be carried out in at least three Veterans Integrated Service Networks selected by the Secretary. Directs the Secretary to carry out a similar program to provide assistance to the primary caretaker of a child or children who is receiving or in need of readjustment counseling and related mental health services from the VA. Requires the latter program to be carried out in at least three Readjustment Counseling Service Regions selected by the Secretary.

(Sec. 10) Directs the Secretary to provide, through the Readjustment Counseling Service of the Veterans Health Administration, reintegration and readjustment services in group retreat settings to women veterans who are recently separated from service after a prolonged deployment. Requires the receipt of services to be at the election of the veteran. Repeals superseded pilot program authority under the Caregivers and Veterans Omnibus Health Services Act of 2010.</summary>
</bill>
