<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 SRES 584 ATS: Commending Jerald D. Linnell on his service to the United States Senate.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2014-11-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. RES. 584</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20141119">November 19, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S198">Mr. Reid</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S174">Mr. McConnell</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Commending Jerald D. Linnell on his service to the United States Senate.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas><text>Whereas Jerry Linnell, a native of Minnesota, graduated from the court reporting program of the
			 Minnesota School of Business in Minneapolis;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Jerry Linnell, joined the Official Reporters of Debate of the United States Senate in 1982
			 and became Chief Reporter in 1999 supervising a staff of reporters and
			 transcribers and producing the Senate's portion of the Congressional
			 Record with remarkable accuracy;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Jerry Linnell has earned the respect and affection of the Senators, their staffs and all of
			 his colleagues for his professionalism, dedication and good humor;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Jerry Linnell now retires from the Senate after 32 years to spend more time with his wife
			 Jane, his four children and five grandchildren: Now, therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body>
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the Senate expresses its appreciation to Jerry Linnell and commends him for his lengthy,
			 faithful and outstanding service to the Senate.</text>
		</section><section id="id4C7087A335D341AAA2E9F7F6F4A44870" section-type="resolved"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the Secretary of the Senate shall transmit a copy of this resolution to Jerald D. Linnell.</text></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


