<bill session="113" type="s" number="2315" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-05-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improving the Nation's Visitors' International Travel Experience Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">INVITE Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to expand the Global Entry Program and strengthen the Model Ports of Entry Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412507"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2014-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412471" joined="2014-05-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Customs enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/8/2014--Introduced.
Improving the Nation's Visitors' International Travel Experience Act of 2014 or INVITE Act of 2014 - Directs the Secretary of State and the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to explore the feasibility of: (1) coordinating the enrollment and interview processes for individuals who are nationals of countries with which the United States has a reciprocal trusted traveler program agreement, applying simultaneously for a U.S. visa and global entry program enrollment, and collecting a single application fee from such applicants; and (2) coordinating the passport application and global entry program enrollment processes for eligible U.S. citizens.

Amends the Implementing Recommendations of the 9/11 Commission Act of 2007 to: (1) modify the model ports of entry program, including by increasing the number of program airports; and (2) direct U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) to develop metrics to measure the program's performance.

Directs the DHS Secretary to establish the model ports of entry grant program to award up to 10 grants to CBP-designated airports to improve the international arrival process at U.S. airports.

Directs CBP to report to Congress each year: (1) regarding average passenger wait times and peak wait times for each month at each port of entry, and (2) describing efforts to develop new technologies and procedures to improve the passenger screening process at U.S. ports of entry.

Directs the Secretary to collect and analyze traveler feedback to develop customer service best practices, ensure a welcoming environment, and improve the U.S. image.</summary>
</bill>
