<bill session="113" type="s" number="2487" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Access to Capital, Access to Opportunity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Small Business Act to increase the maximum loan limits under the microloan program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412556"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412471" joined="2014-06-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/18/2014--Introduced.
Access to Capital, Access to Opportunity Act - Amends the Small Business Act to increase from $50,000 to $100,000 the maximum amount of a loan under the microloan program.

Authorizes the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) to use amounts made available for administrative expenses to carry out the direct and guaranteed loan programs to pay for any costs associated with these increases.

Requires the Administrator to develop and adopt outcome-oriented standards to measure the microloan program's performance, including the recommendations provided in the SBA Office of Inspector General Memorandum ROM-10-10, "SBA's Administration of the Microloan Program under the Recovery Act," issued December 28, 2009.

Authorizes the Administrator to educate individuals, including owners and operators of small businesses and aspiring entrepreneurs, about the microloan program.</summary>
</bill>
