<bill session="113" type="h" number="4616" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-05-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Express Appeals Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out a pilot program to provide veterans the option of using an alternative appeals process to more quickly determine claims for disability compensation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412575"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412513" joined="2014-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412511" joined="2014-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412286" joined="2014-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412191" joined="2014-11-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/8/2014--Introduced.
Express Appeals Act - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) to: (1) carry out a five-year pilot program to provide the option of an alternative appeals process to determine appeals of claims for disability compensation more quickly, and (2) inform claimants about such program.

Authorizes a claimant to elect to file an express appeal by filing with the Secretary: (1) a notice of disagreement, (2) all evidence that the claimant believes is needed for the appeal, (3) a statement of the argument in support of the claim, and (4) the claimant's written election to have the appeal determined under the pilot program. Requires the Secretary to transfer jurisdiction over an express appeal directly to the Board of Veterans' Appeals.

Requires a claimant to make such election: (1) at any time during the traditional appeal process if the claimant has filed a traditional appeal before the pilot program commences, or (2) by 90 days after the Secretary provides notice of the determination of the claim if the claimant has not filed a traditional appeal.

Directs the Secretary to inform a claimant who seeks to change a traditional appeal to an express appeal about whether any time will be saved. Allows a claimant who elects to file an express appeal to elect to revert to a traditional appeal at any time.

Requires the Board of Veterans' Appeals to: (1) maintain express appeals on a separate docket, (2) hear express appeals in the order received, and (3) decide not more than one express appeal for each four traditional appeals decided.

Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) the effects of new evidence submitted or additional information needed after an express appeal is filed, and (2) a prohibition against the Board providing hearings for express appeals.</summary>
</bill>
