<bill session="113" type="s" number="2963" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-12-02">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-12-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-11-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to remove a limitation on a prohibition relating to permits for discharges incidental to normal operation of vessels.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300011"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2014-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412598" joined="2014-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2014-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2014-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2014-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2014-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2014-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2014-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2014-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300078" joined="2014-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300081" joined="2014-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412542" joined="2014-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2014-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2014-12-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-11-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-12-02" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-12-04">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported by Senator Boxer without amendment. With written report No. 113-284.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-12-04" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="613">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 613.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2943"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/4/2014--Reported to Senate without amendment.
Makes permanent a provision which prohibits the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) from requiring a National Pollutant Discharge Elimination System permit under the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act) for a vessel that is less than 79 feet in length or a fishing vessel for any discharge: (1) of effluent from properly functioning marine engines; (2) of laundry, shower, and galley sink wastes; or (3) that is incidental to the normal operation of those vessels. (Currently, the prohibition is temporary and the time period in which the EPA is prohibited from requiring a NPDES permit ends on December 18, 2014. This prohibition does not apply with respect to garbage discharged overboard, other discharges when the vessel is operating in a capacity other than as a means of transportation, discharges of ballast water held in ships to increase stability, or any discharge that contributes to a violation of a water quality standard or poses an unacceptable risk to human health or the environment.)</summary>
</bill>
