<bill session="113" type="h" number="357" updated="2015-09-01T10:18:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-02-03T19:07:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-02-03T19:07:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">GI Bill Tuition Fairness Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">GI Bill Tuition Fairness Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">GI Bill Tuition Fairness Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to require courses of education provided by public institutions of higher education that are approved for purposes of the educational assistance programs administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to charge veterans tuition and fees at the in-State tuition rate.</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by house">To amend title 38, United States Code, to require courses of education provided by public institutions of higher education that are approved for purposes of the educational assistance programs administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to charge veterans tuition and fees at the in-State tuition rate, to make other improvements in the laws relating to benefits administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400279"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412500" joined="2013-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412502" joined="2013-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412436" joined="2013-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412250" joined="2013-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400031" joined="2013-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412516" joined="2013-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412258" joined="2013-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412470" joined="2013-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400077" joined="2013-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412563" joined="2013-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412193" joined="2013-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400137" joined="2013-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412529" joined="2013-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400147" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412401" joined="2013-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2013-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2013-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412283" joined="2013-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412460" joined="2013-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2013-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412286" joined="2013-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412557" joined="2013-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412191" joined="2013-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412256" joined="2013-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400244" joined="2013-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400257" joined="2013-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412540" joined="2013-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400274" joined="2013-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412518" joined="2013-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412409" joined="2013-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412575" joined="2013-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400310" joined="2013-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412523" joined="2013-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400316" joined="2013-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412310" joined="2013-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412411" joined="2013-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412519" joined="2013-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412449" joined="2013-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400647" joined="2013-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412396" joined="2013-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412219" joined="2013-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412509" joined="2013-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412461" joined="2013-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412520" joined="2013-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412318" joined="2013-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412538" joined="2013-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412214" joined="2013-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412412" joined="2013-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400433" joined="2013-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="2013-03-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-02-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-10">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-25">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-04-25">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-08">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-05-08" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-06-03T15:58:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Veterans' Affairs. H. Rept. 113-94.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-06-03T15:59:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="66">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 66.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-02-03T17:14:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Miller (FL) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-03T17:15:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1520-1526" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-03T17:47:00-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-03T19:00:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1527-1528" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="33" datetime="2014-02-03T19:07:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 390 - 0 (Roll no. 33).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1520-1522" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-02-03T19:07:00-05:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-04">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSVR10" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="s" number="257"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2258"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/3/2014--Passed House amended.
GI Bill Tuition Fairness Act of 2014 - (Sec. 4) Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA), for purposes of the All-Volunteer Force Educational Assistance Program and the program providing educational assistance to individuals who commenced service in the Armed Forces on or after September 11, 2001, to disapprove courses of education provided by a public institution of higher education (IHE) that charges tuition and fees for veterans living in the state in which the IHE is located at a higher rate than it charges residents of such state, regardless of the veteran's state of residence.

Makes this provision applicable only to: (1) veterans who were discharged or released from at least 90 days of active service less than three years before their date of enrollment in the applicable course, and (2) courses that commence on or after July 1, 2016.

Prohibits the Secretary from disapproving a public IHE's course on the grounds that the IHE conditions such veterans' receipt of in-state tuition rates on their: (1) demonstrating an intent, by means other than physical presence, to establish residency in the state; or (2) satisfying other requirements not related to residency.

(Sec. 5) Makes eligible under VA homeless veterans reintegration program those homeless veterans who are: (1) participating in the VA supported housing program for which rental assistance is provided under the United States Housing Act of 1937, and (2) veterans who are transitioning from being incarcerated.

(Sec. 6) Extends from 12 to 17 years after discharge or release from active-duty service the authorized period for veterans with service-connected disabilities to enroll in certain VA vocational training and rehabilitation programs.

(Sec. 7) Reauthorizes through June 30, 2018 (under current law, the authorization expires as of June 30, 2013) certain qualifying work-study activities for individuals receiving educational assistance through the VA.

(Sec. 8) Sets forth the responsibilities of each Director and Assistant Director of Veterans' Employment and Training (assigned to each state by the Secretary from among personnel within the Veterans' Employment and Training Service), including: (1) monitoring the performance of veterans' training and employment programs, with special emphasis on services to disabled veterans; (2) addressing program performance deficiencies and establishing higher performance goals; and (3) reviewing program funding and assisting with funding requests.

(Sec. 9) Amends provisions concerning the Transition Assistance Program of the Department of Defense (DOD) (employment and job training assistance and related services for members of the Armed Forces being separated from active duty and their spouses) to require such Program to include: (1) information about disability-related employment and education protections, (2) instruction in the use of educational assistance entitlements, (3) appropriate courses, (4) instruction on the financing of post-secondary education, and (5) information on benefits provided under laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) and in other subjects determined by the Secretary concerned.

Requires the VA Secretary to submit to the congressional veterans and defense committees the results of a study to determine the feasibility of providing veterans' benefits instruction at all overseas locations where such instruction is provided through a joint contract with the Secretary of Labor. (Sec. 10) Requires veterans' disability compensation and dependency and indemnity compensation that is being increased in compliance with the Veterans' Compensation Cost- of-Living Adjustment Act of 2013 to an amount that is not a whole dollar amount to be rounded to the next lower whole dollar amount. (Sec. 11) Prohibits the Secretary from paying any performance award to a VA Senior Executive Service employee during FY2014-FY2018. (Sec. 12) Directs the Secretary to make semiannual reports to Congress that include the cost and certain other details regarding travel by VA employees: (1) outside this country or its territories, commonwealths, possessions, or territorial waters if the federal government is paying for the travel; and (2) to any location inside or outside this country if a person or entity other than the federal government is paying for the travel. (Sec. 13) Directs the Secretary to report: (1) each case of a notifiable infectious disease or condition that is diagnosed at a VA medical facility to the appropriate state entity and to Congress, and (2) each of those cases that is also classified as a health-care-associated infection sentinel event to the facility's accrediting organization. Authorizes a state, if the Secretary fails to report such a disease or condition, to a file civil action against the Secretary to recover the penalty the state would require a non-federal medical facility to pay for failing to do so. Directs the Secretary to suspend a director of a Veterans Integrated Service Network that fails to comply with such reporting requirements. (Sec. 14) Requires the Secretary to establish procedures to ensure that a visual recording made by the Secretary during the provision of medical care is made only with the full and informed consent of the patient or the patient's representative. Excepts recordings made: (1) pursuant to a determination by a physician or psychologist that such recording is medically necessary or necessary for the patient's safety, (2) pursuant to a court order or warrant, or (3) for general security purposes in a public setting where a person would not have a reasonable expectation to privacy. (Sec. 15) Amends the VOW to Hire Heroes Act of 2011 to extend through May 31, 2014, the veterans retraining assistance program. Directs the Secretary to submit to Congress an interim report on the retraining assistance provided under such program.</summary>
</bill>
