<bill session="113" type="h" number="5484" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Toxic Exposure Research Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish in the Department of Veterans Affairs a national center for research on the diagnosis and treatment of health conditions of the descendants of veterans exposed to toxic substances during service in the Armed Forces, to establish an advisory board on exposure to toxic substances, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412436"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412250" joined="2014-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412516" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412427" joined="2014-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2014-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2014-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2014-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412524" joined="2014-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400641" joined="2014-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2014-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2014-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412557" joined="2014-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412256" joined="2014-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400244" joined="2014-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412521" joined="2014-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400246" joined="2014-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2014-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412307" joined="2014-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412331" joined="2014-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400331" joined="2014-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2014-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400343" joined="2014-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400349" joined="2014-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412219" joined="2014-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412213" joined="2014-11-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-16">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-16">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR03" subcommittee="Health" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4816"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1602"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="s" number="2738"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Birth defects"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Hereditary and development disorders"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/16/2014--Introduced.
Toxic Exposure Research Act of 2014 - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to select a medical center in the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to serve as the national center for research on the diagnosis and treatment of health conditions of descendants (i.e., a biological child, grandchild, or great-grandchild) of individuals exposed to toxic substances while serving as members of the Armed Forces that are related to that exposure.

Requires the national research center to employ at least one licensed clinical social worker to coordinate the access of individuals to appropriate federal, state, and local social and health care programs and to handle case management.

Directs the Secretary to establish an advisory board to: (1) advise the national research center, (2) determine which health conditions in the descendants of individuals who were exposed to toxic substances while serving in the Armed Forces result from such exposure for purposes of determining those descendants' eligibility for VA medical care, and (3) study and evaluate claims of service-related exposure to toxic substances by current and former members of the Armed Forces.

Authorizes the Secretary of Defense (DOD) to declassify documents (other than documents that would materially and immediately threaten national security) related to any known incident in which not less than 100 members of the Armed Forces were exposed to a toxic substance that resulted in at least one case of disability.

Directs the Secretary, the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), and the DOD Secretary to jointly conduct a national outreach and education campaign directed at members of the Armed Forces, veterans, and their family members to communicate information on: (1) incidents of exposure to toxic substances, health conditions resulting form such exposure, and the potential long-term effects of such exposure; and (2) the national research center.</summary>
</bill>
