<bill session="113" type="h" number="4849" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Phantom Fuels Elimination Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Clean Air Act to allow advanced biofuel, biomass-based diesel, and cellulosic biofuel to satisfy the mandates of the renewable fuel program only if domestically produced, to eliminate the corn ethanol mandate under such program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412464"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1807"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/12/2014--Introduced.
Phantom Fuels Elimination Act of 2014 - Amends the Clean Air Act to revise the renewable fuel program by requiring advanced biofuel, biomass-based diesel, and cellulosic biofuel to be produced in the United States.

Directs the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), for any year in which the projected volume of advanced biofuel and biomass-based diesel production is less than the applicable volume standard established under the program, to reduce the volume of advanced biofuel and biomass-based diesel required to be blended into transportation fuel to the projected volume available for that year.

Directs the Energy Information Administration to provide the EPA an estimate, with respect to the following year, of the volumes of advanced biofuel projected to be sold or introduced into commerce.

Eliminates the volume standards under the program applicable to corn-starch ethanol.</summary>
</bill>
