<bill session="113" type="s" number="1802" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-12-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-12-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-12-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Public Power Risk Management Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide equal treatment for utility special entities using utility operations-related swaps, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412205"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2013-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400040" joined="2014-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="402675" joined="2013-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2013-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412554" joined="2013-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2013-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2014-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="2013-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412391" joined="2014-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412243" joined="2013-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412491" joined="2014-01-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2013-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400546" joined="2014-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412247" joined="2013-12-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-12-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="1038"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4413"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commodities markets"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/11/2013--Introduced.
Public Power Risk Management Act of 2013 - Amends the Commodity Exchange Act to direct the Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC), when it determines whether to provide an exemption to designation as a swap dealer, to treat a utility operations-related swap entered into with a utility special entity as if such swap were entered into with an entity that is not a special entity. (Thus exempts an entity entering into a utility operations-related swap with a utility special entity from mandatory registration as a swap dealer.)

Requires transactions in utility operations-related swaps to be reported according to requirements for the reporting of uncleared swaps.

Defines "utility special entity" as a special entity, or any instrumentality, department, or corporation of or established by a state or local government, that: (1) owns or operates an electric or natural gas facility or an electric or natural gas operation; (2) supplies natural gas or electric energy to another utility special entity; (3) has public service obligations under federal, state, or local law or regulation to deliver electric energy or natural gas service to customers; or (4) is a federal power marketing agency.

Redefines swap to include a utility operations-related swap.

Defines "utility operations-related swap" as one that: (1) is entered into to hedge or mitigate commercial risk; (2) is associated with specified transactions in electric energy or natural gas; and (3) is not a contract, agreement, or transaction based on, derived on, or referencing

 an interest rate, credit, equity, or currency asset class; or a metal, agricultural commodity, or crude oil or gasoline commodity of any grade, except as used as fuel for electric energy generation.</summary>
</bill>
