<bill session="113" type="s" number="2795" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Career and Technical Education Opportunity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to expand the definition of eligible program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400013"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2014-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412324" joined="2014-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412582" joined="2014-09-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/11/2014--Introduced.
Career and Technical Education Opportunity Act - Amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to include as a program that is eligible to participate in the William D. Ford Federal Direct Loan program and the Federal Perkins Loans program an educational program that: (1) provides students with at least 250 clock hours of instruction over a minimum of five weeks, and (2) leads to an industry-recognized credential.

Defines an "industry-recognized credential" as one that:

 is demonstrated to be of high quality by the institution of higher education offering the educational program in its title IV participation agreement with the Secretary of Education; meets the current or projected needs of a local or regional workforce for recruitment, screening, hiring, retention, or advancement purposes; and is, where applicable, endorsed by a nationally recognized trade association or organization representing a significant part of the industry or sector.</summary>
</bill>
