<bill session="113" type="h" number="5092" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FAIR Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fair and Accountable IHS Recompense Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act to expedite civil actions, claims, and appeals under that Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400440"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee Indian and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII24" subcommittee="Indian and Alaska Native Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/11/2014--Introduced.
Fair and Accountable IHS Recompense Act of 2014 or the FAIR Act - Requires the annual report on the implementation of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act to be made available to the public.

Amends the Act to presume that in any civil action, claim, or related appeal brought under the Act the deficiency amounts reported to Congress accurately reflect the minimum damages due to any Indian tribe or tribal organization upon whose behalf such civil action, claim, or appeal was filed absent fraud or mathematical error.

Bars any of the funds awarded in such a case from being allocated for or used to pay attorney fees until: (1) the fees are documented and charged at reasonable hourly rates, and (2) the required documentation has been made available to specified congressional committees and the public.</summary>
</bill>
