<bill session="113" type="h" number="4105" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-02-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-02-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-02-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Maritime Goods Movement Act for the 21st Century</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a Maritime Goods Movement User Fee and provide grants for international maritime cargo improvements and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400262"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2014-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412505" joined="2014-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412584" joined="2014-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412583" joined="2014-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400232" joined="2014-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2014-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400379" joined="2014-02-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-02-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E268"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-27">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-27">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW07" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="1509"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Army Corps of Engineers"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/27/2014--Introduced.
Maritime Goods Movement Act for the 21st Century - Directs the U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) to impose a Maritime Goods Movement User Fee of 0.125% on all commercial cargo (except a U.S. export) that: (1) is unloaded from or loaded on a commercial vessel at a U.S. port, or (2) enters a U.S. point of entry.

Prescribes a special rule prohibiting the imposition of such fee on: (1) cargo (except crude oil with respect to Alaska) loaded on a vessel in a mainland U.S. port and transported for use or consumption in Alaska, Hawaii, or any U.S. possession; (2) cargo loaded on a vessel in Alaska, Hawaii, or any U.S. possession and transported for use or consumption in the U.S. mainland, Alaska, Hawaii, or U.S. possession; (3) the unloading of such cargo in Alaska, Hawaii, or U.S. possession, or U.S. mainland, respectively; or (4) cargo loaded on a vessel in Alaska, Hawaii, or U.S. possession and unloaded in the state or U.S. possession in which loaded, or passengers transported on U.S.-flag vessels operating solely within Alaskan or Hawaiian waters and adjacent international waters.

Prohibits imposition of such fee on: (1) on the United States or any U.S. agency, or (2) a nonprofit organization or cooperative for cargo intended for use in humanitarian or development assistance overseas.

Requires use of up to $10 million of fees collected during any fiscal year for administrative expenses of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS), the Army Corps of Engineers, and the Department of Transportation (DOT).

 Makes certain fee allocations for: (1) harbor maintenance programs; (2) low-use ports; and (3) super donor ports to carry out projects or activities under a competitive grant for maritime improvement projects for movement of goods, as well as for other specified maritime improvement projects for movement of international maritime cargo.

Defines "super donor port" as a port for which average expenditures in the 5 previous fiscal years: (1) from the Harbor Maintenance Trust Fund, for fiscal years beginning before enactment of this Act, are less than 10% percent of the total average amount of harbor maintenance taxes collected through landings at the port in such fiscal years; or (2) from the amounts collected for the Maritime Goods Movement User Fee, for fiscal years starting after enactment of this Act, are less than 10% of the total average amount of such fees collected through landings at the port.

Establishes a Competitive Grant Program for Goods Movement.

Amends the Internal Revenue Code to repeal the harbor maintenance tax.

Declares that nothing in this Act shall be construed to prevent application of requirements that locally prevailing wages (Davis-Bacon Act) be paid to various classes of laborers and mechanics working on harbor maintenance improvement projects.</summary>
</bill>
