<bill session="113" type="h" number="4886" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Forest System Trails Stewardship Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Agriculture to publish in the Federal Register a strategy to significantly increase the role of volunteers and partners in National Forest System trail maintenance, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412294"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412541" joined="2014-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412539" joined="2014-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412252" joined="2014-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412571" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412379" joined="2014-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412400" joined="2014-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412549" joined="2014-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="2014-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412505" joined="2014-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412463" joined="2014-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400151" joined="2014-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400154" joined="2014-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412388" joined="2014-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400221" joined="2014-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412419" joined="2014-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412191" joined="2014-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412295" joined="2014-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400266" joined="2014-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412189" joined="2014-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400290" joined="2014-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="408211" joined="2014-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400313" joined="2014-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400316" joined="2014-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412489" joined="2014-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412315" joined="2014-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412581" joined="2014-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412214" joined="2014-06-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-18">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-18">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Energy, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG15" subcommittee="Conservation, Energy, and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="Public Lands and Environmental Regulation" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/18/2014--Introduced.
National Forest System Trails Stewardship Act of 2014 - Directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to publish a national strategy to significantly increase the role of volunteers and partners in trail maintenance.

Requires the strategy to: (1) augment and support the capabilities of federal employees to carry out or contribute to trail maintenance; (2) provide opportunities for volunteers and partners to carry out trail maintenance in each region of the Forest Service; (3) address the barriers to increased volunteerism and partnerships; (4) prioritize increased volunteerism and partnerships in those regions with the most severe trail maintenance needs, and where backlogs are jeopardizing access to national forest lands; and (5) aim to increase trail maintenance by volunteers and partners by 100% within 5 years.

Directs USDA to study opportunities to improve trail maintenance by addressing opportunities to use fire crews in trail maintenance activities.

Deems a volunteer with a partner organization to be considered a federal employee for the purposes of civil claims relating to damage to, or loss of, personal property of a volunteer incident to volunteer services.

Sets forth provisions for the selection of priority areas for increased trail maintenance accomplishments.

Directs USDA to establish a pilot program to offset all or part of the land use fee for outfitting and guiding permits.</summary>
</bill>
