<bill session="113" type="h" number="5393" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-08-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-08-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Hospice Opportunities for Supporting Patients with Integrity and Care Evaluations (HOSPICE) Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for required Medicare hospice program surveys, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412393"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400403" joined="2014-08-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-08-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-08-01">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-08-01">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-08-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/1/2014--Introduced.
Hospice Opportunities for Supporting Patients with Integrity and Care Evaluations (HOSPICE) Act of 2014 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to subject any entity certified as a hospice program to a standard survey by an appropriate state or local survey agency, or an approved accreditation agency, at least once every 36 months.

Specifies funding from the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund for FY2014-FY2016 for such survey requirements.

Applies certain rules for the limitation of a beneficiary's liability with respect to denial of a Medicare payment for hospice care provided to an individual for more than 180 days in the same manner as such limitation applies with respect to denial of a payment for items and services as not reasonable or necessary for the diagnosis or treatment of an illness or injury.</summary>
</bill>
