<bill session="113" type="h" number="5772" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-12-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-12-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-12-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safeguarding Individual Privacy Against Government Invasion Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend section 552a of title 5, United States Code, to unequivocally authorize an award of provable damages, including damages that are not pecuniary damages.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412272"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-12-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-01">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-01">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU10" subcommittee="Constitution and Civil Justice" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/1/2014--Introduced.
Safeguarding Individual Privacy Against Government Invasion Act of 2014 - Amends the Privacy Act of 1974 to specify that the liability of the United States in a civil action brought by an individual adversely affected by a federal agency's intentional or willful failure to maintain accurate records concerning the individual is provable damages, including damages that are not pecuniary damages, sustained by the individual as a result of the refusal or failure, or $1,000, whichever is greater. (Currently, the United States is liable for actual damages, a term that is interpreted to be limited to economic harm or pecuniary damages, which excludes damages for mental or emotional distress.)</summary>
</bill>
