<bill session="113" type="s" number="2328" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-05-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fair Debt Collection Practices Technical Clarification Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Fair Debt Collection Practices Act to preclude law firms and licensed attorneys from the definition of a debt collector when taking certain actions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400408"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400418" joined="2014-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412321" joined="2014-05-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2892"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Debt collection"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/13/2014--Introduced.
Fair Debt Collection Practices Technical Clarification Act of 2014 - Amends the Fair Debt Collection Practices Act to exclude from the definition of "debt collector" any law firm or licensed attorney: (1) serving, filing, or conveying formal legal pleadings, discovery requests, or other documents pursuant to the applicable rules of civil procedure; or (2) communicating in, or at the direction of, a court of law or in depositions or settlement conferences, in connection with a pending legal action to collect a debt on behalf of a client.

Prohibits such amendments from being construed to exempt any law firm or licensed attorney engaged in any activity other than those activities specifically described in the amendments from being subject to any other applicable provision of the Fair Debt Collection Practices Act.</summary>
</bill>
