<bill session="113" type="h" number="5286" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Equitable Treatment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to provide for a more equitable geographic allocation of funds appropriated to the Department of Veterans Affairs for medical care.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400233"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-08-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR03" subcommittee="Health" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/2014--Introduced.
Veterans Equitable Treatment Act - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) to: (1) establish a maximum specialist referral period (the period between the date a veteran is referred to a VA specialty clinic by the veteran's VA primary care physician and the date the veteran is scheduled for an appointment with a VA specialist), subject to such exceptions as the Secretary considers necessary and consistent with current VA treatment policies based on clinical need and with the VA's 30-30-20 performance goal for such referral period; and (2) take steps to ensure that the VA is able to provide appropriate transportation services for qualified veterans within a reasonable time period of a scheduled appointment.

Requires the Secretary to: (1) promptly provide for such specialty care or transportation from a private source if the Secretary is not able to meet such standards, (2) reimburse such private provider or the reasonable value of such care or services, and (2) take steps to expedite such required reimbursement, consistent with the Veterans Health Administration policy that 90% of all non-VA contract care claims are processed within 30 days of receipt.

Terminates the requirement that a veteran must have received care from the VA within the 24-month period preceding the furnishing of emergency treatment at a non-VA facility in order to be considered an active VA health-care participant who is eligible for reimbursement for such treatment.</summary>
</bill>
