<bill session="113" type="s" number="1742" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-11-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-11-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-11-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Entrance Fee Suspension Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to temporarily suspend the collection of entrance fees at units of the National Park System and the National Wildlife Refuge System.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412582"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-11-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8365"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Customs enforcement"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/20/2013--Introduced.
Entrance Fee Suspension Act of 2013 - Directs the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the National Park Service and the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, during the period April 10-25, 2014, to suspend the collection of fees for admission to units of the National Park System and units of the National Wildlife Refuge System, respectively.

Requires the Secretary to report to the Secretary of the Treasury and the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) on the total amount of fees that would have been collected for admission to such units if collection had not been suspended.

Directs the Secretary, during FY2014, to transfer amounts equivalent to such uncollected fees from discretionary unobligated balances that are not designated as emergency or overseas contingency operations. Entitles the Secretary to receive and use such amounts to carry out this Act without further appropriation.

Amends the Consolidated Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1985, as an offset to such funds transfers, to extend from October 29, 2021, to November 5, 2021, the authority of the Secretary of the Treasury to charge and collect specified customs fees.</summary>
</bill>
