<bill session="113" type="h" number="5180" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Financial Stability Oversight Council Improvement Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Financial Stability Act of 2010 to improve the transparency of the Financial Stability Oversight Council, to improve the SIFI designation process, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412411"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="2014-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412541" joined="2014-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412544" joined="2014-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412292" joined="2014-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412527" joined="2014-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412509" joined="2014-07-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="Financial Stability Oversight Council"/>
    <term name="Financial crises and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/23/2014--Introduced.
Financial Stability Oversight Council Improvement Act of 2014 - Amends the Financial Stability Act of 2010 to subject the Financial Stability Oversight Council (Council) to the Administrative Procedure Act.

Requires the Council to make publicly available any final report study or analysis it has prepared, unless exempt from disclosure.

Requires the Council, when determining whether to subject a U.S. or a foreign nonbank financial company to supervision by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System and to prudential standards, to consider the appropriateness of imposing such standards as opposed to other forms of regulation to mitigate identified risks to U.S. financial stability.

Requires the Council, when reevaluating determinations with respect to a nonbank financial company under Federal Reserve Board supervision, to provide written notice to the company and afford it opportunity to submit written materials to contest the determination.

Directs the Council, upon identifying a nonbank financial company for comprehensive analysis of its potential to pose a threat to U.S. financial stability, to provide: (1) written notice that explains with specificity the basis for the identification, and (2) an opportunity to submit written materials for Council consideration.

Prescribes procedural requirements for proposed determinations and final decisionmaking by the Council, including periodic review of individual determinations.

Directs the Council every five years to study: (1) the impact of its determinations to subject nonbank financial companies to Federal Reserve Board supervision and prudential standards, and (2) whether such determinations have the intended result of improving domestic financial stability.</summary>
</bill>
