<bill session="113" type="h" number="4614" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-05-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Park Partner Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To enhance and clarify the ability of the National Park Service to work cooperatively with Park Partners to better use philanthropic and other non-Federal investments to achieve common objectives, public purposes and benefits, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412511"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412571" joined="2014-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412294" joined="2014-05-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="Public Lands and Environmental Regulation" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/8/2014--Introduced.
Park Partner Enhancement Act - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior, through the National Park Service, to enter into challenge cost-share agreements and certain cooperative agreements with educational institutions and nonprofits (Park Partners) to advance National Park Service programs and projects.

Includes among these any programs and projects to: (1) manage cooperatively improvements on lands and programs within or related to at least one unit of the National Park System (NPS); (2) assist the National Park Service to plan and construct National Park facilities and trails and restore landscapes and resources within or related to at least one NPS unit; (3) provide educational and interpretive programs and services; (4) develop, distribute, or sell educational and interpretive materials and projects; and (5) raise funds and assets through donation to support such projects and programs.

Allows the Secretary to consider the fair value of services performed by persons who volunteer their services required for the agreement to the National Park Service, and who are recruited, trained, and supported by a Park Partner, as up to 50% of any in-kind contribution of the Park Partner for cost sharing purposes.

Requires any funds donated, proceeds received, or cost-recovery amounts provided through agreements to remain available, without future appropriation, until expended for preservation, restoration, operation, maintenance, interpretation, public programs, and related expenses of the National Park Service or Park Partner.</summary>
</bill>
