<bill session="113" type="hr" number="499" updated="2015-09-01T10:18:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-03-11T19:12:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-03-11T19:12:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Condemning the violation of Ukrainian sovereignty, independence, and territorial integrity by military forces of the Russian Federation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400348"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400071" joined="2014-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412513" joined="2014-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412385" joined="2014-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="2014-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412553" joined="2014-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2014-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412435" joined="2014-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412465" joined="2014-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412421" joined="2014-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412468" joined="2014-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412540" joined="2014-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412569" joined="2014-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400652" joined="2014-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2014-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412534" joined="2014-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400371" joined="2014-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="409888" joined="2014-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412186" joined="2014-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="2014-03-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-03-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-05">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-05">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-05">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-06">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-03-06" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-03-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-07">
      <text>Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-11T15:55:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Royce moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2268" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-11T15:55:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2268-2273" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-11T15:55:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Res. 499.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-11T16:31:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-11T19:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2286" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="117" datetime="2014-03-11T19:12:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 402 - 7, 1 Present (Roll no. 117).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2268-2269" label="text"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Border Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international banking"/>
    <term name="Foreign property"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="Ukraine"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/11/2014--Passed House amended.
Condemns Russia's military violation of Ukrainian sovereignty, independence, and territorial integrity.

 States that Russia's military intervention: (1) is in breach of its United Nations (U.N.) obligations, and of the 1994 Budapest Memorandum on Security Assurances in which it pledged to respect Ukraine's independence and existing borders; and (2) poses a threat to international peace and security.

Calls on Russia to remove its military forces from Ukraine's Crimean peninsula, other than those operating in accordance with its 1997 agreement on the Status and Conditions of the Black Sea Fleet Stationing on the Territory of Ukraine, and to refrain from interference in all regions of Ukraine, including ending support of separatist and paramilitary forces in Crimea.

Declares that the Ukrainian people have the right to determine their own future free from outside interference.

Commends the Ukrainian government for its restraint and avoidance of military provocations.

Calls on: (1) the Ukrainian government to continue to protect the rights of minority populations within Ukraine, and (2) all Ukrainians to respect the legitimate government authorities in all parts of Ukraine.

Calls for the deployment of independent monitors from the Organization for Security and Cooperation in Europe in Crimea and other areas of Ukraine.

Calls on North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) allies and European Union (EU) member states to suspend military cooperation with Russia.

Calls upon the President and the leaders of other democratic states to boycott the G-8 summit in Sochi, Russia, to convene a G-7 summit in June 2014 that does not include Russia, and to consider expelling Russia from the group.

Calls on the Administration to work with our European allies and other countries to impose visa, financial, trade, and other sanctions on senior Russian officials and others complicit in Russia's intervention, and on appropriate entities.

States that the United States should participate with its European allies and other countries to provide the Ukrainian government with financial, economic, and technical assistance.

Calls on the United States, its European allies, and other countries and international organizations to provide assistance to ensure that new elections scheduled for May 2014 are free and in full accordance with international standards.

Calls on the United States and its European allies, other countries, and international organizations to develop a long-term strategy to support economic development in Ukraine.

 Calls on Ukraine and European countries and former Soviet Republics to support energy diversification to reduce Russian control of energy exports.

Supports Ukrainian efforts to: (1) achieve energy independence, and (2) combat corruption and protect individual rights through an independent judiciary and the rule of law.

Affirms the right of all countries in the region to exercise their sovereign rights within their internationally recognized borders free from outside intervention and to conduct their foreign policy in accordance with their determination of the best interests of their peoples.</summary>
</bill>
