<bill session="113" type="h" number="3913" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-30">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-01-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956 to require agencies to make considerations relating to the promotion of efficiency, competition, and capital formation before issuing or modifying certain regulations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412488"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412479" joined="2014-02-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-01-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-15">
      <text>Hearings Held by the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit Prior to Referral.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-30">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-07-30" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 32 - 22.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, Markup"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Commodity Futures Trading Commission"/>
    <term name="Competition and antitrust"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC)"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="National Credit Union Administration"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/16/2014--Introduced.
Amends the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956 with respect to certain prohibitions against proprietary trading by banking entities and certain relationships of such entities with hedge funds and private equity funds (Volcker rule).

Directs the Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC), the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC), and the appropriate federal banking agencies, when issuing or modifying any regulation related to such prohibitions, to consider: (1) whether it is necessary or appropriate in the public interest; (2) whether it will promote efficiency, competition, and capital formation; and (3) the impact it would have on competition.

Prohibits such agencies from adopting a regulation that would impose a burden on competition neither necessary nor appropriate in furtherance of the Act.

Directs such agencies to include in the statement of basis and purpose incorporated in the regulation the reasons for determining that any burden on competition imposed by the regulation is necessary or appropriate in furtherance of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
