<bill session="113" type="h" number="3322" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-10-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-10-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Eliminating Disparities in Diabetes Prevention, Access, and Care Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to prevent and treat diabetes, to promote and improve the care of individuals with diabetes, and to reduce health disparities, relating to diabetes, within racial and ethnic minority groups, including the African-American, Hispanic American, Asian American, Native Hawaiian and Other Pacific Islander, and American Indian and Alaskan Native communities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400101"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412565" joined="2014-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2014-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="2014-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400063" joined="2014-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412379" joined="2013-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412327" joined="2013-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="2013-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412584" joined="2014-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400179" joined="2013-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2014-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412561" joined="2014-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="2014-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2014-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="2013-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412558" joined="2014-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412293" joined="2014-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400663" joined="2014-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2013-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412518" joined="2014-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412575" joined="2014-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412585" joined="2014-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412308" joined="2014-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2013-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400347" joined="2014-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412219" joined="2014-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400422" joined="2014-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400431" joined="2013-10-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Behavioral sciences"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Digestive and metabolic diseases"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Genetics"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/23/2013--Introduced.
Eliminating Disparities in Diabetes Prevention, Access, and Care Act of 2013 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to: (1) expand, intensify, and support ongoing research and other activities with respect to prediabetes and diabetes, particularly type 2, in minority populations; (2) make grants for establishing a mentoring program for health care professionals to be more involved in weight counseling, obesity research, and nutrition; (3) provide for the participation of minority health professionals in diabetes-focused research programs; and (4) make grants for programs to establish a pipeline from high school to professional school that will increase minority representation in diabetes-focused health fields by expanding Minority Access to Research Careers (MARC) program internships and mentoring opportunities for recruitment.

Directs the Diabetes Mellitus Interagency Coordinating Committee to submit to Congress: (1) a report on federal research and public health activities with respect to prediabetes and diabetes in minority populations, and (2) an effective and comprehensive federal plan to address prediabetes and diabetes in minority populations.

Requires the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) to: (1) conduct and support research and public health activities with respect to diabetes in minority populations; (2) direct the Division of Diabetes Translation to conduct and support programs to educate the public on diabetes in minority populations and programs to educate minority populations about the causes and effects of diabetes; and (3) conduct and support programs to educate specific minority populations through culturally and linguistically appropriate information campaigns about prevention of, and managing, diabetes.

Requires the Director of the Health Resources and Services Administration to conduct and support specified programs to educate health professionals on the causes and effects of diabetes in minority populations.

Requires the Indian Health Service to: (1) conduct and support research and other activities with respect to diabetes; and (2) coordinate the collection of data on clinically and culturally appropriate diabetes treatment, care, prevention, and services by health care professionals to the American Indian population.

Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to seek to enter into an arrangement for the Institute of Medicine to submit to Congress an updated version of its 2002 report entitled "Unequal Treatment: Confronting Racial and Ethnic Disparities in Health Care," which shall address how racial and ethnic health disparities have changed since publication of the original report.</summary>
</bill>
