<bill session="113" type="h" number="4973" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Spurring Teacher Education Movement for STEM Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">STEM for STEM Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the rural and low-income program under the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to include professional development in STEM education, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400313"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED14" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/25/2014--Introduced.
Spurring Teacher Education Movement for STEM Act or the STEM for STEM Act - Expresses the sense of Congress that:

 the United States should be at the forefront of science, technology, engineering, and math (STEM) education; students in low-income and rural areas have limited access to STEM resources; teachers should have high-quality professional development opportunities in STEM; and teacher professional development should provide strategies for integrating STEM education across all demographics. Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to allow local educational agencies to use grant funds under the Rural and Low-Income School program to train teachers to provide STEM education.</summary>
</bill>
