<bill bill-stage="Enrolled-Bill" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HF08E26CA7E024704BEE0E7F6E2B21377" public-private="public" stage-count="1">  
<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"> HR 4189 ENR: To designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 4000 Leap Road in Hilliard, Ohio, as the “Master Sergeant Shawn T. Hannon, Master Sergeant Jeffrey J. Rieck and Veterans Memorial Post Office Building”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"/>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>One Hundred Thirteenth Congress of the United States of America</congress> <session>At the Second Session</session>
    <enrolled-dateline>Begun and held at the City of Washington on Friday, the third day of January, two thousand and fourteen</enrolled-dateline> 
<legis-num>H. R. 4189</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no"/> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 4000 Leap Road in Hilliard, Ohio, as the <quote>Master Sergeant Shawn T. Hannon, Master Sergeant Jeffrey J. Rieck and Veterans Memorial Post Office Building</quote>.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H316CBD85962944C994B56F0BF7E779ED" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7FFC3B8D83774151A179A3B886F6BFB3" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Master Sergeant Shawn T. Hannon, Master Sergeant Jeffrey J. Rieck and Veterans Memorial Post Office Building</header> 
<subsection id="H6EAAC7A71EBB4273B979F9FA6E6F83FF">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Designation</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The facility of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="1800" entity-type="federal-body">United States Postal Service</cato:entity-ref> located at 4000 Leap Road in Hilliard, Ohio, shall be known and designated as the <quote>Master Sergeant Shawn T. Hannon, Master Sergeant Jeffrey J. Rieck and Veterans Memorial Post Office Building</quote>.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H74B15C1754824BFBA2C3A8694D04BAB5">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>References</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any reference in a law, map, regulation, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the facility referred to in subsection (a) shall be deemed to be a reference to the <quote>Master Sergeant Shawn T. Hannon, Master Sergeant Jeffrey J. Rieck and Veterans Memorial Post Office Building</quote>.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
</legis-body> <attestation>
    <attestation-group>
      <role>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</role>
    </attestation-group>
    <attestation-group>
      <role>Vice President of the United States and President of the Senate.</role>
    </attestation-group>
  </attestation>
</bill>