<bill session="113" type="s" number="2957" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-11-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-11-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-11-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Do Not Disturb Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to limit the disturbance to American families caused by electioneering phone calls by expanding the National Do Not Call Registry to include Super PACs and other third-party political groups, to prohibit robo-calls to Americans who have listed their telephone numbers on the Registry, and to prohibit push-polling.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412326"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-11-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/20/2014--Introduced.
Do Not Disturb Act of 2014 - Directs the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to expand the list of entities prohibited from making telephone calls to numbers on the FTC's "do-not-call" registry to include: (1) political committees that accept donations or contributions that do not comply with contribution limits or source prohibitions (commonly known as Super PACs), and (2) tax exempt non-profit social welfare organizations engaged in political activities.

Requires the FTC to expand rules against abusive telemarking to prohibit: (1) computer-dialed telephone calls with prerecorded messages (robo-calls) to numbers on the registry, and (2) push-polling calls regarding a candidate for public office in which voters are asked certain questions about opposing candidates or are likely to construe the call as a survey for an independent organization.

Provides exceptions to allow robo-calls for emergencies or with the consent of the called party.</summary>
</bill>
