<bill session="113" type="h" number="5307" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">America's Energy Security Trust Fund Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to reduce carbon pollution in the United States, invest in the Nation's infrastructure, and cut taxes for working Americans.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400233"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Employment taxes"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2014--Introduced.
America's Energy Security Trust Fund Act of 2014 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to impose an excise tax, beginning in calendar year 2016, on any taxable carbon substance sold by its manufacturer, producer, or importer. Defines "taxable carbon substance" as: (1) coal (including lignite and peat); (2) petroleum and any petroleum products; and (3) natural gas that is extracted, manufactured, or produced in the United States, or entered into the United States for consumption, use, or warehousing.

Establishes in the Treasury the America's Energy Security Trust Fund to assist industries negatively affected by this Act, make transfers to the Highway Trust Fund to cover shortfalls, and provide payroll tax relief.

Allows individual taxpayers a tax credit equal to carbon tax rebate amounts calculated by the Secretary of the Treasury.

Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to study and report to Congress on the best methods to assess and collect taxes on non-carbon greenhouse gases.

Expresses the sense of Congress that the United States should establish binding agreements with major greenhouse gas emitting nations to reduce global greenhouse gas emissions.</summary>
</bill>
