<bill session="113" type="h" number="4350" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-05-29">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-05-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Northern Cheyenne Lands Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Northern Cheyenne Lands Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to take lands and mineral rights on the reservation of the Northern Cheyenne Tribe of Montana and other culturally important lands into trust, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412549"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee Indian and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-07">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-29">
      <text>Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-29">
      <text>Subcommittee Indian and Alaska Native Affairs Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-29">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-05-29" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-09-15T16:42:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 113-597.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-09-15T16:42:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="444">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 444.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII24" subcommittee="Indian and Alaska Native Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2256"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2442"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Energy revenues and royalties"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/1/2014--Introduced.
Northern Cheyenne Lands Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to take approximately 1,568 acres of land in Montana depicted on two specified maps into trust for the Northern Cheyenne Tribe.

Requires, after the Secretary receives notice from the Tribe that it has a revenue sharing agreement with Great Northern Properties regarding future development of the Northern Cheyenne Federal Tracts:

 Great Northern Properties to convey to the Tribe its coal and iron ore mineral interests underlying the land on the Northern Cheyenne Reservation generally depicted on the map entitled "Northern Cheyenne Land Act: Coal Tracts" and dated February 27, 2014, and the Secretary to convey to Great Northern Properties all of the United States' coal mineral interests underlying the land generally depicted as "Bull Mountains" and "East Fork" on the map entitled "Northern Cheyenne Federal Tracts" and dated February 27, 2014. Directs the Secretary to ensure that the deed for those federal coal mineral interests includes a covenant, running with the land, that precludes surface mining of the coal absent the written consent of the surface owner.

Requires the coal and iron ore mineral interests conveyed to the Tribe under this Act to be held, upon the Tribe's request, in trust for the Tribe.

Prohibits Montana from taxing the mineral interests this Act conveys to the Tribe.

Requires that, in return for this Act's mineral conveyances:

 the Tribe must waive all of its claims arising from the continuing failure of the United States to acquire those private coal and iron ore mineral interests in trust for the Tribe as part of its Reservation as directed by Congress in 1900, and Great Northern Properties must waive any claim against the United States relating to the value or completion of this Act's conveyances of mineral interests. Requires the Northern Cheyenne Trust Fund (Fund) to be transferred to the Tribe and deposited into the Tribe's Permanent Fund. Requires the Tribe, in return for such transfer, to waive all of its claims arising from U.S. management of the Fund.</summary>
</bill>
