<bill session="113" type="h" number="2983" updated="2015-09-01T10:19:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safe Hydration is an American Right in Energy Development Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Safe Drinking Water Act to require testing of underground sources of drinking water in connection with hydraulic fracturing operations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400360"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412571" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2013-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400184" joined="2013-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2013-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="412511" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2013-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="2014-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="2013-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412521" joined="2013-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2014-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412560" joined="2013-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412585" joined="2014-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412219" joined="2013-09-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-08-02">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5353"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and the Economy.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF18" subcommittee="Environment and the Economy" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/2/2013--Introduced.
Safe Hydration is an American Right in Energy Development Act of 2013 - Amends the Safe Drinking Water Act to require states, in order to obtain primary enforcement responsibility for a state underground injection control program, to prohibit the underground injection of fluids or propping agents pursuant to hydraulic fracturing operations related to oil, gas, or geothermal production activities unless the person proposing to conduct the hydraulic fracturing operations agrees to conduct testing and report data in accordance with this Act.

Directs regulations under such Act for state underground injection control programs to require any person conducting such hydraulic fracturing operations to: (1) conduct testing of underground sources of drinking water in accordance with sampling and testing requirements described in this Act, and (2) report to the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) on the results of such testing.

Exempts hydraulic fracturing operations from such testing and reporting requirements if there is no accessible underground source of drinking water within a radius of one mile of the site where the operations occur.

Requires the Administrator to establish and maintain a publicly accessible and searchable database of such results.</summary>
</bill>
