<bill session="113" type="h" number="4467" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-04-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-04-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Best Return on America's Investment Now Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">BRAIN Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to provide for visas for certain advanced STEM graduates, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400063"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Border Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/10/2014--Introduced.
Best Return on America's Investment Now Act or BRAIN Act - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to make up to 10% of the worldwide employment-based immigration level available to qualified immigrants who: (1) hold a doctorate degree in a field of science, technology, engineering, or mathematics (STEM degree) from a U.S. doctoral institution of higher education; and (2) have taken all doctoral courses in a STEM field, including all courses taken by correspondence or by distance education, while physically present in the United States.

Reduces the number of immigrant visas available to skilled workers, professionals, and other workers.

Revises the computation of the total number of immigrant visas that may be made available to natives of any single foreign state or dependent area in a fiscal year.

States that: (1) the permanent priority date for any employment-based petition shall be the date on which the petition is filed with Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) (or the Secretary of State, if applicable), unless such filing was preceded by the filing of a labor certification with the Secretary of Labor, in which case that date shall constitute the priority date; and (2) an alien who is the beneficiary of an employment-based petition that was approvable when filed shall retain that petition's priority date in the consideration of any subsequently filed employment-based petition.</summary>
</bill>
