<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HBC1C1E56E3094EAB9F745D5C96D1258E" key="H" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HR 5734 IH: Right of Return Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2014-11-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 5734</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20141118">November 18, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000937">Mr. Stockman</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To achieve a lasting peace in the Middle East and improve the economic situation for its people.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H8153A8D1C6E6459AB0F12AEE9F230CBF" style="OLC">
		<section id="HB42E83A8164843FB9FC06387235D2054" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
			<text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Right of Return Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id4C51107ED1454AD195CEB8888CBCEDBD" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Plan for peace</header><subsection id="id5506714AE413492E9D38F81D3A188460"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds as follows:</text><paragraph id="id45EB281120664922A5C43004BB41E8F0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The policy of the two-state solution and the concept of <quote>land for peace</quote> have consistently failed to bring about a lasting peace in the Land of Israel.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7965F2C5BC8F4833841DA6F64247161B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In November 2014, Suha Arafat, wife of former Palestine Liberation Organization chair Yasser
			 Arafat, stated in the Italian newspaper La Repubblica that <quote>The armed struggle today will not lead to anything. We will only end up crushed.</quote>. In that same interview, Arafat also stated that <quote>Hamas has taken people hostage</quote> and <quote>A generation … is growing up in violence, with no education, with no hope but emigration</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id43CE969C69C14AE6A76CF787AFF09C0E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Palestinian Authority has been offered a sovereign state in virtually the entirety of the
			 disputed territories on multiple occasions, including in 2000, 2001, and
			 2008, and has rejected it each time.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idE356377C0BAC482980D7A45AE42BE03F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The 2011 unemployment rate at 28.4 percent for Palestinian Arabs, compared with 5.1 percent for
			 Israeli Arabs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idBB06A44BF6114342A3380131A23736A3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A September 2007 survey by the Center for Palestinian Policy and Research found that 32 percent of
			 Palestinian Arabs want to emigrate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idE5E82107E7204968A0A68A34C36A626C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Emirate of Transjordan was created out of the British Mandate for Palestine for the explicit
			 purpose of being the home for Palestinian Arabs by the Transjordan
			 Memorandum in 1922.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id77AC54D9E3CE45E38657AD639EB8914B"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The concept of enabling people to move to new homes in other territories was recommended as a
			 solution to the conflict by the Peel Commission in 1937 and was also
			 recommended as a solution to the conflict by the United Nations Partition
			 Plan for Palestine in 1947.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2659D5EE01DA41D59D3B091EC7002FAB"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The 2012 Levy Report found that the region of Judea and Samaria does not fall under the
			 jurisdiction of the 1949 Fourth Geneva Convention.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idE32B7D5B101C45CEA60541AE75788564"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The purpose of this bill is to increase the economic wealth and civil rights of Palestinian Arabs.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1285053965E6473990C79B906B66F1A2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Plan for peace</header><text>The Congress of the United States shall take the following course of action:</text><paragraph id="id690EE2E4D2CB4DE1862502A0F7963B80"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary of State shall call for the State of Israel to increase the standard of living of
			 those living in Judea, Samaria, and Gaza by extending its sovereignty over
			 those territories, and for the Palestinian Arab residents currently
			 residing in those areas to be granted citizenship in the countries that
			 controlled those territories from 1949 to 1967 and have a right of return
			 to those countries.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8E6B8F4CE9C743BDA7BC5CE89FCA2826"><enum>(2)</enum><text>As long as part of the unity government of the Palestinian Authority refuses to allow the right of
			 return to the countries that controlled Judea, Samaria, and Gaza from 1949
			 to 1967, no funds appropriated by Congress under any Act may be obligated
			 or expended to provide any United States assistance, loan guarantee, or
			 debt relief to the Palestinian Authority.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idC6E0553A89B04669A341DC917CA5C016"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Secretary of State of the United States shall take such action as will ensure that refugees are
			 allowed to be properly allowed to return into their host countries in
			 accordance with the regulations set forth by the United Nations High
			 Commission for Refugees (UNHCR).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idBBD1B6C937DA47EC9B326382D2055BCA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>All United States assistance, loan guarantee, and debt relief that currently goes to the United
			 Nations Relief and Works Agency for Palestinian Refugees in the Near East
			 (UNRWA) shall instead be used to assist those who exercise their right of
			 return to the countries who controlled Judea, Samaria, and Gaza from 1949
			 to 1967.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


