<bill session="113" type="h" number="5857" updated="2015-09-01T17:50:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-12-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-12-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-12-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Infrastructure and Global Tax Competitiveness Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To eliminate the incentive for corporations to continue to hold accumulated earnings offshore, to invest in domestic infrastructure, to provide for international tax reform, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412544"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-12-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-11">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-11">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW12" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Business expenses"/>
    <term name="Capital gains tax"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Government corporations and government-sponsored enterprises"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Income tax rates"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Insurance industry and regulation"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Internal Revenue Service (IRS)"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Taxation of foreign income"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/11/2014--Introduced.
Infrastructure and Global Tax Competitiveness Act of 2014 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to the taxation of earnings and profits of a deferred foreign income corporation, to: (1) make such earnings and profit subject to taxation in the last taxable year prior to January 1, 2015, (2) reduce the rate of tax on such earnings and profits by allowing an exemption of 75%, and (3) allow such corporations to elect to pay such tax in eight installments.

Establishes the American Infrastructure Fund to provide assistance to states, local governments, and other public and private entities for investment in public infrastructure projects.

Appropriates tax revenues from this Act to the Highway Trust Fund.

Establishes the Highway Trust Fund Solvency Commission to propose recommendations and legislation for achieving long-term solvency of the Highway Trust Fund.

Establishes an 18-month deadline for the enactment of legislation that reforms the international tax system by eliminating the incentive to hold earnings in low-tax jurisdictions.

Sets forth provisions for the reform of the international tax system (to be effective if reform legislation is not enacted by the 18-month deadline established by this Act), including provisions relating to subpart F income and insurance income, gains and losses from the sale or exchange of stock in controlled foreign corporations, limitations on the foreign tax credit, and the tax treatment of previously deferred foreign income.</summary>
</bill>
