<bill session="113" type="s" number="2175" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-03-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-03-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-03-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Enhancing Access for Agents and Brokers Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to enhance access for independent agents and brokers to information regarding marketplace enrollment.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300063"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412326" joined="2014-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412554" joined="2014-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412391" joined="2014-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2014-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412321" joined="2014-03-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-03-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Insurance industry and regulation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/27/2014--Introduced.
Enhancing Access for Agents and Brokers Act - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish a toll-free customer service support help line to enable certified health insurance agents and brokers to seek assistance regarding qualified health plans offered in the federal health insurance marketplace.

Amends the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to require the Secretary to establish procedures to permit a broker name and National Producer Number to be added to an application for enrollment in a health plan offered through a health care exchange at any time during the application process and for any enrollment period.

 Requires such procedures to ensure that the National Producer Number is designed to assist consumers in obtaining needed assistance to complete enrollment, ensure that brokers are adequately compensated, and provide consumer protections by identifying each agent or broker that has worked on an enrollment case.

Directs the Secretary to:

 make available on the federal government website for health insurance coverage a list of all certified agents and brokers; contract with the National Insurance Producers Registry to regularly verify the licensure status of all such agents and brokers and develop a mechanism to enable submission of changes to contact and licensure information; and provide trained navigators, agents, and brokers, no later than five business days after promulgation or issuance of any new cost- or enrollment-related policies, with a clear description of such policy changes.</summary>
</bill>
