<bill session="113" type="hr" number="600" updated="2015-09-01T10:18:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-09T16:17:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-06-09T16:17:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-05-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Urging the Government of Afghanistan, following a successful first round of the presidential election on April 5, 2014, to pursue a transparent, credible, and inclusive run-off presidential election on June 14, 2014, while ensuring the safety of voters, candidates, poll workers, and election observers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412276"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400071" joined="2014-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412283" joined="2014-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400195" joined="2014-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412468" joined="2014-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412540" joined="2014-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2014-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400348" joined="2014-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400371" joined="2014-05-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-05-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-28">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-28">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-05-29">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-05-29" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-06-09T16:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Royce moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-09T16:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5106-5108" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-06-09T16:03:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Res. 600.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2014-06-09T16:17:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5106-5107" label="text"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Political movements and philosophies"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Voting rights"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/9/2014--Passed House amended.
Commends the government of Afghanistan for holding a successful first round of the presidential election and expresses support for a credible second round on June 14, 2014.

 Supports the mandate of Afghan electoral bodies such as the Independent Election Commission (IEC) and the Electoral Complaints Commission (ECC) to administer polls to prevent fraud and misconduct.

Encourages the government of Afghanistan to implement measures that will increase voter participation, particularly among the Afghan female population.

Recognizes the determination of the Afghan people to exercise their right to vote and determine their country's destiny.

Urges the government of Afghanistan to assure that fraudulent electoral activities do not take place during the runoff.

 Urges the IEC to better mitigate fraud, improve electoral transparency, and communicate these measures to the people of Afghanistan.

Urges: (1) communication between the IEC and the Afghanistan National Security Forces (ANSF) to provide security for vulnerable areas of the country during the election period; and (2) the ANSF to ensure the safety of voters, candidates, poll workers, and election observers.

Encourages all elements of Afghan society to refrain from fomenting disturbances in voting areas.

Supports the full participation of Afghan civil society in the election process.

Recognizes that a democratically-elected government that reflects the will of the Afghan people and is committed to combating terrorism would promote the long-term stability and security interests of Afghanistan, its neighbors, and its partners in the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) International Security Assistance Force, including the United States.

Recognizes the sacrifices of U.S. and coalition armed forces to Afghanistan's security and stability.</summary>
</bill>
