<bill session="113" type="s" number="2016" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-02-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-02-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-02-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">California Emergency Drought Relief Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of Commerce, and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to take actions to provide additional water supplies and disaster assistance to the State of California due to drought, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300043"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2014-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2014-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2014-02-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-02-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S891-892"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S893-896" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="4039"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4039"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4239"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2198"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation and pollution"/>
    <term name="Agricultural practices and innovations"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Aquaculture"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Farmland"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Insects"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Migrant, seasonal, agricultural labor"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/11/2014--Introduced.
California Emergency Drought Relief Act of 2014 - Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), the Secretary of Commerce, and the Secretary of the Interior (Secretaries), in response to the declaration of a state of drought emergency in California, to provide the maximum quantity of water supplies possible to Central Valley Project (CVP) and Klamath Project agricultural, municipal and industrial, and refuge service and repayment contractors, State Water Project contractors, and any other locality or municipality in California by approving, consistent with applicable laws: (1) any project or operations to provide additional water supplies if there is any possible way the Secretaries can do so, unless the project or operations constitute a highly inefficient way of providing additional water supplies; and (2) any projects or operations as quickly as possible based on available information to address the emergency conditions.

Sets forth actions to be taken to increase water supply, including: (1) ensuring that the Delta Cross Channel Gates remain open to the greatest extent possible, (2) requiring the Director of the National Marine Fisheries Service to recommend revisions to operations of the CVP and the California State Water Project, (3) adopt a 1:1 inflow to export ratio for the increased flow of the San Joaquin River, (4) require the Director and the Commissioner of the Bureau of Reclamation to complete all requirements under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (NEPA) and the Endangered Species Act of 1973 necessary to make final permit decisions on water transfer requests, and (5) make WaterSMART grant funding administered by the Bureau of Reclamation available for eligible projects on a priority and expedited basis.

Authorizes financial assistance under the Reclamation States Emergency Drought Relief Act of 1991 for projects to increase water supply.

Requires federal agency heads to consult with the Council on Environmental Quality to develop alternative arrangements to comply with NEPA.

Directs the EPA to prioritize projects under state water pollution control revolving funds to provide water to areas at risk of having an inadequate&#160;supply of water for&#160;public health and safety purposes.

Requires the Commissioner of Reclamation to provide water supply planning assistance in preparation for and in response to dry, critically dry, and below normal water year types, upon request, to CVP or Klamath Project contractors or other reclamation project contractors in California, including contractors who possess contracts for refuge water supplies or who deliver refuge water supplies.

Reauthorizes: (1) the Calfed Bay-Delta Act, (2) the Reclamation States Emergency Drought Relief Act of 1991, and (3) the Secure Water Act.

Amends the Klamath Basin Water Supply Enhancement Act of 2000 to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to take actions to reduce water consumption or demand or to restore ecosystems in the Klamath Basin watershed, including tribal fishery resources held in trust.

Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to transfer to the Secretary of Agriculture emergency supplemental appropriations to provide: (1) drought assistance to agricultural producers and for mitigation activities related to drought and wildfire hazards, (2) emergency community water assistance grants to address impacts of drought, and (3) grants to assist low-income migrant and seasonal farm workers affected by drought and for forest restoration.

Amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to expand federal emergency assistance to provide for disaster unemployment, emergency nutrition, and crisis counseling assistance.

Designates this Act as an emergency requirement for budgetary purposes.</summary>
</bill>
