<bill session="113" type="hr" number="622" updated="2015-09-01T10:18:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives regarding the national security interests of the United States and its allies and partners with respect to the Palestinian Authority.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400141"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412216" joined="2014-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412541" joined="2014-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400018" joined="2014-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412395" joined="2014-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412252" joined="2014-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412531" joined="2014-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412472" joined="2014-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412463" joined="2014-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400651" joined="2014-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412397" joined="2014-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412401" joined="2014-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412434" joined="2014-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412460" joined="2014-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412226" joined="2014-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400220" joined="2014-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412191" joined="2014-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412256" joined="2014-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400630" joined="2014-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412487" joined="2014-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400441" joined="2014-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412569" joined="2014-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412551" joined="2014-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400320" joined="2014-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412309" joined="2014-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412310" joined="2014-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412581" joined="2014-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="410396" joined="2014-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412522" joined="2014-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412574" joined="2014-06-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-09-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Middle East and North Africa.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA13" subcommittee="Middle East and North Africa" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Arab-Israeli relations"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development programs"/>
    <term name="Palestinians"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/12/2014--Introduced.
Reaffirms U.S. law and appropriations legislation conditioning assistance to, and cooperation with, the Palestinian Authority (PA).

Reaffirms the U.S. commitment to a democratic framework for peace decided through direct negotiations between Israeli and Palestinian leadership, without the interference of Hamas.

 Calls on the Department of State to work with European partners to support implementation of all necessary measures on suspending multilateral assistance to, and and security cooperation with, the PA.

Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that since Hamas and Fatah have unified, regardless of the unity government being made up of Hamas and Fatah technocrats, the Secretary of State should, if the unity government is not dissolved, designate the PA and such unity government as a foreign terrorist organization and redesignate the Palestinian Liberation Organization (PLO) as a foreign terrorist organization.

 Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that it is in the national security interests of the United States and its partners that the following objectives and conditions be achieved:

 the PA dissolving the unity government with Hamas, a long-designated foreign terrorist organization, and for the PA to renounce violence, outlaw terrorist groups, and re-enter into bilateral negotiations with Israel; the PA formally and publicly recognizing the Jewish state of Israel's right to exist, accepting previous Israeli-Palestinian agreements, and ending all anti-U.S and anti-Israel incitement; repealing the Law of the Prisoner and abolishing the Ministry of Prisoners and programs relating to compensation and recognition of convicted terrorists; rescinding the names and the naming of public institutions and civil projects after convicted terrorist and murders; ending all efforts to circumvent the statehood process at the United Nations (U.N.), including applications and memberships to international institutions outside direct negotiations with Israel; enacting reforms to advance religious freedom and recognition for all religions and ethnicities, ensuring the freedoms of speech, the press, and political assembly, and reforming the political process through elections without any influence or participation by Hamas; and abiding by all U.S laws on foreign assistance to the PA.</summary>
</bill>
