<bill session="113" type="s" number="25" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-02-15">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-02-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-01-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">South Utah Valley Electric Conveyance Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">South Utah Valley Electric Conveyance Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">South Utah Valley Electric Conveyance Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of the Interior to convey certain Federal features of the electric distribution system to the South Utah Valley Electric Service District, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by senate">An act to ensure that the reduced annual cost-of-living adjustment to the retired pay of members and former members of the Armed Forces under the age of 62 required by the Bipartisan Budget Act of 2013 will not apply to members or former members who first became members prior to January 1, 2014, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="enacted">To ensure that the reduced annual cost-of-living adjustment to the retired pay of members and former members of the Armed Forces under the age of 62 required by the Bipartisan Budget Act of 2013 will not apply to members or former members who first became members prior to January 1, 2014, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300052"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412495" joined="2013-01-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-01-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-03-14" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-04-22">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Wyden without amendment. With written report No. 113-15.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-04-22" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="46">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 46.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2013-06-19" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4717-4722" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S4717-4718" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-06-20T14:00:00-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-20">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-20T15:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-11T14:03:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Fitzpatrick moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-11T14:03:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1739-1741" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-11T14:03:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 25.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-11T14:21:00-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-11T15:02:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1743" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote2" roll="60" datetime="2014-02-11T15:11:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_BACK:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 326 - 90, 1 Present (Roll no. 60).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1739" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-02-12">
      <text>Message on House action received in Senate and at desk: House amendment to Senate bill.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="pingpong" roll="35" datetime="2014-02-12" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>Senate agreed to House amendment to Senate bill by Yea-Nay Vote. 95 - 3. Record Vote Number: 35.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S934-935" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S934" label="text as Senate agreed to House amendment"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-02-12">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2014-02-14">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2014-02-15" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="113-82" type="public" datetime="2014-02-15">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 113-82.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="hc" number="81"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="251"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="251"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/15/2014--Public Law.
Amends the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985, with respect to the implementation of direct spending reductions, to require the President to order a sequestration for FY2024 on the date the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) issues its sequestration preview report for such fiscal year.

Makes the reduction in annual cost-of-living adjustments of military retired pay for armed forces members under age 62 enacted by the Bipartisan Budget Act of 2013 inapplicable to those who first became members before January 1, 2014. (That Act reduced the cost-of-living adjustments from the full Consumer Price Index [CPI] to the CPI less 1%.)

Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to replace the requirement to establish a Medicare Improvement Fund with one that requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish a Transitional Fund for Sustainable Growth Rate (SGR) Reform, available to provide funds to pay for physicians' services under part B (Supplementary Medical Insurance) to supplement the conversion factor for 2017 if the conversion factor for that year is less than that for 2013. Makes $2.3 billion available to the Fund from the Federal Supplementary Medical Insurance Trust Fund for expenditures during or after 2017.</summary>
</bill>
