<bill session="113" type="hr" number="548" updated="2015-09-01T10:18:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-04-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-04-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Amending the Rules of the House of Representatives to require the mandatory annual ethics training offered to Members, officers, and employees of the House to include a specific program of training in the prevention and deterrence of sexual harassment in employment, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412259"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2996"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers and employees"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/8/2014--Introduced.
Amends Rule XI (Procedures of Committees and Unfinished Business) of the Rules of the House of Representatives to require the House Ethics Committee's mandatory annual ethics training offered to Members and House officers and employees to include a specific program of training in the prevention and deterrence of sexual harassment in employment.

Describes this program as one which provides information and practical guidance regarding any applicable federal and state laws concerning the prohibition against and the prevention and correction of sexual harassment and the remedies available to victims of it in employment.

Requires the program to:

 include practical examples aimed at instructing supervisors in the prevention of harassment, discrimination, and retaliation; be presented by individuals with knowledge and expertise in the prevention of these activities; and provide at least one hour of training, except that in the case of a new House officer or employee, at least two hours. Defines "sexual harassment" as any conduct directed at an individual which consists of unwelcome sexual advances, requests for sexual favors, or any other conduct of a sexual nature, if submission by the individual to such conduct is made either explicitly or implicitly a term or condition of the individual's employment, submission to or rejection of such conduct by the individual is used as the basis for employment decisions affecting the individual, or such conduct has the purpose or effect of interfering with the individual's work performance or creating an intimidating, hostile, or offensive working environment.</summary>
</bill>
