<bill session="113" type="s" number="2676" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Domestic Violence Gun Homicide Prevention Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a grant program to encourage States to adopt certain policies and procedures relating to the transfer and possession of firearms.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412490"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2014-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2014-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412582" joined="2014-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="2014-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412194" joined="2014-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412507" joined="2014-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412542" joined="2014-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-07-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/29/2014--Introduced.
Domestic Violence Gun Homicide Prevention Act of 2014 - Authorizes the Director of the Office of Community Oriented Policing Services of the Department of Justice (DOJ) to make grants to assist eligible states in carrying out policies, procedures, protocols, laws, or regulations relating to the possession or transfer of firearms or ammunition that:

 impose restrictions and penalties substantially similar to or more comprehensive than those applicable to possession by or transfer to persons subject to a court order for stalking-related offenses against an intimate partner or child or persons convicted of a misdemeanor crime of domestic violence; require the seizure or surrender of all firearms and ammunition from an individual convicted of any crime for which any such restrictions or penalties apply or against whom a court has issued a protection order; require state and local courts to consider, at the initial appearance before a magistrate of any individual arrested for any crime for which such restrictions or penalties apply, if the individual possesses a firearm or ammunition that has been or is likely to be used to threaten, harass, or harm the victim or the victim's child or otherwise pose a danger to them and to issue a protection order prohibitting the possession of any firearm or ammunition and require the surrender or seizure of any firearm or ammunition possessed; give state and local law enforcement the authority to seize a firearm or ammunition when responding to specified domestic violence situations, if there is probable cause to believe such firearm or ammunition is contraband or illegally in the possession of the suspected offender and is likely to be used to threaten, harass, menace, or harm, or to otherwise pose a danger to, the victim or the victim's child; and provide for the safe return of any seized or surrendered firearm or ammunition when such restrictions and penalties no longer apply.</summary>
</bill>
