<bill session="113" type="h" number="3567" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-11-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-11-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-11-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medicare Link Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for additional coverage options for beneficiaries under the original Medicare fee-for-service program through a Medicare Link program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412315"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412489" joined="2013-11-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-11-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-20">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-20">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/20/2013--Introduced.
Medicare Link Act of 2013 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish a Medicare Link Program through which individuals entitled to enroll in a Medicare Advantage (MA) plan under Medicare part C (Medicare+Choice), but who are not enrolled in one, are eligible to enroll with a nongovernmental Medicare Link contractor which shall provide: (1) a specified variety of optional care management services as well as coverage of the same items and services covered under Medicare parts A and B, and (2) a reduction or rebate in the premium otherwise applicable under Medicare part B as well as in cost-sharing.</summary>
</bill>
