<resolution xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" dms-id="HDFDE16AA24594B0B8F0F20003710DC90" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-concurrent" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">113 HCON 85 IH: Expressing the sense of Congress that a commemorative postage stamp should be issued in honor of the Buffalo Soldiers.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">2014-02-21</dc:date>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. CON. RES. 85</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20140221">February 21, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc>
        <sponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="E000292">Mr. Enyart</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001063">Ms. Hahn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001251">Mr. Butterfield</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001175">Ms. Speier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001166">Mr. McNerney</cosponsor>) submitted the following concurrent resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>
      </action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>CONCURRENT RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of Congress that a commemorative postage stamp should be issued in honor of
			 the Buffalo Soldiers.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas>
      <text>Whereas, on July 28, 1866, Congress established six all-Black regiments, later consolidated to
			 four, to help rebuild the country after the Civil War and to patrol the
			 remote western frontier during the Indian wars;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas Colonel Charles Young was a Buffalo Soldier and the highest ranking African-American
			 commanding officer in the United States Army from 1894 until his death in
			 1922;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas more than 200,000 African-Americans served in World War I and more than 1 million served in
			 World War II;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Buffalo Soldiers received their name because of the buffalo’s fierce bravery and
			 fighting spirit;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas African-American troops accepted the name, Buffalo Soldiers, with pride and honor;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Buffalo Soldiers fought alongside White regiments in many conflicts and were
			 instrumental in the exploration and settlement of western lands;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas, over the 82 years of the Buffalo Soldiers’ existence, 23 men received the Congressional
			 Medal of Honor, the highest recognition awarded by the United States
			 Government for military service;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Buffalo Soldiers ceased to exist in 1948 when President Harry Truman signed Executive
			 Order 9981 mandating equal treatment and opportunity for African-American
			 servicemen;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas the Buffalo Soldiers are a significant part of American military history;</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas a stamp was issued in honor of the Buffalo Soldiers on April 22, 1994, and this stamp was
			 placed on <quote>off sale</quote> in December 1995; and</text>
		</whereas>
    <whereas>
      <text>Whereas reissuing a postage stamp to honor the Buffalo Soldiers is fitting and proper: Now,
			 therefore, be it</text>
    </whereas>
  </preamble>
	<resolution-body id="H46EDC9FE0EFA4F08BF8596095905C469" style="traditional">
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H53D775365DA0465A9D27470357F7EE7F" section-type="undesignated-section">
      <enum/>
      <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That it is the sense of <cato:entity-ref entity-type="federal-body" entity-id="0001">Congress</cato:entity-ref> that—</text>
			<paragraph id="H3DF3BC97749D4C98B0EDA18E17E4E869">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
        <text>a commemorative postage stamp should be issued in honor of the Buffalo Soldiers; and</text>
			</paragraph>
      <paragraph id="HF4368F00B1004EFD8A7D337F82DC20DE">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
        <text>the <cato:entity-ref entity-id="1865" entity-type="federal-body">Citizens' Stamp Advisory Committee</cato:entity-ref> should recommend to the Postmaster General that such a stamp
			 be issued.</text>
			</paragraph>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>