<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="H68977263A22341BF95522A85C3AC1E00" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HRES 565 IH: Calling on Attorney General Eric H. Holder, Jr., to appoint a special counsel to investigate the targeting of conservative nonprofit groups by the Internal Revenue Service.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2014-05-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 565</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20140502">May 2, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000289">Mr. Jordan</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001255">Mr. Boustany</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000289">Mr. Goodlatte</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000071">Mr. Camp</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="I000056">Mr. Issa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000244">Mr. Sensenbrenner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001076">Mr. Chaffetz</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000566">Mr. Gowdy</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Calling on Attorney General Eric H. Holder, Jr., to appoint a special counsel to investigate the
			 targeting of conservative nonprofit groups by the Internal Revenue
			 Service.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas><text>Whereas in February of 2010, the Internal Revenue Service (<quote>IRS</quote>) began targeting conservative nonprofit groups for extra scrutiny in connection with applications
			 for tax-exempt status;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas on May 14, 2013, the Treasury Inspector General for Tax Administration (TIGTA) issued an
			 audit report entitled, <quote>Inappropriate Criteria Were Used to Identify Tax-Exempt Applications for Review</quote>;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the TIGTA audit report found that from 2010 until 2012 the IRS systematically subjected
			 tax-exempt applicants to extra scrutiny based on inappropriate criteria,
			 including use of the phrases <quote>Tea Party</quote>, <quote>Patriots</quote>, and <quote>9/12</quote>;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the TIGTA audit report found that the groups selected for extra scrutiny based on
			 inappropriate criteria were subjected to years-long delay without cause;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the TIGTA audit report found that the groups selected for extra scrutiny based on
			 inappropriate criteria were subjected to inappropriate and burdensome
			 information requests, including requests for information about donors and
			 political beliefs;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas on January 27, 2010, in his State of the Union Address, President Barack Obama criticized
			 the Citizens United v. Federal Election Commission decision, saying: <quote>With all due deference to separation of powers, last week the Supreme Court reversed a century of
			 law that I believe will open the floodgates for special
			 interests—including foreign corporations—to spend without limit in our
			 elections</quote>;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas throughout 2010, President Barack Obama and congressional Democrats publicly criticized the
			 Citizens United decision and conservative-oriented tax-exempt
			 organizations;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Exempt Organizations Division within the IRS’s Tax-Exempt and Government Entities
			 Division has jurisdiction over the processing and determination of
			 tax-exempt applications;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas on September 15, 2010, Lois G. Lerner, Director of the Exempt Organizations Division,
			 initiated a project to examine political activity of 501(c)(4)
			 organizations, writing to her colleagues, <quote>[w]e need to be cautious so it isn’t a per se political project</quote>;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas on October 19, 2010, Lois G. Lerner told an audience at Duke University’s Sanford School of
			 Public Policy that <quote>everybody</quote> is <quote>screaming</quote> at the IRS <quote>to fix the problem</quote> posed by the Citizens United decision;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas on February 1, 2011, Lois G. Lerner wrote that the <quote>Tea Party matter [was] very dangerous,</quote> explaining <quote>This could be the vehicle to go to court on the issue of whether Citizen’s [sic] United overturning
			 the ban on corporate spending applies to tax exempt rules</quote>;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Lois G. Lerner ordered the Tea Party tax-exempt applications to proceed through a <quote>multi-tier review</quote> involving her senior technical advisor and the Chief Counsel’s office of the IRS;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Carter Hull, a 48-year veteran of the Federal Government, testified that the <quote>multi-tier review</quote> was unprecedented in his experience;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas on June 1, 2011, Holly Paz, Director of Rulings and Agreements within the Exempt
			 Organizations Division, requested the tax-exempt application filed by
			 Crossroads Grassroots Policy Strategies for review by Lois G. Lerner’s
			 senior technical advisor;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas in June 2011, Lois G. Lerner ordered the Tea Party cases to be renamed because she viewed
			 the term <quote>Tea Party</quote> to be <quote>pejorative</quote>;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas on March 22, 2012, IRS Commissioner Douglas Shulman was specifically asked about the
			 targeting of Tea Party groups applying for tax-exempt status during a
			 hearing before the House Committee on Ways and Means, to which he replied, <quote>I can give you assurances … [t]here is absolutely no targeting.</quote>;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas on April 26, 2012, IRS Exempt Organizations Director Lois G. Lerner informed the House
			 Committee on Oversight and Government Reform that information requests
			 were done in <quote>the ordinary course of the application process</quote>;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas on May 4, 2012, IRS Exempt Organizations Director Lois G. Lerner provided to the House
			 Committee on Oversight and Government Reform specific justification for
			 the IRS’s information requests;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas prior to the November 2012 election, the IRS provided 31 applications for tax-exempt status
			 to the investigative website ProPublica, all of which were from
			 conservative groups and nine of which had not yet been approved by the
			 IRS, and Federal law prohibits public disclosure of application materials
			 until after the application has been approved;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the initial <quote>test</quote> cases developed by the IRS were applications filed by conservative-oriented Tea Party
			 organizations;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the IRS determined, by way of informal, internal review, that 75 percent of the affected
			 applications for 501(c)(4) status were filed by conservative-oriented
			 organizations;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas on January 24, 2013, Lois G. Lerner e-mailed colleagues about Organizing for Action, a
			 tax-exempt organization formed as an offshoot of President Barack Obama’s
			 election campaign, writing: <quote>Maybe I can get the DC office job!</quote>;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas on May 8, 2013, Richard Pilger, Director of the Election Crimes Branch of the Department of
			 Justice’s Public Integrity Section, spoke to Lois G. Lerner about
			 potential prosecution for false statements about political campaign
			 intervention made by tax-exempt applicants;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas on May 10, 2013, IRS Exempt Organizations Director Lois G. Lerner apologized for the IRS’s
			 targeting of conservative tax-exempt applicants during a speech at an
			 event organized by the American Bar Association;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Ways and Means Committee determined that, of the 298 applications delayed and set aside
			 for extra scrutiny by the IRS, 83 percent were from right-leaning
			 organizations;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Ways and Means Committee also determined that, as of Lois G. Lerner’s May 10, 2013
			 apology, only 45 percent of the right-leaning groups set aside for extra
			 scrutiny had been approved, while 70 percent of left-leaning groups and
			 100 percent of the groups with <quote>progressive</quote> names had been approved;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Ways and Means Committee has also determined that, of the groups that were
			 inappropriately subject to demands to divulge confidential donors, 89
			 percent were right-leaning;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas on May 15, 2013, Attorney General Holder testified before the Judiciary Committee that the
			 Department of Justice would conduct a <quote>dispassionate</quote> investigation into the IRS matter, and <quote>[t]his will not be about parties … this will not be about ideological persuasions … anybody who has
			 broken the law will be held accountable</quote>;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas on May 15, 2013, President Barack Obama called the IRS’s targeting <quote>inexcusable</quote> and promised that he would <quote>not tolerate this kind of behavior in any agency, but especially in the IRS, given the power that
			 it has and the reach that it has into all of our lives</quote>;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Attorney General has stated that the Department of Justice’s investigation involves
			 components from the Civil Rights Division and the Public Integrity
			 Section;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Civil Rights Division of the Department of Justice has a history of politicization, as
			 evident in the report by the Department of Justice Office of Inspector
			 General entitled, <quote>A Review of the Operations of the Voting Rights Section of the Civil Rights Division</quote>;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Barbara Bosserman, a trial attorney in the Civil Rights Division who in the past several
			 years has contributed nearly $7,000 to the Democratic National Committee
			 and President Barack Obama’s political campaigns, is playing a leading
			 role in the Department of Justice’s investigation;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Public Integrity Section communicated with the IRS about the potential prosecution of
			 tax-exempt applicants;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas on December 5, 2013, President Barack Obama declared in a national television interview
			 that the IRS’s targeting of conservative tax-exempt applicants was caused
			 by a <quote>bureaucratic</quote>
				<quote>list</quote> by employees in <quote>an office in Cincinnati</quote>;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas on April 9, 2014, the House Committee on Ways and Means referred Lois G. Lerner to the
			 Department of Justice for criminal prosecution;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the House Committee on Ways and Means found that Lois G. Lerner used her position to
			 improperly influence agency action against conservative tax-exempt
			 organizations, denying these groups due process and equal protection
			 rights as guaranteed by the United States Constitution, in apparent
			 violation of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/242">section 242</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the House Committee on Ways and Means found that Lois G. Lerner targeted Crossroads
			 Grassroots Policy Strategies while ignoring similar liberal-leaning
			 tax-exempt applicants;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the House Committee on Ways and Means found that Lois G. Lerner impeded official
			 investigations by knowingly providing misleading statements to the
			 Treasury Inspector General for Tax Administration, in apparent violation
			 of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/1001">section 1001</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the House Committee on Ways and Means found that Lois G. Lerner may have disclosed
			 confidential taxpayer information, in apparent violation of section 6103
			 of the Internal Revenue Code;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas former Department of Justice officials have testified before a subcommittee of the House
			 Committee on Oversight and Government Reform that the circumstances of the
			 Administration’s investigation of the IRS’s targeting of conservative
			 tax-exempt applicants warrant the appointment of a special counsel;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Department of Justice regulations counsel attorneys to avoid the <quote>appearance of a conflict of interest likely to affect the public perception of the integrity of the
			 investigation or prosecution</quote>;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas since May 15, 2013, the Department of Justice and the Federal Bureau of Investigation have
			 refused to cooperate with congressional oversight of the Administration’s
			 investigation of the IRS’s targeting of conservative tax-exempt
			 applicants;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas on January 13, 2014, unnamed officials at the Department of Justice leaked to the media
			 that no criminal charges would be appropriate for IRS officials who
			 engaged in the targeting activity, which undermined the integrity of the
			 Department of Justice’s investigation;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas on February 2, 2014, President Barack Obama stated publicly that there was <quote>not even a smidgen of corruption</quote> in connection with the IRS targeting activity;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas on April 16, 2014, electronic mail communications between the Department of Justice and the
			 IRS were released showing that the Department of Justice considered
			 prosecuting conservative nonprofit groups for engaging in political
			 activity that is legal under Federal law, which damaged the integrity of
			 the Department and undermined its investigation; and</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Code of Federal Regulations requires the Attorney General to appoint a Special Counsel
			 when he or she determines—</text>
			<paragraph id="H1DE0D124B81E48BEA50412D6A883360B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>that criminal investigation of a person or matter is warranted,</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HBBF828B3D3004A878FBAC3332DDF09FF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>that investigation or prosecution of that person or matter by a United States Attorney’s Office or
			 litigating Division of the Department of Justice would present a conflict
			 of interest for the Department or other extraordinary circumstances, and</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H3F665F3117CC4A59A6C0DC72B54F6815"><enum>(3)</enum><text>that under the circumstances, it would be in the public interest to appoint an outside Special
			 Counsel to assume responsibility for the matter: Now, therefore, be it</text></paragraph></whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body id="H9DBD58978653432C92DD37D7F9ACEBDE" style="multiple-resolved-clause">
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H6FAD924411B34FD2AF02110D00681F75" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That it is the sense of the House of Representatives that—</text>
			<paragraph id="H0ACA930BC0894B9882CA2D3722E3B5A7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the statements and actions of the IRS, the Department of Justice, and the Obama Administration in
			 connection with this matter have served to undermine the Department of
			 Justice’s investigation;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HC3EDD2419DEC4F6F8FD2CB5A76FDE346"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Administration’s efforts to undermine the investigation, and the appointment of a person who
			 has donated almost seven thousand dollars to President Obama and the
			 Democratic National Committee in a lead investigative role, have created a
			 conflict of interest for the Department of Justice that warrants removal
			 of the investigation from the normal processes of the Department of
			 Justice;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HAA0AD76BC4384CD48BEDD24423CDD26B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>further investigation of the matter is warranted due to the apparent criminal activity by Lois G.
			 Lerner, and the ongoing disclosure of internal communications showing
			 potentially unlawful conduct by Executive Branch personnel;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H266BAA29FAF04FFCB5255043898FF7CD"><enum>(4)</enum><text>given the Department’s conflict of interest, as well as the strong public interest in ensuring that
			 public officials who inappropriately targeted American citizens for
			 exercising their right to free expression are held accountable,
			 appointment of a Special Counsel would be in the public interest; and</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H3D7675EC59B442A3A98D2344E4D5DEEB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Attorney General Holder should appoint a Special Counsel, without further delay, to investigate the
			 IRS’s targeting of conservative nonprofit advocacy groups.</text>
			</paragraph></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


