<bill session="113" type="s" number="1471" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-12-20">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-12-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Alicia Dawn Koehl Respect for National Cemeteries Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Alicia Dawn Koehl Respect for National Cemeteries Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Alicia Dawn Koehl Respect for National Cemeteries Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Alicia Dawn Koehl Respect for National Cemeteries Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Secretary of Veterans Affairs and the Secretary of the Army to reconsider decisions to inter or honor the memory of a person in a national cemetery, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402675"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2013-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412205" joined="2013-08-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-30">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 113-280.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-18">
      <text>Senate Committee on Veterans' Affairs discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-18">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8135-8136" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2013-11-18" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8136" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-11-18T20:43:00-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-18">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-18">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-18">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-11T12:43:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Miller (FL) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-11T12:43:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7640-7642" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-11T12:43:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 1471.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-11T12:54:00-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-11T16:10:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7667-7668" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote2" roll="634" datetime="2013-12-11T16:17:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 398 - 1 (Roll no. 634).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7640-7641" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="2013-12-13">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2013-12-20" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="113-65" type="public" datetime="2013-12-20">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 113-65.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged"/>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR09" subcommittee="Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="3106"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Michigan"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s2146"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>12/20/2013--Public Law.
Alicia Dawn Koehl Respect for National Cemeteries Act - Authorizes the appropriate federal official (either the Secretary of Veterans Affairs [VA] or the Secretary of the Army) to reconsider a decision to inter or honor the memory of a person in the National Cemetery Administration or in Arlington National Cemetery upon receiving information that such person may have committed a federal or state capital crime but was not convicted by reason of unavailability for trial due to death or flight to avoid prosecution.

Requires such official, upon finding, after an opportunity for a hearing, that the person committed but was not convicted of such crime, to provide notice to the individual's next of kin or other person authorized to arrange burial or memorialization of the deceased person of the decision to disinter such person's remains or remove a memorial headstone or marker. Allows such next of kin or other person 60 days to file a notice of disagreement, which shall initiate appellate review. Authorizes the appropriate federal official, when a decision becomes final, to disinter the remains or remove the memorial headstone or marker.

Modifies the exception to the prohibition against interment or memorialization in the National Cemetery System or Arlington National Cemetery of a person convicted of a federal or state capital crime to require receipt of written notice of a conviction before interment or memorialization takes place (currently, receipt of such notice is required before the appropriate federal official approves an application for interment or memorialization).

Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs: (1) to disinter the remains of Michael LaShawn Anderson from Fort Custer National Cemetery (Michigan); (2) to notify his next of kin of the impending disinterment; and (3) upon disinterment, to relinquish the remains to the next of kin or, if the next of kin of record is unavailable, arrange for the appropriate disposition of the remains.</summary>
</bill>
