<bill session="113" type="s" number="2870" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-09-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">On the Job Training Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend certain provisions of the Social Security Act relating to demonstration projects designed to provide unemployed workers with the information, skills, and relationships they need for reemployment.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400325"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412545" joined="2014-09-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-09-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3864"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/18/2014--Introduced.
On the Job Training Act - Amends title III (Grants to States for Unemployment Compensation Administration) of the Social Security Act, with respect to grants to states by the Secretary of Labor for reemployment demonstration projects, to allow grants to up to 10 states per year instead of a maximum of 10 states altogether.

Allows a designee of a state governor, instead of only the governor, to apply for such a grant.

Requires any project to be commenced by December 31, 2017.

Allows direct disbursements under a project to employers who hire individuals receiving unemployment compensation to include disbursements promoting retention.

Requires the Secretary of Labor to: (1) approve completed grant applications in the order of receipt; (2) determine, before approving an application, whether its assurances are credible that the project would not result in increased costs to the state's account in the Unemployment Trust Fund; and (3) disapprove any application making assurances determined not credible.

Revises requirements for termination of a project to require the Secretary to: (1) notify a state in writing with sufficient detail describing any violation of the substantive terms or conditions of a project justifying its termination, and (2) determine that the state has not taken action to correct the violation within 90 days after notification.

Authorizes appropriations for FY2015-FY2020 for additional payments to states for the administrative costs of demonstration projects.

Directs the Secretary to evaluate the impact of each demonstration project, using existing data sources and methodology appropriate to determine project effects, including the effect on individual skill levels, earnings, and employment retention.</summary>
</bill>
