<bill session="113" type="h" number="4124" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-02-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-02-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-02-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Youth from Solitary Confinement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 18, United States Code, to ensure that juveniles adjudicated in Federal delinquency proceedings are not subject to solitary confinement while committed to juvenile facilities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412517"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400093" joined="2014-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2014-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412560" joined="2014-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2014-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400364" joined="2014-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412522" joined="2014-02-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-02-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-04-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/28/2014--Introduced.
Protecting Youth from Solitary Confinement Act - Amends the federal criminal code to prohibit subjecting a juvenile in federal custody in a juvenile facility to solitary confinement.

Requires the Director of the Board of Prisons to report annually to the President and Congress on: (1) the most recent data regarding the rate at which juveniles are subject to solitary confinement; and (2) the trends demonstrated by data on juveniles subjected to solitary confinement with regard to the types of offenses for which the juveniles were incarcerated, the race, gender, and age of such juveniles, how many hours such juveniles were subject to solitary confinement, and the purposes of the solitary confinement.</summary>
</bill>
