<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H98F1764526FC488D8EEF6885D174D480" public-private="public" stage-count="1">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HR 3326 : Trinity County Land Exchange Act of 2014</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2014-11-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3326</legis-num>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action><action-date date="20141117">November 17, 2014</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To provide for an exchange of land between the United States and the Trinity Public Utilities
			 District of Trinity County, California, involving a parcel of National
			 Forest System land in Shasta-Trinity National Forest.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H3DABBD7181D345BA8C932375689AA37F" style="OLC">
		<section id="H4C50694DD5AF4D5AAF4D8F60116051E5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Trinity County Land Exchange Act of 2014</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="H59AE5DE052EB4D7984E33D7430A47A2E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Land exchange, Trinity Public Utilities District, Trinity County, California, the Bureau of Land
			 Management, and the Forest Service</header>
			<subsection id="H89EF838787B54D8B853F2D1297E363B8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Land exchange required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If not later than 3 years after enactment of this Act, the Utilities District conveys to the
			 Secretary of the Interior all right, title, and interest of the Utilities
			 District in and to Parcel A, subject to such terms and conditions as the
			 Secretary of the Interior may require, the Secretary of Agriculture shall
			 convey Parcel B to the Utilities District, subject to such terms and
			 conditions as the Secretary of Agriculture may require, including the
			 reservation of easements for all roads and trails considered to be
			 necessary for administrative purposes and to ensure public access to
			 National Forest System lands.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H8489531516F648AE9CE0C6F38C8DF9C3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Availability of maps and legal descriptions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Maps are entitled <quote>Trinity County Land Exchange Act of 2014 – Parcel A</quote> and <quote>Trinity County Land Exchange Act of 2014 – Parcel B</quote>, both dated March 24, 2014. The maps shall be on file and available for public inspection in the
			 Office of the Chief of the Forest Service and the appropriate office of
			 the Bureau of Land Management. With the agreement of the parties to the
			 conveyances under subsection (a), the Secretary of the Interior and the
			 Secretary of Agriculture may make technical corrections to the maps and
			 legal descriptions.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H7AE629844D1147979D0696EB45054FB7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Equal value exchange</header>
				<paragraph id="HA2CF76AD8F364904977846F8BB4AA5C6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Land Exchange Process</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The land exchange under this section shall be an equal value exchange. Except as provided in
			 paragraph (3), the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of
			 Agriculture shall carry out the land exchange in accordance with section
			 206 of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1716">43 U.S.C. 1716</external-xref>).</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H2DF6B4992A7943F293CF0C25E7EFC87A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appraisal of parcels</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The values of Parcel A and Parcel B shall by determined by appraisals performed by a qualified
			 appraiser mutually agreed to by the parties to the conveyances under
			 subsection (a). The appraisals shall be approved by the Secretary of
			 Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture and conducted in conformity with
			 the Uniform Appraisal Standards for Federal Land.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H76081F780573487B82350DB798D29F6B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Cash equalization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the values of Parcel A and Parcel B are not equal, the values may be equalized through the use
			 of a cash equalization payment, however, if the final appraised value of
			 Parcel A exceeds the value of Parcel B, the surplus value of Parcel A
			 shall be considered to be a donation by the Utilities District.
			 Notwithstanding section 206(b) of the Federal Land Policy and Management
			 Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1716">43 U.S.C. 1716(b)</external-xref>), a cash equalization payment may be made in excess of 25 percent of the appraised value of the
			 Parcel B.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H402B6262AAA84DCB96FEA832CE2B0E83"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Disposition of proceeds</header>
				<paragraph id="H7A57FED924004E1E8E99B2D61E8108CB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any cash equalization payment received by the United States under subsection (c) shall be deposited
			 in the fund established under <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/90/171">Public Law 90–171</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/484a">16 U.S.C. 484a</external-xref>; commonly known as the Sisk Act).</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HE2A0F3A33ACB4BF981BFCC5C5DABA45F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of proceeds</header><text>Amounts deposited under paragraph (1) shall be available to the Secretary of Agriculture, without
			 further appropriation and until expended, for the improvement,
			 maintenance, reconstruction, or construction of a facility or improvement
			 for the National Forest System.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5500CB1B63F64811A4F4FBD9E92D440E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Survey</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The exact acreage and legal description of Parcel A and Parcel B shall be determined by a survey
			 satisfactory to the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of
			 Agriculture.</text>
			</subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDE00642C54CD448D88B63A31C02582C3"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Costs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As a condition of the land exchange under subsection (a), the Utilities District shall pay the
			 costs associated with—</text>
				<paragraph id="H26F3536F0C664DC4A95B30D6162DA4AB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the surveys described in subsection (e);</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HA0866840F0474A86AC939C5047AD6D55"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the appraisals described in subsection (c)(2); and</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HF072706554F84CA6A4CF855D664CFECE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any other reasonable administrative or remediation cost determined by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3D8BAEDC191E4CA49D4B7F88150F63E7"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Management of acquired land</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon the acquisition of Parcel A, the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Redding Field
			 Office of the Bureau of Land Management, shall administer Parcel A as
			 public land in accordance with the Federal Land Policy and Management Act
			 of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1701">43 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>) and the laws and regulations applicable to public land administered by the Bureau of Land
			 Management, except that public recreation and public access to and for
			 recreation shall be the highest and best use of Parcel A.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H98BCC09D8C774AFD862F2332FADD673F"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Completion of land exchange</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Once the Utilities District offers to convey Parcel A to the Secretary of the Interior, the
			 Secretary of Agriculture shall complete the conveyance of Parcel B not
			 later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H0739575F798D4860BE04E6E5A5DE85A9"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For the purposes of this section:</text>
				<paragraph id="HED289609B8F54CD29D33554831EC3CC1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Parcel <enum-in-header>A</enum-in-header></header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Parcel A</term> means the approximately 47 acres of land, known as the <quote><short-title>Sky Ranch parcel</short-title></quote>, adjacent to public land administered by the Redding Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management
			 as depicted on the map entitled <quote>Trinity County Land Exchange Act of 2014 – Parcel A</quote>, dated March 24, 2014, more particularly described as a portion of Mineral Survey 178, south
			 Highway 299, generally located in the S1/2 of the S1/2 of Section 7 and
			 the N1/2 of the N1/2 of Section 8, Township 33 North, Range 10 West, Mount
			 Diablo Meridian.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H421D6EFEADA948BE9694B23A9131C897"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Parcel <enum-in-header>B</enum-in-header></header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Parcel B</term> means the approximately 100 acres land in the Shasta-Trinity National Forest in the State of
			 California near the Weaverville Airport in Trinity County as depicted on
			 the map entitled <quote>Trinity County Land Exchange Act of 2014 – Parcel B</quote> dated March 24, 2014, more particularly described as Lot 8, SW1/4 SE1/4, and S1/2 N1/2 SE, Section
			 31, Township 34 North, Range 9 West, Mount Diablo Meridian.<pagebreak></pagebreak></text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H89C9561111D74D9E9DCBA6A7179F2B9B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Utilities District</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Utilities District</term> means the Trinity Public Utilities District of Trinity County, California.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
	<attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date chamber="House" date="20141113">Passed the House of Representatives November 13, 2014.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk</role></attestation-group></attestation>
</bill>


