<bill session="113" type="h" number="3002" updated="2015-09-01T10:19:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">No Bailouts for State and local Governments Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit the provision of Federal funds to State and local governments for payment of obligations, to prohibit the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System from financially assisting State and local governments, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412541"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400032" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412395" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400655" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412275" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400221" joined="2013-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412419" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412510" joined="2013-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412445" joined="2013-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412443" joined="2013-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412309" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412489" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412310" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412426" joined="2013-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400606" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412261" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412392" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412574" joined="2013-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412564" joined="2013-11-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-08-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-02">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-02">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="101"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/2/2013--Introduced.
Prohibits the use of federal funds to purchase or guarantee obligations of, issue lines of credit to, or provide direct or indirect grants-in-aid to any state, municipal, local, or county government which, on or after January 1, 2013, has filed for bankruptcy, has defaulted on its obligations, is at risk of defaulting, or is likely to default, without such federal assistance if such purchase, guarantee, extension of credit, or grant is made to assist the government in: (1) avoiding defaulting on the payment of principal or interest due on an obligation of the government, or (2) curing such a default.

Prohibits the Secretary of the Treasury from using, directly or indirectly, general fund revenues or borrowed funds to purchase or guarantee, for the same purposes, any asset or obligation of any such state, municipal, local, or county government.

Prohibits the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System from: (1) providing or extending to, or authorizing with respect to, such a state, municipal, local, or county government, or other entity with taxing authority or bonding authority, for the same purposes, any funds, loan guarantees, credits, or any other financial instrument or other authority, including bond purchases; or (2) otherwise assisting such a government entity, for the same purposes, under any Board authority.

Waives the application of this Act for federal assistance provided in response to a natural disaster.</summary>
</bill>
