<bill session="113" type="h" number="3562" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-11-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-11-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-11-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fairness in Obamacare Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To clarify the application of all laws, including the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act, to the Federal Government and Congress, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400221"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-11-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, and House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-20">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-20">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-20">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/20/2013--Introduced.
Fairness in Obamacare Act of 2013 - Declares that Congress and the executive branch are expressly and equally bound by any federal law which is intended to be broadly enforced upon the American people.

Amends the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (PPACA) to restrict the health plans that the federal government may make available to Members of Congress, the President, the Vice President, and appointed federal workers to only those health plans that are created under PPACA or offered through a health care exchange. (Currently, this restriction applies to Members of Congress and congressional staff.)

Defines "appointed federal worker" as an individual who is: (1) employed in a position listed in the Executive Schedule; (2) a limited term, limited emergency, or noncareer appointee in the Senior Executive Service; or (3) employed in an executive branch position of a confidential or policy-determining character under the regulations concerning excepted schedules.

Prohibits such restrictions from affecting the continued coverage of annuitants in certain plans under the Federal Employees Health Benefits Program in effect as of the enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
