<bill session="113" type="hr" number="772" updated="2015-09-01T10:18:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-12-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-12-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-12-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Directing the House of Representatives to bring a civil action for declaratory or injunctive relief to challenge certain policies and actions taken by the executive branch relating to immigration.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412572"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412510" joined="2014-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412290" joined="2014-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412295" joined="2014-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412442" joined="2014-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="412574" joined="2014-12-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-12-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Rules, and in addition to the Committee on House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-08">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-12-08">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional-executive branch relations"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/8/2014--Introduced.
Directs the House of Representatives to bring a civil action in U.S. District Court for the District of Columbia for declaratory or injunctive relief to challenge Department of Homeland Security (DHS) policy to:

 exercise prosecutorial discretion with respect to individuals who came to the United States as children, as announced by DHS on June 15, 2012; or exercise further prosecutorial discretion with respect to certain other unlawfully present aliens, as directed in a November 20, 2014, memorandum and related executive branch memoranda. Declares that:

 any amounts obligated or expended by the House to carry out this resolution shall be derived from existing appropriations for House salaries and expenses, and nothing in this resolution may be construed as authorizing an increase of House budget authority; and nothing in this resolution may be construed to affect the Speaker's authority to initiate, or intervene in, any civil action on behalf of the House.</summary>
</bill>
