<bill session="113" type="h" number="3355" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-10-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-10-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reducing Employer Burdens, Unleashing Innovation, and Labor Development Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">American Energy Independence and Price Reduction Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Efficient Use of Government Spectrum Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Investing in America's Workforce Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Repealing the Health Care Law Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To increase the competitiveness of American manufacturing by reducing regulatory and other burdens, encouraging greater innovation and investment, and developing a stronger workforce for the twenty-first century, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412278"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6809"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, Armed Services, Education and the Workforce, Natural Resources, House Administration, the Judiciary, Rules, Appropriations, Science, Space, and Technology, and Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-28">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-28">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-28">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-28">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-28">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-28">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-28">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-28">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-28">
      <text>Referred to House Appropriations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-28">
      <text>Referred to House Science, Space, and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-28">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee Indian and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-12-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-01-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Intelligence, Emerging Threats &amp; Capabilities.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS26" subcommittee="Intelligence, Emerging Threats &amp; Capabilities" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Training" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED02" subcommittee="Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII24" subcommittee="Indian and Alaska Native Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU05" subcommittee="Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY20" subcommittee="Energy" name="House Science, Space, and Technology"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="49"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="132"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="497"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="762"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1582"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2739"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="3042"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="453"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Arctic and polar regions"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Energy revenues and royalties"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission (FCC)"/>
    <term name="General energy matters"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Insurance industry and regulation"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Tax reform and tax simplification"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements and negotiations"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
    <term name="Youth employment and child labor"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/28/2013--Introduced.
Reducing Employer Burdens, Unleashing Innovation, and Labor Development Act of 2013 - Expresses the sense of Congress that increasing the competitiveness of U.S. manufacturers will strengthen the national economy.

Title I: Investing in America's Workforce - Investing in America's Workforce Act - Amends the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 to require state or local workforce investment systems to use youth activities funds allocated to a local area for programs that provide training, which may include priority consideration for training programs that lead to recognized postsecondary credentials aligned with in-demand occupations or industries in the local area involved.

Authorizes the operator and employees of a one-stop center, in assisting individuals in selecting programs of training services, to give priority consideration to such programs.

 Adds to eligibility requirements for providers of training services and providers of youth activities for such programs. Requires programs of training services and youth activities programs that lead to a recognized postsecondary credential to meet quality criteria established by the state governor.

Amends the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 and the Trade Act of 1974 to require the same priority consideration in the state and local plans for career and technical education programs as well as in tech prep programs and trade adjustment assistance (TAA) programs.

Title II: Research and Development Tax Credits - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) extend through 2014 the tax credit for increasing research activities, and (2) increase and make permanent the alternative simplified research tax credit.

Title III: Comprehensive Tax Reform - Directs the Chair of the Joint Committee on Taxation to notify Congress of any introduced tax reform bill that contains proposals for: (1) a transition to a more globally competitive corporate tax code, (2) a reduction in the complexity of the tax code, and (3) the elimination of special interest loopholes in the tax code. Sets forth procedures for expedited congressional consideration of such bill.

Title IV: Federal Oil and Gas Resources - Subtitle A: Expanding Offshore Energy Development - Amends the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (OCSLA) regarding the Outer Continental Shelf (OCS) oil and natural gas leasing program to direct the Secretary of the Interior (Secretary in this title) to make lands available for leasing and to conduct lease sales that include: (1) at least 50% of the available unleased acreage within each OCS planning area considered to have the largest undiscovered, technically recoverable oil and gas resources, with an emphasis upon offering the most geologically prospective parts; and (2) any state subdivision of an OCS planning area whose state governor requests that the land be made available for leasing.

Directs the Secretary to make available for leasing in each five-year oil and gas leasing program, OCS planning areas that are estimated to contain more than 2.5 billion barrels of oil or more than 7.5 trillion cubic feet of natural gas.

Directs the Secretary, when determining such planning areas, to use the document entitled "Minerals Management Service Assessment of Undiscovered Technically Recoverable Oil and Gas Resources of the Nation's Outer Continental Shelf, 2006."

Requires the Secretary, when developing a five-year oil and gas leasing program that applies before 2027, to determine increased domestic strategic production goals.

Subtitle B: Coastal Plain of Alaska - American Energy Independence and Price Reduction Act - Directs the Secretary to: (1) establish a competitive oil and gas leasing program that will result in an environmentally sound program for the exploration, development, and production of the oil and gas resources of the Coastal Plain; and (2) ensure the oil and gas exploration, development, and production activities on the Coastal Plain will result in no significant adverse effect on fish and wildlife, their habitat, subsistence resources, or the environment, including by requiring the application of the best commercially available technology for oil and gas exploration, development, and production to all exploration, development, and production operations under this subtitle in a manner that ensures the receipt of fair market value by the public for the mineral resources to be leased.

Amends the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act of 1980 to repeal the prohibition against production of oil and gas from the Arctic National Wildlife Refuge (ANWR) and against leasing or other development leading to such production.

Authorizes the Secretary to designate as a Special Area up to 45,000 acres of the Coastal Plain.

Permits directional drilling in the Special Area.

Directs the Secretary to implement a competitive leasing program for the exploration, development, and production of oil and gas resources on the Coastal Plain of Alaska.

Permits lease sales to be conducted through an Internet leasing program.

Prescribes procedures governing Coastal Plain lease sales, as well as lease terms and conditions.

Authorizes the Secretary to grant Coastal Plain lands to the highest responsible qualified bidder in a lease sale upon the lessee's payment of a bonus.

Sets forth: (1) a "no significant adverse effect" standard to govern Coastal Plain activities, and (2) guidelines for expedited judicial review of complaints.

Requires the Secretary to prepare and update periodically a plan for the siting and construction of facilities for the exploration, development, production, and transportation of Coastal Plain oil and gas resources.

Establishes the ANWR Alternative Energy Trust Fund as repository for 50% of the amount of bonus, rental, and royalty revenues from federal oil and gas leasing and operations authorized under this title.

Title V: Energy Consumers Relief - Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), before promulgating a final rule that regulates any aspect of the production, supply, distribution, or use of energy (or that provides for such regulation by state or local governments) and that is estimated by the Administrator or the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to impose aggregate costs of more than $1 billion, to submit a report that contains: (1) an estimate of the total costs and benefits of the rule, (2) an estimate of the increases in energy prices that may result from implementation or enforcement of the rule, and (3) a detailed description of the employment effects that may result from implementation or enforcement of the rule.

Requires the Secretary of Energy (DOE): (1) to prepare an independent analysis to determine whether such rule will cause any increase in energy prices for consumers, any impact on fuel diversity of the nation's electricity generation portfolio or on electric reliability, or any adverse effect on energy supply, distribution, or use; and (2) upon making such a determination, to determine whether the rule will cause significant adverse effects to the economy and publish such determination in the Federal Register.

Prohibits the Administrator from promulgating any such final rule if the Secretary determines that such rule will cause significant adverse effects to the economy.

Prohibits the Administrator from using the social cost of carbon in any cost-benefit analysis relating to an energy-related rule estimated to cost more than $1 billion unless and until a federal law is enacted authorizing such use.

 Title VI: Repeal of the Health Care Law and Health Care-Related Provisions in the Health Care and Education Reconciliation Act of 2010 - Repealing the Health Care Law Act - Repeals the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act and the health care provisions of the Health Care and Education and Reconciliation Act of 2010, effective as of their enactment. Restores or revives provisions amended or repealed by such Act or such health care provisions.

 Title VII: Cooperative Governing of Individual Health Insurance Coverage - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require that the laws of the state designated by a health insurance issuer (primary state) shall apply to individual health insurance coverage offered by that issuer in the primary state and in any other state (secondary state), but only if the coverage and issuer comply with conditions of this title.

Title VIII: Renewal of Trade Promotion Authority - Amends the Bipartisan Trade Promotion Authority Act of 2002 to authorize the President to enter into trade agreements with foreign countries regarding tariff and nontariff trade barriers: (1) on and after enactment of this Act and before July 1, 2018; or (2) on and after July 1, 2018, and before July 1, 2020, if certain congressional trade authorities procedures for implementing trade bills are extended for that period.

Applies certain congressional and presidential trade authorities requirements to trade agreements that resulted from negotiations commenced before enactment of this Act.

Title IX: Reform of Export Control Policies - Expresses the sense of Congress that the Export Administration Act of 1979, as continued in effect by the International Emergency Economic Powers Act, is obsolete and should be reformed and reauthorized.

Title X: Efficient Use of Government Spectrum - Efficient Use of Government Spectrum Act of 2013 - Directs the Federal Communications Commission (FCC), within three years after enactment of the Middle Class Tax Relief and Job Creation Act of 2012: (1) to reallocate electromagnetic spectrum between the frequencies from 1755 to 1780 megahertz (currently, such frequencies are occupied by the Department of Defense [DOD] and other federal agencies) for commercial use; and (2) as part of the competitive bidding auctions required by such Act, to grant new initial licenses, subject to flexible-use service rules, for the use of such spectrum, paired with the spectrum between frequencies from 2155 to 2180 megahertz already designated for auction.

Directs the proceeds attributable to the competitive bidding of the 1755 to 1780 megahertz range to be allocated in the same manner as other specified frequencies pursuant to such Act for uses including reimbursements to agencies for relocation and sharing costs, the building of the nationwide public safety broadband network, and deposits or reimbursements to the U.S. Treasury.

Requires such spectrum to be relocated in a manner to ensure cooperation between federal and commercial entities under procedures in the National Telecommunications and Information Administration Organization Act, except for DOD-operated spectrum, which shall be relocated under the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2000.

Directs federal entities operating a federal government station, within a specified period before commencement of competitive bidding, to identify stations that cannot be relocated without jeopardizing essential military capability. Requires the transition plans of federal entities identifying such essential spectrum to: (1) provide for non-federal users to share such stations, and (2) limit any necessary exclusion zones to the smallest possible zones.

Directs the President to withdraw assignments upon relocation or to modify assignments to permit federal and non-federal use.</summary>
</bill>
