<bill session="113" type="s" number="1259" updated="2015-09-01T10:21:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-06-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-06-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-06-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">AGE-IN Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Assistance in Gaining Experience, Independence, and Navigation Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Services Act to provide research, training, and navigator services to youth and young adults on the verge of aging out of the secondary educational system, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400272"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-06-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="5436"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Hereditary and development disorders"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
    <term name="Youth employment and child labor"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/27/2013--Introduced.
Assistance in Gaining Experience, Independence, and Navigation Act of 2013 or the AGE-IN Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to make a grant to a research organization to: (1) conduct a comprehensive analysis of research on the topic of youth and young adults with an autism spectrum disorder or other developmental disability as such individuals age out of the school-based support system (transitioning youth), (2) conduct research on the existing infrastructure for transitioning youth, and (3) develop a comprehensive strategic plan for the establishment of a Transition Navigator grant program to provide transitioning youth with a comprehensive and interdisciplinary set of support services.

Directs the Secretary to establish a Transition Navigator Grant Program to award multiyear grants to establish and carry out a collaborative, interdisciplinary training and services initiative to train transition navigators to provide transitioning youth with the services and skills necessary to lead an independent, integrated life. Provides procedures for evaluation of grantee success in meeting the goal of the strategic plan submitted under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
