<bill session="113" type="s" number="1709" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-11-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-11-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-11-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Manufacturing Competitiveness Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Committee on Technology of the National Science and Technology Council to develop and update a national manufacturing competitiveness strategic plan, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400222"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2013-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2013-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412390" joined="2013-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="2014-01-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="2014-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2013-11-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-11-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="2447"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Industrial policy and productivity"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/14/2013--Introduced.
American Manufacturing Competitiveness Act of 2013 - Directs the Committee on Technology under the National Science and Technology Council to develop, in coordination with the National Economic Council, in lieu of the currently required strategic plan to guide federal programs and activities in support of advanced manufacturing research and development, a national manufacturing competitiveness strategic plan to improve government coordination and provide long-term guidance for federal programs and activities in support of U.S. manufacturing competitiveness, including advanced manufacturing research and development.

Requires the Secretary of Commerce, in developing and updating the plan quadrennially, to serve as the chairperson of the Committee.

Specifies the goals of the plan to be to: (1) promote growth, job creation, sustainability, and competitiveness in the U.S. manufacturing sector; (2) support the development of a skilled manufacturing workforce; (3) enable innovation and investment in domestic manufacturing; and (4) support national security.

Requires the Committee, as part of the development of the plan, to conduct an analysis of specified factors that impact the competitiveness and growth of the U.S. manufacturing sector.

Permits the chairperson of the Committee to appoint an advisory panel of private sector and nonprofit leaders to provide input, perspective, and recommendations to assist in the development of the plan.

Requires the President to submit the plan to Congress and publish it on an Internet website accessible to the public.</summary>
</bill>
