<bill session="113" type="h" number="3897" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-01-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-01-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-01-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to strengthen the rules for approved structured settlement factoring transactions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412571"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412208" joined="2014-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2014-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400641" joined="2014-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2014-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2014-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="2014-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2014-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400291" joined="2014-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2014-01-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-01-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Contracts and agency"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/16/2014--Introduced.
Amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to the tax exemption for structured settlement factoring transactions (i.e., transfers of the right to receive periodic payments under a settlement of a legal claim for damages in exchange for a lump sum payment)&#160;to require that&#160;court orders approving such transfers include additional requirements, including that: (1)&#160;the annual discount rate of the consideration for&#160;a transfer does not exceed the prime interest rate plus 5%; (2) the aggregate amount of charges, fees, and other expenses payable by the payee of the lump sum&#160;payment&#160;do not exceed 2% of the value of the consideration to the payee; (3) the payee is not liable for any penalty or forfeiture if the transfer does not satisfy the additional requirements imposed by this Act; (4) the transferee (the entity receiving the right to the periodic payments)&#160;has given written notice of its name, address, and taxpayer identification number to the annuity issuer and the structured settlement obligor and has filed a copy of such notice with the state court or other authority issuing the&#160;order approving the transfer; (5) the transfer is fair and reasonable; and (6) the transferee makes certain disclosures to the payee.</summary>
</bill>
