<bill session="113" type="h" number="3906" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-01-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-01-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-01-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fixing America's Inconsistent Redistricting (FAIR) Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require States to carry out Congressional redistricting in accordance with plans developed by nonpartisan service agencies of the legislative branch of State governments, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412208"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412209" joined="2014-01-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-01-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU10" subcommittee="Constitution and Civil Justice" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional districts and representation"/>
    <term name="State and local courts"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/16/2014--Introduced.
Fixing America's Inconsistent Redistricting (FAIR) Act - Requires any congressional redistricting conducted by a state to be conducted in accordance with a redistricting plan developed by a nonpartisan agency of the legislative branch of the state government and enacted into law by the state.

Requires each state, by December 31 of the year preceding a redistricting year, to establish a nonpartisan agency in the state government's legislative branch to develop the state's redistricting plan according to specified criteria. Requires the state to appoint a Temporary Redistricting Advisory Commission by February 15 of each redistricting year to: (1) guide the agency in development of the plan, (2) analyze and review the plan, and (3) recommend to the state legislature whether it should be adopted or rejected. Requires the state legislature to approve or reject the plan within three days after receiving the Commission's report.

Prescribes requirements for development and submission of revised plans when preceding plans are rejected.</summary>
</bill>
