<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB71A7F3791F04AFFA3C228A9D535E910" public-private="public"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HR 3300 RH: FEMA Reauthorization Act of 2013</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code>
<calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 563</calendar>
<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num>H. R. 3300</legis-num>
<associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 113–732, Part I]</associated-doc>
<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action>
<action-date date="20131022">October 22, 2013</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001154">Mr. Shuster</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000011">Mr. Rahall</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001269">Mr. Barletta</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson of Indiana</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00" added-display-style="italic" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<action>
<action-date date="20150102">January 2, 2015</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported with an amendment and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name> for a period ending not later than January 2, 2015, for consideration of such provisions of the bill and amendment as fall within the jurisdiction of that committee pursuant to clause 1(j) of rule X</action-desc>
<action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction> 
</action>
<action>
<action-date date="20150102">January 2, 2015</action-date>
<action-desc>The <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc>
<action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on October 22, 2013</action-instruction>
</action>
<action display="yes">
<action-desc display="yes"><pagebreak/></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To reauthorize the programs and activities of the Federal Emergency Management Agency.<pagebreak/></official-title>
</form>
<legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HPW00" reported-display-style="italic" id="H4A730B5A9F1D47638276F741BE3E9369">
<section id="HDE4B69D8DFD348F184A5BB1790930FC3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>FEMA Reauthorization Act of 2013</short-title></quote>.</text></section>
<title id="HEB8459B53CBF44748133CF22BBAEE284"><enum>I</enum><header>Reauthorization of FEMA and Modernization of Integrated Public Alert and Warning System</header>
<section id="H32198565B43E4F13A9B6E5EFBFA26990"><enum>101.</enum><header>Reauthorization of Federal Emergency Management Agency</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 699 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/295">Public Law 109–295</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/811">6 U.S.C. 811</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H5F8A5E341E4847E4A095AC0380092FA7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote><short-title>administration and operations</short-title></quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote><short-title>management and administration</short-title></quote>;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4B1A8942DB52489F92007BF8B2EE41D8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2) by striking <quote><short-title>and</short-title></quote>;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF6D710890763435888F1FEA277B31F0F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (3) by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote><short-title>; and</short-title></quote>; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF443181733154C5E9764DD1574E89E27"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="HAD7F8534C38644ADAC15147665510865" style="OLC">
<paragraph id="H3350299907974C59BEDC7A330F286BAB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>for fiscal year 2014, $972,145,000;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H788D73693CC144528D4B1A1CFE86BC73"><enum>(5)</enum><text>for fiscal year 2015, $972,145,000; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6481B65F43CB44CDB7E4FB8654FC0548"><enum>(6)</enum><text>for fiscal year 2016, $972,145,000.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section>
<section id="H6012DFE856394681895D6A1FC1857E2E"><enum>102.</enum><header>Integrated public alert and warning system modernization</header>
<subsection id="H6EC55B1D9B3E42FF909A329443692DB4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text>This section may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Integrated Public Alert and Warning System Modernization Act of 2013</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H6AF3EC1433424393A6692B4D4E959713"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Integrated public alert and warning system modernization</header>
<paragraph id="H7A693628FF594161AF9BC61997047C79"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To provide timely and effective disaster warnings under this section, the President, acting through the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, shall—</text>
<subparagraph id="HF2FDA9CBA92C439293FAB0CF36CB7612"><enum>(A)</enum><text>modernize the integrated public alert and warning system of the United States (in this section referred to as the <term>public alert and warning system</term>) to ensure that the President under all conditions is able to alert and warn governmental authorities and the civilian population in areas endangered by disasters; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H964802EE72444C47BDE47287A12447E3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>implement the public alert and warning system.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H12DB4905164A4E62894D9DA94272B4F6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Implementation requirements</header><text>In carrying out paragraph (1), the Administrator shall, consistent with the recommendations in the final report of the Integrated Public Alert and Warning System Advisory Committee (established under subsection (c))—</text>
<subparagraph id="HDF0964A69C65429BB1CB155DE402F286"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establish or adopt, as appropriate, common alerting and warning protocols, standards, terminology, and operating procedures for the public alert and warning system;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H76F01E608A5B4114829F746631D5C584"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include in the public alert and warning system the capability to adapt the distribution and content of communications on the basis of geographic location, risks, or personal user preferences, as appropriate;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H97CD9200D3CC4AC1BA34AD98561A92C7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>include in the public alert and warning system the capability to alert and warn, and provide the equivalent amount of information to individuals with disabilities and individuals with access and functional needs;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2FB9BF5716FE4D05A789BBEC26DE9FFF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>ensure that training, tests, and exercises are conducted for the public alert and warning system and that the system is incorporated into other training and exercise programs of the Department of Homeland Security, as appropriate;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H562699D2C648460D928F5B4A2E44F476"><enum>(E)</enum><text>establish and integrate into the National Incident Management System a comprehensive and periodic training program to instruct and educate Federal, State, tribal, and local government officials in the use of the Common Alerting Protocol enabled Emergency Alert System;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H70F52171B9D74AE89947D3682F9B7DAE"><enum>(F)</enum><text>conduct, at least once every 3 years, periodic nationwide tests of the public alert and warning system; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE483021259884E0DAABF3EB1DA7E72EE"><enum>(G)</enum><text>ensure that the public alert and warning system is resilient, secure, and can withstand acts of terrorism and other external attacks.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE15E1DA5D51541E1AFED7CBE64D11ED2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>System requirements</header><text>The public alert and warning system shall—</text>
<subparagraph id="H1804425C492B4FD7BF2B3B4AF050EAA1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>incorporate multiple communications technologies;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD89FE6511ED342CF8AD22D118F1AAE39"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be designed to adapt to, and incorporate, future technologies for communicating directly with the public;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H87DDA493EA744BB1A357AFA7562DDC59"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to the extent technically feasible, be designed to provide alerts to the largest portion of the affected population, including nonresident visitors and tourists and individuals with disabilities and access and functional needs, and improve the ability of remote areas to receive alerts;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HED7C52C17BD84D808A3FD5035015D4C3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>promote local and regional public and private partnerships to enhance community preparedness and response;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6CAD2F1761B04F69B5BC37CADAB1D670"><enum>(E)</enum><text>provide redundant alert mechanisms if practicable so as to reach the greatest number of people regardless of whether they have access to, or utilize, any specific medium of communication or any particular device; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HDA08B07B18AA4644B183856BF9B13BE9"><enum>(F)</enum><text>include a mechanism to ensure the protection of individual privacy.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H76C4F2D87BDB4E3AA0685835BCF671E9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Implementation plan</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of submission of the report of the Integrated Public Alert and Warning System Advisory Committee, the Administrator shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure and the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a detailed plan to implement the public alert and warning system. The plan shall include a timeline for implementation, a spending plan, and recommendations for any additional authority that may be necessary to fully implement this subsection.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HAC62B423B2A04918A22D583907179B89"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Maximum funds</header><text>The Administrator may use not more than $12,733,000 of the amount made available pursuant to section 699 of the Post-Katrina Emergency Management Reform Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/811">6 U.S.C. 811</external-xref>) for each of fiscal years 2014, 2015, and 2016 to carry out the provisions of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H51B178EEFE2C4B598AF38C2726BCABE2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Integrated public alert and warning system advisory committee</header>
<paragraph id="HC3B66C0D234A445FB600C10FD9102FE0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall establish an advisory committee to be known as the Integrated Public Alert and Warning System Advisory Committee (in this subsection referred to as the <term>Advisory Committee</term>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCA4BC09C6CFF4725B9FF86F75950F699"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The Advisory Committee shall be composed of the following members (or their designees) to be appointed by the Administrator as soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act:</text>
<subparagraph id="H87AF03F567564D3E8FBC4830D9921205"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Chairman of the Federal Communications Commission.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HCD9124666BAA477BAA138F6284405DF0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration of the Department of Commerce.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HBB61666ADC0B43DB88D8BF3B9A028FCE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Assistant Secretary for Communications and Information of the Department of Commerce.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H0A318F961E6B4FE2AA609E0B594C9AE1" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Office of Disability Integration and Coordination of the Federal Emergency Management Agency.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7343F116DC3C45AAB9690C47B181FFC2"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Representatives of State and local governments, representatives of emergency management agencies, and representatives of emergency response providers, selected from among individuals nominated by national organizations representing governments and personnel.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF273D2F679684C8F9E946559D7D259FE"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Representatives from federally recognized Indian tribes and national Indian organizations.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC28392063B224FBE90A15AADD43F2D21"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Individuals who have the requisite technical knowledge and expertise to serve on the Advisory Committee, including representatives of—</text>
<clause id="H7D22615753ED43A29694A10CEBC72F16"><enum>(i)</enum><text>communications service providers;</text></clause>
<clause id="HCA14C494EA794EA7B7EF616AA1FED81D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>vendors, developers, and manufacturers of systems, facilities, equipment, and capabilities for the provision of communications services;</text></clause>
<clause id="H7CF1444106F84D09B0C478A0A3751AA1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>third-party service bureaus;</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" id="H4A49C78BFC6D4450BDE54AE3F9BCED04"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the broadcasting industry, including commercial and noncommercial radio and television stations;</text></clause>
<clause id="H85F034F7637F432091BD1DE45FB01D20"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the commercial mobile radio service industry;</text></clause>
<clause id="HB24E5D82E3664B16B6D8F9DB871ECB1B"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the cable industry;</text></clause>
<clause id="H51F4C99002474F458096B07D3C1A9DAA"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the satellite industry; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H14F91632B7CA4979BFA204BD24CC4769"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>national organizations representing individuals with disabilities and access and functional needs and national organizations representing the elderly.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H89B14B5A74954F1EB727B13E46CAE9F5"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Qualified representatives of such other stakeholders and interested and affected parties as the Administrator considers appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE55050DAD09743F7ACA87B20C5D2FEA9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Chairperson</header><text>The Administrator shall serve as the Chairperson of the Advisory Committee.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9817EDAA580B4D80965FAC72C59911C3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Meetings</header>
<subparagraph id="HE663944A94E84084A6F4764DBFAFC322"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Initial meeting</header><text>The initial meeting of the Advisory Committee shall take place not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H535A9DCB0118487D8B8604D5D0A4072F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Other meetings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After the initial meeting, the Advisory Committee shall meet, at least annually, at the call of the Chairperson.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H9CCF93EF983B44B7BB772CD6467D1F04"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Notice; open meetings</header><text>Meetings held by the Advisory Committee shall be duly noticed at least 14 days in advance and shall be open to the public.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD7AAF2D8C04E441D9206DB76945DDA66"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Interested persons</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Interested persons shall be permitted to attend, appear before, or file statements with the Advisory Committee, in accordance with subsection (c) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/552b">section 552b</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4666E606FE644078A361CAC555798881"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Meeting minutes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Advisory Committee shall keep detailed minutes of each meeting, which shall contain a record of the persons present, a complete and accurate description of matters discussed and conclusions reached, and copies of all reports received, issued, or approved by the Advisory Committee.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB796C7FB50C4416CB7D87C22E5CCBDBB"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Availability of information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The records, reports, transcripts, minutes, appendixes, working papers, drafts, studies, agenda, or other documents which were made available to or prepared for or by the Advisory Committee shall be available for public inspection and copying, subject to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/552">section 552</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, at a single location in the office of FEMA until the Advisory Committee ceases to exist.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7763F8749930422C86037DD1D2811CA0"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Rules</header>
<subparagraph id="HABCC0D84753A4D2A8A0DE42BE172869A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Quorum</header><text>One-third of the members of the Advisory Committee shall constitute a quorum for conducting business of the Advisory Committee.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H09BAB5472C694E218C0495B2E6BE92DC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Subcommittees</header><text>To assist the Advisory Committee in carrying out its functions, the Chairperson may establish appropriate subcommittees composed of members of the Advisory Committee and other subject matter experts as the Chairperson considers necessary.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HFECF06B54FD74055930479DEE66CD51B"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Additional rules</header><text>The Advisory Committee may adopt such other rules as are necessary to carry out its duties.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H027B18085B674A0EA0DC4080567BABD5"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Consultation with nonmembers</header><text>The Advisory Committee and the program offices for the integrated public alert and warning system for the United States shall regularly meet with groups that are not represented on the Advisory Committee to consider new and developing technologies that may be beneficial to the public alert and warning system. Such groups may include—</text>
<subparagraph id="HAB57712143DC44DB983845290A653C49"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB99B2B59AA0042A3963986E454A78F6A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>entities engaged in federally funded research; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6B8446D4CCD046FCBBF928DC35380AAB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>academic institutions engaged in relevant work and research.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H522755E97B1D4887B7B73B6163680BF7"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Recommendations</header><text>The Advisory Committee shall develop recommendations for an integrated public alert and warning system, including—</text>
<subparagraph id="HAE64CC927E504674A6455F049EE1D00B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>recommendations for common alerting and warning protocols, standards, terminology, and operating procedures for the public alert and warning system; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H69A9F194485347FBA21CFFC539914A16"><enum>(B)</enum><text>recommendations to provide for a public alert and warning system that—</text>
<clause id="H1493FB15F2914A5187EAC4806E9DD805"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has the capability to adapt the distribution and content of communications on the basis of geographic location, risks, or personal user preferences, as appropriate;</text></clause>
<clause id="H2256651CE4F04C49A9A5C2EFD59995AB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has the capability to alert and warn individuals with disabilities and individuals with limited English proficiency;</text></clause>
<clause id="H2B233AA673A94FA3AAB3973BE0B4DA87"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>incorporates multiple communications technologies;</text></clause>
<clause id="HFF59DFA4AEB742F2A612C1C58EA7FF2D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>is designed to adapt to, and incorporate, future technologies for communicating directly with the public;</text></clause>
<clause id="HDBE10179966C4BDB809DCAEAF1555A94"><enum>(v)</enum><text>is designed to provide alerts to the largest portion of the affected population feasible, including nonresident visitors and tourists, and improve the ability of remote areas to receive alerts;</text></clause>
<clause id="H6603529C98844F168006EAA4A3E4286F"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>promotes local and regional public and private partnerships to enhance community preparedness and response; </text></clause>
<clause id="H4C00C11B1985492B8568689F8E4AACB6"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>provides redundant alert mechanisms if practicable in order to reach the greatest number of people regardless of whether they have access to, or utilize, any specific medium of communication or any particular device; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H31A338B30EBE41AEBFA6C37A49D4D677"><enum>(viii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">promotes the participation of representatives from traditionally underserved and underrepresented communities, to ensure that alerts and warnings reach such populations.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H731FCD121678492C91165619A4D9746C"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Initial and annual report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Advisory Committee shall submit to the Administrator, the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure and the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report containing the recommendations of the Advisory Committee.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB3FA074FCACA4F948EABBE6F2C7B69D2"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Federal advisory committee act</header><text>Neither the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.) nor any rule, order, or regulation promulgated under that Act shall apply to the Advisory Committee.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2251AC44C7F640C78F5AE8C64BB71B3C"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The Advisory Committee shall terminate not later than 6 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" id="H7DC99B02CE1F402C83C5917A2C3AE9E8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation on statutory construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to authorize or require FEMA or any other government entity to require any action on the part of the Federal Communications Commission, the Department of Commerce, the Office of Emergency Communications, or any other nongovernment entity nor impact any existing obligations of these entities.</text></subsection></section></title>
<title id="H3BB5AB18C8244F92B518D2DC5B34D84B"><enum>II</enum><header>Stafford Act and Other Programs</header>
<section id="HF8EA113147DA44AAA1B83EC5E475521E"><enum>201.</enum><header>Reauthorization of urban search and rescue response system</header>
<subsection id="H0B3C0F8AAD824D759C73C46F5EC5249E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Title III of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5141">42 U.S.C. 5141 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="H91A4A02AE38C4FA5980CE48A578A8FB7" style="OLC">
<section id="H3E463A3047C84AA9A3E14C39601F82D3"><enum>327.</enum><header>National urban search and rescue response system</header>
<subsection id="H6B34AE7913424CBCAE7C5C9710E0A8EF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section, the following definitions apply:</text>
<paragraph id="HD3E242B6E48349DCBD19B95C343DBC9C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H45E367651B4A41168FD2BC8FFB0C1D9C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Agency</header><text>The term <term>Agency</term> means the Federal Emergency Management Agency.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA2BF39E5145F443696900DF77B421DE1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Hazard</header><text>The term <term>hazard</term> has the meaning given that term by section 602.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H43DFA49B88F348999F73BE95FC50D8ED"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Nonemployee system member</header><text>The term <term>nonemployee System member</term> means a System member not employed by a sponsoring agency or participating agency.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H68D58B156AA943589A81D20099F671FB"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Participating agency</header><text>The term <term>participating agency</term> means a State or local government, nonprofit organization, or private organization that has executed an agreement with a sponsoring agency to participate in the System.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF9C4A50FB73E41FCB67E131542228A79"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Sponsoring agency</header><text>The term <term>sponsoring agency</term> means a State or local government that is the sponsor of a task force designated by the Administrator to participate in the System.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2B1402BBB6AA4F02B56A400AED40D9D0"><enum>(7)</enum><header>System</header><text>The term <term>System</term> means the National Urban Search and Rescue Response System to be administered under this section.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H094AC8C46E854F0B904D808C042D73C0"><enum>(8)</enum><header>System member</header><text>The term <term>System member</term> means an individual who is not a full-time employee of the Federal Government and who serves on a task force or on a System management or other technical team.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H866F130E84064116A4A82A343706FCDF"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Task force</header><text>The term <term>task force</term> means an urban search and rescue team designated by the Administrator to participate in the System.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H74036EFA6FF44CA29D03A198CC1EECCB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>General authority</header><text>Subject to the requirements of this section, the Administrator shall continue to administer the emergency response system known as the National Urban Search and Rescue Response System.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HA804E1BDDDC749078F72500E5749557A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Functions</header><text>In administering the System, the Administrator shall provide for a national network of standardized search and rescue resources to assist States and local governments in responding to hazards.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HCB9B2FF386E541CFA213D7B7BFC8AEEB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Task forces</header>
<paragraph id="H6CB33BDF04724B91BD801F6AADF13218"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>The Administrator shall designate task forces to participate in the System. The Administrator shall determine the criteria for such participation.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H186DA2E345534B248721EE0EE422B14D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sponsoring agencies</header><text>Each task force shall have a sponsoring agency. The Administrator shall enter into an agreement with the sponsoring agency with respect to the participation of each task force in the System.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF6AEDDE63D85403DAE4D373748984653"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Composition</header>
<subparagraph id="HAB74AFA622B4464BA835581687B62227"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Participating agencies</header><text>A task force may include, at the discretion of the sponsoring agency, one or more participating agencies. The sponsoring agency shall enter into an agreement with each participating agency with respect to the participation of the participating agency on the task force.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2B0FE017C9C1441896A46DB1C365866B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Other individuals</header><text>A task force may also include, at the discretion of the sponsoring agency, other individuals not otherwise associated with the sponsoring agency or a participating agency. The sponsoring agency of a task force may enter into a separate agreement with each such individual with respect to the participation of the individual on the task force.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HBF950D8AF3514DE9811CB81F102DAECD"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Management and technical teams</header><text>The Administrator shall maintain such management teams and other technical teams as the Administrator determines are necessary to administer the System.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H511D4FAB3F2C423394F6495F997441AD"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Appointment of system members into federal service</header>
<paragraph id="HA97A6F2B7E8E46DB813A8ABF141ECC10"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator may appoint a System member into Federal service for a period of service to provide for the participation of the System member in exercises, preincident staging, major disaster and emergency response activities, and training events sponsored or sanctioned by the Administrator.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8ACCC9B6C732440F90A8B9C1DD396EFF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Nonapplicability of certain civil service laws</header><text>The Administrator may make appointments under paragraph (1) without regard to the provisions of title 5, United States Code, governing appointments in the competitive service.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H666C2B8A51C1446E8DA99FBBCDDE2E1D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Relationship to other authorities</header><text>The authority of the Administrator to make appointments under this subsection shall not affect any other authority of the Administrator under this Act.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC4FD0726AC854413A1A01F885E7FA866"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>A System member who is appointed into Federal service under paragraph (1) shall not be considered an employee of the United States for purposes other than those specifically set forth in this section.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H441FCA814E5E45FBAFAE2479208C2C33"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Compensation</header>
<paragraph id="H161A464DD2624834B7E2C70D6F292EBA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Pay of system members</header><text>Subject to such terms and conditions as the Administrator may impose by regulation, the Administrator shall make payments to the sponsoring agency of a task force—</text>
<subparagraph id="HE217B972948242A69D723299C157A780"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to reimburse each employer of a System member on the task force for compensation paid by the employer to the System member for any period during which the System member is appointed into Federal service under subsection (f)(1); and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE7EF231D94174C04AA4C12A3D6BD5C78"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to make payments directly to a nonemployee System member on the task force for any period during which the non-employee System member is appointed into Federal service under subsection (f)(1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC46D0A258D15489DB183AF35755DDB0C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reimbursement for employees filling positions of system members</header>
<subparagraph id="H94F4B16CB7F14EB4B35D2F5D95E70FEE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to such terms and conditions as the Administrator may impose by regulation, the Administrator shall make payments to the sponsoring agency of a task force to reimburse each employer of a System member on the task force for compensation paid by the employer to an employee filling a position normally filled by the System member for any period during which the System member is appointed into Federal service under subsection (f)(1).</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2681F99063FF41FFB61AD97B62A9A468"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Costs incurred by an employer shall be eligible for reimbursement under subparagraph (A) only to the extent that the costs are in excess of the costs that would have been incurred by the employer had the System member not been appointed into Federal service under subsection (f)(1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEAE3CE453D524AC4AF4C271E9360FFC8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Method of payment</header><text>A System member shall not be entitled to pay directly from the Agency for a period during which the System member is appointed into Federal service under subsection (f)(1).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HAEFBFDA4D79343FDB09678374D8C52A4"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Personal injury, illness, disability, or death</header>
<paragraph id="H19D670D5289648E4B2F2B257D9444149"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A System member who is appointed into Federal service under subsection (f)(1) and who suffers personal injury, illness, disability, or death as a result of a personal injury sustained while acting in the scope of such appointment shall, for the purposes of subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/81">chapter 81</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, be treated as though the member were an employee (as defined by section 8101 of that title) who had sustained the injury in the performance of duty.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H59638301BAF0494F8FF68AB5FA07F5B0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Election of benefits</header>
<subparagraph id="H7B074B4FA1A4466F9A505B3AC09B3B95"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If a System member (or, in the case of the death of the System member, the System member’s dependent) is entitled—</text>
<clause id="HF044448ABCF546D4B2B264CF08AB8D32"><enum>(i)</enum><text>under paragraph (1) to receive benefits under subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/81">chapter 81</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, by reason of personal injury, illness, disability, or death, and</text></clause>
<clause id="HA1185E9CBBA649EB810CB0AA03CE75B5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to receive benefits from a State or local government by reason of the same personal injury, illness, disability, or death,</text></clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">the System member or dependent shall elect to receive either the benefits referred to in clause (i) or (ii).</continuation-text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF47C0F93A58843DBBCF962FDA9C98AC1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text>A System member or dependent shall make an election of benefits under subparagraph (A) not later than 1 year after the date of the personal injury, illness, disability, or death that is the reason for the benefits or until such later date as the Secretary of Labor may allow for reasonable cause shown.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H99F8AF09AE9940B89F047812E2EB6B9C"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Effect of election</header><text>An election of benefits made under this paragraph is irrevocable unless otherwise provided by law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H765E638CAEB54DEEB304951A78AB4432"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reimbursement for state or local benefits</header><text>Subject to such terms and conditions as the Administrator may impose by regulation, in the event that a System member or dependent elects benefits from a State or local government under paragraph (2)(A), the Administrator shall reimburse the State or local government for the value of those benefits.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H16117EA0C3654BD189C9A2FD171864C3"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Liability</header><text>A System member appointed into Federal service under subsection (f)(1), while acting within the scope of the appointment, is deemed an employee of the Federal Government under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/28/1346">section 1346(b)</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, and chapter 171 of that title, relating to tort claims procedure.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H63CE71FFF9B44FEDB3F27FB42E7F94F0"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Employment and reemployment rights</header><text>With respect to a System member who is not a regular full-time employee of a sponsoring agency or participating agency, the following terms and conditions apply:</text>
<paragraph id="H2CA8FEE559864878A730214E2D109FB2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Service</header><text>Service as a System member is deemed <term>service in the uniformed services</term> for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/43">chapter 43</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, relating to employment and reemployment rights of individuals who have performed service in the uniformed services (regardless of whether the individual receives compensation for such participation). All rights and obligations of such persons and procedures for assistance, enforcement, and investigation shall be as provided for in such chapter.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB2DE0BF4D2944847B8F0720613AB4BD4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Preclusion</header><text>Preclusion of giving notice of service by necessity of appointment under this section is deemed preclusion by <term>military necessity</term> for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/4312">section 4312(b)</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, pertaining to giving notice of absence from a position of employment. A determination of such necessity shall be made by the Administrator and shall not be subject to judicial review.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HE71D95093A654A3E989922577F45BA17"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Licenses and permits</header><text>If a System member holds a valid license, certificate, or other permit issued by any State or other governmental jurisdiction evidencing the member’s qualifications in any professional, mechanical, or other skill or type of assistance required by the System, the System member is deemed to be performing a Federal activity when rendering aid involving such skill or assistance during a period of appointment into Federal service under subsection (f)(1).</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H97AA7E67C2F1444898B578B22D036470"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Advisory committee</header>
<paragraph id="HF44092B515864C9B93E9B146325DAEA1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall establish and maintain an advisory committee to provide expert recommendations to the Administrator in order to assist the Administrator in administering the System.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H106724BE1D5E4909B82811BB1C138376"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Composition</header><text>The advisory committee shall be composed of members from geographically diverse areas, and shall include—</text>
<subparagraph id="H8D4010A1711E456497A6C9FA33EC1C01"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the chief officer or senior executive from at least three sponsoring agencies;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF441B78CAB5C4802A6F4C2E9B35B3424"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the senior emergency manager from at least two States that include sponsoring agencies; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA749C978DC314B86BBD7140A13EFB6C5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>at least one representative recommended by the leaders of the task forces.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDEB896B7B06846329B1CE009D16B0D27"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Inapplicability of termination requirement</header><text>Section 14(a)(2) of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.) shall not apply to the advisory committee under this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H823E3BD95F2F41D9A68D92A4F28FC13F"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Preparedness cooperative agreements</header>
<paragraph id="H051C4DBD7A344565BA632AC1C1546F55"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to the availability of appropriations for such purpose, the Administrator shall enter into an annual preparedness cooperative agreement with each sponsoring agency. Amounts made available to a sponsoring agency under such a preparedness cooperative agreement shall be for the following purposes:</text>
<subparagraph id="H4525614467994FF6ACC01C494B00C6E5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Training and exercises, including training and exercises with other Federal, State, and local government response entities.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF5BC3FFE0EBA4026B889A9FDF970B723"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Acquisition and maintenance of equipment, including interoperable communications and personal protective equipment.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H5FA5F6823F7349BCAF123F2B112825A1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Medical monitoring required for responder safety and health in anticipation of and following a major disaster, emergency, or other hazard, as determined by the Administrator.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF5B6B56F4C5A448486A3E3D4AAD59E95"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Availability of Appropriations</header><text>Notwithstanding <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/1552">section 1552(b)</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code, amounts made available for cooperative agreements under this subsection that are not expended shall be deposited in an agency account and shall remain available for such agreements without fiscal year limitation.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HC5D66A037F38425D98FFC5FF252733E1"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Response cooperative agreements</header><text>The Administrator shall enter into a response cooperative agreement with each sponsoring agency, as appropriate, under which the Administrator agrees to reimburse the sponsoring agency for costs incurred by the sponsoring agency in responding to a major disaster or emergency.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H00F382B2967647F995EA680C8BB1A985"><enum>(o)</enum><header>Obligations</header><text>The Administrator may incur all necessary obligations consistent with this section in order to ensure the effectiveness of the System.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H1A041F7B508E4B10B893819A71FDA77A"><enum>(p)</enum><header>Authorization of Appropriations</header>
<paragraph id="H460D0D36FFBC45B498D5CD11BC59168E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out the System and the provisions of this section $35,180,000 for each of fiscal years 2014, 2015, and 2016.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCAEEEF4FC9DD415B94AC5700EADBA4D3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administrative expenses</header><text>The Administrator may use not to exceed 6 percent of the funds appropriated for a fiscal year pursuant to paragraph (1) for salaries, expenses, and other administrative costs incurred by the Administrator in carrying out this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="H45BAFFFB147D4DCCA282061D35406A09"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header>
<paragraph id="H09F25B7EB3AF42F0A9124156658E8A0E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Applicability of title 5, united states code</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/8101">Section 8101(1)</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text>
<subparagraph id="HAC3B77EE64314D09B3E0C0D6CFE16605"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D) by striking <quote><short-title>and</short-title></quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB6649928827144188165754700F4A61B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by moving subparagraph (F) to appear after subparagraph (E);</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HCB935C3D4BF6419692B0766A6977ADCE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subparagraph (F)—</text>
<clause id="HADDA570538FC4729808C5200B3ABCE8F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote><short-title>United States Code,</short-title></quote>; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H86B367C555AC4C66809679F6B06B2A69"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by adding <quote><short-title>and</short-title></quote> at the end; and</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2D6658691E8F42F9998C6DC54C899356"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (F) the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="HAADDEB1CC9144C419DEEFBC483E007E3" style="OLC">
<subparagraph id="H2F2D3AB5BB604BDDB990D453C3730F9E"><enum>(G)</enum><text>an individual who is a System member of the National Urban Search and Rescue Response System during a period of appointment into Federal service pursuant to section 327 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5D4A979E5DC54D96B93FA80C1FFCA6DD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inclusion as part of uniformed services for purposes of USERRA</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/4303">Section 4303</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text>
<subparagraph id="HBC1200A4D1A14B7BBF17DF53A47C56B4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (13) by inserting <quote><short-title>, a period for which a System member of the National Urban Search and Rescue Response System is absent from a position of employment due to an appointment into Federal service under section 327 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act</short-title></quote> before <quote><short-title>, and a period</short-title></quote>; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H265A3A614E874EED924A86156B1D626E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (16) by inserting after <quote><short-title>Public Health Service,</short-title></quote> the following: <quote><short-title>System members of the National Urban Search and Rescue Response System during a period of appointment into Federal service under section 327 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act,</short-title></quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H1C89D00F21FC4AB9A6018662691B1BC4" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>202.</enum><header>Eligibility of public broadcasting facilities for certain disaster assistance</header>
<subsection id="HE5F73DA5D2EE4470A92CA82F51F2912A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Private nonprofit facility defined</header><text>Section 102(11)(B) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5122">42 U.S.C. 5122(11)(B)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>public broadcasting facilities,</quote> after <quote>workshops,</quote>.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HE449985E586F495DB5BD148DD5636A57"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Critical services defined</header><text>Section 406(a)(3)(B) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5172">42 U.S.C. 5172(a)(3)(B)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>communications,</quote> and inserting <quote>communications (including public broadcasting),</quote>.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="HCAB54F45ACEF4A88AF88A70AD11E7CA9"><enum>203.</enum><header>Federal disaster assistance nonprofit fairness</header>
<subsection id="H7BB2DFA43F4B4E53BF5866B748D3A600"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition of private nonprofit facility</header><text>Section 102(10)(B) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5122">42 U.S.C. 5122(10)(B)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
<quoted-block id="HE89DA8C5A5E64733AF9AE10D094B7C8B" style="OLC">
<subparagraph id="HDB4F36A506D84A8898D128727B9251DE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Additional facilities</header><text>In addition to the facilities described in subparagraph (A), the term <quote>private nonprofit facility</quote> includes any private nonprofit facility that provides essential services of a governmental nature to the general public (including museums, zoos, performing arts facilities, community arts centers, community centers, including houses of worship exempt from taxation under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, libraries, homeless shelters, senior citizen centers, rehabilitation facilities, shelter workshops, and facilities that provide health and safety services of a governmental nature), as defined by the President.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="H584ECC3113674377A0DDD1E222CCE1B5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Repair, restoration, and replacement of damaged facilities</header><text>Section 406(a)(3) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5172">42 U.S.C. 5172(a)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="H0FE57E78BF1A41AFAE257CDFEEF25915" style="OLC">
<subparagraph id="H9D2D3CF370E041CDB3B8399D6CE10070"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Nonprofit fairness</header><text>A church, synagogue, mosque, temple, or other house of worship, and a private nonprofit facility operated by a religious organization, shall be eligible for contributions under paragraph (1)(B), without regard to the religious character of the facility or the primary religious use of the facility.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="HEE31FB1F2061409292E466D8794C3755"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>This section and the amendments made by this section shall apply to the provision of assistance in response to a major disaster or emergency declared on or after October 28, 2012.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="H24058012087C4D7BB23528C331B4EB8C"><enum>204.</enum><header>Reauthorization of emergency management assistance compact grants</header>
<subsection id="H4ABAFE7573754E4E938DD6C69B74EB7F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subtitle A of title VI of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5196">42 U.S.C. 5196 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="HC66986F084B9405BA330D6119CA5DC6F" style="OLC">
<section id="HCB9A2B885A3741EE822C2C0ADD872AE0"><enum>617.</enum><header>Emergency management assistance compact grants</header>
<subsection id="HC61C12DE51444650937CA1F46A36AB15"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency may make grants to provide for implementation of the Emergency Management Assistance Compact consented to by Congress in the joint resolution entitled <quote><short-title>Joint resolution granting the consent of Congress to the Emergency Management Assistance Compact</short-title></quote> (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/321">Public Law 104–321</external-xref>; 110 Stat. 3877).</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H48E89BE812FF41A2B28802F6C3DDB97B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible grant recipients</header><text>States and the Administrator of the Emergency Management Assistance Compact shall be eligible to receive grants under subsection (a).</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HAEC5BA37C7E54A65B222C934EE4E6CC1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>A grant received under this section shall be used—</text>
<paragraph id="H640ECF706B8D4B4187D802C5D92E7F2F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to carry out recommendations identified in the Emergency Management Assistance Compact after-action reports for the 2004 and 2005 hurricane seasons;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7B9F75FC593F48438BC677AFA41BDEBC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to administer compact operations on behalf of States, as such term is defined in the compact, that have enacted the compact;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2A8B360A96744EE4AA0412093B40A9DE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to continue coordination with the Federal Emergency Management Agency and appropriate Federal agencies;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF58F826C857243E49FB01E433B20C2EB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to continue coordination with States and local governments and their respective national organizations; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF4B6630C2B0B420E8633351AB27FF017"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to assist State and local governments, emergency response providers, and organizations representing such providers with credentialing the providers and the typing of emergency response resources.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H6E5218CFD6474EC9898054C3E961200A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>The Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall consult with the Administrator of the Emergency Management Assistance Compact to ensure effective coordination of efforts in responding to requests for assistance.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HF912B6C87A9F41AFABEE174BB3C9DDD8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of Appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $2,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2014, 2015, and 2016. Such sums shall remain available until expended.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="HF4F9D286BADC47359A46C40878B7D0CE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Repeal</header><text>Section 661 of the Post-Katrina Emergency Management Reform Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/761">6 U.S.C. 761</external-xref>) is repealed.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="HAA0BB27BD0E043EFACA51FB8E7F8D379"><enum>205.</enum><header>Physical testing standards for electric utility facilities</header>
<subsection id="H22A11DA9FFA54E21BEE90E3E99C38224"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall conduct a study to compare the differences between—</text>
<paragraph id="HA0841D0AF3FD43BD99F4D71DC2449BEC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the physical testing standards that the Administrator applies with respect to electric utility facilities as a condition for Federal assistance; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0AEB7086786E4B12A0EB80F88423B197"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the physical testing standards that are applied to electric utility facilities by the electric utilities industry and by the Rural Utilities Service of the Department of Agriculture.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H8EEC7DC33308412BBE72218189FD29FB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee of the Senate a report on the results of the study.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HE067D2E678E348AC841F17BBF2538A5C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>The Administrator shall carry out this section using funds available to the Administrator for management and expenses.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="HE9B4213A7E6747A78EDE65D72CC2B3F4"><enum>206.</enum><header>Review and report regarding the eligibility of certain housing entities to receive disaster assistance</header>
<subsection id="H9C96DF02905348B194E205BB3B91D659"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) shall, using funds from FEMA’s management and expenses account, complete a review of, and submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives a report describing, options, both commercial and governmental, available to housing cooperatives and condominium associations to assist in repairing and rebuilding common areas following a major disaster. </text></subsection>
<subsection id="H4D4CD86C851840B68C662720DD261B8F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report specifics</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report shall include—</text>
<paragraph id="H0DD4BEB96F5749F18AA0F3B63177EF29"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of the current eligibility of housing cooperative and condominium association owners and residents to receive disaster relief funds under FEMA disaster relief programs;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H593E90662918467C826C1309A9D14E9D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the availability of individual assistance for such owners and residents to help cover the costs of repairing disaster-related damage to common areas, including any details of instances in the past 10 years in which cooperative or condominium owners or residences received such assistance to help cover costs and assessments for repairs to common areas;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF1122EEFB12840BE993DE106D70AF5DA"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of commercial options and requirements, including insurance coverage, that may be applicable; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HFAFC0F0B97CC43AEB985D29E6217D352"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a discussion of options, including any proposed changes to law, for addressing any gaps identified in available assistance to address disaster-related damage to common areas.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H4C57A9FE46E84CE8985F0ABF5E77ED4F"><enum>207.</enum><header>Audit timeframe limitation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall issue a rule that limits the timeframe of any audit conducted under section 318 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5161">42 U.S.C. 5161</external-xref>).</text></section></title>
</legis-body>
<endorsement display="yes">
<action-date date="20150102">January 2, 2015</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported with an amendment and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name> for a period ending not later than January 2, 2015, for consideration of such provisions of the bill and amendment as fall within the jurisdiction of that committee pursuant to clause 1(j) of rule X</action-desc>
<action-date date="20150102">January 2, 2015</action-date>
<action-desc>The <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement>
</bill> 


