<bill session="113" type="h" number="3271" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-10-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2013-10-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-10-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Military and Federal Civilian Employee Pay Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Making continuing appropriations for the compensation of Federal employees and certain military personnel in the event of a Government shutdown, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412191"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-10-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Appropriations, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-07">
      <text>Referred to House Appropriations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-10-07">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/7/2013--Introduced.
Military and Federal Civilian Employee Pay Act - Makes continuing appropriations for FY2014 to provide the pay and allowances of: (1) federal employees, (2) members of the reserve components of the Armed Services who perform inactive duty training during such period, and (3) the commissioned corps of the Public Health Service and the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA). Provides for payment of the pay and allowances of those employees who were furloughed due to a lapse in appropriations that began on or about October 1, 2013, for the period of such lapse in appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
