<bill bill-stage="Enrolled-Bill" dms-id="HE64885EE74F14278B64E0F591A79DB64" public-private="public" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata>
<dublinCore>
<dc:title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"> HR 3375 ENR: To designate the community-based outpatient clinic of the Department of Veterans Affairs to be constructed at 3141 Centennial Boulevard, Colorado Springs, Colorado, as the “PFC Floyd K. Lindstrom Department of Veterans Affairs Clinic”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"/>
<dc:format xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>One Hundred Thirteenth Congress of the United States of America</congress> <session>At the Second Session</session>
    <enrolled-dateline>Begun and held at the City of Washington on Friday, the third day of January, two thousand and fourteen</enrolled-dateline> 
<legis-num>H. R. 3375</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no"/> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To designate the community-based outpatient clinic of the Department of Veterans Affairs to be constructed at 3141 Centennial Boulevard, Colorado Springs, Colorado, as the <quote>PFC Floyd K. Lindstrom Department of Veterans Affairs Clinic</quote>.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H6CC11FE46EEE4F96BB6181378F6934EE" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC786B85FB34D4CACAEE6A096909E6284" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>PFC Floyd K. Lindstrom Department of Veterans Affairs Clinic</header> 
<subsection id="H8CDED47855F144B4B135260775B268EA">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Designation</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The community-based outpatient clinic of the <cato:entity-ref xmlns:cato="http://namespaces.cato.org/catoxml" entity-id="3600" entity-type="federal-body">Department of Veterans Affairs</cato:entity-ref> to be constructed at 3141 Centennial Boulevard, Colorado Springs, Colorado, shall be known and designated as the <quote>PFC Floyd K. Lindstrom Department of Veterans Affairs Clinic</quote>.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H3BAEBC6196AF45BD877700E96984F957">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>References</header>
        <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any reference in a law, regulation, map, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the building referred to in subsection (a) shall be deemed to be a reference to the <quote>PFC Floyd K. Lindstrom Department of Veterans Affairs Clinic</quote>.</text> </subsection>
    </section> 
</legis-body> <attestation>
    <attestation-group>
      <role>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</role>
    </attestation-group>
    <attestation-group>
      <role>Vice President of the United States and President of the Senate.</role>
    </attestation-group>
  </attestation>
</bill>