<bill session="113" type="h" number="2882" updated="2015-09-01T10:19:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-03-05">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-03-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improving Opportunities for Service-Disabled Veteran-Owned Small Businesses Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Small Business Act and title 38, United States Code to provide for a consolidated definition of a small business concern owned and controlled by veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412271"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2013-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412480" joined="2013-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400158" joined="2013-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412454" joined="2013-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412486" joined="2014-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400279" joined="2013-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412527" joined="2014-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412310" joined="2013-08-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Small Business</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-03-05">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2014-03-05" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-12-11T15:42:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Small Business. H. Rept. 113-662, Part I.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR10" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="4435"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="s" number="2334"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/31/2013--Introduced.
Improving Opportunities for Service-Disabled Veteran-Owned Small Businesses Act of 2013 - Amends the Small Business Act to expand the definition of "small business concern owned and controlled by service-disabled veterans" for purposes of federal agencies awarding small business contracts pursuant to Small Business Administration (SBA) programs to include: (1) a small business concern not less than 51% of which is owned by one or more veterans with service-connected disabilities that are permanent and total who are unable to manage the daily business operations of such concern; or (2) in the case of a publicly owned business, a small business concern not less than 51% of the stock of which is owned by one or more such veterans. (Currently, such veterans with permanent and total disabilities are provided for in a separate small business program under veterans' benefits laws carried out by the Department of Veterans Affairs [VA].)

Revises the VA definition of "small business concern owned and controlled by veterans" to be the same as the SBA definition of such term, thereby making the eligibility requirements for participation in veteran-owned small business contracting programs consistent for both SBA programs and VA programs.

Provides that if the death of a service-disabled veteran causes a small business concern to be less than 51% owned by one or more such veterans, the surviving spouse who acquires ownership rights shall be treated as if the surviving spouse were the veteran for the purpose of maintaining the business's status as a small business concern owned and controlled by service-disabled veterans until the earlier of the date on which the surviving spouse either remarries or relinquishes the ownership interest or 10 years after the veteran's death.

Directs the SBA Administrator to enter into a memorandum of understanding with the VA Secretary that transfers from the Secretary to the Administrator control and administration of a required database of veteran-owned businesses.</summary>
</bill>
