<bill session="113" type="s" number="2196" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-04-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-04-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-04-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Good Samaritan Health Professionals Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to limit the liability of health care professionals who volunteer to provide health care services in response to a disaster.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300075"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-04-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="113" type="h" number="1733"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/1/2014--Introduced.
Good Samaritan Health Professionals Act of 2014 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to shield a health care professional from liability under federal or state law for harm caused by any act or omission if: (1) the professional is serving as a volunteer in response to a disaster; and (2) the act or omission occurs during the period of the disaster, in the professional's capacity as such a volunteer, and in a good faith belief that the individual being treated is in need of health care services.

Makes exceptions where: (1) the harm was caused by an act or omission constituting willful or criminal misconduct, gross negligence, reckless misconduct, or a conscious flagrant indifference to the rights or safety of the individual harmed; or (2) the professional rendered the health care services under the influence of intoxicating alcohol or an intoxicating drug.

Declares that, nothing in this Act shall supplant any other provision of federal, state, local, or tribal law that establish liability schemes or liability protections that exceed those provided by this Act, including without limitation the Federal Tort Claims Act.</summary>
</bill>
