<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 SRES 579 ATS: Relative to the death of Howard O. Greene, Jr., former Sergeant at Arms of the United States Senate.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2014-11-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. RES. 579</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20141117">November 17, 2014</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S174">Mr. McConnell</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S198">Mr. Reid</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Relative to the death of Howard O. Greene, Jr., former Sergeant at Arms of the United States
			 Senate.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas><text>Whereas Howard O. Greene, Jr., began his service to the United States Senate as a Doorkeeper in
			 January 1968;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Howard O. Greene, Jr., served the United States Senate as Republican cloakroom assistant,
			 Assistant Secretary for the Minority, Secretary for the Minority, and
			 Secretary for the Majority;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Howard O. Greene, Jr., was elected as Senate Sergeant at Arms during the 104th Congress;
			 and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Howard O. Greene, Jr.'s more than 28 years of service was characterized by a deep and
			 abiding respect for the institution and customs of the Senate: Now,
			 therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body>
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the Senate has heard with profound sorrow and deep regret the announcement of the death of
			 Howard O. Greene, Jr.</text>
		</section></resolution-body>
	<resolution-body><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S2" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Secretary of the Senate communicate these resolutions to the House of Representatives and
			 transmit an enrolled copy thereof to the family of the deceased.</text></section></resolution-body><resolution-body><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S3" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That when the Senate adjourns today, it stand adjourned as a further mark of respect to the memory
			 of Howard O. Greene, Jr.</text></section></resolution-body></resolution>


