<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HDE4F3A90F2B84BC9940C11CE06329C61" key="H" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HR 5893 IH: Ansel Adams Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>113th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>2d Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 5893</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150102">January 2, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000937">Mr. Stockman</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To restore the First Amendment Rights of Photographers.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HDBE1CFA1CB0D47CE94E1CE21FE7716F4" style="OLC">
		<section id="HC9210380EEBE4641969432254E65A3D0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ansel Adams Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="H1FA5538A29314E09B9BFA24D486A0AC7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds as follows:</text>
			<paragraph id="H7D9D2859D71142E199647CDFB9D15510"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In recent years, the Federal Government has enacted regulations to prohibit or restrict photography
			 in National Parks, public spaces, and of government buildings, law
			 enforcement officers, and other government personnel carrying out their
			 duties.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H1AF0777A05C34032A713EABA1C27B7C7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In recent years, photographers on Federal lands and spaces have been threatened with seizure and
			 forfeiture of photographic equipment and memory cards, and have been
			 arrested or threatened with arrest for merely recording what the eye can
			 see from public spaces.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HFDAFBA7C7B3F4BC3A9F061B880AC0C2E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Even in the absence of laws or regulations, Federal law enforcement officers, other government
			 personnel, and private contractors have been instructed to prohibit
			 photography from public spaces, and threatened photographers with arrest
			 or seizure of photographic equipment.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HC630275EFE8E420CBDE4539C810F9295"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Arresting photographers, seizing photographic equipment, and requirements to obtain permits, pay
			 fees, or buy insurance policies are abridgments of freedom of speech and
			 of the press.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H7EF7DE5C0F974B588A9D9AF3B5890D49"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The First Amendment of the United States Constitution states, <quote>Congress shall make no law … abridging the freedom of speech, or of the press.</quote>.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H44FE921BF5864F27AA93E6514E2462B0"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Still and motion photographs are speech.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H28D75C5031214AB2962D9B08E0127D3A"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The photography by Ansel Adams and other famous photographers helped bring home to Americans the
			 beauty and fragility of our natural resources.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H5203C44B41E749BFB4B14EC4827932E4"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Ansel Adams’ photographs helped build public support to make Yosemite into a National Park.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H047C54620A95490D818CFD846AB39747"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Future <quote>Ansel Adams</quote> must not have their paths blocked, regulated and made more expensive with fees and fines, or be
			 threatened with arrest and seizure of their equipment.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H7193BF1CCA5240DD99463CA5A2D22E2F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Restoration of first amendment rights to photographers</header>
			<subsection id="H696FCD7ECA7343329AAE0C3EEDAF6970"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>It is contrary to the public policy of the United States to prohibit or restrict photography in
			 public spaces, whether for private, news media, or commercial use.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H7C0E81D653CC4937B2A10B2C34641E5B"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Should a Federal agency seek to restrict photography of its installations or personnel, it shall
			 obtain a court order that outlines the national security or other reasons
			 for the restriction. Such court order shall allow restrictions of
			 photography when such photography may lead to the endangerment of public
			 safety or national security. Nothing in this Act shall restrict Federal
			 agencies from taking lawful steps to ascertain whether or not photography
			 may consist of reconnaissance for the purpose of endangerment of public
			 safety or national security or for other unlawful activity. Nothing in
			 this Act shall be construed to repeal, invalidate, or supersede section
			 795 of title 18, United States Code.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H0736E7D097C04D978325192F56DC704E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prohibition on fees, permits, or insurance</header><text>No Federal Government agency shall require fees, permits or insurance as a condition to take still
			 or moving images on Federal lands, National Parks and Forests, and public
			 spaces, whether for private, media, or commercial use.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H81654DE5A8B842E8B5E1723988EEB0B6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Prohibition on the seizure and forfeiture of photographic equipment</header><text>Federal law enforcement officers or private contractors shall not seize any photographic equipment
			 or their contents or memory cards or film, and shall not order a
			 photographer to erase the contents of a camera or memory card or film.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H875C319EF9C34EF1B209E9F3BE248B0A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"><term>Photography</term> means any form or method of capturing and recording or transmitting still or moving images.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


