<bill session="113" type="s" number="2536" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SAVE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Advertising Victims of Exploitation Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 18, United States Code, to provide for enhanced criminal and civil remedies in the protection of children and other victims of commercial sexual exploitation and related crimes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400222"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2014-06-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Pornography"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/26/2014--Introduced.
Stop Advertising Victims of Exploitation Act of 2014 or the SAVE Act - Amends the federal criminal code to prohibit: (1) knowingly selling, commercially promoting, placing, or maintaining an adult advertisement (an advertisement designed to induce a commercial exchange for a sexual act or sexual contact, sexually explicit conduct, a commercial sex act, or the goods or services of an adult escort or erotic performer involving such a commercial exchange) in a medium whose predominant purpose is to facilitate commercial transactions; and (2) acting with reckless disregard of the fact that an adult advertisement facilitates an offense of sex trafficking of children or by force, fraud, or coercion in which the victim was under age 18 or an offense in violation of a state law prohibiting felony offenses relating to child pimping, child prostitution, child sexual abuse, assault on children, or the sex trafficking of children.

Shields from liability under such prohibition an Internet access service provider, browser provider, common carrier, telecommunications carrier, or other generic search or utility provider solely based on providing generic search or utility services.

Requires anyone selling, commercially promoting, or placing an adult advertisement to: (1) verify the identity of each person purchasing advertisement space for, and each person depicted in, such advertisement; (2) verify that each person whose goods or services are advertised is not under age 18; (3) create and maintain individually identifiable records pertaining to each such person for at least seven years; and (4) affix to each adult advertisement a statement describing where such records may be located

Sets civil and criminal penalties (including forfeiture) for violations of this Act.

Sets forth increased penalties for failure by an electronic communication service provider or a remote computing service provider to report apparent violations of provisions regarding sexual abuse of children and child pornography, with reckless disregard of the requirement to make such report.</summary>
</bill>
