<bill session="113" type="s" number="2167" updated="2015-09-01T10:22:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-03-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-03-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-03-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Computer Science Career Education Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a grant program for career education in computer science.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412223"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-03-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="113" type="h" number="4929"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/27/2014--Introduced.
Computer Science Career Education Act of 2014 - Directs the Secretary of Education to award competitive grants to consortia composed of at least one local educational agency, at least one institution of higher education (IHE), and community representatives for the development and operation of four- or six-year computer science career education programs.

Requires each program to include the development of computer science programs for both secondary and postsecondary education that:

 are aligned with rigorous computer science standards for kindergarten through grade 12 computer science education; link secondary schools and IHEs through non-duplicative sequences of courses in computer science career fields; use, if appropriate and available, work-based or worksite learning in conjunction with business; use educational technology and distance learning, as appropriate, to involve all members of the consortium more fully in the development and operation of the programs; stay current with business needs, expectations, and methods; and create innovative opportunities for students that lead to student attainment of industry-recognized credentials. Requires each program to also provide: (1) professional development for teachers, (2) career and academic counseling for students, and (3) equal access to the full range of career education programs to members of underrepresented groups and special populations.</summary>
</bill>
