<bill session="113" type="h" number="4958" updated="2015-09-01T10:20:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2014-06-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2014-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2014-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Identify and Recover Sent E-Mails Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide monetary awards to any individual who provides information pertaining to the electronic communications sent by Lois Lerner during her employment at the Internal Revenue Service, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412480"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400651" joined="2014-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412302" joined="2014-07-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2014-06-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Internal Revenue Service (IRS)"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/25/2014--Introduced.
Identify and Recover Sent E-Mails Act - Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to: (1) pay a cash award of $1 million to any individual or group who retrieves and submits to Congress the electronic communications sent by Lois Lerner during her employment with the Internal Revenue Service (IRS), and (2) pay a cash award of $500,000 to any individual or group who provides pertinent information sufficient for the prosecution of individuals involved in any illegal activities with respect to the destruction of the electronic communications sent by Lois Lerner during her employment with IRS. Directs payment of such awards from the IRS Taxpayer Services Account.

Limits the amount of funds that may be obligated for IRS employee salaries in 2014 until the electronic communications sent by Lois Lerner have been recovered and submitted to Congress.</summary>
</bill>
